import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as k,C as b,M as w,U as y,F as p,p as c,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},S={class:"review-content"};function M(e,a,s,d,t,u){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",S,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(k(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const T=g(q,[["render",M],["__scopeId","data-v-a93fc36c"]]),O=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"ጥያቄ፡- የእስልምና አቆጣጠር በየትኛው ዑደት ላይ የተመሰረተ ነው? ","answer":"መልስ፡- በጨረቃ ደት ላይ የተመሰረተ ነው፡፡"},{"question":"จงต่อบทความนี้ให้สมบูรณ์: ในฟุตบอลโกปาอเมริกา ปี2015ที่ชิลีเป็นเจ้าภาพ ใน","answer":"นัดชิงชนะเลิศที่ชิลีพบกับอาร์เจนตินา เมื่อครบ 120 นาที รวมถึงการต่อเวลาพิเศษแล้วก็ยังไม่มีการทำประตูกันได้ จึงต้องยิงลูกจุดโทษตัดสิน ซันเชซเป็นผู้ยิงประตูที่ 4 ให้แก่ชิลี ซันเชซยิงอย่างเนิบๆแบบอันโตนิน ปาเนียกา อดีตนักฟุตบอลชาวเชก ซึ่งเป็นประตูที่ตัดสินให้ชิลีชนะอาร์เจนตินาไปในที่สุด จนได้แชมป์โกปาอาเมริกาเป็นสมัยแรกมาครอง"},{"question":"Sa layo murag motor apan sa duol doktor\\t","answer":"Lamok"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny AKFM?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny AKFM dia :Antokon'ny Kongresin'ny Fahaleovantenan'i Madagasikara."},{"question":"A cikin wanne nau'in ra'ayi za ku rarraba tweet mai zuwa? Mai kyau, Marar kyau, ko tsaka tsaki?cin danko hadda su kaza","answer":"Zan rarraba tweet ɗin da aka bayar a matsayin: Marar kyau"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Được điều động đến các Quốc gia Đất thấp, Model với bộ chỉ huy của ông ta đặt tại Osterbeek gần Arnhem, đã bị bất ngờ vào ngày 17 tháng 9 khi quân Đồng minh bắt đầu Chiến dịch Market Garden","answer":". Cụm tập đoàn quân B tham chiến trong Trận chiến Bulge. Sau đó, nó bị cô lập tại Cái túi Ruhr ở miền Bắc Đức, và sau khi bị chia cắt thành các cụm quân ngày càng nhỏ. Bộ phận cuối cùng của Cụm tập đoàn quân B đã đầu hàng quân Đồng minh vào ngày 21 tháng 4 năm 1945."},{"question":"Vraag: Welk element heeft het symbool \\"Fe\\" in het periodiek systeem? A. Zilver, B. IJzer, C. Goud, D. Koper","answer":"Antwoord: B. IJzer"},{"question":"नेसनल आईसीटी अवार्ड-२०१५","answer":"नेसनल आईसीटी अवार्ड-२०१९ बाट नेपाल प्रहरी सम्मानित भएको । सार्वजनिक सेवा प्रवाहमा सूचना तथा सञ्चार प्रविधिको प्रभावकारी प्रयोगको मूल्यांकनका आधारमा नेपाल प्रहरीले सो अवार्ड प्राप्त गरेको । यसअघि नेपाल प्रहरीले २०७५ भाद्रमा अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय स्तरको डिजिटल गभर्नेन्स अवार्ड प्राप्त गरेको थियो ।"},{"question":"Kañ la nelson Mandelaa faatu ?","answer":"2013."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"misy lela izy kanefa tsy mahatsapa tsiro\\" ? ","answer":"Valiny: antsy. Satria misy lelany ny antsy kanefa tsy afaka mahatsapa tsiro. "},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিতে একটি নিবন্ধ লিখুন :বাংলাদেশের উচ্চ আদালত মোট কতগুলি ভাগে বিভক্ত ?","answer":"সংবিধানের বিধান অনুযায়ী বাংলাদেশ সুপ্রীম কোর্ট-এর দুটি বিভাগ আছেঃ আপীল বিভাগ এবং হাইকোর্ট বিভাগ।সংবিধানের ১০১ ধারায় হাইকোর্টের এখতিয়ার বর্ণিত আছে৤ ১০৩ ধারায় আপীল বিভাগের এখতিয়ার বর্ণিত আছে৤ হাইকোর্ট বিভাগ নিম্ন আদালত এবং ট্রাইবুনাল থেকে আপিল শুনানি করে থাকে। এছাড়াও, বাংলাদেশের সংবিধানের আর্টিকেল ১০২ এর অধীনে রিট আবেদন , এবং কোম্পানী এবং সেনাবিভাগ বিষয় হিসেবে নির্দিষ্ট সীমিত ক্ষেত্রে মূল এখতিয়ার আছে। হাইকোর্ট বিভাগ থেকে আপিল শুনানির এখতিয়ার রয়েছে আপিল বিভাগের।[5][6] সুপ্রিম কোর্টের নির্বাহী শাখার স্বাধীন এবং রাজনৈতিকভাবে বিতর্কিত ক্ষেত্রে সরকারের বিরুদ্ধে আদেশ দিতে পারে।[7]"},{"question":"வினா: நீர் முள்ளிச் செடியின்மருத்துவக் குணங்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக.","answer":"விடை:நீர் முள்ளிச் செடியின்மருத்துவக் குணங்கள்:-நீர் முள்ளி, தமிழர் வாழ்க்கையோடு பிணைந்த ஒரு மூலிகைச்செடி. முண்டகம்,  நிதகம், இக்குரம், காகண்டம், தூரகத மூலம் என்ற பெயர்களில் இலக்கியங்களில் போற்றிப் பாடப்படும். குறுகலான ஈட்டி வடிவத்தில் இலைகளையும் நீலக் கருஞ்சிவப்பு நிறத்தில் மலர்களையும் கணுக்களில் அணில் பற்களைப் போன்ற வெள்ளை நிற முட்களையும் கொண்டது. 60 செ.மீ வரை வளரும். சதுரமான இதன் தண்டுப்பகுதியில் சிறு முடிகள் காணப்படும். பூ ஒரு செ.மீ நீளம் இருக்கும்.விதைகள் கறுமையான காணப்படும்.குத்துச் செடியான இது நீர் நிறைந்த பகுதியில் தானாக வளரக்கூடியது. செப்டம்பர் மற்றும் ஏப்ரல் மாதங்களில் பூக்கும். தமிழகம் எங்கும் காணப்படும் இந்தச் செடி முழுவதும் மருத்துவப் பயனுள்ளது. முக்கியமாக சிறுநீரைப் பெருக்கி வியர்வையை அதிகப்படுத்தி உடலுக்கு ஊட்டம் தரக்கூடியது. வெண்புள்ளி, மேகநீர், சொறி சிரங்கு, சிறுநீர்த் தாரையில் ஏற்படும் எரிச்சல், தலைவலி, காய்ச்சல், மலச்சிக்கல் போன்றவற்றை சரி செய்வதோடு ஆண்மைப் பெருக்கியாகவும் செயல்படுகிறது.நீர் முள்ளியின் சமூலத்தை (முழுச் செடி) கஷாயம் செய்து தினமும் குடித்து வந்தால் உடல் சோர்வு நீங்கி புத்துணர்வு கிடைக்கும். சிறுநீரகக் கல் அடைப்பு உள்ளவர்கள் இந்தக் கஷாயத்தை காலை மாலை என அருந்தி வந்தால்  கல் கரைந்து சிறுநீருடன் வெளியேறி விடும். நீர் முள்ளியுடன் திரிபலாச் சூரணம் சேர்த்து கஷாயம் செய்து குடித்து வந்தால் மலச்சிக்கல் பிரச்னை சரியாகும். வாயுக்களின் சீற்றத்தாலும் செரிமானக் கோளாறுகளாலும் ஏற்படக்கூடிய வயிற்றுப்புண்ணைக் குணப்படுத்த இதன் இலைகளைக் கஷாயம் செய்து குடித்து வந்தால் பலன் கிடைக்கும்.மாதவிலக்குக் கோளாறு உள்ள பெண்களும் வெள்ளைப்படுதலால் அவதிப்படும் பெண்களும் நீர் முள்ளிக் கஷாயத்தைக் குடித்து வந்தால் முழுமையான நிவாரணம் கிடைக்கும். நீர் முள்ளி விதையுடன் முருங்கை விதை, தாமரை விதை, வெங்காய விதை சம அளவு சேர்த்து பாலில் கலந்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் ஆண்மை சக்தி பெருகி தாம்பத்யத்தில் முழு பலன் கிடைக்கும். இதன் விதையைத் தனியாக அரைத்துப் பசும்பாலுடன் கலந்து சாப்பிட்டாலும் பலன் கிடைக்கும்.இதன் விதையைப் பொடியாக்கி ஒரு வேளைக்கு அரை கிராம் முதல் ஒரு கிராம் வரை பாலில் கலந்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் வயிற்றுப்போக்கு, நீர் கோத்தல், இரைப்பிருமல், மேக நோய் போன்றவற்றைக் குணப்படுத்துவதுடன் ரத்தத்தைச் சுத்திகரித்து ஆண்களுக்கு உயிரணு ஊறச் செய்யும். 40 கிராம் நீர் முள்ளி விதை, 20 கிராம் நெருஞ்சில் விதை, 10 கிராம் வெள்ளரி விதை சேர்த்துச் சிதைத்து ஒரு லிட்டர் தண்ணீரில் கலந்து 200 மி.லி அளவாகக் காய்ச்சி பனங்கற்கண்டு சேர்த்து ஒரு வாரம் தொடர்ந்து காலை மாலை என குடித்து வந்தால் உடலில் உள்ள கெட்ட நீர் அனைத்தும் வெளியேறிவிடும். அத்துடன் நீர் எரிச்சல், மேக நீர், வாத நீர் நீங்கி உடலில் உள்ள தாதுக்கள் வலுப்பெற்று உடல் பலம் பெறும்.நீர் முள்ளி விதை 30 கிராம், பாதாம் பருப்பு 10 கிராம், கசகசா 10 கிராம் எடுத்து ஒரு மணி நேரம் தண்ணீரில் ஊற வைத்துக் காய்ச்சி பாலுடன் சேர்த்துக் குடித்து வந்தால் தாது பலப்படும். அத்துடன் தாம்பத்யத்தில் மிகுந்த ஆர்வத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும். நீர் முள்ளிச் சமூலம் 200 கிராம் எடுத்து நன்றாகக் கழுவி சிதைத்து அதனுடன் பெருஞ்சீரகம், நெருஞ்சில் விதை, தனியா தலா 50 கிராம் சேர்த்து இரண்டு லிட்டர் தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அரை லிட்டராகும் வரை நன்றாகக் காய்ச்ச வேண்டும். அதில் 125 மி.லி வீதம் ஒரு நாளைக்கு நான்கு வேளை குடித்து வந்தால் பருத்த உடல் வாகு கொண்டவர்கள் உடல் மெலியத் துவங்குவர். அத்துடன் வாத வீக்கம், கீல் வாதம், அழற்சி போன்றவை மூன்று நாள்களில் சரியாகும்.வயிற்றுப்போக்கால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் அரை டீஸ்பூன் இதன் விதைப் பொடியை 200 மி.லி மோரில் கலந்து காலை, மாலை ஒரு வாரம் குடித்து வந்தால் நோய் குணமாகும். நீர் முள்ளி விதையுடன் சம அளவு மாதுளம் விதைப் பொடி சேர்த்து ஒரு ஸ்பூன் வெண்ணெய் கலந்து சாப்பிட்டால் ஆண்மை பெருகி தாம்பத்யம் சிறக்க உதவும்.நீர் முள்ளி விதையை ஐந்து விரலால் அள்ளும் அளவு எடுத்து இரவில் ஒரு செவ்வாழைப் பழத்தின் உள்ளே வைத்து விட வேண்டும். அதை மறுநாள் காலை வெறும் வயிற்றில் மென்று சாப்பிட வேண்டும். இப்படி 30 நாள்கள் தொடர்ந்து சாப்பிட்டால் தாது பலப்பட்டு தாம்பத்யம் சிறக்க உதவும். இதேபோல் அமுக்கராங் கிழங்கு, ஓரிதழ் தாமரை, பூனைக்காலி விதை, ஜாதிக்காய், தண்ணீர்விட்டான் கிழங்கு மற்றும் நீர் முள்ளி விதை அனைத்தையும் சம அளவு எடுத்துத் தூளாக்கி கோலிக்குண்டு வருமளவு எடுத்து தேனுடன் கலந்து காலை மாலை சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் ஆண்மை பலம் கிடைக்கும்."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn dana sun eeyan mẹwaa, wọn dumbu awọn kan, wọn si ko obinrin meje wọgbo lọ ni Niger","answer":"Ipayinkeke ko ti i kuro nilẹ lawọn agbegbe bii Kachiwe ati Shape, nipinlẹ Niger, nitori laarin ọsẹ lawọn oniṣẹ ibi ya wọ ibẹ. Wọn dana sun eeyan mẹwaa, wọn dumbu awọn mi-in bii ẹran, wọn dana sun ile bo ṣe wu wọn, wọn si ko awọn iyawo oniyawo meje wọgbo lọ.Agbegbe Sarkin Pawa, nijọba ibilẹ Munya, ipinlẹ Niger, niibi ti wọn n pe ni Kachiwe yii wa. Akọwe ijọba ibilẹ naa, Ọgbẹni James Jagaba, ṣalaye iṣẹlẹ buruku ti ko ti i tan nilẹ naa pe, ”Awọn janduku naa dana sun gbogbo ile ni, wọn jo eeyan mẹwaa nina lojukoroju, wọn ko awọn obinrin olobinrin mẹwaa lọ. Nigba ti wọn ṣe iyẹn tan ti wọn n lọ, wọn pade awọn eeyan meji kan lọna, mọto awọn iyẹn bajẹ ni. Wọn da wọn duro, wọn si pa wọn soju ọna nibẹ. Nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe iyẹn lọwọ ni mẹta ninu awọn obinrin mẹwaa ti wọn n ko lọ ti raaye sa mọ wọn lọwọ, bi wọn ṣẹ ko awọn meje yooku wọgbo lọ niyẹn.“Gbogbo ilu ni wọn fọwọ ba, ti wọn sọ di ahoro. Awọn obinrin mẹta to sa mọ wọn lọwọ yẹn lo jẹ ka mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ. Awọn naa ko gbadun, ara wọn n gbọn ni, niṣoju wọn ni wọn ṣe dana sun awọn eeyan mẹwaa, niṣoju wọn ni wọn ṣe dumbu awọn mi-in, ohun ti wọn ri yẹn ko jẹ kawọn naa wa ni alaafia ara titi dasiko yii.”Ọkunrin yii tẹsiwaju pe awọn apaayan naa tun lọ si Abule Shape, wọn dumbu eeyan mẹsan-an nibẹ, awọn ti wọn raaye sa lọ nibẹ, ẹni ori yọ o dile ni wọn fi dọgbọn sa lọ. O ni lẹyin ti wọn kuro nibẹ ni wọn tun lọ sibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Gogope, nipinlẹ Niger kan naa, wọn si tun paayan meje.Lori bi wọn ṣe ri gbogbo iṣẹ buruku yii ṣe lai jẹ pe ẹnikẹni da wọn lọwọ kọ, wọn ni ẹrọ ibara ẹni sọrọ ti ko ṣiṣẹ lawọn ilu naa lo fa a, nitori ko si bawọn eeyan ṣe fẹẹ pe ibomi-in pe aburu n ṣẹlẹ lọwọ lapa ọdọ awọn.Ki wọn too gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa ni Kansu ilu paapaa, ilẹ ti ṣu gbere, nnkan si ti bajẹ kọja sisọ."},{"question":"மரத்தின் பழங்கள் _____________ (குரைவாக / குறைவாக)உள்ளன.","answer":"மரத்தின் பழங்கள் ___குறைவாக___(குரைவாக / குறைவாக)உள்ளன."},{"question":"Манас эпосу тууралуу кандай маалыматың бар?","answer":"Сөз жок, «Манас» эпосунда реалдуу турмуш, тарыхый окуялар (кыргыз элинин тагдырына байланыштуу) чагылганы талашсыз. Ал турмак, эпостун келип чыгышы да белгилүү бир тарыхый кырдаалга байланыштуу болушу мүмкүн. Бирок, «Манас» тарыхый санжыра эмес. Бул баарынан мурда ошол тарыхый жана реалдуу окуялардын негизинде кыргыз элинин чыгармачылык генийинен жаралган, улам такталып, тазарып, артыкбаш жүктөрдөн бошонуп, керектүү, зарыл жаңы кошумчаларды кабыл алып, тулку боюна сиңирип өзүнүн бүгүнкү көз кайкыган бийиктигине жеткен көркөм чыгарма. Ошондуктан бул чыгармада кадимки кадыресе жашоо тиричилик менен катар, акыл жеткис укмуштуу фантастика, тарыхый окуялардын алыскы чагылышы менен катар, шумдуктуу миф табийгый түрдө бирге, жанаша жашайт. Аларды биринен бирин ажыратууга, бөлүп алууга болбойт. Алар бирине бири өтмө катар чырмалышкан. Элдин көркөмдүк аң-сезими аркылуу муундан-муунга, укумдан-тукумга өткөн «Манас» эпосу, ошентип, бышып жетилип, чыңалып, күчүнө толуп турган кезде бизге, биздин күнгө туш келди. "},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 政府は、これから寒くなると、電気が足りなくなる心配があると考えています。このため、日本全部の家庭や会社に、使う電気を少なくしてほしいと言うことを決めました。節電のお願いをするのは、今年12月から来年3月までの間です。冬の季節では、前に節電のお願いをしたのは2015年度でした。例えば、建物の中では服をたくさん着て暖房の温度を下げたり、使わない部屋の明かりを消したりしてほしいと言っています。政府は、何％の節電をお願いするか、数字を決めていません。経済産業省の西村大臣は「夏と同じように、冬も節電のお願いをします。できることをして協力してください」と言いました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"ලංකවේ ජාතික ගීය රචනා  කලේ කව්ද?","answer":"ආනන්ද සමරකෝන් විසින්"},{"question":"\\"Nahita sarintany mifono mistery tao amin'ny bokin'ny raibeko aho:\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha?A. Nitondra harena miafina tao amin'ny tanin'ny fianakaviana ilay sarintany.B. Ny sarintany dia hita fa noforonina  avy amin'ny tantara iray.","answer":"A. no fiafarana azo inoana indrindra"},{"question":" Zer da Leibnizen eta Newtonen kalkulua?","answer":"Kalkulua matematikaren adar bat da, non funtzioen aldaketak aztertzen diren. Kalkulua Leibnizek eta Newtonek independenteki sortu zuten XVII. mendean, eta deribatuak eta integralak definitzen ditu. Kalkulua fisikan, ingeniaritzan, ekonomian, eta beste zientzia askotan erabiltzen da."},{"question":"Nitori ti wọn lu oyinbo ni jibiti, Gbọlahan atawọn meji mi-in dero ẹwọn n’Ibadan","answer":"Lẹyin ti wọn ti gba gbogbo dukia ti Afọlabi Gbọlahan, Gbọlahan Sodiq Atanda ati Saheed Ayọmide Rabiu fi ọpọlọpọ ọdun ko jọ lọwọ wọn, ile-ẹjọ ti tun sọ awon afurasi onijibiti ti wọn n pe ni Yahoo mẹta sẹwọn.Ajọ to n gbogun ti magomago owo ati iwa ibajẹ, iyẹn  Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, EFCC, lo pe wọn lẹjọ si kootu  l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, nitori ti wọn n lu awọn eeyan ni jibiti lori ẹrọ ayelujara.Eyi to n jẹ Gbọlahan ninu wọn l’Onidaajọ Olurẹmi Oguntoyinbo ti ile-ẹjọ giga ijọba apapọ to wa laduugbo Ring Road, niluu Ibadan, sọ sẹwọn oṣu meje.Gẹgẹ bii ẹsun ti ajọ EFCC fi kan an ni kootu, wọn ni Gbọlahan lu oyinbo kan to n jẹ Brown Brain ni jibiti owo to to ẹgbẹrun kan dọla lori ẹrọ ayelujara.Ilu Abẹokuta ni wọn ti ṣẹjọ Rabiu ati Atanda, nibi ti Onidaajọ Olurẹmi Oguntoyinbo ti ile-ẹjọ giga ijọba apapọ nibẹ ti fi Rabiu sẹwọn oṣu kan, to si fi ẹwọn oṣu mẹta ta Atanda lọrẹ.Yatọ si sẹria ẹwọn ti wọn da fun awọn afurasi onijibiti wọnyi, ile-ẹjọ ni ki wọn da owo ti wọn fi ọgbọn alumọkọrọyi gba lọwọ awọn eeyan pada fun kaluku wọn. Bakan naa nile-ẹjọ gbẹsẹ le foonu olowo nla iphone ti wọn n lo fun iṣẹ jibiti wọn ọhun."},{"question":"Доолуу күндө көмөк, жоолуу күндө жөлөк\\"- дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Манаска \\"доолуу күндө көмөк, жоолуу күндө жөлөк\\"  Алмамбет досу болгон. Ар дайыма жанында көмөктөшүп жөлөк болуп жүргөн."},{"question":"Diin si Jesus karon?","answer":"Si Jesus karon anaa sa langit kauban sa Dios nga Amahan."},{"question":"Абыргандар деген эмне ?","answer":"Абыргандар (лат. Pteromyidae) — салааларында жаргагы бар тыйындарга жакын кемиргич айбандардын бир тукуму, булардын кыйла уруулары жана түрлөрү бар: кидик абырган (лат. Petaurillus hosei), кадимки абырган (Pteromys volans), зоо абырганы (Eupetaurus cinereus), баштыкчан абырган (Acrobates pygmaeus), жапон абырганы (Pteromys momonga), накта абыргандар (уруу) (Pteromys), Америка абыргандары (уруу) (Claucomys)."},{"question":"Türkiye ile Bulgaristan arasında yaşanan sorun nedir?","answer":"1985 yılı Bulgaristan Türkleri açısından çok önemli bir sorun yılı olmuş, yabancı ve yerli basında, Türk kamu oyunda ve bu arada Türk hükümetinin çalışma gündeminde bir güncellik oluşturmuştur. Bu sorun, Bulgaristan'daki Türklerin adlarının kitle olarak zorla değişti rilmesi olayıdır."},{"question":"Phrase 1: Sur les claviers AZERTY belges et les claviers QWERTZ suisses, l’underscore est en touche -.Phrase 2: Sur les claviers AZERTY français, l’underscore est en touche 8. (mais sur les claviers AZERTY des ordinateurs Apple, l’underscore est en touche -).Est-ce que le mot \\"underscore\\" est utilisé en même sens dans les deux phrases?  ","answer":"Oui, le mot \\"underscore\\" est ultisé en même sens dans les deux phrases. Le mot fait référence au symbole représenté par le code ASCII 95."},{"question":"ساختار «شاهنامه» به چه شکل است؟","answer":"شاهنامه را بیشتر به سه بخش اساطیری (از روزگار کیومرث تا پادشاهی فریدون)، پهلوانی (از خیزش کاوهٔ آهنگر تا کشته شدن رستم و فرمانروایی بهمن پسر اسفندیار) و تاریخی (از پادشاهی بهمن و پیدایش اسکندر تا گشودن ایران به دست اعراب) بخش‌بندی می‌کنند. اما این بخش‌بندی همیشه و کامل درست نیست و بیشتر، برپایهٔ سنگینی یکی از سه درون‌مایه دربرابر دو بخش دیگر است. ازاین‌رو، هیچ‌یک از بخش‌های سه‌گانه از موضوع دو بخش دیگر تهی نیست. از دیگرسو در هر بخش، نشانه‌هایی از قالب‌های ادبی مانند اندرز، رمانس، داستان تاریخی، آیین خسروان و ادبیات مردمی و شگفتی‌هایی چون جادو، افسون و عجائب و غرائب دیده می‌شود. در نگاهی کلی، درون‌مایهٔ اساطیر و شگفتی‌ها بیشتر در بخش پیشدادی؛ شگفتی‌ها، داستان‌های پهلوانی و رمانس بیشتر در بخش کیانی؛ تاریخ، آیین خسروان و اندرز و ادبیات عامیانه بیشتر در بخش ساسانی؛ داستان تاریخی یا کارنامه بیشتر در بخش اشکانی و ساسانی به‌چشم می‌خورد."},{"question":"السؤال: يوجد نظام تصنيف للنقاط لتصنيف شدة إعاقة اللاعب. ما عدد النقاط التي يمكن أن تصنف الشخص الذي يعاني من إعاقة طفيفة جدًا ، مثل الشيء الذي يسبب له العرج فقط؟","answer":"الإجابة: 4.5"},{"question":"કૈલાશ ખેરનું \\"તેરી દીવાની\\" ગીત નું વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"કૈલાશ ખેરનું \\"તેરી દીવાની\\" ગીત એક સુંદર અને રોમેન્ટિક ગીત છે જે પ્રેમ અને ભક્તિની ભાવનાને ઉજાગર કરે છે. ગીતમાં, ગાયક તેના પ્રિયને \\"તમે\\" તરીકે સંબોધે છે અને તેમની સાથેના તેના પ્રેમ વિશે ગાય છે.ગીતની શરૂઆતમાં, ગાયક તેના પ્રિયની સુંદરતા અને આકર્ષણ વિશે ગાય છે. તેઓ તેમને તેમના જીવનમાં સૌથી મહત્વપૂર્ણ વ્યક્તિ તરીકે ઓળખે છે.ગીતના મધ્યભાગમાં, ગાયક તેના પ્રિય સાથેના તેના પ્રેમની શક્તિ વિશે ગાય છે. તેઓ તેમને તેમના જીવનમાં આશા અને આનંદનો સ્ત્રોત તરીકે ઓળખે છે.ગીતના અંતમાં, ગાયક તેના પ્રિય સાથે કાયમી એકતાની ઇચ્છા વ્યક્ત કરે છે. તેઓ તેમની સાથે હંમેશા રહેવા અને તેમના પ્રેમથી ભરેલું જીવન જીવવાની આશા રાખે છે.\\"તેરી દીવાની\\" ગીત એક સુંદર અને રોમેન્ટિક ગીત છે જે લોકોના જીવનમાં પ્રેમ અને આનંદનો સ્ત્રોત બની શકે છે. ગીતની શબ્દો અને સંગીત એકબીજા સાથે સંપૂર્ણ સુસંગત છે અને ગીતને એક અનન્ય અને યાદગાર અનુભવ આપે છે."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిహరింపు అంటే ఏమిటి ?","answer":"గనులు, క్వారీలు, నూనే బావులు మొదలైన వాటిని నిరవధికముగా ఉపయోగించడం వలన అవి ఉద్గ్రహణ చెందుతాయి. ఈ ఆస్తుల విషయములో భూగర్భ సంపద, ఖనిజాలను వెలికి తీసేకొలదీ ప్రకృతి వనరులు తగ్గిపోవడం లేదా హరించుకుపోవడం జరుగుతుంది."},{"question":"ما مدة دوران المشتري حول نفسه ؟","answer":"9:55 دقيقة"},{"question":"සිංහල විහිළු කතාවක් කියන්න.","answer":"කෙටි පණිවුඩ සේවාව කෙල්ල : කොහමද පණ ?? කොහේද ඉන්නේ??කොල්ලා : මම හොදින් පැටියෝ.. ගෙදර ඉන්නෙ.. (Message sent failed)කෙල්ල : කෝ ඔයා??? වැඩක්ද??කොල්ලා : මම ඔයාට Msg එකක් එව්වා.. ඒත් deliver උනේ නැ..(Message sent failed)කෙල්ල : මම ඔයාට මෙච්චර Msg එවනවා.. ඔයාට මාව ගානක් නැද්ද?? ඇය් උත්තරයක් නැත්තේ??කොල්ලා: නැ රත්තරන්.. මම Msg එව්වට යන්නේ නැ.. Network problem එකක්.. (Message sent failed)කෙල්ල: හරි කමක් නැ.. ආයිත් මම ඔයාට කතාකරන්නේ නැ.. මටත් මගේ පාඩුවේ ඉන්න දෙන්න..කොල්ලා: ඕන මගුලක් කරගන්නවා... (Message sent successfully.)"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండికన్సైన్ మెంటు వ్యాపారములో కన్సైనార్ ఎవరు ? కన్సైనీ ఎవరు ?","answer":"కన్సైన్మెంటు వ్యాపారములో ఇద్దరు వ్యక్తులు ఉంటారు. ఒకరు కన్సైనార్, రెండవ వ్యక్తి కన్సైనీ. కన్సైనార్ను యజమాని అని, కన్సైనీని ప్రతినిధి అంటారు. వీరి మధ్య గల సంబంధము కేవలం యజమాని, ప్రతినిధి సంబంధము మాత్రమే. కన్సైనార్ సరుకును కేవలం అమ్మకం కోసమే పంపుతాడు. కనుక కన్సైనీ ఆ సరుకును అమ్మినంతవరకు యాజమాన్యపు హక్కు కన్సైనార్కు మాత్రమే ఉంటుంది. కన్సైనీ కేవలం అమ్మకపు ఏజంటు. వస్తువులను అమ్మినందుకు కన్సైనార్ కమీషన్ చెల్లిస్తాడు. కన్సైన్మెంటు వచ్చే లాభనష్టాలు కన్సైనార్కు చెందుతాయి."},{"question":"आमाको बारेमा कविता लेख्नुहोस।  ","answer":"हरेक सुन्दर बिहानीएउटा सिंगो रातलाई छिचोलेर हुन्छ।अनि जीवन पनि त्यै रात जस्तै हो,कुनै रात दिन भरको थकान मेट्न आतुर हुन्छन्,कुनै आउँदै नआए हुने नि भन्दा नि आउँछन्,कुनै यति सम्म लामा रात हुन्छन् कित्यै एउटा रात छिचोल्न नसक्दाजीवन नै अन्तिम हुन्छ।आमाम जति खुसी थिएँ नि,हजुरको पाठेघरमा हुँदा थिएँ।म जति सुरक्षित थिएँ नि हजुरकै त्यो न्यानो पाठेघर अनिकाखमा थिएँ।मैले कति गल्ती अन्जानमै गर्थें हुँलाती गल्तीलाई हजुरले विकासको एउटा खुड्किलो सम्झेर मख्ख पर्नु हुन्थ्यो।आमाम अझै नि कति अन्जान छु।हजुरले झैं नानी बाबु भनेर मलाई सम्बोधन गर्दा मेरै आमाको माया जस्तै भनेर झुकिएछु।हुन त गल्ती मेरै छ आमा म हजुरले सिकाएको हरेक बाटो हिँडी रहेछु।तर हजुरको कुनै दोष छैन।हजुरले १ दिन पनि विद्यालयको ढोका सम्मकोकिलामा कागजका पाना च्यापेर जानु भएन,अनि हजुरले आफूले जे सिक्नु भयाे मैले नि त्यै सिकेंसहनशीलता, धर्यता,नम्र स्वभाव,थोरै बोल्ने सत्य बोल्नेतर त्यो अहिले गलत भै सकेछ किनकि अहिले ठूल्ठूला विश्व विद्यालय पढ्नेको घुइँचो छ।अहिले समय परिस्थिति अनुसार चल्नु पर्ने रहेछ।म त्यै झुकिएछु आमा हजुरको संस्कारमातर म युग फेरिए नि हजुरले सिकाएको ज्ञान फेर्ने छैन हरेक पल भगवानसँग प्रार्थना गर्छु किहजुर बिनाको जीवनमा मलाई आत्म विश्वासी, निडर, घमण्डी अनि मूर्ख बनाइदेऊत्यस्तै गरेर अरूका आमालाई हजुरको स्थानमा कहिले राख्न नसकूँहजुरको एक मुस्कान मेरा लागि करोडौंको आत्मबल बन्ने छ।हजुर सधैं मुस्कुराउनु हैमेरी आमा "},{"question":"Ki készítette a C programozási nyelvet?","answer":"A C egy általános célú programozási nyelv, melyet Dennis Ritchie fejlesztett ki Ken Thompson segítségével 1969 és 1973 között a UNIX rendszerekre AT&T Bell Labs-nál."},{"question":"Ke tikologong efe yeo naga ya Somerset e bonego nywagakgolo wa bo 10? Ka baka la potšišo e fetilego, ngwala taba yeo e dikologilego yeo e nago le karabo. E ka ba dipolelo tše 1 go ya go tše 20. Taba e Dikologilego:","answer":"Kgolo ya palo ya badudi ke e phagamego go feta ya naga ka bophara, ka koketšego ya 6.4% lefelong la Lekgotla la Selete la Somerset, ga e sa le go tloga ka 1991, le koketšego ya 17% ga e sa le go tloga ka 1981. Bogolo bja badudi ke batho ba 1,4 godimo ga hektare, yeo e ka bapišwago le batho ba 2,07 godimo ga hektare tikologong ya Borwa-bodikela. Ka gare ga selete, palo ya badudi e tloga go 0.5 ka Bodikela bja Somerset go ya go batho ba 2.2 godimo ga hektare ka Taunton Deane. Palo ya baagi bao ba šomago ka tša boiphedišo e godimo go feta palogare ya selete le ya setšhaba, gomme tekanyo ya go hloka mošomo e ka tlase ga palogare ya selete le ya setšhaba."},{"question":"Dolphin Estate, Ikoyi","answer":"Ohun- ini Dolphin jẹ agbegbe gated ni Ikoyi, ipinle Lagos, Nigeria.Ohun-ini Dolphin jẹ ọkan ninu awọn agbegbe ti o kọkọ ni Ikoyi. ti a ṣe nipasẹ Messrs HFP Engineering Nigeria ni 1990 fun Idagbasoke Ipinle Eko ati Ile-iṣẹ Ohun-ini, LSDPC. Eyi ni ipari ti alakoso kan, eyiti o jẹ ikole ti awọn ẹya 646. Ipele meji ti ise agbese na, ti o tun ni idagbasoke nipasẹ Messrs HFP, ni itumọ ti awọn ẹya 1458. Ipele kẹta ṣafikun awọn ile giga ti a ti ṣe tẹlẹ lori awọn bulọọki mẹjọ ti Ohun-ini naa, lakoko lati gbe awọn ti a fipa si nipo nipasẹ iṣẹ ikole.O jẹ ohun-ini ti Funsho Williams, ti gbajugbaja oludije fun ipo gomina egbe PDP ni Eko, ti pa ni ọjọ kerin din logbon Oṣu Karun ọdun 2006 ni ile rẹ ni Corporation Drive.Ni Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 2015, awọn afurasi Boko Haram 45 ni wọn mu lẹhin ti wọn gbero lati kolu ile-iṣẹ naa, ṣugbọn won pada rii pe o jẹ bugbamu gaasi.Ni Oṣu Keje ọdun 2017, ijọba beere lọwọ gbogbo awọn oniwun awọn ohun-ini ti a kọ ni ilodi si lori oke nẹtiwọọki idominugere lati lọ kuro ni ile wọn ki o lọ si ibomiiran, ni ẹsun wiwa wọn fun awọn iṣan omi ti o tun wa ni agbegbe, ati ṣiṣe awọn iparun ileri ti arufin-ini ni osu kanna. Ni Oṣu Kẹsan ọdun 2018, iṣan omi nla kan kọlu Ohun-ini Dolphin, ati lẹẹkansi ni Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 2019. Eto omi ti o gba silẹ ko le tu gbogbo omi ti o gba sinu okun ni ẹẹkan, ti o mu ki o wa ni agbegbe Ikoyi ki o si dide soke.Ohun-ini naa jẹ ile si kilasi aarin ati awọn agbegbe ibugbe ti owo-wiwọle giga. Ibudo ọlọpa wa laarin Ile-ini naa. Consulate Ọla ti Ilu Meksiko tun wa ni Ohun-ini Dolphin. O ti wa ni ka ọkan ninu awọn julọ gbowolori ibi lati gbe ni Lagos.Awọn ẹya ti a ṣe ni awọn ọdun 1990 ti bẹrẹ lati wọ, ati agbegbe ti o ga julọ ti yipada si agbegbe ti o kere ju pẹlu eto idominugere ti ko dara ati awọn ọro aabo. Okun atọwọda kan wa ti n ṣiṣẹ kọja Ohun-ini ṣugbọn o ti di.Ohun-ini naa gbalejo ọpọlọpọ awọn ile itura bii Oakwood Park Hotel, Casa Hawa-Safe Court, Le Paris Continental Hotel ati Pelican Intercontinental Hotel, ati eka ohun ile itaja."},{"question":"Déan achoimre ar an alt:  Tá bean 21 bliain d'aois, a d'fhreastail ar scoil ard acadamh míleata mór le rá, cúisithe le dúnmharú dlíodóir pósta a fuarthas staon chun báis i óstán ard DC. Gabhadh Jamyra Gallmon, de Washington D.C., Dé Céadaoin, de réir na póilíní. Tá sí cúisithe le dúnmharú coiriúil den chéad chéim agus armtha ar mharú David Messerschmitt 30 bliain d'aois. D'eisigh na póilíní físeán faireachais de 'duine spéise' a fheictear ag dul isteach in Óstán Donovan go gairid tar éis do Messerschmitt téacs a chur chuig a bhean chéile Kim Vuong ag 7.45pm chun a rá léi go mbeadh sé sa bhaile i gceann uair an chloig ar 9 Feabhra. Níor tháinig Messerschmitt ar ais riamh agus an lá dar gcionn fuarthas é marbh tar éis dó a bheith staon sa chúl ina seomra óstáin le 'cairt creidmheasa éagsúla scaipthe timpeall'. Scrollaigh síos le haghaidh físeáin. Tá bean a gabhadh i ndáil le dúnmharú Washington, DC dlíodóir 30 bliain d'aois David Messerschmitt. Ar dheis, an 'duine spéise' a gabhadh ar fhíseán faireachais ag dul isteach san óstán áit a maraíodh Messerschmitt ar 9 Feabhra. D'fhreastail Jamyra Gallmon ar Acadamh Míleata Forestville i Maryland agus bhí sé ina mhic léinn samplach, a dúirt múinteoir Déardaoin. Fuarthas David Messerschmitt (sa phictiúr lena bhean chéile Kim) marbh ina seomra óstáin DC i mí Feabhra. Níor nocht na póilíní go díreach cad a bhí á dhéanamh aige san óstán. Baineadh ríomhaire, greamaitheach, coiscíní, fón póca agus trealamh enema as an láthair. Dúirt foinsí póilíneachta le NBC Washington gurb é Gallmon an bhean sa físeán agus go ndeachaigh sí chuig an óstán an tráthnóna sin chun 'imeacht gnéis' a dhéanamh. I measc na n-earraí a fuarthas ón seomra bhí ríomhaire, greamaitheach, coiscíní, fón póca agus trealamh enema, d'aithin Fox DC. Fuarthas imprisean uimhreacha sa seomra freisin. Dúirt foinsí forfheidhmithe dlí leis an Washington Post gur chreidtear go raibh robáil mar chúis le bás Messerschmitt. Labhair máthair Gallmon le NBC agus dúirt sí nach raibh a hiníon i dtrioblóid riamh roimhe seo agus go raibh uaillmhian aici dul isteach san arm. ","answer":"Gabhadh Jamyra Gallmon, 21, Dé Céadaoin ar chúiseamh dúnmharaithe den chéad chéim a bhaineann le bás David Messerschmitt an 9 Feabhra. Dúirt an dlíodóir 30 bliain d' aois lena bhean go mbeadh sé sa bhaile an tráthnóna sin ach níor thaispeáin sé; fuarthas é go raibh sé staonadh chun báis an lá dar gcionn in óstán. I measc na n-earraí a fuarthas ón seomra bhí ríomhaire, greamaitheach, coiscíní, fón póca agus trealamh enema. Dúirt foinsí póilíní le NBC Washington go raibh Gallmon san óstán an tráthnóna sin le haghaidh 'coinneála gnéis' Labhair máthair Gallmon le NBC agus dúirt sí nach raibh a hiníon i dtrioblóid riamh roimhe seo agus go raibh sí ag smaoineamh ar dul isteach san arm."},{"question":"Complete the following sentence: Have you been subject to any disciplinary","answer":"Have you been subject to any disciplinary proceedings against you for misconduct which resulted in a disciplinary sanction from any organization?"},{"question":"We zoeken de naam van een soort beleggingsfonds, ook wel Exchange Traded Fund genoemd, dat op de beurs verhandeld wordt. Het investeringsdoel van een dergelijk fonds is het zo nauwkeurig mogelijk volgen van een onderliggende beursindex met behulp van geautomatiseerde handelscomputers. Meestal doen deze indexbeleggingen het ook beter dan de traditionele beleggingsfondsen. Wat is de courante benaming voor een dergelijk beursindexfonds ? ","answer":"Het antwoord is Indextracker."},{"question":"「サディズム」という言葉の語源となった人物はマルキ・ド・サドですが、「マゾヒズム」という言葉の語源となったオーストリアの作家は誰でしょう？","answer":"ザッヘル・マゾッホ"},{"question":"வினா:  ”திருவிடைமருதூர் மும்மணிக்கோவை”  - குறிப்பு எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை: திருவிடைமருதூர் மும்மணிக்கோவை:  திருவிடைமருதூர் மும்மணிக்கோவை என்னும் சைவ நூல் பதினோராம் திருமுறையில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது. மும்மணிக்கோவை என்பது ஒரு சிற்றிலக்கியம் இதன் ஆசிரியர் பட்டணத்துப் பிள்ளையார். சென்னையிலுள்ள திருவொற்றியூர் பகுதியில் வாழ்ந்தவர். காலம் பத்தாம் நூற்றாண்டு.திருவிடைமருதூர்க் கோயிலிலுள்ள சிவபெருமானை இந்த நூல் போற்றிப் பாடுகிறது.நூல் அமைதி: இந்த ஆசிரியர் இயற்றிய திருக்கழுமல மும்மணிக்கோவையிலுள்ள ஆசிரியப்பாக்கள் இணைகுறள் ஆசியப்பாக்களாக உள்ளன. இந்த நூல் நேரிசை ஆசிரியப்பாக்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது.வெண்பா: (5)கண்ணென்றும் நந்தமர்க்கோர் காப்பென்றும் கற்றிருக்கும்எண்ணென்றும் மூல எழுத்தென்றும் – ஒண்ணைமருதவப்பா என்றுமுனை வாழ்த்தாரேல் மற்றும்கருதவப்பால் உண்டோ கதி.கட்டளைக்கலித்துறை (9)வந்திக்கண் டாய்அடி யாரைக்கண் டான்மற வாதுநெஞ்சேசிந்திக்கண் டாய்அரன் செம்பொன் கழல்திரு மாமருந்தைச்சந்திக்கண் டாயில்லை யாயின் நமன்தமர் தாம்கொடுபோய்உந்திக்கண் டாய்நிர யத்துன்னை வீழ்த்தி உழக்குவரே.புதுமையான சொல்-தொடர்கள்: வந்திக்கண்டாய், சிந்திக்கண்டாய், சந்திக்கண்டாய், உந்திக்கண்டாய் என்னும் புதுமையான தொடர்கள் இவரது நூலில் காணப்படுகின்றன. அவை முறையே வந்திப்பாயாக (வாழ்த்துவாயாக), சிந்திப்பாயாக, சந்திப்பாயாக, உந்திப்பாயாக (துள்ளிக் குதித்துச் செல்வாயாக) என்னும் பொருள் தருபவை."},{"question":"Unsa ang resulta kung ipuno ans 8 sa 8?","answer":"Ang resulta kay 16."},{"question":"Inona ary izao: \\"Andriamatoa tia sangy, Andrianaivo be sangy mahery, Ifaralahy mpanao fo lentika tsinain-drangahibe miteniteny.\\"","answer":"Valiny : torimaso torana fahafatesana. Milaza ny fisehon'ny torimaso."},{"question":"Staj defterinde hangi yazı tipi kullanılır?","answer":"Staj defterinde metin sayfaları düzenli bir şekilde karton kapaklar arasına ciltlenmelidir. Yazılar Times New Roman yazı tipi kullanılarak kâğıdın yalnız bir yüzüne yazılmalıdır."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Kiribati ?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Kiribati mu ngi tuddu Tarawa."},{"question":"Solve for 'y' in the equation: 4y - 2 = 14.To isolate 'y', add 2 to both sides of the equation: 4y = 14 + 2, which simplifies to 4y = 16. Finally, divide both sides by 4: y = 16 / 4, which equals 4.","answer":"समीकरणमा 'y' को लागि समाधान गर्नुहोस्: 4y - 2 = 14।'y' लाई अलग गर्नको लागि, समीकरणको दुबै छेउमा 2 थप्नुहोस्: 4y = 14 + 2, जसले 4y = 16 लाई सरल बनाउँछ। अन्तमा, दुवै पक्षहरूलाई 4: y = 16 / 4 ले विभाजन गर्नुहोस्, जुन 4 बराबर हुन्छ।"},{"question":" sheeg asxaabigii hogaaminayay dagaalkii yarmuug?","answer":"wuxu ahaa khaalid bin waliid rc."},{"question":"Nnkan de! Sunday ti wọn mu pe o n pa awọn eeyan l’Akinyẹle ti sa lọ lagọọ ọlọpaa n’Ibadan","answer":"Iroyin ibanujẹ gbaa lo jẹ fawọn olugbe ijọba ibilẹ Akinyẹle, awọn olugbe Ibadan ati gbogbo ara ipinlẹ Ọyọ lapapọ nigba ti oỌga agba olọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CP Joe Nwachukwu Enwonwu, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe Sunday Shodipẹ, afurasi ọdaran to n pa kukuru, pa gigun kaakiri agbegbe Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, ti sa jade latimọle awọn.Ninu atẹjade ti Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ yii, SP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fi ṣọwọ sawọn oniroyin lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ọga agba ọlọpaa fidi ẹ mulẹ pe loootọ lọmọkunrin ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun (19) to ti paayan bii mẹwaa laarin oṣu kan aabọ ọhun ti sa mọ awọn lọwọ ninu atimọle ti awọn fi i pamọ si.Lọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2020 yii, iyẹn ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee to kọja, ni wọn lọmọkunrin naa sa mọ awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ ninu ahamọ ti wọn fi i si lẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ ti wọn ti n ṣewadii iwa ọdaran laduugbo Iyaganku, n’Ibadan.Gẹgẹ bi SP Olugbenga ṣe kọ ọ sinu atẹjade ọhun, “ọga agba awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ fi asiko yii kede pe ọga awọn afurasi ọdaran to n pa awọn eeyan kiri l’Akinyẹle, ẹni ta a ṣafihan  oun pẹlu awọn afurasi ọdaran ẹgbẹ ẹ meji mi-in papọ lọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu keje, ọdun 2020 yii, ti sa kuro ninu ahamọ lọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, lẹyin ta a ti gbe e lọ si kootu, tile-ẹjọ si ti paṣẹ pe ka fi i pamọ sinu ahamọ wa.“Nitori idi eyi, a rọ ẹyin eeyan lati ba wa foju léde, kẹ́ ẹ le mu ọmọkunrin naa nibikibi tẹ ẹ ba ti ri i, kẹ ẹ si fa a le awọn agbofinro lọwọ ni teṣan ọlọpaa to ba sun mọ yin ju lọ, ka le gbe igbesẹ to ba yẹ lori ẹ.”Bakan naa ni CP Enwonwu rọ ẹnikẹni to ba ni iroyin to le ran awọn agbofinro lọwọ lori bi wọn ṣe le ri afurasi ọdaran naa mu pada, lati tete ta awọn ọlọpaa lolobo nipa ẹ."},{"question":"Sunday Shodipẹ, apaayan Akinyẹle ti foju bale-ẹjọ","answer":"Gbajugbaja afurasi apaayan l’Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, nni, Sunday Shodipẹ, ti dero ahamọ ọgba ẹwọn bayii.L’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii ni Onidaajọ Patricia Adetuyibi ti ile-ẹjọ Majisireeti to wa ni Iyaganku, n’Ibadan, paṣẹ pe ki wọn sọ ọ sahaamọ ọgba ẹwọn Abolongo, to wa niluu Ọyọ, lori ẹsun ipaniyan.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọpọlọpọ eeyan lẹni ọdun mọkandinlogun yii fẹnu ara ẹ jẹwọ pe oun ti pa nijọba ibilẹ Akinyẹle, n’Ibadan, nitori ọkan ṣoṣo ninu awọn eeyan to pa, iyẹn Abilekọ Funmilayo Oladeji, lọga agba awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CP Joe Nwachukwu Enwonwu, tori ẹ pe e lẹjọ.Ẹsun kan ṣoṣo ti i ṣe ipaniyan ni wọn ka si olujẹjọ naa lẹsẹ, adajọ ko si fun un lanfaani awijare kankan to fi paṣẹ pe ki wọn fi i pamọ si ahamọ ọgba ẹwọn Abolongo, to wa niluu Ọyọ, titi digba ti igbẹjọ naa yoo tun maa tẹsiwaju. Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ni nnkan bii aago meji aabọ ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2020 yii, ni Sunday wọle tọ Abilekọ Funmilayọ lọ, to fi gbogbo agbara ṣa obinrin ẹni ọdun marundinlaaadọta (45) naa ni ṣọbiri lori lai mọye igba titi ti iya naa fi dagbere faye sileewosan ti awọn aladuugbo rẹ sare gbe e lọ fun itọju.Ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn (26), oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun 2020 yii, nigbejọ naa yoo tun waye ni kootu Majisireeti ọhun kan naa, iyẹn ti ileeṣẹ eto idajọ ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ba fidi ẹ mulẹ pe olujẹjọ ẹsun ipaniyan yii lẹjọ ọ jẹ, nitori wọn ti gbe ẹjọ naa lọ sọdọ ijọba fun itọsọna to yẹ."},{"question":"Wọn pa ‘Star boy’, gbajumọ ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun n’Ilọrin","answer":"Awọn afurasi ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ti ṣeku pa ọkan lara wọn tawọn eeyan mọ si Star boy, lagbegbe Olumawu, niluu Ilọrin.ALAROYE gbọ pe laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, lawọn araadugbo atawọn to n kọja niyana Olumawu, lọna Police Link road, ṣadeede ri agbari ọdọmọkunrin naa nibi ti wọn gbe e ju si.Iwadii fi han pe lẹyin tawọn to ṣeku pa a ge ori rẹ, wọn gbe iyooku ara rẹ ju sinu igbo to wa nitosi ibi ti wọn gbe ori rẹ si.Ikorita Olumawu gan-an ni wọn patẹ agbari Star Boy si fun gbogbo awọn to ba n kọja lati fi ṣeran wo.Iṣẹlẹ naa ti sọ awọn to n gbe agbegbe ọhun sinu ibẹru, idi ni pe wọn n ro o pe o ṣee ṣe kawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun tun fija pẹẹta.Wọn ke si awọn agbofinro lati gbe igbesẹ lọna ati fopin si bawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ṣe n pa ara wọn nipakupa."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Izay mitovy ro .......................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Izay mitovy ro milambagna \\"' "},{"question":"காரல் மார்க்சின் - மேற்கோள் தந்து விளக்குக ","answer":"ஜெர்மனியைச்  சேர்ந்த தத்துவஞானியும், பொருளாதார வல்லுனரும், சமூகவியலாளரும் மற்றும் முதன்முதலில் பொதுவுடைமைக் கொள்கையை முன்வைத்தவரும்தான் கார்ல் மார்க்ஸ் . மேலும் மார்க்சியம்  எனும் மெய்யியல் கோட்பாடு தோன்றக் காரணமானவரும் இவரே. மேலும் அரசியல், பொருளியல் சார்ந்த பல நூல்களையும் எழுதியுள்ளார் கார்ல் மார்க்ஸ். உதாரணமாக மூலதனம் என்ற நூல் இவர் எழுதியதுதான்.ஒரு எழுத்தாளர் வாழ்வதற்காகவும் எழுதுவதற்காகவும் பணம் சம்பாதிக்க வேண்டும், ஆனால் அவர் பணம் சம்பாதிக்கும் நோக்கத்திற்காக வாழவும் எழுதவும் கூடாது.முதலாளித்துவத்தின் ஒற்றுமையை, பாட்டாளி வர்க்கத்தின் ஒற்றுமையால் மட்டுமே அசைக்க முடியும். "},{"question":"அம்பேத்கரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"எவனொருவன் தானே சரணடையாமல், மற்றவர்களின் இச்சைப்படி செயல்படாமல், எதனையும் சோதனைக்குஒரு லட்சியத்தை மேற்கொள்ளுங்கள் அதை அடைவதற்காக விடா முயற்சியுடன் உழைத்து முன்னேறுங்கள்.ஆண்மை என்ற சொல்லை அழிக்காமல் பெண்களுக்கு விடுதலை இல்லை, மதம் என்ற சொல்லை அழிக்காமல் மக்களுக்கு விடுதலை இல்லை.உன்னுடைய விடுதலை அரசியல் அதிகாரத்தில் இருக்கிறது. காவடி தூக்குவதிலோ உண்ணா விரதத்திலோ இல்லை.தீண்டாமை அடிமைத்தனத்தை விட ஆபத்தானது. அது மதத்தை மட்டுமல்லாமல் பொருளாதாரத்தையும் அடிமைப்படுத்துகிறது.சாதித் திமிறும் அதன் கோரப்பிடியும் அழிந்தால் தான் அரசியல், பொருளாதாரச் சீர்திருத்தம் ஏற்படும்.குருட்டு பக்தி தன்னறிவை இழக்கச் செய்யும். பகுத்தறிவைப் பயன்படுத்தாமல் யாருடைய வாக்குறுதியையும் நம்பக்கூடாது.அரசாங்கத்தை விமர்சிக்க நினைக்கும் தனிமனிதனால் அதனைச் செய்ய முடியாது. தனி மனிதன் செய்ய நினைத்தால் பல குறுக்கீடுகள் ஏற்படுகின்றன.சமூகத்தை உயர்த்த வேண்டும் என்ற விழுமிய நோக்கத்தால் உந்தப்படுபவரே உயர்ந்த மனிதர்.வறுமையிலும் அறியாமையிலும் வாடும் தம் சகோதரருக்குப் பணி செய்வது கற்றவர் ஒருவரின் தலையான கடமை.நீதியின் அடித்தளத்தின் மீது எழுப்பப்படாத தேசம் ஒரு தேசமே அல்ல.நான் யாருக்கும் அடிமை இல்லை, எனக்கு யாரும் அடிமை இல்லை.தனி மனிதன் இயல்பாக உரிமைகளைப் பெற்றுள்ளான். அரசியல் அமைப்பு அவ்வுரிமைகளைப் பாதுகாக்கிறது.பலிபீடத்தில் வெட்டப்படுபவை ஆடுகள் தான், சிங்கங்கள் அல்ல. சிங்கங்களாக இருங்கள்.ஒரு அடிமைக்கு அவன் அடிமை என்பதை முதலில் உணர்த்து, அவன் தானாகவே கிளர்ந்து எழுவான்.வெற்றியோ தோல்வியோ எதுவரினும் கடமையைச் செய்வோம். யார் பாராட்டினாலும் பாராட்டாவிட்டாலும் கவலை வேண்டாம், நம் திறமையும் நேர்மையும் வெளிப்படும் போது பகைவனும் நம்மை மதிக்கத் தொடங்குவான்.அம்பேத்கர்: \\"பகைவனும் நம்மை மதிக்க தொடங்குவான்\\" - உங்கள் சிந்தனையை மாற்றும் பொன்மொழிகள்B R Ambedkar History: இந்தியாவின் அறிவாயுதம் பாபா சாகேப் அம்பேத்கர் | Videoசமூகத்தால் செய்யப்படும் சர்வாதிகாரம், அரசியலால் செய்யப்படும் சர்வாதிகாரத்தை விட மிகக் கொடியது.ஒரு சமூகத்தில் பெண்கள் அடைந்துள்ள வளர்ச்சியைக் கொண்டு அந்த சமூகத்தின் வளர்ச்சியை அளவிடலாம்.மாபெரும் லட்சியத்தையும் நம்பிக்கையையும் வாழ்க்கையில் ஏற்றுக்கொண்டால் யாரும் உயர்ந்த நிலையை அடையலாம்.இந்த சமூகம் சுதந்திரமான உணர்வைத் தராதவரை சட்டம் எத்தகைய விடுதலையை அளித்தாலும் அதனால் பயனில்லை.கற்பி! ஒன்று சேர்! புரட்சி செய்!ட்படுத்தி அறிவு வெளிச்சத்தில் அலசி ஏற்கின்றானோ அவனே சுதந்திர மனிதன்."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Con 2 tuổi chưa biết đi, bố mẹ đưa đến bệnh viện, bác sĩ yêu cầu: Gọi cảnh sát! Nội dung chính của đoạn văn là giai đoạn trước 3 tuổi là quan trọng trong việc nuôi dạy trẻ, và nhiều bố mẹ bận rộn công việc nên cần sự hỗ trợ của người khác để chăm sóc con. Nhân vật chính là chị Xiao Juan, người phải tìm bảo mẫu để giúp chăm sóc con sau khi sinh. Chị Xiao Juan và chồng đã nhờ một bảo mẫu mới vào nghề và trẻ ban đầu rất thích bảo mẫu. Tuy nhiên, sau một thời gian, đứa trẻ vẫn không biết đi và có triệu chứng suy dinh dưỡng nghiêm trọng. Sau khi đưa con đến bệnh viện, họ phát hiện bảo mẫu đã ăn trộm thực phẩm dinh dưỡng của đứa trẻ để đem về cho con của mình, dẫn đến tình trạng suy dinh dưỡng nặng. Điều này thể hiện tình trạng người trông trẻ không đáng tin cậy và cần lựa chọn kỹ càng để tìm người trông trẻ có năng lực và trách nhiệm.","answer":"Trong quá trình nuôi dạy một đứa trẻ, giai đoạn trước 3 tuổi là giai đoạn khó khăn và quan trọng nhất. Khoảng thời gian này, trẻ sẽ biết đi, biết nói chuyện, biết ăn và lớn lên. Vì thế trẻ học hỏi rất nhiều và bố mẹ cũng sẽ rất vất vả trong khoảng thời gian này. Tuy nhiên ngày nay nhiều bố mẹ không thể tận tay chăm sóc các con bởi bận rộn công việc và làm kinh tế. Vì thế họ thường nhờ sự hỗ trợ của ông bà hoặc người giúp việc. Gia đình chị Xiao Juan cũng vậy, 1 tháng sau sinh con, chị Xiao Juan đã phải tìm bảo mẫu hỗ trợ chăm con bởi sức khỏe chị yếu, chồng thường xuyên công tác xa nhà. Không có người quen, gia đình chị Xiao phải nhờ đến một công ty chuyên giới thiệu bảo mẫu. Người mà họ giới thiệu ở tuổi U40, là người nhiệt tình, tháo vát mới vào nghề nhưng rất yêu trẻ con. Những ngày đầu tiên thấy vị bảo mẫu rất được lòng con nhỏ nên vợ chồng chị Xiao yên tâm giao phó.  Khi con được ngoài 6 tháng, chị Xiao bắt đầu đi làm nhiều hơn. Vợ chồng chị nhiều khi đi công tác nước ngoài cả tháng không về nên ít khi gặp con hơn. Họ mua rất nhiều sản phẩm dinh dưỡng đắt tiền và quần áo đẹp cho con nhưng lại không có nhiều thời gian bên con. Đến khi con được 1,5 tuổi nhưng vẫn chưa biết đi, bảo mẫu nói với vợ chồng Xiao rằng đây là một dấu hiệu của sự may mắn và đứa trẻ nhất định sẽ là người cao quý, giàu có trong tương lai. Vì thế vợ chồng Xiao đành tin vào lời vị bảo mẫu nhưng vài tháng sau đó, đứa trẻ 2 tuổi vẫn chưa biết đi. Xiao cảm thấy có điều gì đó không ổn nên đưa con đến bệnh viện. Sau khi bác sĩ thăm khám cho đứa trẻ phát triển bé bị nhuyễn xương do suy dinh dưỡng lâu ngày. Ngoài ra trí thông minh của bé cũng chậm hơn rất nhiều so với bạn cùng tuổi.  Xiao cảm thấy không thể tin được bởi chị đã mua rất nhiều thực phẩm bổ sung dinh dưỡng cho con nhưng như vậy chẳng là vô ích sao. Lúc này, bác sĩ đã nhận ra vấn đề, bà nói người nhà hãy lập tức gọi cảnh sát. Quả thực sau quá trình điều tra đã thấy được, vị bảo mẫu ăn trộm toàn bộ thực phẩm dinh dưỡng và những thức ăn ngon của đứa trẻ để mang về cho con của mình. Kết quả là con của nhà chủ lại không được chăm sóc nên dẫn tới tình trạng suy dinh dưỡng nặng, không thể đi dù đã 2 tuổi. Những trường hợp người trông trẻ không đáng tin cậy như vậy không phải là hiếm và có nhiều trường hợp còn nguy hiểm hơn đến tính mạng như bảo mẫu âm thầm ngược đãi trẻ, cho trẻ uống thuốc an thần để không quấy khóc... Mặc dù vậy, do hoàn cảnh mỗi gia đình nên mọi người vẫn cần đến bảo mẫu, người giúp việc. Vì vậy không còn cách nào khác, mỗi gia đình hãy lựa chọn kỹ càng để tìm được người trông trẻ có năng lực, có trách nhiệm với con của mình là điều vô cùng quan trọng."},{"question":"විෂාදය රෝග ලක්ෂණ නම් කරන්න.","answer":"විෂාදය රෝග ලක්ෂණ පහත දැක්වේ.දිගුකල් පවත්නා දුක, නොසන්සුන් බව හෝ හිස් බවකෑම අරුචිය හෝ බර අඩුවීම හෝ බර වැඩිවීම සහනින්ද නොයාම , වැඩිපුර නිදා ගැනීමනොසන්සුන්තාවය සහ ‍නොරුස්සනා ස්වභාවයනොගැළපෙන වරදකාරී හැගීම් , අසරණ බවබලාපොරොත්තු කඩවූ , අසුභවාදී හැගීම්චින්තනයේ , අවධානය පවත්වා ගැනීම් , මතක තබා ගැනීමේ , තීරණ ගැනී‍මේ අපහසුතාවය.මරණය ගැන සිතීම හෝ සියදිවි හානි කර ගැනීමට තැත් කිරීමතමා ප්‍රීතිමත් වූ ක්‍රියාවන්වලින් සොම්නස ලබා ගැනීමට නොහැකි වීම.සමාජ ආශ්‍රයෙන් , යහළුවන්ගෙන් ඈත් වීමශක්තිය අඩුවීම, ක්‍රියාවන්ගෙන් වේගය අඩුවීමදිගුකල් පවත්නා , ප්‍රතිකාරයන්ගෙන් සුව නොවන කායික රෝගලක්ෂණ උදා - හිසරදය, ආහාර ජීර්ණ පද්ධතියේ රෝග ලක්ෂණ, වේදනාවචාලක ක්‍රියාවන්හි වේගය අඩු වීමසිය රෝගීන් මෙම රෝග ලක්ෂණ සියල්ලන්ගෙන්ම පෙළීමට ලක් නොවේ. රෝග ලක්ෂණයන්ගේ තීව්‍රතාවය පුදගලයා මත රඳා පවතියි. එනමුත් සියදිවි හානි කර ගැනීමට සිතීම හෝ තැත් කිරීම හැර අනෙක් රෝග ලක්ෂණය අඩුම වශයෙන් සති 2ක් පැවතීම විෂාදය රෝග නිර්ණය කිරීම අවශ්‍ය වේ."},{"question":"ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਹੀਦੀ ਦਾ ਤੱਤਕਾਲੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ ?","answer":"ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਹੀਦੀ ਮੁਗ਼ਲ ਬਾਦਸ਼ਾਹ ਜਹਾਂਗੀਰ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਮਈ, 1606 ਈ: ਵਿਚ ਹੋਈ । ਇਸ ਸ਼ਹੀਦੀ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਜਹਾਂਗੀਰ ਦੀ ਕੱਟੜ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਨੀਤੀ ਦਾ ਹੱਥ ਸੀ । ਉਹ ਸਿੱਖ ਧਰਮ ਦੀ ਵਧਦੀ ਹੋਈ ਲੋਕਪ੍ਰਿਅਤਾ ‘ਤੇ ਰੋਕ ਲਗਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ । | ਗੁਰੂ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਜਹਾਂਗੀਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਦਰੋਹੀ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਖੁਸਰੋ ਨੂੰ ਅਸ਼ੀਰਵਾਦ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਆਉਣ ‘ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਆਦਰ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਲੰਗਰ ਵੀ ਛਕਾਇਆ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਕਾਰਜ ਰਾਜਨੀਤਿਕ ਅਪਰਾਧ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਗਿਆ ।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਕਹਿਆ ਕਰਣਾ ਦਿਤਾ ਲੈਣਾ ॥ਗਰੀਬਾ ਅਨਾਥਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਮਾਣਾ ॥ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਤੂੰਹੈ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਕੁਦਰਤਿ ਕਉ ਬਲਿ ਜਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਭਾਣੈ ਉਝੜ ਭਾਣੈ ਰਾਹਾ ॥ਭਾਣੈ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਗਾਵਾਹਾ ॥ਭਾਣੈ ਭਰਮਿ ਭਵੈ ਬਹੁ ਜੂਨੀ ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਤਿਸੈ ਰਜਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਨਾ ਕੋ ਮੂਰਖੁ ਨਾ ਕੋ ਸਿਆਣਾ ॥ਵਰਤੈ ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਾਣਾ ॥ਅਗਮ ਅਗੋਚਰ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਅਥਾਹਾ ਤੇਰੀ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਕਹਣੁ ਨ ਜਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਖਾਕੁ ਸੰਤਨ ਕੀ ਦੇਹੁ ਪਿਆਰੇ ॥ਆਇ ਪਇਆ ਹਰਿ ਤੇਰੈ ਦੁਆਰੈ ॥ਦਰਸਨੁ ਪੇਖਤ ਮਨੁ ਆਘਾਵੈ ਨਾਨਕ ਮਿਲਣੁ ਸੁਭਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੭॥੧੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 98 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਤੂੰ ਹੁਕਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਤੂੰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਉਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਗਰੀਬਾਂ ਤੇ ਅਨਾਥ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ । ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਮਰਥਾ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੧।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ (ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ) ਗ਼ਲਤ ਰਸਤਾ ਫੜ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਕਈ ਸਹੀ ਰਸਤਾ ਫੜਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਕਈ ਜੀਵ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੀ) ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੌਂਦਾ ਫਿਰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਇਹ) ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਆਪਣੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ ਨਾਲ) ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਜੀਵ ਮੂਰਖ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਨਾਹ ਹੀ ਕੋਈ ਸਿਆਣਾ ਹੈ(ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) ਸਭ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਹੀ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਅਪਹੁੰਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਹੇ ਇੰਦ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਹੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਹੇ ਅਥਾਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !। ਤੇਰੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਸ਼ੈ ਦੱਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ।ਹੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਧੂੜ ਦੇਹ ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਆ ਡਿੱਗਾ ਹਾਂ,ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ) ਦਰਸਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਮਨ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੭।੧੪।\\""},{"question":"भगवान बुद्ध यांना ज्ञानाची प्राप्ती कोठे झाली होती?उत्तर :","answer":"बोधगया"},{"question":"சேர்தல் என்ற சொல் குறிக்கும் பொருள் ………………………தேடுதல்பிரிதல்இணைதல்களைதல்","answer":"விடை : சேர்தல் என்ற சொல் குறிக்கும் பொருள் …………இணைதல்"},{"question":"ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਕਰਾਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਾਸਪੋਰਟ ਰੀਨਿਊ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਆਈ ਸੀ। ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰ ਦੀਪਕ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ 4 ਜਨਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਟਾਰੀ-ਦਿੱਲੀ ਟ੍ਰੇਨ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਪਹੁੰਚਣਾ ਸੀ।  ਪਰ ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦੇ ਨਾ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ 'ਤੇ ਉਹ ਉਸਦਾ ਪਤਾ ਲਗਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਗਏ। ਉਸਦੇ ਨਾ ਮਿਲਣ 'ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਐਫਆਈਆਰ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਈ।ਰੇਲਵੇ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਦੇ ਏਆਈਜੀ ਦਲਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਰਾਣਾ ਨੇ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ 8 ਜਨਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦੇ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇਦਾਰਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਲਾਪਤਾ ਦੀ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਈ ਗਈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਸੀਸੀਟੀਵੀ ਕੈਮਰੇ ਖੰਗਾਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦੇ ਪਤੀ ਅਮਰਸੀ ਪ੍ਰਤਾਪ ਹਿਰਾਨੀ ਨੇ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਹਗਾ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਆਏ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਸਵਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ਦੇਖੀ ਸੀ ਜਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਐਕਸਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਅਟਾਰੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਸਨ। ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵੀ ਉਸ ਸੂਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਉਸਦੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲੀ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਉਸਦੀ ਉਡੀਕ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ।ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਗੁਜਰਾਤ ਦੇ ਜਾਮਨਗਰ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਰਾਚੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਅਮਰਸੀ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ 10 ਸਾਲ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਆਉਣ ਲਈ ਵੀਜ਼ਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਇਕੱਲੀ ਹੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਦੀਪਕ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਸੀਸੀਟੀ ਫੂਟੇਜ ਤੋਂ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤਸਰ ਰੇਲਵੇ ਸਟੇਸ਼ਨ 'ਤੇ ਤਾਂ ਪਹੁੰਚੀ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਗੁਆਚ ਗਈ। (ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ।)","answer":"ਭਾਰਤੀ ਨਾਗਰਿਕ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਜਿਵੀਬੇਨ ਪ੍ਰਤਾਪ ਹਿਰਾਨੀ 3 ਜਨਵਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਐਕਸਪ੍ਰੈੱਸ ਜ਼ਰੀਏ ਅਟਾਰੀ ਪਹੁੰਚੀ ਸੀ, ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਉਹ ਲਾਪਤਾ ਹੋ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Ai là người đã phát hiện hang Sơn Đoòng?","answer":"Hành trình tìm ra Sơn Đoòng bắt nguồn từ một người đàn ông địa phương tên Hồ Khanh. Ông sinh ra và lớn lên ở xã Sơn Trạch, nay là thị trấn Phong Nha, huyện Bố Trạch, tỉnh Quảng Bình.Năm 1990, trong một chuyến vào rừng tìm trầm hương, ông Khanh gặp một cơn giông đột ngột và phải tìm chỗ trú. Lúc đó, ông tình cờ phát hiện một vòm hang đá nhỏ lấp ló sau vách núi đá. Khi đến gần, Hồ Khanh thấy những đám sương mù dày đặc thổi ra từ cửa hang nhỏ, có thể nghe thấy âm thanh của một dòng suối chảy từ trong hang vọng ra.Năm 2007, ông Howard Limbert và bà Deb Limbert, hai thành viên dẫn đầu Đội thám hiểm hang động Anh - Việt đến Phong Nha. Một lần trò chuyện với Howard, ông Hồ Khanh tình cờ nhắc đến cửa hang mà ông vô tình nhìn thấy nhưng đã quên mất vị trí chính xác.Một năm sau, trong một chuyến đi rừng, Hồ Khanh may mắn tìm lại được vị trí cửa hang, ghi nhớ và liên lạc với đội thám hiểm. Năm 2009, ông Howard Limbert thực hiện chuyến thám hiểm khảo sát hang. Đây cũng là lần đầu tiên Hồ Khanh vào bên trong."},{"question":"\\"Курманбек\\" эпосу жөнүндө факты...","answer":"Аккан — достуктун жаркын мисалы. Курманбек менен Аккан Манас менен Алмамбеттин достугун эске салат. Бул эки инсандын достугу кийинки эле XVI–XVII кылымдардагы эки тарапты, эки элди байланыштырып, аралыкты аттап өткөн акыреттик мамилелердин белгиси катары баалоого болот. Жоодон бели мертинип, кырк жигити кыйгап өтүп, өзүнүн атасынан ажалга түртүлгөн, канаты болгон тулпары Телторусуз кор болгон Курманбек ай-талаада жарадар болгон учурунда кашгарлык досу Аккан үстүнөн чыгат. Курманбекти аман алып калыш үчүн жан-алакетке түшөт. Курманбек ажал тапса, өзүнө канжар уруп, досунун артынан кетүүгө даяр турушу чыныгы досчулуктун үлгүсүн түзүп, угуучулардын ички сезимин козгойт. Бул эпизод дастанды комуздун коштоосунда уккан адамды кайдыгер калтырбаган учурлардан. Аны уккан көкүрөгү көр киши да досчулуктун бул улуулугуна таң бербей коё албайт.Курманбек талаада каза болуп бара жатып, досу Акканга керээзин айтат…Атам какбаш ат бербей, Калдым кара талаага, Менден салам айта бар, Каралдым жалгыз балага. Сенин таза жаныңа Жарадар жаным садага. Кызыл жорго тайыңды Мине турган алым жок; Кызыл кымкап шайыңды Киерге бүтүн далым жок…… Эл-журтума мен жактан Айтып өт досум саламды. Ардактап жакшы багып ал,Аркамда жалгыз баламды…"},{"question":"Quelles sont les paroles de la chanson \\"La vie en rose\\" ? ","answer":"\\"La vie en rose\\" est une chanson française très connue. Les paroles de la version d'Édith Piaf sont:[Couplet 1]Des yeux qui font baisser les miensUn rire qui se perd sur sa boucheVoilà le portrait sans retoucheDe l'homme auquel j'appartiens[Refrain]Quand il me prend dans ses brasQu'il me parle tout basJe vois la vie en roseIl me dit des mots d'amourDes mots de tous les joursEt ça m'fait quelque chose[Couplet 2]Il est entré dans mon cœurUne part de bonheurDont je connais la causeC'est lui pour moi, moi pour lui dans la vieIl me l'a dit, l'a juré, pour la vieEt dès que je l’aperçoisAlors, je sens en moiMon cœur qui bat[Pont]Des nuits d'amour à plus finirUn grand bonheur qui prend sa placeDes ennuis, des chagrins s'effacentHeureux, heureux, à en mourir[Refrain]Quand il me prend dans ses brasQu'il me parle tout basJe vois la vie en roseIl me dit des mots d'amourDes mots de tous les joursEt ça m'fait quelque chose[Couplet 3]Il est entré dans mon cœurUne part de bonheurDont je connais la causeC'est toi pour moi, moi pour toi dans la vieTu me l'as dit, m'as juré pour la vieEt, dès que je t’aperçoisAlors, je sens en moiMon cœur qui bat"},{"question":"Ahoana no hanaovana vinaigrette an-trano?","answer":"Toy izay ny fanaovana vinaigrette: afangaro ny menaka oliva, vinaigitra, voantsinapy, sira ary dipoavatra."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబులు రాయండి.చేతికి రబ్బరు తొడుగు వేసుకొని వీధి దీపాలను బాగుచేస్తున్న ఒక వ్యక్తిని చూసి నీహారికకు అనేక సందేహాలొచ్చాయి. ఆ సందేహాలు ఏమై ఉండవచ్చు?","answer":"విద్యుత్ దీపాలు బాగుచేస్తున్న వ్యక్తి చేతికి రబ్బరు తొడుగు ఎందుకు వేసుకున్నాడు?రబ్బరు తొడుగుకు విద్యుత్ కి ఉన్న సంబంధం ఏమిటి?రబ్బరు తొడుగు ఉండటం వల్ల మనం ఎలా రక్షించబడతాము?విద్యుత్తు తీగపైన ప్లాస్టిక్ తొడుగు ఉంటుంది. ఎందుకు?"},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي \\"ما إسم النبيان اللذان رفعهما الله إلى السماء ؟\\".","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي \\"سيدنا عيسى وإدريس عليهما السلام\\"."},{"question":"තම ක්‍රීඩා දිවිය තුළ වැඩිම ටෙස්ට් කඩුලු සංඛ්‍යාවක් ලබාගත් ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"මුත්තයියා මුරලිදරන්"},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Айбалта тийген башымдан корком, Атала боорсок ашыңдан корком,  деген саптар Музоокенин кайсы күүсүнөн? а) “Үн алыш” б) “Сынган бугу” в) “Мундуу күү”  в) “Коңур күз”","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в) \\"Коңур күз\\"."},{"question":"కింది పేరాను చదవండి. ఎక్కడ?, ఏమిటి?, ఎందుకు?, ఎవరు?, ఎలా? అనే పదాలతో ప్రశ్నలు రాయండి.వేమన జన్మించింది, తిరిగిందీ రాయలసీమే ఐనా ఆయన పద్యాలు, ఆయన సందేశం, ప్రభావం ఆంధ్రదేశము అంతా వుంది. వీరి పద్యాలు వివిధ భాషల్లోకి అనువాదమయ్యాయి. వేమన సందేశానికి దేశ వ్యాప్తంగానే కాక ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా గుర్తింపు వచ్చింది. సమాజంలోని ఎక్కువ తక్కువలు, వివక్షలు, అంటరానితనం, అంధ విశ్వాసాలు, మూఢాచారాలు, జీవహింస, అవినీతి, అధర్మం మొదలైన విషయాలపై తన సరళమైన పద్యాల ద్వారా ప్రజల మనస్సులో హత్తుకుపోయేటట్లు విమర్శనాత్మక రచనలు చేశాడు. కులవ్యవస్థపై దాడి చేశాడు. స్వానుభవమైన, ఆచరణయోగ్యమైన తత్త్వాన్ని సరళభాషలో ప్రజలకు చెప్పి ప్రజాకవిగా తెలుగువారి మదిలో శాశ్వతస్థానం పొందారు.","answer":"ప్రశ్నలు :1) వేమన ఎక్కడ జన్మించాడు?2) వేమన ఎక్కడ తిరిగాడు?3) వేమన పద్యాలూ, సందేశం ప్రభావం ఎక్కడ ఉంది?4) ఆంధ్రదేశమంతా ఏమిటి ఉంది?5) వేమన పద్యాలు ఎలా అనువాదమయ్యా యి?6) వేమన సందేశానికి ఎక్కడెక్కడ గుర్తింపు వచ్చింది?7) వేమన ఏ విషయాలపై రచనలు చేశాడు?8) వేమన ఎలా విమర్శనాత్మక రచనలు చేశాడు?9) వేమన దేనిపై దాడిచేశాడు?10) కులవ్యవస్థపై దాడిచేసింది ఎవరు?11) వేమన ఎందుకు విమర్శనాత్మక రచనలు చేశాడు?12) వేమన పద్యాలు ఎలా ఉంటాయి?13) వేమన ప్రజాకవి ఎలా అయ్యాడు?14) వేమన ఎటువంటి తత్త్వాన్ని ప్రజలకు చెప్పాడు?15) వేమన ఎవరి మదిలో శాశ్వత స్థానం పొందాడు?"},{"question":"Haka ne ko kuma a'a, shin abin da ke gaba gaskiya ne? \\"A tarihi, Paul I na Rasha ya yi sarauta a matsayin Sarkin Rasha\\". ? ","answer":"Paul I na Rasha mutum ne na tarihi wanda ya mallaki kursiyin Rasha a ƙarshen 1700s. Saboda haka, amsar ita ce E haka ne."},{"question":"*في أي عصر ظهر أول طير في التاريخ ؟","answer":"العصر الجوارسي"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta arba'in da tara a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 49"},{"question":"Thạch Sanh đã làm gì khiến cho quân chư hầu không còn nghĩ đến chuyện đánh nhau và phải cúi đầu lạy tạ?","answer":"Thạch Sanh đã đánh đàn và sử dụng niêu cơm thần thết đãi khiến cho quân chư hầu không còn nghĩ đến chuyện đánh nhau và phải cúi đầu lạy tạ."},{"question":"भगवद्गीता नेपालीमा अध्याय २, श्लोक ४७","answer":"कर्मण्येवाधिकारस्ते मा फलेषु कदाचन ।मा कर्मफलहेतुर्भूर्मा ते सङ्गोऽस्त्वकर्मणि ॥ ४७ ॥तिम्रो अधिकार निश्चय नै आफ्नो निर्धारित कर्ममा मात्र छ, तर त्यस कर्मको फल पाउने वा नपाउने कुरा तिम्रो वशमा छैन । तिमीले आफूलाई कर्मफलको कारण पनि नसोच र कर्म गर्नबाट सङ्कोच पनि कहिल्यै नलिउ ।"},{"question":"Vraag: Uit welk land komt Limoncello? A. Spanje, B. Italië, C. Griekenland, D. Litouwen","answer":"Antwoord: B. Italië"},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de François Jacob para a biologia?","answer":"François Jacob desempenhou um papel crucial na elucidação dos mecanismos de regulação genética. Ele, juntamente com Jacques Monod, propôs o modelo de operon para explicar como os genes são controlados e expressos em organismos, contribuindo significativamente para a biologia molecular."},{"question":"Mene ne Tatsuniya?","answer":"Tatsuniya, ƙagaggun labarai ne na ƙarya waɗanda babu ƙanshin gaskiya a cikinsu, waɗanda Hausawa kan shirya don annashuwa da hira (Junaidu da ‘Yaraduwa, 2002)."},{"question":"Adet bittikten sonra kaç gün içinde hamile kalınır?","answer":"Yumurtlama bir sonraki adet başlangıcından 14 gün önce gerçekleşmektedir. Aynı şekilde adetten önceki 12-18 gün arasında da meydana gelebilir. Regl döngüsü 35 günse 19 ile 25. günde doğurganlık dönemi olabilir. Eğer 23 günlük bir döngü varsa 7 ile 13. günler arasında yumurtlama gerçekleşebilir."},{"question":"Kañ lañu  fal Mustafa ?","answer":"Digante 1983 beu 2001"},{"question":"नताल इंडियन काँग्रेसची स्थापना कोणी केली ?","answer":"महात्मा गांधींनी"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸਟਪਦੀ ॥ਮਿਥਿਆ ਨਾਹੀ ਰਸਨਾ ਪਰਸ ॥ਮਨ ਮਹਿ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨਿਰੰਜਨ ਦਰਸ ॥ਪਰ ਤ੍ਰਿਅ ਰੂਪੁ ਨ ਪੇਖੈ ਨੇਤ੍ਰ ॥ਸਾਧ ਕੀ ਟਹਲ ਸੰਤਸੰਗਿ ਹੇਤ ॥ਕਰਨ ਨ ਸੁਨੈ ਕਾਹੂ ਕੀ ਨਿੰਦਾ ॥ਸਭ ਤੇ ਜਾਨੈ ਆਪਸ ਕਉ ਮੰਦਾ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਬਿਖਿਆ ਪਰਹਰੈ ॥ਮਨ ਕੀ ਬਾਸਨਾ ਮਨ ਤੇ ਟਰੈ ॥ਇੰਦ੍ਰੀ ਜਿਤ ਪੰਚ ਦੋਖ ਤੇ ਰਹਤ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਕੋਟਿ ਮਧੇ ਕੋ ਐਸਾ ਅਪਰਸ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 274 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜੀਭ ਨਾਲ ਝੂਠ ਨੂੰ ਛੋਹਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ, ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਦੀ ਤਾਂਘ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ;ਜੋ ਪਰਾਈ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੇ ਹੁਸਨ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਤੱਕਦਾ,ਭਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਟਹਲ (ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਤੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ (ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ);ਜੋ ਕੰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਸੇ ਦੀ ਭੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੁਣਦਾ, ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਮਾੜਾ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ;ਜੋ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਦਾ ਸਦਕਾ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ) ਪਰੇ ਹਟਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਵਾਸਨਾ ਮਨ ਤੋਂ ਟਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ;ਜੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਕਾਮਾਦਿਕ ਪੰਜੇ ਹੀ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਬੰਦਾ “ਅਪਰਸ” (ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।\\""},{"question":"آیا نوع یا دوام باتری در خرید گوشی هوشمند فاکتور مهمی است؟","answer":" اگر جزو کاربرانی هستید که از برنامه‌های مالتی مدیا یا بازی زیاد استفاده می‌کنید، بهتر است به سراغ گوشی هایی با باتری بادوام بروید."},{"question":"چهار بزرگراه در تهران را نام ببر.","answer":"به عنوان 4 بزرگراه تهران بزرگراههای همت، کردستان، شهید حکیم و صدر را می توان نام برد."},{"question":"¿Cómo ha impactado la Torre Eiffel en la cultura y la identidad de París?","answer":"La Torre Eiffel, construida para la Exposición Universal de 1889, se ha convertido en un símbolo icónico de París y de la ingeniería moderna. Su presencia destaca la capacidad de la arquitectura para influir en la identidad cultural de una ciudad."},{"question":"చట్టం పదవృత్తాంతాన్ని వివరించండి.","answer":"‘చట్టం’ అనే పదం టైటానిక్ భాష (జర్మన్) లోని ‘లాగ్’ అనే పదం నుండి గ్రహించబడింది. లాగ్ అనగా ‘స్థిరంగా ఉండటం’ అని అర్థం. పద అర్థాన్ని బట్టి సార్వభౌమత్వ రాజకీయ అధికారిచే ప్రతిపాదించబడి, అమల్లోకి వచ్చిన ప్రవర్తనా నియమావళియే చట్టం అని భావించవచ్చు. మరికొందరు రాజనీతిజ్ఞులు ‘చట్టం’ అనే పదం లాటిన్ భాషలోని ‘జస్’, ‘జంగేరి’ అనే రెండు పదాల నుండి గ్రహించబడిందని పేర్కొన్నారు. లాటిన్ భాషలోని ఈ రెండు పదాలకు ‘బంధం’ అనే అర్థం ఉంది."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਘਰੁ ੮ ਕਾਫੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਮੈ ਬੰਦਾ ਬੈ ਖਰੀਦੁ ਸਚੁ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਮੇਰਾ ॥ਜੀਉ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਸਭੁ ਤਿਸ ਦਾ ਸਭੁ ਕਿਛੁ ਹੈ ਤੇਰਾ ॥੧॥ਮਾਣੁ ਨਿਮਾਣੇ ਤੂੰ ਧਣੀ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਰਵਾਸਾ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਾਚੇ ਅਨ ਟੇਕ ਹੈ ਸੋ ਜਾਣਹੁ ਕਾਚਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੇਰਾ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਅਪਾਰ ਹੈ ਕੋਈ ਅੰਤੁ ਨ ਪਾਏ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਗੁਰੁ ਪੂਰਾ ਭੇਟਸੀ ਸੋ ਚਲੈ ਰਜਾਏ ॥੨॥ਚਤੁਰਾਈ ਸਿਆਣਪਾ ਕਿਤੈ ਕਾਮਿ ਨ ਆਈਐ ॥ਤੁਠਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਜੋ ਦੇਵੈ ਸੋਈ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਈਐ ॥੩॥ਜੇ ਲਖ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਈਅਹਿ ਕਿਛੁ ਪਵੈ ਨ ਬੰਧਾ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਕੀਤਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਰ ਹੋਰੁ ਛੋਡਿਆ ਧੰਧਾ ॥੪॥੧॥੧੦੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 396 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਮੇਰਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਲ-ਖ਼ਰੀਦ ਗ਼ੁਲਾਮ ਹਾਂ,ਮੇਰੀ ਇਹ ਜਿੰਦ ਮੇਰਾ ਇਹ ਸਰੀਰ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਸ ਮਾਲਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੇਰੇ ਪਾਸ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਭੀ ਹੈ ਸਭ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੈਂ ਨਿਮਾਣੇ ਦਾ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਮਾਣ ਹੈਂ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਭਰਵਾਸਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਝਾਕ ਭੀ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹੇ, ਉਹ ਸਮਝੋ ਅਜੇ ਕਮਜ਼ੋਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਦਾ ਅੰਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ, (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ) ਚਤੁਰਾਈਆਂ ਤੇ ਸਿਆਣਪਾਂ (ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਕੋਈ ਸਿਆਣਪ ਕੋਈ ਚਤੁਰਾਈ) ਕਿਸੇ ਕੰਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ;ਉਹੀ ਸੁਖ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਸੁਖ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਚੱਕਰ ਤੁਰਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਵਿਰਤੀ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਜੇ ਲੱਖਾਂ ਹੀ (ਮਿਥੇ ਹੋਏ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ (ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਰਾਹ ਵਿਚ) ਕੋਈ ਰੋਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦੀ ।ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ, ਤੇ (ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਹੋਰ ਦੌੜ-ਭੱਜ ਛੱਡ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।੧੦੩।\\""},{"question":"Trong đoạn trích Lẽ ghét thương thuộc tác phẩm Lục Vân Tiên, đây là lời của nhân vật nào?\\"Ghét việc tầm phào,Ghét cay, ghét đắng, ghét vào tận tâm.\\"","answer":"đây là lời của ông QuánÔng Quán chỉ là nhân vật phụ trong truyện nhưng rất được yêu thích, bởi đó là biểu tượng cho tình cảm yêu ghét phân minh, trong sáng của quần chúng. Lẽ ghét thương là một đoạn thơ trích từ câu 473 đến 504 của truyện Lục Vân Tiên, được giảng dạy trong chương trình Văn học và Ngữ văn hàng chục năm qua.Đoạn trích kể lại cuộc đối thoại giữa ông Quán với bốn chàng nho sinh Vân Tiên, Tử Trực, Trịnh Hâm, Bùi Kiệm khi họ cùng uống rượu, làm thơ trong quán của ông trước lúc vào trường thi."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Cuál es la teoría del Big Bang?. ","answer":"La teoría del Big Bang es una explicación científica ampliamente aceptada sobre el origen del universo. Según esta teoría, imagina que el universo era como una burbuja muy pequeña y muy caliente. En un momento explotó como un fuego artificial gigante. Y se convirtió en lo que vemos hoy en día, pero no hay evidencias científicas de esta teoría. "},{"question":"-  Sheeg Goorma Ayuu Dhacay Dagaalkii Qanda?","answer":"Wuxu Dhacay Sanadkii 8-Aad Ee Hijriyada"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe turbo amin'ny fiara?","answer":"Ny turbo dia fitaovana mampitombo ny herin'ny maotera amin'ny alàlan'ny fanerena ny rivotra miditra ao amin'ny cylinders."},{"question":"Nwata Nna ya ziri ohi","answer":"N'agba ọkpa na Ụzọ."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Pakistan tana da iyaka da Kasar Sin ta bangaren arewa. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"tohizo ity ohabolana ity: \\"ny havan-tiana ...\\"","answer":"ny tohin'ny ohabolana dia hoe : \\"ny havan-tiana tsy mahalavi-tany\\""},{"question":"கவிஞர் பாரதிதாசனின் அழகின்சிரிப்பு - குன்றம் - ஒளியும் குன்றும் பாடலில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள நடைச்சிறப்பினைத் தொகுத்து உரையாக வழங்குக.ஒளியும் குன்றும் அருவிகள் வைரத்தொங்கல் அடர்கொடிப் பச்சைப்பட்டே குருவிகள் தங்கக் கட்டி குளிர்மலர் மணியின் குப்பை எருதின்மேல் பாயும் வேங்கை நிலவுமேல் எழுந்த மின்னல் சருகெலாம் ஒளிசேர் தங்கத் தகடுகள் பாரடா நீ                    - பாரதிதாசன் ","answer":"இயற்கை வருணனையைப் பாரதிதாசன் செம்மைப் படுத்துவதில் வல்லவர். இப்பாடலில், வானுயிர்ந்த மலையின் அழகை தனக்கே உரித்தான நடையில் உருவகப்படுத்துகிறார். • மலையினின்று விழும் வெண்மையான அருவிகள் மலையாகிய பெண்ணின் காதில் அணிந்திருக்கும் வைரத்தாலான தொங்கலாக உள்ளது. • மலையில் அடர்த்தியாகப் படாந்திருக்கும் பசுமையான கொடிகள் அப்பெண் உடுத்தியிருக்கும் பச்சைப் பட்டாடையாகக் காணப்படுகிறது. • மலையில் காணப்படும் குருவிகள் சூரிய ஒளியின் காரணமாகக் தங்கக் கட்டிகளாகக் காணப்படுன்றன. • பூத்திருக்கும் பூக்கள் நவமணிகள் ஆகக் காட்சியளிக்கின்றன.• எருதின் மேல் பாயும் வேங்கைக் காட்சிகள், முன்வைக்கப்படுகிறது. • நிலவின்மேல் ஓடுகின்ற மின்னலின் வரிகள் விழுந்து கிடக்கும் சருகுகள் ஒளியின் பிரகாசத்தால் தங்கத்தகடுகளாகக் காட்சியளிக்கின்றன."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : deporte. ","answer":"¿Qué jugador de baloncesto de la NBA es conocido por su apodo \\"The King\\" y ha jugado tanto para los Cleveland Cavaliers como para los Angeles Lakers?. "},{"question":"Suaal: Waxaad Sheegtaa taariikhda ay Somalia xornimada qaadatay?","answer":"Jawaab: Waxa ay qaadatay sanadkii 1960kii"},{"question":"कम्प्युटरको बारेमा केहि जानकारी देउ","answer":"कम्प्युटर एउटा विधुतीय प्रोग्रामेबल, अर्थान निश्चित निर्देशनअनुसार कार्य सम्पादन गरी नतिजा प्रस्तुत गर्ने यन्त्र हो । कम्प्युटरलाई नेपालीमा \\"सुसाङ्ख्य\\" भनिन्छ। विशेष गरी कम्प्युटर दुई वटा तत्वहरू मिलेर बनेको हुन्छ । ती हुन् कम्प्युटर हार्डवेयर र कम्प्युटर सफ्टवेर । यी दुई बिच निकै घनिष्ठ सम्बन्ध रहेको हुन्छ । हार्डवेयर विना सफ्टवेरले केही काम गर्न सक्दैन र सफ्टवेर विना पनि हार्डवेयरले केही कार्य सञ्चालन गर्न सक्दैन । यी दुवै हार्डवेयर र सफ्टवेरको पुर्ण मिलन भएपछि मात्र कम्प्युटरले कार्य सञ्चालन गर्न सक्छ । त्यसैले यी दुई तत्वहरूलाई एकै सिक्काको दुई पाटोको रूपमा वर्णण गर्न सकिन्छ ।"},{"question":"වන්නි ගල් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"වන්නි ගල් එසේත් නැතිනම් රජරට ලොකු ගඩොල් යනු ගඩොල් විශේෂයකි."},{"question":"\\"Темага байланыштуу Ибни Аббастан келген бир риваятты эскерте кетүүнү туура көрдүм: Алла Таала Обо энени Адам атанын сол жак кабыргасынан жаратты. Адам ата ал учурда  ....\\"-окуяны кандай улантсак болот ? ( 2-4 сүйлөм болушу мүмкүн )","answer":"Окуянын мындайча өнүгүшү мүмкүн :\\"Темага байланыштуу Ибни Аббастан келген бир риваятты эскерте кетүүнү туура көрдүм: Алла Таала Обо энени Адам атанын сол жак кабыргасынан жаратты. Адам ата ал учурда уйкуда болчу. Ойгонуп, жанында жаткана Обо энени көрүп, жүрөгү жылый ага колун узатты. Периштелер: “– Эй, Адам, ага жакындаба! Силердин никеңер кыйыла элек!” - деп тоскоол болушту. \\""},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Canada?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Canada mu ngi tudd Ottawa."},{"question":"కణవిభజనను ప్రేరేపించే ఫైటో హార్మోనుA) జిబ్బరెల్లిన్B) ఇథైలిన్C) ఆక్సిన్D) సైటోకైనిన్","answer":"D) సైటోకైనిన్"},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் முதல் பிரதமர் யார்?(அ) ஜவகர்லால் நேரு(ஆ) இந்திரா காந்தி(இ) ராஜீவ் காந்தி(ஈ) நரேந்திர மோடி","answer":"பதில்: (அ) ஜவகர்லால் நேருஜவகர்லால் நேரு (நவம்பர் 14, 1889 – மே 27, 1964), இந்தியாவின் முதல் பிரதமர் ஆவார். இவர் பண்டிட் நேரு மற்றும் பண்டிதர் நேரு என்றும் அழைக்கப் பெற்றார். இவர் குழந்தைகள் மேல் மிகவும் அன்பு கொண்டவர். இவர் பிறந்தநாள் அன்று இந்தியாவில் குழந்தைகள் தினம் கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது.இந்தியா, 1947 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆகத்து 15 அன்று ஆங்கிலேயரிடமிருந்து விடுதலை பெற்றபோது அதன் முதலாவது தலைமை அமைச்சராகப் பதவியேற்றார். 1964, மே 27 இல், காலமாகும் வரை இப்பதவியை வகித்து வந்தார்.இந்திய சுதந்திர இயக்கத்தின் முன்னோடியான நேரு, காங்கிரசுக் கட்சியினால் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டு, 1952 இல் இந்தியாவின் முதல் பொதுத்தேர்தலில் காங்கிரசு வெற்றி பெற்றதும் குடியரசு இந்தியாவின் முதல் பிரதமராகப் பதவி ஏற்றார். அணி சேரா இயக்கத்தை உருவாக்கியவர்களில் ஒருவரான நேரு, போருக்குப் பின்னான காலத்தில் அனைத்து உலக அரசியலில் மிக முக்கிய நபரானார்."},{"question":"Nekutanga, svika kune mumwe wezvakakosha.","answer":"Nekutanga, svika kune mumwe wezvakakosha. Tanga kubvunza zvinhu zvemunhu uye zvirongwa zvake, uye gwira zvinhu zvakanaka zvekuzviita."},{"question":"Ọpẹ o, wọn ti ri dokita ati nọọsi ti wọn ji gbe n’Imẹkọ gba pada","answer":"Dokita Ọladunni Ọdẹtọla ati Nọọsi Bamgboṣe tawọn ajinigbe ji l’Ọjọruu Wẹsidee, ọsẹ to kọja, yii, lójú ọna Abẹokuta s’Imẹkọ, ti gba itusilẹ, alẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ti i ṣe ọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹrin yii, ni wọn gba ominira.Balogun Isalẹ ilu Ìmẹ̀kọ, Oloye Ganiu Akinloye, to jẹ ki ominira dokita ati nọọsi yii di mimọ, ṣalaye ninu atẹjade to fi sita pe, loootọ lawọn ti wọn ji gbe naa gba itusilẹ lalẹ Mọnde. O ni awọn ajinigbe naa yọnda wọn fun ilu lọwọ alẹ.Bo ṣe dupẹ lọwọ Ọlọrun lo dupẹ lọwọ Gomina Dapọ Abíọ́dún, Balogun dupẹ lọwọ Onimẹkọ pẹlu awọn eeyan to polongo ijinigbe ọhun lori ẹrọ ayelujara. Ṣugbọn nipa boya owo ni wọn sàn ki wọn too ri wọn gba pada bayii, Balogun ko mẹnu lọ sibẹ rara.Ẹ oo ránti pe nigba ti Dokita Ọdẹtọla, olori ọsibitu Jẹnẹra Imẹkọ, ati Nọọsi Bamgboṣe n lọ ninu mọto Camry to jẹ ti dokita yii lawọn kan yọ si wọn lojiji labule Olubọ, ti wọn ko wọn wọgbo lọ tibọn tibọn lọjọ Wẹsidee to kọja, ti wọn si n beere miliọnu rẹpẹtẹ ki wọn too le tu wọn sílẹ̀.Bakan naa lo tun jẹ pe meji ninu awọn ọlọdẹ to n wa wọn kiri inu igbo, fara gbọta ibọn lọjọ diẹ lẹyin ijinigbe yii. Mọto meji àti ọkada mẹsan -an ti wọn fi n wa wọn ninu igbo lawọn ajinigbe naa si tún dana sun.Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ko ti i wi nnkan kan nipa igbominira naa lasiko yii.Boya oun naa yoo fi atẹjade sita to ba ya."},{"question":"தட்டைப்புழுவின் விலங்கியல் பெயர்?","answer":"தட்டைப்புழு, பிளாட்டிஹெல்மின்த் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Nitori eto abo ti ko daa, awọn alaṣẹ ti ileewe Poli pa l’Ogun","answer":"Ileewe Gbogboniṣe Gateway, to wa ni Ṣapade, nipinlẹ Ogun, ko si ni ṣiṣi bayii, wọn ti i pa gbọingbọin ni.Niṣe ni wọn ni kawọn akẹkọọ maa lọ sile awọn obi wọn kia, eyi ki i ṣe nitori nnkan meji, nitori eto aabo to mẹhẹ ni.Ohun ti a gbọ ni pe niṣe lawọn alaṣẹ ileewe naa so idanwo to yẹ ki wọn ṣe kọ, wọn ni awọn akẹkọọ ki yoo ṣe e afi ti eto aabo ba nipọn si i, ti awọn si pe wọn pada.Ole jija ati ifipabanilopọ ti wọn lo n ṣẹlẹ nileewe naa lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii ni wọn lo n ṣẹlẹ nileewe naa, eyi lo si fa a tawọn alaṣẹ ibẹ ṣe ni kawọn akẹkọọ naa maa lọ sile wọn.Ninu atẹjade ti wọn fi sita lọjọ kejidinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2021, ni wọn ti sọ pe kawọn akẹkọọ maa lọ sile awọn obi wọn bi iṣẹ ọjọ naa ba ti n pari, wọn lẹni ti ko ba pada sile rẹ n mọ-ọn-mọ fi ara rẹ sinu ewu ni.Adele to n ri si igbaniwọle nileewe naa, Ọgbẹni J.O Popọla, paṣẹ fawọn akẹkọọ pe ile awọn obi ni ki kaluku wọn pada si, ki ẹnikẹni ma ṣe loun n duro nile toun n gbe gẹgẹ bii akẹkọọ, nitori bi ohunkohun ba ṣẹlẹ, ko ni ọwọ ileewe naa ninu rara o.Awọn fijilante meji ni wọn tilẹ ni ọwọ ti tẹ lori ohun to n ṣẹlẹ lagbegbe ileewe yii, wọn ni ọwọ wọn ko mọ.Ṣugbọn Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, sọ pe eto aabo ko ti i buru debi ti wọn yoo maa ti ileewe pa, ti wọn yoo maa ni kawọn akẹkọọ maa lọ sile. O ni boya o ni idi mi-in ti wọn fi ni kawọn ọmọ maa lọ sile ni."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bongkok kail nak mendapat'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tipu muslihat itu ialah untuk mencari keuntungan bagi diri sendiri"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 役所の車を電気自動車にするためのサービスが増えている","answer":"三菱商事のグループの会社は7月、東京の世田谷区に電気自動車を200台ぐらい貸す計画を始めました。車を新しく買うよりもかかるお金を少なくすることができます。そして、車から出る二酸化炭素をどのくらい少なくすることができたかデータを出します。世田谷区では、2027年度までに役所の車の半分が電気自動車などになる予定です。東京ガスは、役所や会社などに、電気自動車の充電の機械や管理のシステムを一緒にして売るサービスを始めています。たくさんの車を電気自動車にうまく変えていく計画も作ります。住友商事のグループの会社は、使って古くなった電気自動車を役所に貸す実験を始めています。"},{"question":"வினா:ஹீமோகுளோபினில் உள்ள உலோகம் எது?","answer":"விடை: இரும்பு"},{"question":"أيه احلي الأماكن السياحية في مصر؟","answer":"ممكن الأهرامات أو النيل من أشهر المعالم السياحية في مصر "},{"question":"N'Djamena mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"N'Djamena mooy gëblag réewum Tchad."},{"question":" Sheeg Magaalada Uu Ku Dhashay Maxamed Siyaad Barre?","answer":"Maxamed Siyaad Barre Wuxu Ku Dhashay Magaalada Garbaharey Ee Gobolka Gedo"},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: “ Efa nanandrana mandrakizay aho handalo ny fanadinana ary nataoko tamin'ny farany. ”Fehezanteny B: “ Taorian'ny fitsapana be dia be, dia afaka nandalo ny fitsapana tamim-pahombiazana aho. ”Mitovy ny ve dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Asisat Òṣóàlà","answer":"Asisat Lámínà Òṣóàlà MON tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ Kẹ̀sán-án oṣù kẹwàá ọdún (9 October 1994) jẹ́ agbábọ́ọ̀lùbìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà, tí ó ń gba bọ́ọ̀lù jẹun fún ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ̀lùbìnrin Barcelona ni orílẹ̀ èdè Spain. Ó máa ń gba bọ́ọ̀lù gẹ́gẹ́ agbábọ́ọ̀lù-sáwọ̀n, (Striker)."},{"question":"Siapakah Perdana Menteri Malaysia yang kelapan? ","answer":"Tan Sri Dato' Haji Muhyiddin bin Haji Mohd Yassin (15 Mei 1947 - ) ialah Perdana Menteri Malaysia yang kelapan. Beliau berkhidmat pada 1 Mac 2020 hingga 16 Ogos 2021."},{"question":"How has Sri Lanka's rich cultural heritage contributed to the creation of a vibrant and diverse artistic scene, and what are some notable cultural events that showcase this creativity?","answer":"Sri Lanka's cultural heritage has served as a wellspring of inspiration for its artists. Festivals like the Kandy Esala Perahera, featuring captivating traditional dances and parades, celebrate the country's cultural richness. The Colombo Art Biennale provides a platform for contemporary artists to showcase their talents, blending the traditional with the modern, creating a dynamic and diverse artistic landscape."},{"question":"凱塔王朝在17世紀初至12世紀統治馬利。 凱塔王朝從12世紀到17世紀初統治了馬利的前帝國和帝國. 問:第一句和第二句是否表達相同的意思?","answer":"不是"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai puyuh laga\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud percakapan yang tak pernah habis."},{"question":"Napisz tweeta na temat wyborów w Polsce w 2023 roku.","answer":"Jasne, oto moja propozycja tweeta: \\"Wybory to niezwykle ważna część demokracji. Razem możemy zdecydować o przyszłości Polski. Idźmy wspólnie na wybory #wybory2023 #demokracja\\""},{"question":"కింది సామాన్య వాక్యాలను సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యాలుగా మార్చి రాయండి.మంచి రచనలు వ్రాయండి. మంచి మెప్పు పొందండి.","answer":"మంచి రచనలు వ్రాసి, మెప్పు పొందండి."},{"question":"கிருத்திகா அவர்களின்  வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு  பற்றி விவரிக்க?                    ","answer":"கிருத்திகா                                                                                                                                                                                                       (இயற்பெயர்: மதுரம் பூதலிங்கம், 1915 - பெப்ரவரி 13, 2009) தமிழகத்தின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பெண் எழுத்தாளர். தமிழிலும் ஆங்கிலத்திலும் பல நூல்களை எழுதியவர். வாஸவேஸ்வரம் என்னும் புதினம் மூலம் தமிழ் நாவல் உலகில் அழுத்தமான தடத்தைப் பதித்தவர். பல புதினங்கள், நாடகங்கள், கட்டுரைகளை எழுதியவர். தமிழில் கிருத்திகா என்ற புனைபெயரிலும் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மதுரம் பூதலிங்கம் என்ற பெயரிலும் எழுதினார்.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்புகிருத்திகா கன்னியாகுமரி மாவட்டத்தில் நாகர்கோயில் அருகே உள்ள பூதப்பாண்டி என்ற ஊரில் பிறந்தவர். பம்பாயில் படித்து வட மாநிலங்களிலேயே அதிகம் வசித்தவ்ர். பூதப்பாண்டிக்கு அயலூரான திருப்பதிசாரத்தைச் சேர்ந்த பூதலிங்கம்பிள்ளையை மணம் செய்துகொண்டார். காலஞ்சென்ற பூதலிங்கம் அரசாங்கத்தில் பதவிகள் வகித்தவர். உருக்குத் துறையிலும், நிதித்துறையிலும் செயலாளராகப் பணியாற்றியவர். பிலாய் உருக்காலை நிர்மாணத்தில் இவருக்குப் பெரும் பங்கு உண்டு. கிருத்திகாவின் மகள் மீனா, வேளாண்மை அறிவியலாளர் எம்.எஸ்.சுவாமிநாதனின் மனைவி ஆவார்.இந்தியா முழுவதும் பயணம் செய்தவர் கிருத்திகா. இந்தியக் கோயில்கள், கலைகள் போன்றவை குறித்துக் கலைமகளில் பல கட்டுரைகளை எழுதி வந்தார். ஆங்கிலத்தில் மிக அழகாக மேடையில் பேசக்கூடியவர். சம்ஸ்கிருதத்திலும் பெரும்புலமை படைத்தவர். குழந்தைகளுக்காக, இராமாயணம், மகாபாரதம், பாகவதம், என பல ஆங்கில நூல்களை எழுதினார். பாரதியின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்றை ஆங்கிலத்தில் எழுதியுள்ளார். இதிகாச மறுஆக்கம், இலக்கிய அறிமுகம், தமிழகச் சிற்பக்கலை ஆகியவற்றைப்பற்றி எழுதியிருக்கிறார். கிருத்திகா எழுதிய வாசவேச்வரம் என்ற புதினத்தை சிறீராமன் என்பவர் ஆங்கிலத்தில் மொழிபெயர்த்துள்ளார்.விமர்சகர் சிட்டி பெ. கோ. சுந்தரராஜன் மதித்த எழுத்தாளர்களில் கிருத்திகாவும் ஒருவர். கிருத்திகா ஒரு முன்னணி எழுத்தாளராக ஆவதற்குச் சிட்டி உறுதுணையாக இருந்தார். தில்லியிலும், பல்வேறு நகரங்களிலும் வசித்த கிருத்திகா சிட்டிக்கு எழுதிய கடிதங்களும், சிட்டி அவருக்கு எழுதிய பதில் கடிதங்களும் புகழ் பெற்றவை. இவை நூலுருப் பெறவில்லை. கிருத்திகா எழுதிய நூல்களில் 'வாசவேஸ்வரம்' என்னும் நூல் தமிழில் வெளிவ்ந்த மிகச்சிறந்த படைப்புகளில் ஒன்றாக இலக்கிய உலகில் அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றது.எழுத்தாளர் கிருத்திகா தனது 93வது அகவையில் 2009, பெப்ரவரி 13 இல் சென்னையில் காலமானார்."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أطول آية في القرآن الكريم، وأين توجد؟","answer":"الإجابة: آية الدين أو آية المداينة هي أطول آية في القرآن الكريم وهي الآية 282 من سورة البقرة."},{"question":"陸上競技を英語で言ったとき、走り高跳びはハイジャンプですが、棒高跳びは何というでしょう？","answer":"ポールジャンプ（ポールボールト）です。"},{"question":"1969年にアメリカのケネス・クーパー博士によって提唱されたエクササイズで、日本語では「有酸素運動」と呼ばれるものは何でしょう？","answer":"エアロビクスです。"},{"question":"வினா : போர்ஸின் கோபுரம் எங்குள்ளது ?","answer":"விடை : நாங்கிங்,"},{"question":"Awọn eeyan Ipetu Ijẹṣa ni ki gomina Ọsun le Ọwa Obokun kuro nipo, nitori to gba kabiyesi wọn leti","answer":"Ko si ọmọ ilu Ipetu-Ijẹṣa nipinlẹ Ọṣun to gbọ nípa wahala to sẹlẹ láàrin Ọwá Obòkun Ilẹ Ìjẹ̀ṣà, Ọba Adekunle Aromọlaran ati Ọba wọn, Ajalaye ti Ipetu Ìjèṣà, Ọba Adeleke Agunbiade, ti inu ko maa bi gidigidi lori bi Ọwa Obokun ṣe fun baba naa ni igbati meji nita gbangba.Ninu atẹjade ti olùrànlọwọ nipa iroyin fun Ajalaye ilu Ipetu Ijeṣa, Afọlábí Akinọla, fi sita lo ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu iwa idojutiní ti Obòkun hu si Ajalaye pẹlu bo ṣe fọ ọ leti lẹẹmeji leralera.O ni, “Eyi ni lati fi to gbogbo eeyan leti nipa iwa ifiyajẹni ati idojutini nita gbangba ti Ọwa Obokun ti ilu Ileṣa ṣe fun Ọba wa, Adeleke Agunbiade, nibi ayẹyẹ kan laipẹ yii lori ẹsun wi pe kabiyesi ko ki i bo ti yẹ.“Ẹẹmeji ọtọtọ ni Ọwa gba ọba wa leti, bẹẹ abuku nla ni eleyii jẹ fun gbogbo ilẹ Ipetu Ijẹṣa, bẹẹ lo lodi si ofin awọn alalẹ. Ohun ibanujẹ lo jẹ fun mi lori bi awọn oniroyin ṣe n pe mi lati fidi ọrọ ọhun mulẹ, eyi to mu mi pe Olori Bọla Agunbiade, ti wọn si ti fi da mi loju bayii pe Ajalaye ti tori iwa buruku yii pe Ọwa Obokun lẹjọ.“Pẹlu iṣẹlẹ yii, mo fẹẹ fi asiko yii ke si ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun lati paṣẹ fun Ọwa ko fi ori apere Ọba to wa silẹ ko lọọ rọ ọ kun nile na, nitori iwa idojutini gbaa lo hu si ọba ẹgbẹ ẹ, bẹẹ nirufẹ iwa bẹe ko yẹ ọba alade. Abuku nla ni eleyii jẹ fun wa nilẹ Ipetu Ijẹṣa, bẹẹ la o ni i fọwọ kekere mu un rara.”"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Nakaiza ny tanteliko teto oh, lanin'ny _ oh\\"","answer":"\\"Nakaiza ny tanteliko teto oh, lanin'ny vitsika oh\\""},{"question":"Wat is de Engelse Premier League?","answer":"De Engelse Premier League is de hoogste voetbalcompetitie van Engeland."},{"question":"Uyagula yini baba awakhuluma nje namuhla?Usebuyile yini umakoti?Akakabuyi. Kusho ukuthi ngabe uphethwe kabi ukuhamba kwaloluhlanya lwengane?Cha impela kwenzeke into embi mkami. Okokuqala asiyazi nokuthi iphile ngane. Kokunye izithele phezu kwezigebengu zayenzakalisa.Phela lapho ngabe umvundla ziyawunqanda phambili. Yona yiniingasilaleli uma siyitshela ngesiko lesintu.Namasiko lawa asefuna ukubhekisiswa. Sengathi akhona asephelelwayisikhathi manje. Amanye kufuneka achazwe kahle aziwe yibo bonkeabantu.Ubona sengathi umakoti akalazi leli siko. Ulazi kahle uyazihlanyisa.Mina ngibona sengathi sinecala manje.Icala lani? Musa ukudlala wena Manzini. Phela thina asiyixoshanga lengane lapha ekhaya. Izihambele. Uyangizwa? Izihambele.UMsindo onjengalo uzosixabanisa namadlozi.Nawo ngabe ayaganga lawo madlozi. Angayeka ukubuyisa uhlanyalukamakoti, axabane nathi? Kanti awalazi yini wona leli siko esilitshelale ntombazane.Mina ngisafuna ukuhlala phansi ngiyichazele kahle intombazane.Kokunye uma isizwe kahle iyobubona ubuhle baleli siko.Wena ubona sengathi izokulalela njengoba isiwumdlwembe nje? (Athiukuhleka) Kodwa ungichazile uDumisani. Wajika eduzenjengenkalankala.Nami ungimangazile impela lo mfana.1. Yisiphi isizathu esabangela ukuthi uThenjiwe angabe esayinaka indabayokucela imvume emzini uma ezoya kubo?","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo: Yingoba uMaMbatha wamenqabela uThenjiwe ngesikhathi emcela ukuthiagoduke Yingoba uThenjiwe wayengasafuni vele ukuhlala kwaZungu. Wayecasulwa ukuthi ilungelo lakhe lalingahlonishwa. UMaMbatha wayembiza ngomdlwembe okwenza uThenjiwe wangabeesamhlonipha umamezala."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 bị vẽ bậyHoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Liên quan đến vụ cháu bé 1 tuổi bị đánh, bịt miệng bằng băng dính, ngày 31/7, Công an quận Đống Đa, TP Hà Nội cho biết, đơn vị đã tạm giữ hình sự Đoàn Diệu Linh (SN 1996; thường trú tại thị xã Sơn Tây) và Hoàng Thế Vũ (SN 1994, chồng của Linh) để làm rõ hành vi Hành hạ người khác. Cặp vợ chồng Linh, Vũ đang bị tạm giữ hình sự. Theo Công an quận Đống Đa, hiện cháu L.Q.Tr. (SN 2021) đang được điều trị tích cực tại bệnh viện. Các bác sỹ chẩn đoán sốc nhiễm khuẩn, theo dõi chân tay miệng mức độ 4. Trên thân thể cháu Tr. còn có các vết lằn tổn thương da tại vùng chân, tay, mông nghi bị bạo hành. Trước đó, ngày 21/7, mẹ cháu Tr. là chị H. (SN 1994) thuê Đoàn Diệu Linh trông cháu Tr. với giá 3.000.000 đồng/tháng tại ngõ 198 Xã Đàn, phường Phương Liên, quận Đống Đa, để đi làm công nhân tại Bắc Giang.","answer":"Trong quá trình trông trẻ, do cháu Tr. bị sốt và quấy khóc nên Linh và chồng là Vũ đã dùng dây sạc điện thoại buộc chân, dùng que gỗ, búa nhựa đánh vào đầu, người, dùng chăn quấn vào người và dùng băng dính bịt miệng cháu Tr. Ngày 26/7, thấy cháu Tr. mệt mỏi, khó thở, Vũ và Linh đã đưa cháu đến bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương cấp cứu. Tại đây, cả hai tự xưng là bố và mẹ của cháu bé. Nhận thấy sự việc có dấu hiệu bất thường, phía bệnh viện đã báo tin tới Công an phường Láng Thượng. Ngày 28/7, chị H. đã đến trụ sở công an phối hợp làm việc đồng thời trình báo, đề nghị xử lý sự việc theo quy định của pháp luật."},{"question":" Ma sheegi kartaa Daliil caddaynayain Iimaanku uu ka guda ballaadhanyahay lixda tiir ee Iimaanka?","answer":" Haa, waxaa daliil u ah Xadiithka Nabiga (scw) oo ahaa in : \\"Iimaanku wuxuu kakoobanyahay dhawr iyo toddobaatan\\"\\f"},{"question":"Viết mở bài cho \\"TUYÊN NGÔN ĐỘC LẬP\\"","answer":"Trải qua mấy ngàn năm lịch sử, dân tộc ta phải đương đầu với đủ loại ngoại xâm: Từ Bắc xuống, từ Nam lên, từ Tây sang, từ Đông vào cho nên cùng với những chiến công hiển hách: phá Tống, bình Nguyên, diệt Minh, đuổi Thanh; nền văn học chúng ta cũng đã có những áng văn kiệt tác khẳng định đanh thép chủ quyền độc lập của dân tộc. Nếu như “Nam quốc sơn hà” của Lý Thường Kiệt mở đầu bằng một lời tuyên ngôn đanh thép :“Nam quốc sơn hà Nam đế cư”,“Đại cáo bình Ngô” của Nguyễn Trãi với lời khẳng định một chân lí lịch sử: “Việc nhân nghĩa cốt ở yên dân - Quân điếu phạt trước lo trừ bạo”, thì “Tuyên ngôn độc lập” của Hồ Chí Minh kế thừa tinh thần yêu nước và cảm hứng nhân văn của hai bản tuyên ngôn trên. Đồng thời mở ra một kỉ nguyên mới là kỉ nguyên độc lập dân tộc của một dân tộc thuộc địa như Việt Nam lần đầu tiên vùng dậy chặt đứt mọi xiềng xích của thực dân giành quyền giải phóng cho mình. Nói như Nguyễn Đình Thi trong bài thơ “Đất nước”“Nước Việt Nam từ máu lửaRũ bùn đứng dậy sáng loà”Tuy nhiên, đứng từ góc độ văn chương nghệ thuật để thẩm thấu thì “Tuyên ngôn độc lập” là đỉnh cao của văn chương chính luận nước nhà đạt đến trình độ mẫu mực cả về nội dung và nghệ thuật."},{"question":" Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Ninkii Ey U Kireysteen Rasuulka (NNKH) Iyo Abuu-Bakar Rc Inuu Jidka tuso markii ey u hijroonaayeen Madiina?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Dal aqoonkii La’oran Jiray C/Laahi Bin Ariiqadh"},{"question":"Solve for 'y' in the given equation: 2y - 5 = 11.","answer":"To isolate 'y', add 5 to both sides of the equation: 2y = 11 + 5, simplifying to 2y = 16. Finally, divide both sides by 2: y = 16 / 2, which equals to 8.or 2y = 11+52y = 16y = 16/2y = 8"},{"question":"ما هو الحدث المهم في هذا النص: أزالي هُو فيلم دراما غاني صدر سنة 2018 وأخرجه كوابينا غيانسا. اختير الفيلم ليكون الترشيح الرسمي لدولة غانا بخصوص جائزة أفضل فيلم روائي طويل دولي في حفل توزيع جوائز الأوسكار الثاني والتسعين، لكنه لم يُرشح ضمن القائمة النهائية للجائزة. تُعد هذه المرة الأولى التي تُرشح فيها غانا فيلمًا للتنافس ضمن جائزة الأوسكار لأفضل فيلم روائي طويل دولي. رُشح الفيلم أيضا لنيل جائزة أفضل فيلم في لُغة أفريقية في حفل توزيع جوائز الأكاديمية الأفريقية للأفلام الخامس عشر، لكنه لم يفُز بها.","answer":"حفل توزيع جوائز الأوسكار الثاني والتسعين"},{"question":"Ngozi Okobi","answer":"Ngozi Okobi jẹ agbabọọlu lobinrin órilẹ ede naigiria ti a bini 14, óṣu December ni ọdun 1993. Arabinrin naa ṣere fun Swedish club Eskilstuna United DFF gẹgẹbi ipo forward.Ngozi kopa ninu FIFA U-17 Cup awọn obinrin agbaye ni ọdun 2008, 2010 ati FIFA U-20 Cup awọn obinrin agbaye ni ọdun 2012 nibi ti o jẹ àṣoju team awọn obinrin apapọ ilẹ naigiria lori bọọlu[4].Ngozi kopa ninu ere idije awọn obinrin ilẹ afirica ni ọdun 2010, 2012 ati 2014."},{"question":"ਈਟਾਨਗਰ, 23 ਫਰਵਰੀਅਰੁਣਾਚਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਕੱਤਰੇਤ ’ਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀਆਂ ’ਤੇ ਪੁਲੀਸ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਚਲਾਈ ਗਈ ਗੋਲੀ ’ਚ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਨਿਯੁਕਤ ਇੱਕ ਪੈਨਲ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਗ਼ੈਰ-ਅਰੁਣਾਚਲ ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਥਾਈ ਰਿਹਾਇਸ਼ੀ ਸਰਟੀਫਿਕੇਟ (ਪੀਆਰਸੀ) ਦੇਣ ਦੀਆਂ ਮਦਾਂ ’ਚ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਇਹ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ।ਇਸ ਘਟਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਤਣਾਅ ਦੇ ਮੱਦੇਨਜ਼ਰ ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ’ਚ ਇੰਟਰਨੈੱਟ ਸੇਵਾਵਾਂ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ। ਫੌਜ ਨੇ ਨਾਹਰਲਾਗੁਨ ਤੇ ਈਟਾਨਗਰ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਫਲੈਗ ਮਾਰਚ ਕੀਤਾ। ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਲੰਘੀ ਰਾਤ ਕਈ ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਸਕੱਤਰੇਤ ’ਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਮਜਬੂਰ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪੁਲੀਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੋਲੀ ਚਲਾਉਣੀ ਪਈ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਬੀਤੀ ਸ਼ਾਮ 50 ਵਾਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗ ਲਗਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਅਤੇ 100 ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਹੋਰ ਵਾਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਭੰਨ-ਤੋੜ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਲ ਅਰੁਣਾਚਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਸਟੂਡੈਂਟਸ ਯੂਨੀਅਨ ਤੇ ਆਲ ਨਿਆਸੀ ਸਟੂਡੈਂਟਸ ਯੂਨੀਅਨ ਦੇ ਦਫ਼ਤਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾੜ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ?","answer":"ਅਰੁਣਾਚਲ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਕੱਤਰੇਤ ’ਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਮੁਜ਼ਾਹਰਾਕਾਰੀਆਂ ’ਤੇ ਪੁਲੀਸ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਚਲਾਈ ਗਈ ਗੋਲੀ ’ਚ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"« Tsy tao an-tsain’ny Malagasy intsony ny fanajana ny Rariny noho ny maha-Rariny azy, fa noho izy entam-barotra azo amidy dia samy mampideradera azy ny isam-bavarana. Voatototry ny Vola ny Rariny ! Dia mitsimoka ho azy tao an’eritreritry ny Malagasy ity fisainana feno fahakiviana ity : « Tsy misy olombelona azo itokiana intsony ! » Lanin’ny sainao izao ny rijan-kevitra ajoron’ny fikambanana iray ! Olona fantatrao sady ankasitrahanao ireo mpitolona ao anatiny !… Nefa dia tsy maintsy miahotra ianao, fa tsy azo sakanana fisokon’ny ahiahy tsy ihavanana hoe : « Sao dia.. » Inona ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra eo ambony io ?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra io dia ny rariny."},{"question":"Дасторкон адеби...","answer":"\\"Киши жаманы кирип-чыкканча\\" дейт кыргызда. Адамдын кандай экенин анын тамак ичеринен, керек болсо бут кийимне карап эле баамдап койсоң болот. Көп учурда бул нерселерге анчейин маани бере бербейбиз. Бирок ар бир нерсенин адеби, тартиби бар. Маселен, дасторкон адеби...• Тамактанарда колуңду жууганды унутпа.• Дасторкон четине улуу кишилер жайланышкандан кийин гана орун ал. Отурганда ар жакты кылчактап карай бербе.• Таянып отурба.• Жей турган тамагыңды тарелкага чактап салып ал. Баарын салып алба, анткени сенден башкалар да андан ооз тийиши керек.• «Мага бул бөлүгү жакты, чоң экен, ошону алам» деп тандаба. Кайсы бөлүк сага жакын болсо, ошонусун ал.• Тамакты шашылбай же.• Чайнап жатканда сүйлөбө.• Оозуңдагыны жутуп, анан сүйлө.• Тамактанып жатып, тамактын кемчилигин: \\"тузу кем экен\\" же \\"жакшы бышпай калыптыр\\" деген сыяктуу сындарды айтпа. Антип айтуу менен кожойкени ыңгайсыз абалга калтырасың. \\"Тамак аябай даамдуу болуптур\\" деп унчукпай тамактана бер. • Чайды, суусундуктарды шорулдатып ичпе.• Эгер колуңдагы кашык, айрыны жерге түшүрүп алсаң кечирим сурап, тазасын сура. Анан да эмнеге түшүрүп алганыңды айтып актанба.• Тамакты жеп болгон соң оозуңду колуң же жеңиңдин учу менен аарчыбай, кол аарчыны пайдалан.• Дасторкондон турарда бата кылып, үй ээсине рахмат айтууну унутпа."},{"question":"કાંતિ અશોક ની \\"ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય \\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય,ના ના રે રહેવાય, ના ના રે સહેવાય,ના કોઈ ને કહેવાય..ઓઢણી ઉડે તો ભલે ઉડી જાય, x2તારું મુખડું મલકાય, તારું જોબન છલકાય, x2મારાં હૈયામાં કૈં કૈં થાય..ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય..ઓ રે ઓ રે મેઘ વરસે ને ભીંજે ચીર..હાય હાય હાય વાગે તીર, વાગે તીર.ઓ રે ઓ રે તારું ચંદંન સરીખું શરીર,હાય હાય હાય નીતરે નીર, નીતરે નીર.રૂપ દૂર થી જોવાય, ના ના રે અડકાય,ઇ તો અડતા કરમાય..ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય..ઓ.. મારે નેણ લજ્જા લહેરે છે..હો.. તારા રૂપ ની ભીનાશ તને ઘેરે છે.હું તો સંકોરુ કાય, અંગ અંગથી ભીંસાય,મને મરવાનું થાય..ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય..હાય રે.. ઓલી વીજળી કરે ચમકાર,હાય હાય હાય વારંવાર..ઓ રે.. ઈ તો હૈયાનાં સાંધે તાર,હોયે હોયે હોયે નમણી નાર..મારું મનડું મુંજાય, એવે લાગી રે લ્હાયના ના રે બુજાય..ઓઢણી ઓઢું ઓઢું ને ઉડી જાય.."},{"question":"Varginha (MG) é famosa por quê?","answer":"Varginha é um pequeno município brasileiro localizado na região sul do estado de Minas Gerais. A cidade se tornou famosa no Brasil em janeiro de 1996 quando o noticiário nacional noticiou que um grupo de crianças supostamente teriam visto um ser extraterrestre na cidade."},{"question":"د ملکي خدمتونو مامور د کومو حقوقو لرونکی ده ؟","answer":"ځواب – ۱ – له ضمایمو سره معاش ۲– رخصتي ۳ – ترفیع ۴ – تقاعد ۵ – ټوليز تامینات"},{"question":"மணியம்மையின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினைத்தரவும்.","answer":"கடவுளின் பெயராலும், மதத்தின் பெயராலும், சாஸ்திர சம்பிரதாயங்களின் பெயராலும் அறிவு ஆயுள் கைதியாக அடைக்கப்பட்டிருக்கிறது.மணியம்மைபல நூறு ஆண்டுகளாக மனுஸ்மிருதி தான் இந்தியாவை ஆண்டது. அதுதான் எல்லாவற்றையும் அடிமையாக்கியது. குறிப்பாக மானுட விடுதலைக்கு எதிரானதாக இருந்தது. மனிதனுக்கு, மனிதன்  ஏற்றத் தாழ்வையும், வேறுபாட்டையும் கற்பித்தது. பெண்களை சுயசிந்தனை அற்றவர்களாகவும், அவர்கள் எப்பொழுதும் ஆண்களைச் சார்ந்து இருக்க வேண்டும் எனவும் வற்புறுத்தியது. பால்ய விவாகத்தையும் வலியுறுத்தியது. இளம் விதவைகளையும் மோசமாக வழிநடத்தியது. கணவனை இழந்த பெண்கள் கைம்பெண்கள் என்றும், அவர்கள் கணவன் இறந்த பின்பு சதி என்னும் உடன்கட்டை ஏறும் வழக்கத்தைக் கொண்டிருக்கவும் வலியுறுத்தியது. உடன்கட்டை ஏற விரும்பாத பெண்களையும் வலிய கொண்டு சென்று தீயில் தள்ளியது. இக் கொடுமை உலகில் வேறு எந்த நாட்டிலும் நடந்ததாக வரலாறு இல்லை. மதத்தின் பெயரைச் சொல்லி பெண்களின் பூவையும், பொட்டையும், மஞ்சளையும் அழித்தது. ஆனால் இந்தக் கொடுமையில் ஆயிரத்தில் ஒரு பங்கு கூட ஆண்களுக்கு ஏற்படவில்லை. மட்டுமல்ல மனைவியை இழந்த ஆண்கள் புது மாப்பிள்ளையாகவும் பார்க்கப்பட்டனர். விபச்சாரம் என்ற சொல்லுக்கு ஆண்பால் இல்லை. விதவை என்கின்ற சொல்லுக்கும் ஆண்பால் இல்லை. இப்படி பல சொற்களுக்கு இலக்கியத்தில் பெயரளவிற்கு சொற்கள் கூட இல்லை.இந்தக் கொடுமையை எதிர்த்து ஆண்டாண்டு காலமாக சிந்தனையாளர்கள் போராடி வந்தனர். அவர்களுள் தந்தை பெரியார் மிக முக்கியமானவர். காலமெல்லாம் எதை எதிர்த்துப் போராடினாரோ, அதே காரணத்தை முன்வைத்து பெரியாரை விமர்சனம் என்ற பெயரில் தரம் தாழ்ந்து வசை பாடுகின்றனர்.பெண் விடுதலையில் பெரிதும் அக்கறை கொண்ட பெரியார் 40 வயது வித்தியாசத்தில், மணியம்மையை மறுமணம் செய்தது எந்த அளவிற்கு நியாயம் என்ற விமர்சனம் அவர் மீது வைக்கப்படுகிறது. அந்த காரணத்திற்காகத்தான் அண்ணாதுரை,  பெரியாரை விட்டுப் பிரிந்து சென்று திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகத்தைத் தோற்றுவித்தார். 'அவர் ஒரு பெண் பித்தர். தன் மகள் வயது உடைய மணியம்மையை மணந்து கொண்டார்' என்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகளுக்கு பதில் சொல்லும் தன்மையில் இவ்வாய்வுக் கட்டுரை அமைகிறது.பகுத்தறிவுக் கொள்கையால் பெரிதும் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டு, தந்தை பெரியார் மீது அன்பும், மரியாதையும் கொண்டவர் வேலூர் கனகசபை.  கனகசபைக்கும், பத்மாவதி அம்மையாருக்கும் மார்ச் மாதம் பத்தாம் நாள் 1920 ஆம் ஆண்டு பிறந்த பெண் குழந்தைக்கு இட்ட பெயர் காந்திமதி. அவர் பிறந்து வளர்ந்து வேலூரில் உள்ள உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் பள்ளிக் கல்வியை முடித்தார்.கனகசபை, தந்தை பெரியாருக்கு கடிதம் எழுதும் பழக்கம் கொண்டவர். ஒருநாள் பெரியாரை நலம் விசாரித்து கடிதம் எழுதினார். அதற்கு பெரியார் பதில் எழுதும் பொழுது, \\"எல்லோரும் தூர இருந்தபடி உடம்பை ஜாக்கிரதையாகப் பார்த்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள் என்கிறார்கள். ஆனால் கூட இருந்து உதவி செய்ய யாரும் இல்லை. என்னமோ? என் காலத்தை ஓட்டிக் கொண்டிருக்கிறேன்\\" என்று பதில் கடிதம் எழுதினார். இது நடந்தது 1943ஆம் ஆண்டு. இந்த சொற்கள் கனகசபையை என்னமோ செய்துவிட்டது. எப்பொழுதும் மதிப்பும், மரியாதையும், அன்பும் கொண்ட பெரியாருக்கு ஏற்பட்ட துயரத்தை எண்ணி வருந்தி தன்னுடைய மகள் காந்திமதியை அழைத்துச் சென்று, பெரியாரிடம் 'இனிமேல் இந்தப் பெண் உங்கள் கூட இருந்து, உங்களை கவனித்துக் கொள்வார்' எனச் சொல்லி, அன்று விட்டு வந்தவர்தான் அன்றைய காந்திமதியான,  இன்றைய மணியம்மை.காந்திமதி வருகைக்குப் பிறகு பெரியார் வாழ்க்கையில் மாற்றம் ஏற்பட்டது. புத்துணர்ச்சி உண்டாயிற்று. அதன் பிறகு கால் நூற்றாண்டு காலம் அவர் ஆயுள் நீட்டிப்பு உண்டானது. பகுத்தறிவு கொள்கைக்கு சற்றும் பொருத்தமற்ற மதத்தையும், சாதியையும் காரணம் காட்டி மக்களை பிளவுபடுத்தும் எண்ணத்திற்கு இன்னும் தீவிரமாக பணியாற்றத் தொடங்கினார். சாதிக் கொடுமையைப் போலவே, பெண் கொடுமையையும் இந்து மதம் ஆமோதிக்கிறது. அதனால் இந்து மத நம்பிக்கைகளையும், கொடுமைகளையும் வேரறுக்கவே இன்னும் தீவிரமாக செயல்பட்டார். இப்படி இந்திய சமூகத்தை பீடித்திருந்த நோயை தன் கைத்தடியாலும், வலிமையான சொற்களாலும் சம்மட்டி அடி தந்து நோயைக் குணப்படுத்தப் போராடினார்.மேலும் சாதி என்னும் கொடுநோயை விரட்டி விரட்டி வேட்டையாடினார். முன்பை விட இன்னும் மூர்க்கமாக களப்பணி ஆற்றினார். இவை எல்லாவற்றுக்கும் காரணம் மணியம்மையின் வருகை.  பெரியாரே, பின்வருமாறு பதிவு செய்கிறார். \\"இந்த வயதிலும் நான் சாகாமல் இருக்கிறேன் என்றால், இந்த அம்மாவால் என்பது யாருக்கும் தெரியாது. எனது உடம்புக்கு ஏற்ற உணவை பக்குவப்படி கொடுப்பது, உடை மாற்றுவது எல்லாம் இந்த அம்மா தான்\\" என்று மணியம்மையைப் பற்றி பதிவு செய்தது அனைத்தும் உண்மை. மணியம்மையை வாஞ்சையோடு பொது வெளியிலும், தனி வாழ்க்கையிலும் அம்மா என்றே அழைத்துள்ளார்.மணியம்மை சிறந்த பேச்சாளர், எழுத்தாளர், நிர்வாகத் திறமை மிக்கவர், சமூக சிந்தனையாளர், தொண்டுள்ளம் கொண்டவர், கடவுள் மறுப்பாளர், சாதி எதிர்ப்பாளர், மொழி போருக்காக  சிறைக்குச் சென்ற களப்போராளி, கண்டிப்பு மிக்கவர், தயாள எண்ணம் கொண்டவர், குழந்தைகளைப் பேணி பாதுகாக்கும் வகையில் காப்பகம் நடத்தியவர் என்று அவருக்கு பல முகங்கள் உண்டு.பெரியாரின் அறிமுகத்திற்கு முன்பே தன்னுடைய தந்தை கனகசபையின் பகுத்தறிவுக் கொள்கையால் ஈர்க்கப்பட்ட காந்திமதி, அரசியல் மணி என்றும் அறியப்பட்டார். கனகசபையின் நண்பர் அண்ணல்தாங்கோ என்பவர் அந்தக் காலத்தில் தென்னார்க்காடு மாவட்டத்தின் திராவிட இயக்கத் தலைவர்களில் ஒருவர். அவர்தான் முதன் முதலாக காந்திமதியை, அரசியல் மணி என்று அன்போடு அழைத்தார்.பெரியாரிடம் அறிமுகமான பிறகு அரசியல் மணியும்,  காந்திமதி என்னும் பெயரும் நாளடைவில் மறைந்து திராவிட இயக்கத்தைத் தோழர்கள் அன்போடு மணியம்மை என விரும்பி அழைக்கத் தொடங்கினர்.மணியம்மை தொடர்ந்து ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள் கூடவே இருந்து பெரியாருக்குத் தேவையான பணிவிடை வேலைகள் அனைத்தும் செய்து வந்தார். ஆனாலும் தன்னுடைய கல்வி ஆர்வத்திலும் அக்கறை செலுத்தினார்.குலசேகரப்பட்டினத்தில் உள்ள தமிழ்க் கல்லூரியில் தமிழ்ப் புலவர் பட்டப்படிப்பில் (B.Lit) சேர்ந்து பட்டம் பெற்றார். அவருக்கு இயல்பாகவே மொழி மீதும், இலக்கியத்தின் மீதும் ஆர்வம் அதிகமாக இருந்ததால் விருப்பத்தோடு படித்து பட்டப்படிப்பை நல்ல முறையில் படித்து முடித்தார்.அதன்பிறகு இயக்கப் பணிகளை மேற்கொள்ளும் தன்மையில் பொது வாழ்க்கையில் தன்னை இணைத்துக் கொண்டார். 1944 ஆம் ஆண்டு சேலத்தில் நடந்த திராவிடர் கழக மாநாட்டில் தன்னுடைய முதல் சொற்பொழிவை நிகழ்த்தினார்.திராவிடர் கழகம் வளர்ந்து பெரிய இயக்கமாக உருவாகி வந்தது. மக்களும் திராவிட இயக்கத்தின் பால் நம்பிக்கை கொண்டனர். பெரியாரின் பகுத்தறிவுக் கொள்கை பட்டிதொட்டி எங்கும் பரவத் தொடங்கியது. மக்களும் ஏன்? எதற்கு? எப்படி? என்ற கேள்விகள் கேட்டு பெரியாரின் சிந்தனைகளை செவிமடுக்கத் தொடங்கினர். இப்படி நம்பிக்கை கொண்ட மக்களை நல்வழிப்படுத்தும் எண்ணம் பெரியாருக்கு கடமையாக மாறியது. அந்தக் கடமை உணர்வை எண்ணி தனக்குப் பிறகு இந்த இயக்கத்தைக் கொண்டு செல்ல அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு மடை மாற்ற வேண்டிய தேவை இருந்தது.பெரியார் தனக்குப் பின்னர் இயக்கத்தைக் கொண்டு செல்வதற்கு பகுத்தறிவு சிந்தனையாளர், பெரியாரின் தொண்டர் அர்ஜுனன் என்பவரைத் தத்தெடுத்து அவரிடம் இயக்கத்தை ஒப்படைக்க விரும்பினார். ஆனால் அவர் பெரியாருக்கு முன்பாகவே இறந்துவிட்டார். அதன் பிறகு தன்னுடைய கொள்கை வாரிசாக அண்ணாதுரையை நம்பினார். 1948இல் ஈரோட்டில் நடந்த மாநாட்டில் தனக்குப் பிறகு அண்ணாதான், வழிநடத்தப் போகிறார் அதனால் பெட்டிச் சாவியை அண்ணாவிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப் போவதாக அறிவித்தார்.ஆனால் அண்ணாதுரை பெரியார் பெரிதும் வெறுத்த அரசியல் பாதையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்ததால் அவரை நம்ப மறுத்து விட்டார். அதன் பின்னர் தன்னுடைய அண்ணன் மகன் ஈ.வி.கி.சம்பத்தை பெரிதும் எதிர்பார்த்துக் காத்திருந்தார். அவரும் பெரியாரின் விருப்பத்திற்கு எதிராக நடந்து கொண்டதோடு வீட்டை விட்டு வெளியேறி அண்ணாதுரையின் பின் சென்றது அவர் மீது இன்னும் நம்பிக்கையின்மை வெளிப்படக் காரணமாக அமைந்தது.பெரியார் யாரை எல்லாம் நம்பினாரோ, அவர்களெல்லாம் அவருடைய நம்பிக்கைக்கு எதிராக மாறவே, இந்த தமிழ் சமுகத்தைக் கொண்டு செல்ல வேண்டிய கடமையை எண்ணி அவர் ஒரு முடிவுக்கு வர வேண்டிய சூழலுக்குத் தள்ளப் பட்டார். தன்னுடைய சொத்துக்களையும், இந்த அமைப்பையும் எடுத்துச் செல்வதற்கு நம்பிக்கையான ஒருவர் அவருக்கு தேவைப்பட்டார். தன்னுடைய வாரிசாக இருந்து சட்டப்படி கவனித்துக் கொள்ளவே மணியம்மையை 1949ஆம் ஆண்டு ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 9ஆம் நாள் திருமணம் செய்து கொண்டார். அப்பொழுது பெரியாரின் வயது 72. மணியம்மைக்கு 27 வயது. 40 வயது வித்தியாசத்தில் இருவரின் விருப்பத்துடன் திருமணம் நடந்தது.அந்தத் திருமணத்துக்குப் பிறகுதான் பெரியார் மீது ஆயிரக்கணக்கான வசை சொற்களும், அதே அளவிற்கு கேள்விகளும் எழத் தொடங்கின. அண்ணாதுரையும் திராவிடர் கழகத்தை விட்டு 1949ஆம் ஆண்டு, செப்டம்பர் 17ஆம் நாள் திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் என்ற அரசியல் கட்சியைத் தோற்றுவித்தார். இதனால் பொதுவெளியில் மணியம்மை மீது வைத்த விமர்சனங்கள் பெரிய களங்கத்தை உண்டாக்கியது. ஆனாலும் சற்றும் மனம் தளராமல் மணியம்மை, போற்றுவார் போற்றட்டும், புழுதிவாரி தூற்றுவார் தூற்றட்டும், ஏற்றதொரு கருத்தை துணிந்து சொல்வேன் என்று கொள்கைப் பிடிப்புடன் பயணம் செய்தார். பெரியாரின் வார்ப்பு  எப்படி இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பதற்கு மணியம்மை சான்று. எதைப் பற்றியும் கவலைப்படாமல், மற்றவர்களின் வன்மத்திற்கும் அச்சப்படாமல் தொடர்ந்து இயங்கிக் கொண்டு இருந்தார்.இதற்கிடையில் பெரியார் மணியம்மையை மறுமணம் செய்து கொள்ளாமல் மகளாகவே எண்ணி அவரிடம் இயக்கத்தையும், சொத்தையும் ஒப்படைத்து இருக்கலாம் என்ற வினாவும் எழுந்தன. ஆனால் அன்று இருந்த இந்து சட்டம் பெண்ணைத் தத்தெடுக்கவோ,  தத்து கொடுக்கவோ அனுமதிக்கவில்லை. மட்டுமல்ல பெண்களுக்கு சொத்துரிமை மறுக்கப்பட்ட காலம் அது. அந்தச் சூழலில்தான் பெரியார் முறையாக சட்டப்படி தன்னுடைய கொள்கைக் கோட்பாட்டுக்காக மணியம்மையைத் திருமணம் செய்ய வேண்டிய தேவை இருந்தது.பொதுவெளியில் பெரியார் மீது வைக்கும் விமர்சனம் ஒருவேளை நியாயமென்று ஏற்றுக்கொண்டாலும், பெரியார் பார்வையில் இருந்தும், மணியம்மை பார்வையிலிருந்தும் பார்க்கும் பொழுதும் அதே நியாயத்தை இச் சமூகம் ஏன் ஏற்க மறுக்கின்றது என்பது புரியாத புதிர். ஒருவேளை இந்து சட்டத்தில் பெண்ணை தத்தெடுக்கும் உரிமை  இருந்திருக்குமேயானால், அவர் திருமணம் செய்து கொள்ள வேண்டிய தேவை எழுந்திருக்காது என்ற புரிதல் ஏன் தோன்றவில்லை? அல்லது அந்த விவாதத்திற்கு ஏன் செல்ல மறுக்கிறார்கள் என்பதும் கேள்வியாக எழுகிறது. இது ஒரு சாதி இந்துவின் மனோநிலை. பெரியாரை எந்தக் கோணத்தில் அணுகினாலும் அவருடைய கேள்விக்கு பதில் சொல்ல முடியாதவர்கள் தான் அவரின் தனிப்பட்ட வாழ்க்கையில் மூக்கை நுழைக்கின்றனர். மணியமையும் அப்படி ஒன்றும் அறியாத பருவம் கொண்டவரல்ல. அவரும் பெரியாரின் பெண் விடுதலை, பகுத்தறிவுக் கொள்கையால் பெரிதும் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டவர்.பெரியாரின் அணுகுமுறையும், செயல்பாடும் தவறானது என்று நினைத்திருந்தால் அதைப் பெரியாரிடமே கேட்கும் அளவிற்குத் துணிவு கொண்டு இருந்தார். அவர் காலத்தில் கேட்கவில்லை என்றாலும் பெரியாரின் மறைவுக்குப் பிறகாவது அந்தக் கேள்வியை கேட்டிருக்க முடியும். ஆனால் எங்குமே மனம் கசந்து பெரியாரை நம்பி நான் மோசம் போய்விட்டேன் அல்லது பெரியார் தன்னை நம்ப வைத்து கழுத்தை அறுத்து விட்டார் என்று சொல்லவில்லை.உண்மையில் இருபத்தி ஏழு வயதில் தான் கொண்ட கொள்கைக்காக இந்த தமிழ்ச் சமூகத்திற்காக தன்னுடைய இளமையையும் வாழ்க்கையையும் தியாகம் செய்திருக்கிறார்.பெரியாரின் மனைவி இறந்து 16 ஆண்டுகள் கழித்து 72 வயதில் மறுமணம் செய்து கொண்டபோது உடல் தேவைக்காக மணந்து கொண்டார் என்று சொல்வதில் எந்த அர்த்தமும் இருப்பதாகத் தோன்றவில்லை. பெரியார் நினைத்திருந்தால் நாகம்மையார் இறந்தவுடன் இரண்டாவது திருமணம் செய்திருக்க முடியும். ஆனால் அதை விடுத்து தள்ளாடும் வயதில் கிழவனான போது மறுமணம் செய்துகொள்வது சமூக தேவைக்காகத்தான். அதைப் பெரியாரே, \\"என்னைச் சுற்றி இருக்கும் தோழர்களிடம் நான் எவ்வளவு சகிப்புத்தன்மையோடு பழகினாலும், அவைகளை என் பலவீனமாகவும், ஏமாந்த தனமாகவும் கருதிக்கொண்டு நான் பயப்படும் வண்ணமாய் பெரிதும் அவநம்பிக்கை கொள்ளும் வண்ணமுமாய் நடந்து வருவதை உணர்கிறேன்\\" என்று கூறுகியுள்ளார்.ஆயினும் அண்ணாதுரை, பெரியாரை விட்டுப் பிரிந்து செல்வதற்கு மணியம்மையின் திருமணத்தை மட்டும் காரணம் காட்டுகின்றனர். ஆனால் அது மட்டும் உண்மை இல்லை. அண்ணா பெரியாரை விட்டுச் செல்வதற்கு பல காரணங்கள் சொல்லப்பட்டாலும் முக்கியமான நான்கு காரணங்களைக் கூற முடியும்.இந்திய விடுதலையை பெரியார் கருப்பு தினம் என்றார். ஆனால் இந்திய விடுதலையை வரவேற்றார்.அண்ணாவிற்கு தேர்தல் அரசியல் பாதையில் நாட்டம் இருந்தது.மணியம்மையின் திருமணம்பெரியார் கடவுள் மறுப்பில் இருந்தபோதும், அரசியல் தேவைக்காக 'ஒன்றே குலம் ஒருவனே தேவன்' என்ற முழக்கத்தை ஆதரித்தவர் அண்ணாதுரை.இப்படி நான்கு காரணங்கள் தான் முக்கியமானதாக இருந்தன. ஒருவேளை மணியம்மையை திருமணம் செய்து கொள்ளவில்லை என்றாலும், அண்ணாதுரை திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகத்தை உறுதியாகத் தொடங்கி இருப்பார். இந்தக் காரணங்களை முன்வைத்து 1949 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் 17-ஆம் நாள் திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகம் உதயமானது.ஒரு பக்கம் திராவிட இயக்கத்தில் பெரிய அளவிற்கு பாதிப்பு ஏற்பட்டு இயக்கம் உடையும் போது மணியம்மை சற்றும் மனம் தளராமல் தான் கொண்ட கொள்கையில் பின்வாங்காமல் முன்னேறிக் கொண்டே சென்றார்.பெரியாருடன் இருக்கும் பொழுதும், பெரியார் இறந்த பின்பும் மணியம்மையின் சமூகப் பொறுப்பு இன்னும் கூடுதலாக இருந்தது. தன் இயக்கத்தை கட்டிக் காப்பாற்றுவதற்கு கவனமாக செயல்பட வேண்டிய தேவை இருந்தது.1948ஆம் ஆண்டு அன்றைய அரசு விதித்திருந்த தடைச் சட்டத்தை மீறி மணியம்மை செயல்பட்டார் என்பதற்காக கைது செய்து மூன்று மாதங்கள் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டார்.இந்தித் திணிப்பை எதிர்த்து அன்றைய அரசுக்கு எதிராகவும், இந்தித் திணிப்புக்கு எதிராகவும் 1958-ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனவரி மாதம் 19 ஆம் நாள் \\"இளந்தமிழா புறப்படு போருக்கு\\" என்ற தலைப்பில் கட்டுரை எழுதிய குற்றத்திற்காக கைது செய்து ஒரு மாதம் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டார்.1974ஆம் ஆண்டு டெல்லியில் \\"ராம லீலை\\" நடத்தி ராவணனின் உருவத்தை எரிக்கும் நிகழ்ச்சியில் அன்றைய பிரதமராக இருந்த இந்திரா காந்தி, குடியரசுத் தலைவர் பக்ருதீன் அலி அகமது கலந்து கொள்ளக்கூடாது என்று மணியம்மை வேண்டுகோள் விடுத்தார். அதையும் மீறி அவர்கள் கலந்து கொண்டார்கள்.அந்தக் காரணத்தை முன்வைத்து ராவணன் திராவிடத்தின் அடையாளம், திராவிடத்தை இழிவு செய்தது தவறு, அதனால் அதைக் கண்டிக்கும் விதமாக 1974 டிசம்பர் 25ஆம் நாள் சென்னையில் \\"ராவண லீலை\\" திராவிட கழகத்தின் சார்பில் கொண்டாடப்பட்டது.  அந்த நிகழ்விற்கு மணியம்மை தலைமை தாங்கினார். இப்படி பெரியாரின் கொள்கையில் வாரிசாகவும், கைத்தடியாகவும் இருந்து செயல்பட்டது மறுக்க முடியாது.அவசரகாலப் பிரகடனம் அறிவித்து நெருக்கடி நிலையின் காரணமாக அன்றைக்கு எதிர்க் கட்சித் தலைவர்களையும், சமூகச் சிந்தனையாளர்களையும் அன்றைய அரசாங்கம் கைது செய்தது. அப்பொழுது  1976 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஜனவரி 30 ஆம் நாள் மணியம்மையும் கைது செய்து சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டார். 1977 ஆம் ஆண்டு அக்டோபர் மாதம் பிரதமர் இந்திரா காந்தி அம்மையார் சென்னைக்கு வருகை தந்தபோது கருப்புக்கொடி காட்டி எதிர்ப்பு தெரிவித்ததற்காக கைது செய்து சிறையில் தள்ளப்பட்டார்.இப்படி எல்லா வகையிலும் பெரியாரின் மனைவியாகவும், தொண்டராகவும் இருந்து இயக்கப் பணிகளை தொடர்ந்து முன்னெடுத்துச் சென்றார். பெரியார் பல இடங்களில் தேவையற்ற வீண் செலவு என மறுத்ததை எல்லாம் அவற்றின் நன்மைகளை எடுத்துச் சொல்லி நல்ல ஆலோசகராகவும் இருந்து வழி நடத்தினார். திருச்சியில் உருவாகிய கல்வி நிறுவனங்களையும், குழந்தைகள் காப்பகத்தையும் மணியம்மை திறம்பட நிர்வகித்து உள்ளார்.கல்வி நிறுவனம், குழந்தைகள் காப்பகம், பத்திரிக்கைத்துறை எல்லாவற்றிலும் தன்னுடைய அழுத்தமான திறமையால் முத்திரை பதித்தவர் மணியம்மை. பெண்கள் பொதுவெளியில் இயங்குவதற்கும், தங்கள் கருத்தை துணிந்து சொல்வதற்கும் பகுத்தறிவு இயக்கம் எந்த அளவிற்கு முக்கியமோ, அதே அளவிற்கு பெரியார் கட்டிக் காப்பாற்றிய இயக்கத்தை ஜனரஞ்சகமாக கொண்டு சென்ற பெருமை மணியம்மைக்கு உண்டு.பெரியார் - மணியம்மை திருமணம் அவர்களது சொந்த ஆசாபசங்களுக்காக அல்ல‌, திராவிடர் கழகத்திற்காக,  அதன் இயக்கத்திற்காக நடந்த திருமணம். பணத்தையோ,  சொத்தையோ காரணம் காட்டி விருப்பம் இல்லாத ஓர் இளம்பெண்ணை முதியவர் ஒருவர் கட்டாயத் திருமணம் செய்து கொண்டதைப் போன்ற கருத்து எப்படி உருவாகியது? காரணம் தந்தை பெரியார் காலம் முழுவதும் பெண்ணடிமை தனத்தை எதிர்த்து, சாதிக் கொடுமையை எதிர்த்து, இவற்றுக்கு ஊற்றுக்கண்ணாக திகழும் இந்து மதத்தை எதிர்த்தார் என்பதனால்தான். அந்த சாதி இந்து மனநிலையில்தான் பெரியார் - மணியம்மை திருமணம் எதிர்க்கப்படுகிறது.ஆனாலும் பெரியாரின் மறைவிற்குப் பிறகும், பகுத்தறிவு இயக்கத்தின் தூணாகவும், முன்னோடித் தொண்டராகவும் இருந்து வழிநடத்தியவர் தான் தோழர் மணியம்மை."},{"question":"It is essential","answer":"It is essential to get a deeper understanding of what is obtainable here. Humans are formed by the Word, which makes words powerful. The truth is, many do not have a clue of how powerful it could be, they feel it can just be uttered based on emotions or circumstances around an event.The word himself said ' The word I speak to you, they are spirit and life'.How many consider that which comes out of their mouth?How many process what they have to say and the consequences of its outcome when uttered?How many knows that what they air or listen to affect their decision on words uttered?How many knows that what is uttered is predominant over time in them, awaiting a time of output?How many knows that their next phase of life, is determined by the choice of words in every situation?How many knows that the enemy is awaiting that negative utterance to create an avenue into the soul of man?It is therefore paramount to filter everything and anything made of words (music, messages, gist, conversations, videos, etc) as it is capable of dictating your greatness or your declination. Death and life lies in the power of the tongue. Do not allow negative utterances opt out of you at distress moments, always be calm (be swift to listen, but be slow to speak)."},{"question":"தோற்றம் – இச்சொல்லின் எதிர்ச் சொல் ________________(அ) தொடக்கம்(ஆ) மறைவு(இ) முதல்(ஈ) ஆரம்பம்","answer":"தோற்றம் – இச்சொல்லின் எதிர்ச் சொல் ___(ஆ) மறைவு"},{"question":"من هو الصحابي الذي لقب بسيف الله المسلول ؟","answer":"الإجابة هي : خالد بن الوليد ."},{"question":"nu gëblag Danmaark tudd?","answer":"Kopenaag."},{"question":"س194- كم عدد الأولاد الذكور للملك عبد العزيز ؟","answer":"ج194- 36 ذكر"},{"question":"Con gì ăn cỏĐầu có 2 sừngLỗ mũi buộc thừngKéo cày rất giỏi","answer":"Đáp án:Con trâu"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air jernih, ikannya jinak\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud negeri yang maju dan aman, rakyatnya berbudi bahasa"},{"question":"እቴጌ ጣይቱ በምን ሙያ ይታወቁ ነበር?","answer":"በበገና ቅኝትና ድርደራ"},{"question":"Jakie nominały są najczęściej używane w Stanach Zjednoczonych?","answer":"W Stanych Zjednoczonych oficjalną walutą jest dolar amerykański i najczęściej używane są nominały: 1, 5, 10, 20, 50, 100."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的運河是哪一條？","answer":"答案：中國的京杭大運河"},{"question":"Qual é a resposta correta para esta pergunta?  Qual foi o ato terrorista mais mortal em solo norte-americano?","answer":"A resposta correta para a pergunta é \\"ataques de 11 de setembro\\". Os ataques ou atentados terroristas de 11 de setembro de 2001 (às vezes, referido apenas como 11 de setembro ou 9/11) foram uma série de ataques suicidas contra os Estados Unidos coordenados pela organização fundamentalista islâmica Al-Qaeda em 11 de setembro de 2001. Na manhã daquele dia, dezenove terroristas sequestraram quatro aviões comerciais de passageiros."},{"question":"கேள்வி: சிதறல் என்றால் என்ன? சிதறல் ஏன் நிகழ்கிறது?","answer":"சரியான பதில்: வெள்ளை ஒளி ஏழு வண்ணங்களாகப் பிரிக்கப்படும் இயற்கை நிகழ்வு சிதறல் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. வெள்ளை ஒளியை அதன் கூறுகளில் சிதறடிப்பது அடிப்படையில் வெவ்வேறு அலைநீளங்களின் ஒளியின் வேகத்தில் ஏற்படும் மாற்றத்தால் ஒளி கடந்து செல்லும் பொருள்கள் அல்லது சுற்றுப்புறங்களின் அடர்த்தியில் ஏற்படும் மாற்றத்தால் ஏற்படுகிறது. "},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Tối 31/7, Đoàn Thu Thủy được xướng tên ở ngôi vị cao nhất trong đêm chung kết cuộc thi Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam 2022 tại TP. HCM. Danh hiệu á hậu 2 thuộc về thí sinh Chu Thị Ánh, á hậu 1 là Lê Phương Thảo. Ngay sau khoảnh khắc đăng quang, top 3 đã có cuộc giao lưu ngắn với báo chí để chia sẻ và giải đáp các thông tin liên quan đến bản thân. Nhận được câu hỏi: \\"Hiện tại, trên mạng xã hội có một video về bạn liên quan đến bóng cười. Cảm xúc của bạn thế nào khi phải đón nhận những thông tin không rõ thực hư về bản thân mình sau chiến thắng tại cuộc thi và có thể cam kết với tư cách là Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam về lối sống thực sự lành mạnh hay không?\\". Tân hoa hậu trả lời: \\"Thật sự, đây là câu hỏi tôi mong muốn có cơ hội để trả lời. Đối với tôi, khi nhận được thông tin về clip đó, tôi khá bất ngờ và sốc. Đó là bài học rất lớn đối với tôi. Nhưng ở cương vị của một công dân, tôi cam kết nếu đã làm việc gì trái pháp luật sẽ sẵn sàng đứng ra chịu trách nhiệm. Với cương vị là thí sinh trong cuộc thi Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam 2022, hướng đến lối sống lành mạnh, tôi cũng cam kết sẽ thay đổi lối sống của mình, không hướng đến sự tích cực tôi sẽ chịu trách nhiệm. Và thứ 3, với cương vị là người con và chị gái trong gia đình, tôi muốn chia sẻ chân thành khi một sự thật tôi nói ra nếu khiến mọi người có nhìn nhận và đánh giá không đúng về người khác thì một nửa sự thật","answer":"không phải là sự thật. Em trai tôi ở độ tuổi mới lớn, đang phát triển, đôi khi cách nói chuyện không được rõ ràng, khiến bố mẹ phải suy nghĩ sai hoặc không đúng về những vấn đề nhỏ nhặt. Tôi chính là người nhắc em trai về vấn đề đó, nhưng chuyện trong gia đình khi đưa lên truyền thông thì mức độ nghiêm trọng lại lớn hơn. Đây là vấn đề tôi cảm thấy rất cấp thiết, giống như \\"món ăn tinh thần\\" và chúng ta nên biết cách chọn lọc và kiểm chứng xem thông tin đó đã chính xác hay chưa, liệu có ảnh hưởng đến người khác hay không\\". Thu Thủy nhận mình là người trong clip nhưng trước đây, hiện tại và cả tương lai, cô cam kết chưa từng sử dụng chất kích thích ảnh hưởng đến sức khỏe. Cô không sử dụng bóng cười nhưng đây cũng là bài học lớn đối với cô ở thời điểm hiện tại. \\"Từ trước tới nay, tôi chưa bao giờ đánh giá, phán xét, can thiệp vào đời tư hay sự lựa chọn của những bạn bè xung quanh. Mỗi người có một cuộc sống và cách giải quyết, giải trí khác nhau và có thể cách giải trí khác với của tôi mà đối với nhiều người, điều đó chưa đúng đắn, chưa tốt và lành mạnh nhưng tôi chưa bao giờ đứng ra khuyên bạn bè không được làm như vậy. Với cương vị và trọng trách mới trong thời gian tới, tôi không chỉ xây dựng lối sống lành mạnh riêng, mà sẽ cố gắng sử dụng tiếng nói, hành động để có thể tạo ra cộng đồng xung quanh lành mạnh, tích cực hơn, để những hình ảnh như mọi người đã thấy sẽ không còn nữa\\", tân hoa hậu cho biết. Thiện Nhân - Hiệp Hà"},{"question":"Waa kuwee 10-ka dal ee Afrika ugu awooda badan dhanka milatariga sanadkan?","answer":"10-ka dal ee Afrika ugu awooda badan dhanka milatariga sanadkan waa1:Masar2:Al-jeeriya3:Koonfur Afrika4:Nigeria5:Itoobiya6;Angola7:Morooko8:Suudaan9:Jamhuuriyadda Dimuqraadiga ah ee Koongo10:Liibiya."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: ഇന്ത്യയുടെ വിഭജനം എന്തായിരുന്നു?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: 1947-ൽ നടന്ന ഇന്ത്യയുടെ വിഭജനം, ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് ഇന്ത്യയെ രണ്ട് വ്യത്യസ്ത രാഷ്ട്രങ്ങളായി വിഭജിക്കുകയായിരുന്നു: ഇന്ത്യയും പാകിസ്ഥാനും. ഈ വിഭജനം മതപരമായ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലായിരുന്നു, ഇന്ത്യ പ്രധാനമായും ഹിന്ദു ഭൂരിപക്ഷ രാഷ്ട്രമായതിനാൽ പാകിസ്ഥാൻ മുസ്ലീം ഭൂരിപക്ഷ രാഷ്ട്രമായി സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ടു."},{"question":"Idajọ iku lo yẹ kijọba maa fun apaniṣowo atawọn to ba kowo jẹ-Oluwoo","answer":"Oluwoo tilẹ Iwo, Ọba Abdulrasheed Adewale Akanbi, ti gba Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari nimọran pe ọna abayọ kan ṣoṣo ti orileede yii ko fi ni i fọ si wẹwẹ ni ki Aarẹ ri i pe oun pin in daadaa, oun si fun ẹya kọkọkan ni ohun to tọ si wọn lai ṣegbe tabi gbe lẹyin eya mi-in lori ọrọ pinpin awọn ipo tabi aaye to ba ṣi silẹ ni Naijiria.Ọba Akanbi ni ki Buhari pin awọn ipo tabi aaye to ba ṣi silẹ nieeṣẹ ijọba apapọ ni dọngba-n-dọgba. O rọ Buhari lati wẹyin wo, ko ṣe akiyesi awọn eeyan to ti yan sipo, ko si ṣe atunṣe nibi to ba ti yẹ. O ni eyi ni ọkan ninu ọna lati mu ki okun iṣọkan Naijiria yi da-in-dan-in si i, ki iṣọkan wa si le duro.Ọba Akanbi sọrọ yii niluu Abuja, nibi ifilọlẹ iwe mẹrin ti agbẹjọro agba kan Amofin Aminu Kayọde Aliu kọ.  Bakan naa ni ọba yii rọ awọn ọmọ orileede yii lati fẹran ara wọn, ki wọn si wa ni iṣọkan. O tun koro oju si bi awọn eeyan ṣe n dẹyẹ si ẹya Fulani, o rọ awọn ọmọ orileede yii lati nifẹẹ ara wọn lai fi ti ẹya, ẹsin ede tabi ẹgbẹ oṣelu ti iru ẹni bẹẹ n ṣe.O waa rọ ijọba lati ṣagbeyẹwo awọn iwa ojududu ti ko ba aye ode oni mu mọ ti wọn ba n ṣe. Bẹẹ lo rọ awọn ọdọ lati fi suuru ati ọna to tọ beere ohun ti wọn ba fẹ.Nigba to n sọrọ nipa ọrọ awọn Fulani darandaran, Oluwoo ni a jogun wahala awọn Fulani ni, a si pa wọn ti sinu igbo fun ọdun pipẹ, bẹẹ ni ohun amayedẹrun jinna si wọn. Eyi lo mu ki ọpọlọpọ wọn da bii maaluu ti wọn n sin, a si waa n ba wọn ja, nnkan meji ni, ninu ka pa gbogbo wọn patapata tabi ka fi ifẹ han si wọn.Bakan naa lo tun gba ijọba nimọran pe ki wọn maa dajọ iku fun awọn apaniṣowo atawọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba ti wọn ba ti gba mu fun ẹsun ikowojẹ tabi iwa ibajẹ kan.  Oluwoo kọminu si bi iwa awọn apaniṣowo ṣe pọ kaakiri lorileede yii. O ni nipa pipa awọn eeyan yii yoo mu ki ilẹ Naijiria wa laarin awọn orileede to ti goke agba lagbaaye.O fi kun un pe gbogbo awọn orileede to ti goke agba, ateyi to ṣẹṣẹ n goke ni lati pasẹ ijiya to gbopọn fun awọn oniwa ibajẹ."},{"question":"Qual è la risposta corretta alla seguente domanda: Il primo gioco di Call of Duty è incentrato sulla prima guerra mondiale?","answer":"La risposta corretta alla domanda è: No, il primo gioco del franchise Call of Duty è ambientato nella seconda guerra mondiale."},{"question":"வினா :உலகின் மிகப் பெரிய பேரரசு எது?","answer":"விடை :உலகின் மிகப் பெரிய பேரரசு பிரித்தானிய பேரரசு. இந்தப் பேரரசு சுமார் 1900 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு தோன்றியது. இந்தப் பேரரசு உலகின் பெரும்பாலான பகுதிகளை ஆட்சி செய்தது. இந்தப் பேரரசு உலக வரலாற்றில் மிக முக்கியமான பங்கு வகித்தது."},{"question":"આદિવાસી સંસ્કૃતિ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"આદિકાળથી ગાઢ જંગલ કે દુર્ગમ પ્રદેશના અંતરિયાળ વિસ્તારમાં વસવાટ કરતા લોકોને ભારતમાં આદિવાસી તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. વિશ્વફલક પર એમને મૂળ વસાહતીઓ તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે.ભારત સરકારના બંધારણમાં આદિવાસીઓને અનુસૂચિત જનજાતિ તરીકેનો દરજ્જો આપવામાં આવેલ છે. આ દરજ્જાને કારણે ઘણા આદિવાસીઓ ભણીગણીને પોતાનો વિકાસ સાધી શક્યા છે, પરંતુ હજુ પણ મોટા ભાગના અંતરિયાળ તેમ જ દુર્ગમ વિસ્તારોમાં સદીઓથી રહેતા આદિવાસીઓ, સગવડોથી વંચિત રહેવાને કારણે આજે પણ ગરીબી અને અજ્ઞાનતામાં જીવે છે.ગુજરાત રાજ્યના આદિવાસીઓ એમના ખડતલ તેમ જ ચપળ શરીર માટે જાણીતા છે. ગુજરાત રાજ્યની પૂર્વ સરહદના વિસ્તારોમાં મુખ્યત્વે આદિવાસીઓ વસવાટ કરે છે. ગુજરાતના આદિવાસીઓમાં મુખ્યત્વે ચૌધરી, કૂકણા, તડવી,વારલી, ધોડિયા, ગામિત, વસાવા, ભીલ, નિનામા, રાઠવા, નાયકા, હળપતિ, ડામોર, કટારા, તાવિયાડ, કોટવાળીયા વગેરેનો સમાવેશ થાય છે."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:“Andriamanitra _ fa i Balita no tsy _”","answer":"“Andriamanitra nanome fa i Balita no tsy nambinina”"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ॥ਘੋਖੇ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਬੇਦ ਸਭ ਆਨ ਨ ਕਥਤਉ ਕੋਇ ॥ਆਦਿ ਜੁਗਾਦੀ ਹੁਣਿ ਹੋਵਤ ਨਾਨਕ ਏਕੈ ਸੋਇ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 254 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਾਰੇ ਵੇਦ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਵੇਖੇ ਹਨ, ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਖਦਾ ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਭੀ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਹੈ, ਜੁਗਾਂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਹੈ, ਹੁਣ ਭੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਰਹੇਗਾ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"２位、３位の選手がドーピングにより失格となり、北京オリンピック銅メダル獲得となった男子ハンマー投げの選手といえば誰？","answer":"室伏広治（むろふしこうじ）です。"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Alemaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Alemaina dia Berlin."},{"question":"Quem pintou o quadro Guernica?","answer":"Com 349 cm de altura por 776,5 cm de comprimento, Guernica, uma das obras mais famosas de Pablo Picasso (1881–1973), pintada a óleo em 1937, é uma “declaração de guerra contra a guerra e um manifesto contra a violência”. O quadro, além de ser um ícone da Guerra Civil Espanhola, é hoje um símbolo do antimilitarismo mundial e da luta pela liberdade do ser humano."},{"question":"СЕЛФИ ДЕГЕН ЭМНЕ?","answer":"Бул сөз 2013-жылдан бери дүйнө жүзүндө популярдуу болуп келет. Селфи же өзүн-өзү сүрөткө тартуу башында күзгүнүн жардамы менен тартылып келсе, учурда моноподдун, селфи таякчанын жардамы менен ишке ашырылат.СЕЛФИНИН ТҮРЛӨРҮ•\\tРелфи – сүйүктүүң менен чогуу сүрөткө түшүү;•\\tЛифтлук – лифттеги күзгүдөн өзүңдү тартуу;•\\tДакфейс – «өрдөк жүз» же оозун чормойтуп түшүү;•\\tБелфи – өзүнүн жамбашын тартуу;•\\tШуфиз – бутун жана бут кийимин тартуу;•\\tЭкстрим-селфи – бийик имараттарда, аска сыяктуу кооптуу жайларда жана спорттун экстремалдык түрлөрүндө сүрөткө түшүү."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa caasimadda dalka  Qatar?","answer":"Caasimadda dalka  Qatar waa DOHA."},{"question":"ما عدد المرات التي تم ذكر السيدة مريم في القرآن الكريم؟، (43 مرة،   55 مرة، 42 مرة، 34 مرة)","answer":"الإجابة: 34 مرة"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Hans von Euler-Chelpin. ","answer":"Ceimicí Sualannach a saolaíodh sa Ghearmáin ab ea Hans Karl August Simon von Euler-Chelpin (1873-1964). Roinn sé Duais Nobel na Ceimice le Arthur Harden i 1929 as a shaothar ar choipeadh siúcra is ceimic na n-einsímí coipthe."},{"question":"Apakah soalan kepada: \\"Contohnya, dalam kalendar Gregorian (kalendar solar biasa), Februari dalam tahun lompat mempunyai 29 hari bukannya 28 hari seperti biasa, jadi tahun lompat mempunyai 366 hari sejumlahnya dan bukan 365 seperti tahun biasa\\"? Topiknya adalah tahun lompat.","answer":"\\"Berapakah hari dalam tahun lompat?\\""},{"question":"Please explain RNNs briefly.","answer":"By compiling the data of previous tokens at a previous timestep, RNN models are able to learn the representation of each token and, at the final timestep, the representation of a sentence. Numerous benefits have been observed for this technique, which are listed below:• To begin with, RNN can be rebuilt for language generation in a one-to-many paradigm or the generation of music.Secondly, sentiment analysis and text classification can be done with many-to-one models.examination.Lastly, for NER difficulties, many-to-many models are employed. The subsequent application utilizing many-to-many models is to address encoder-decoder issues like machine translation, responding to inquiries, and summarizing texts."},{"question":"Alparslan Ünalı vuruyor kaçıncı bölüm?","answer":"EDHO 63.BÖLÜM | Alparslan Ünal'ı Vuruyor!"},{"question":"નીચેના રૂઢિપ્રયોગ નો અર્થ આપો:ધૂળમાં મળવું","answer":"કરેલા પ્રયત્નો નિષ્ફળ બનાવવા "},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: నిట్టవొడుచు","answer":"ఉప్పొంగు, రోమాంచితం, విజృంభించు"},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Cho tập A={1; −2; 3; 4}. Có bao nhiêu phân số có tử số và mẫu số thuộc A mà có tử số khác mẫu số và tử số trái dấu với mẫu số?A. 9     B. 6  C. 3D. 12","answer":"Trả lời:Có tất cả 6 phân số.Đáp án cần chọn là: B"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bahasa dalam\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud bahasa khas yang diguna oleh golongan istana."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: 11 mars 2011 drabbades Miyako av en tsunami efter","answer":"en jordbävning vid Tohoku. Tsunamivågen, som beräknades vara 37,8 meter hög, svämmade över den skyddsvall som fanns vid hamnen och vattnet nådde därmed in i staden. Stora delar av Miyakos byggnader och fiskeflotta förstördes. Mer än 600 människor rapporterades ha dött."},{"question":"હું શૈક્ષણિક લેખનમાં મારા વાક્યોના પ્રવાહને કેવી રીતે સુધારી શકું?","answer":"ખાતરી કરો કે દરેક વાક્ય તેના પહેલા અને પછીના એક સાથે તાર્કિક રીતે જોડાય છે. તમારા વિચારો દ્વારા વાચકોને માર્ગદર્શન આપવા માટે સંક્રમણ શબ્દોનો ઉપયોગ કરો.સંક્રમણ શબ્દોનો ઉપયોગ:ફકરામાં વિચારોને જોડવાથી તમારા લેખનનો પ્રવાહ વધુ સરળ બનશે. \\"જો કે,\\" \\"તેથી,\\" અથવા \\"વિપરીત\\" જેવા સંક્રમણ શબ્દોનો ઉપયોગ કરો. વધુમાં, તમે એક વાક્યમાં બે અલગ અલગ વિષયોની તુલના કરવા માટે \\"બીજી તરફ\\" જેવા શબ્દસમૂહોનો ઉપયોગ કરી શકો છો. સંક્રમણ શબ્દો વાચકોને તમારી વિચાર પ્રક્રિયા સાથે અનુસરવાની સરળ રીત આપે છે.સંક્રમણો વાચકોને તમારા વિચારોના પ્રવાહને સમજવામાં મદદ કરે છે અને તેમને અનુસરવા માટે રોડમેપ આપે છે. ઉદાહરણોમાં નીચેનાનો સમાવેશ થાય છે: પરિણામે, તે જ રીતે, વધુમાં, તેથી, વગેરે. તેઓ માત્ર વાચકને વ્યસ્ત રાખશે જ નહીં પરંતુ તેઓ તમારા લેખનમાં માળખું પણ ઉમેરશે.જો કે, ઘણા બધા સંક્રમણો તમારા લેખનને અસ્પષ્ટ બનાવી શકે છે. અને, જો તમે અમુક સંક્રમણ શબ્દોનો વધુ પડતો ઉપયોગ કરો છો, તો તમારું લખાણ પુનરાવર્તિત થવાનું શરૂ થઈ શકે છે. જો તમે તમારી જાતને એક પંક્તિમાં એક જ સંક્રમણ શબ્દનો ઘણી વખત ઉપયોગ કરતા જણાય, તો ઉપયોગ કરવા માટે કોઈ અલગ શબ્દ શોધવાનો પ્રયાસ કરો, અથવા તમારા વાક્યને ફરીથી લખો જેથી સંક્રમણની જરૂર ન રહે."},{"question":"በአማርኛ ቋንቋ አንድ የፊደል ቤት በውስጡ ስንት ፊደላት ይይዛል?1. አስራ ሁለት2. አስራ አራት  3. ስድስት4. ሰባት","answer":"አማራጭ 4- አንድ የፊደል ቤት በውስጡ ሰባት ፊደላት ይይዛል።"},{"question":"ஐந்து கடல்களின் நாடு என்றழைக்கப்படுவது எது?","answer":"ஆஸ்திரேலியா ஒரு தீவு மற்றும் 5 கடல்களுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதால் ஐந்து கடல்களின் நிலம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ఇతర మతాలకు చెందిన ప్రాంతాలకు నీవెప్పుడైనా వెళ్ళావా? అక్కడ నీవు గమనించిన మంచి విషయాలు ఏవి? ఏ సారూప్యతలు నీవు గమనించావు?","answer":"ఇతర మతాలకు చెందిన ప్రాంతాలకు నేను తరచుగా వెళతాను.అక్కడ గమనించిన మంచి విషయాలు :వారు అందరూ కలసి మెలసి ఉంటూ, నన్ను కూడా కలుపుకున్నారు.వారు వారి పెద్దలను గౌరవిస్తూ, వారు చెప్పేది శ్రద్ధగా పాటిస్తున్నారు.వారి పరిసరాలు పరిశుభ్రంగా ఉంచుతూ, శుభ్రతకు ప్రాధాన్యత ఇస్తున్నారు.అందరి మంచిని కోరుకుంటున్నారు. (సర్వేజనా సుఖినోభవంతు అని)గమనించిన సారుప్యతలు :అందరి భావాలు దేవుడు ఒక్కడే అని చెబుతున్నాయి.ప్రేమతత్వాన్ని బోధిస్తున్నాయి.తోటి ప్రాణి మంచిని కోరుతున్నారు.పాప, పుణ్యాల గురించి తెల్పుతున్నాయి."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਿਆਨ ਖੰਡ ਮਹਿ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਪਰਚੰਡੁ ॥ਤਿਥੈ ਨਾਦ ਬਿਨੋਦ ਕੋਡ ਅਨੰਦੁ ॥ਸਰਮ ਖੰਡ ਕੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਰੂਪੁ ॥ਤਿਥੈ ਘਾੜਤਿ ਘੜੀਐ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਅਨੂਪੁ ॥ਤਾ ਕੀਆ ਗਲਾ ਕਥੀਆ ਨਾ ਜਾਹਿ ॥ਜੇ ਕੋ ਕਹੈ ਪਿਛੈ ਪਛੁਤਾਇ ॥ਤਿਥੈ ਘੜੀਐ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਮਤਿ ਮਨਿ ਬੁਧਿ ॥ਤਿਥੈ ਘੜੀਐ ਸੁਰਾ ਸਿਧਾ ਕੀ ਸੁਧਿ ॥੩੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 7 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਗਿਆਨ ਖੰਡ ਵਿਚ (ਭਾਵ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਗਿਆਨ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ) ਗਿਆਨ ਹੀ ਬਲਵਾਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਸਭ ਰਾਗਾਂ, ਤਮਾਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਕੌਤਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉੱਦਮ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਦੀ ਬਨਾਵਟ ਸੁੰਦਰਤਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਕੇ ਮਨ ਦਿਨੋ ਦਿਨ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣਨਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ)। ਇਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ (ਨਵੀਂ) ਘਾੜਤ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਮਨ ਬਹੁਤ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਘੜਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ। ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਬਿਆਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਪਛੁਤਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ,ਉਸ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਵਾਲੀ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਤੇ ਮਤ ਘੜੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਜਾਗ੍ਰਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਸਰਮ ਖੰਡ ਵਿਚ ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਸਿੱਧਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਅਕਲ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩੬।\\""},{"question":"Sanwo-Olu ṣeleri ẹkọ-ọfẹ fawọn ọmọ ọlọpaa ti wọn pa lasiko iwọde SARS","answer":"Lasiko ti Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu, ṣabẹwo sileeṣẹ ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Eko lo kede ẹkọ-ọfẹ fawọn ọmọ ọlọpaa ti wọn padanu ẹmi wọn lasiko rogbodiyan SARS to waye niluu Eko. Bẹẹ lo tun ni o ṣee ṣe ki ijọba ṣeto madamidofo (Insurance) fawọn to ṣi wa lẹnu iṣẹ. O tun fi kun un pe oun yoo tun gbogbo awọn agọ ọlọpaa to jona kọ si ti igbalode.Olu ileesẹ ọlọpaa to wa ni Ikẹja, ni gomina ti ṣeleri yii lasiko to ṣe abẹwo si wọn pẹlu Igbakeji rẹ, Babafẹmi Hamzat, atawọn ọmọ igbimọ ijọba rẹ kan, ni Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi to ti ṣeleri fun awọn agbofinro naa pe gbogbo ibeere awọn ọdọ lasiko iwọde SARS nijọba oun yoo dahun si.Lara awọn ileri ti gomina ṣe ni pe ijọba oun yoo mojuto eto isinku gbogbo awọn ọlọpaa to ku lasiko SARS. O lawọn yoo ṣeto owo ‘gba ma binu’ fun gbogbo mọlẹbi awọn agbofinro to ku lasiko rogbodiyan ọhun.Siwaju si i, Sanwo-Olu ni oun yoo ṣeto ẹkọ-ọfẹ fawọn ọmọ ọlọpaa to ku lasiko wahala SARS yii. O ṣeleri jẹneretọ meji fun olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa naa n’Ikẹja.Gomina ni asiko ti to lati ṣatunṣe si ajọsẹpọ to wa laarin ọlọpaa atawọn araalu.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa, Hakeem Odumosu atawọn agbagba lẹnu iṣẹ naa lo wa nibẹ."},{"question":"Qual a categoria da pergunta a seguir: Quantos anos tinha o 40º Presidente dos Estados Unidos ao morrer?","answer":"A categoria da pergunta é Política"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 港区の公立中学校　東京では初めて外国に修学旅行","answer":"東京の港区は、英語の教育を大事にしています。2024年度は、区がつくった10の公立中学校でシンガポールへ修学旅行に行くことを決めました。子どもたちに英語を使って、違う文化を勉強してもらおうと考えています。今までは京都と奈良に行っていました。修学旅行に行くのは、2024年度に中学3年生になる760人ぐらいです。6月から9月ごろに3泊5日の予定です。生徒の家が出すお金は今までと同じ7万円ぐらいで、区が生徒みんなに1人40万円ぐらいを出します。区は、英語を使う人が多いことや、まちが安全なことなどがシンガポールにした理由だと言っています。シンガポールの学校で授業を受けたり、そこの生徒たちと交流したりすることも考えています。区によると、公立の中学校が外国へ修学旅行に行くのは、東京では初めてです。"},{"question":"Menene aikin Jean Allard a 1563?","answer":"Aikinsa shine aikin soji."},{"question":"Comment dois-je répondre à la question d’entretien suivante : \\"Pourquoi voulez-vous ce poste en particulier ?\\"","answer":"Au-delà du salaire ou du prestige de l’entreprise qui peuvent vous motiver à vous rendre à l’entretien, exposez quelques détails supplémentaires qui vous poussent à occuper ce poste de travail.Dans la réponse, le candidat doit fournir des arguments pour expliquer en quoi le poste correspond à ses compétences et à ses aspirations professionnelles.Par exemple:“Je suis passionné par les sciences et je suis tout à fait capable de travailler de façon autonome. C’est d’ailleurs ce que j’ai fait lors de la rédaction de ma thèse. Ayant besoin de passer du temps en extérieur et étant amoureux de la nature, ce poste de géologue me semble parfait pour moi.”"},{"question":"સ્થાનના આધારે વિશેષણના કેટલા પ્રકાર છે. ","answer":"સ્થાનના આધારે વિશેષણના બે પ્રકાર છે. 1) અનુવાધ(અનુવિધેય) વિશેષણ: વિશેષણ નામની પહેલા આવે.ઉદા. તે શહેર ની શ્રીમંત વ્યક્તિ છે, અહીં શ્રીમંત વિશેષણ છે. ભાવનગર મોટું શહેર છે, અહીં મોટું વિશેષણ છે. 2) વિધેય વિશેષણ: વિશેષણ નામની પછી આવે.ઉદા. આ પુસ્તક દળદાર છે, અહીં દળદાર વિશેષણ છે. સરોવરમાં પાણી શુદ્ધ છે, અહીં શુદ્ધ વિશેષણ છે."},{"question":"வினா: பிரிட்டிஷ் ஆட்சியின் பொழுது சென்னை மாகாணத்தில் கிராமப் பகுதிகளில் வசித்த மக்களை ஒன்று திரட்டும் நோக்கத்துடன் “சென்னை மாகான சங்கம்” என்ற அமைப்பு எப்பொழுது துவக்கப்பட்டது?A. 1887B. 1892C. 1916D. 1905","answer":"விடை : B. 1892சென்னை மாகான சங்கம் துவங்கப்பட்ட ஆண்டு 1892."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bintang hati'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang kesayangan.Contoh ayat: Zahid berasa gelisah kerana bintang hatinya akan ke luar negara."},{"question":"Ko ti i si ijọba kan ni Naijiria yii to gbogun ti iṣẹ ati oṣi bii tiwa o – Buhari lo wi bẹẹ","answer":"Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari kede lana-an yii lasiko to n ba gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria sọrọ pe ko ti i si ijoba kan ni Naijiria yii to gbogun ti iṣẹ ati oṣi bii ijọba tawọn, nitori gbogbo ọna lawọn n wa lati diin iṣoro ati iya to n jẹ awọn ọmọ ilẹ yii ku, nipa pipese fun airina ati airilo wọn. Buhari ni eyi gan-an lo si jẹ ki ọrọ awọn ọdọ ti wọn n fa wahala yii dun oun, nitori eto ti awọn ṣe, tori wọn lawọn ṣe ṣe e.Olori ijọba ilẹ wa naa ni awọn ti ṣeto debii pe miliọnu lọna ọgọrun-un eeyan lawọn yoo yọ kuro ninu iṣẹ laarin ọdun mẹwaa si asiko taa wa yii, ti ko ni i si oniṣẹẹ ninu wọn mọ. O ni awọn ti tun ya biliọnu Naira marundinlọgọrin mi-in sọtọ lati fi pese iṣẹ adaṣe fawọn ọdọ ilẹ wa funra wọn.Buhari ni ki gbogbo eeyan ranti pe ijọba yii naa lo ṣeto ẹyawo oriṣiriṣi fawọn eeyan, nibi ti awọn ti ya awọn agbẹ, awọn iyalọja, ati awọn onileeṣẹ keekeekee lọwọ. O ni lati igba ti arun korona si ti bẹrẹ lawọn ti n wa gbogbo ọna lati fun awọn eeyan lowo ninu ile wọn, ti awọn fẹẹ ba awọn onileeṣẹ keekeekee sanwo oṣu mẹta, ti awọn si wa iṣẹ fun awọn ọdọ kan. Aarẹ ni pẹlu gbogbo eyi, bi yoo ba fi to saa diẹ sasiko yii, ko ni i si kinni kan to da bii oṣi tabi iṣẹ ni ilẹ wa."},{"question":"Pergunta: quanto dinheiro fez o filme Titanic? Resposta:","answer":" 2,471 Bilhões de bilheteria total em dólares"},{"question":"வினா:  திரவ நிலையிலுள்ள உலோகம் எது ?1.அழைப்பு மணி2.மரம்3.பாதரசம்4.உலோகத்துண்டு","answer":"விடை: 3.பாதரசம்பாதரசம் ஒரு கனமான உலோகமாகும். , வெள்ளியைப் போன்ற நிறம் கொண்ட டி- தொகுதியைச் சேர்ந்த தனிமமும் ஆகும். சாதாரண வெப்பநிலை மற்றும் அழுத்தத்தில் திரவ நிலையில் உள்ள ஒரே உலோகம் பாதரசம் என்பது இதன் சிறப்பாகும். பாதரசம் (Mercury) என்பது Hg என்ற மூலக்கூற்று வாய்ப்பாடு கொண்ட ஒரு வேதித் தனிமம் ஆகும். இதனுடைய அணு எண் 80 ஆகும். முற்காலத்தில் இதை ஐதராகிரம் என்று அழைத்தார்கள்."},{"question":"Sheeg magac boqorkii kusoo duulay kacbada?","answer":"Waa  abraha."},{"question":"பின்வருவனவற்றுள் கூட்டுவாக்கியத்திற்கு உதாரணமாக அமைவது?1) மேகம் கலைந்தது; மலை பெய்தது; வெள்ளம் பாய்ந்தது2) மயில் அழகாக ஆடியது3) பாரதி ஒரு மகாகவி என்பது ஆய்வாளர் முடிவாகும்4) கண்ணன் குழல் ஊதினான்","answer":"1) மேகம் கலைந்தது; மலை பெய்தது; வெள்ளம் பாய்ந்தது"},{"question":"متن زیر را با چند جمله تکمیل کنید: بیست و یک گلی که مسی در رقابت‌های مقدماتی جام جهانی فوتبال به ثمر رسانده، وی را در کنار لوییس سوارز، هم‌تیمی‌اش در باشگاه بارسلونا، به بهترین گل‌زن تاریخ رقابت‌های مقدماتی جام جهانی در منطقهٔ کونمبول تبدیل کرده‌است. وی ۹ گل در رقابت‌های کوپا آمریکا به ثمر رساند و در سال‌های ۲۰۰۷، ۲۰۱۵ و ۲۰۱۶ تیم خود را تا فینال این رقابت‌ها رهبری کرد، هرچند هر ۳ مرتبه در نهایت نتوانست قهرمان شود و عنوان نائب قهرمانی را کسب کرد. در چهل و چهارمین دورهٔ این مسابقات (سال ۲۰۱۵) وی ظاهراً جایزهٔ بهترین بازیکن رقابت‌ها را پس زد تا این عنوان از فهرست جوایز حذف شود. او تا به حال ۶ گل در مسابقات جام جهانی فوتبال به ثمر رسانده‌است که شامل یک گل در سال ۲۰۰۶، ۴ گل در سال ۲۰۱۴ و یک گل در سال ۲۰۱۸ می‌شود؛ ","answer":"درخشان‌ترین دورهٔ جام جهانی برای وی جام جهانی ۲۰۱۴ برزیل بود که وی علاوه بر حضور در فینال آن مسابقات ، عنوان توپ طلایی رقابت‌ها را نیز از آن خود کرد. سایر گل‌های ملی مسی عبارت‌اند از ۳۴ گل در بازی‌های دوستانه. وی همچنین دو گل نیز در بازی‌های المپیک تابستانی ۲۰۰۸ به ثمر رسانده که در ردهٔ بزرگسال نبوده است."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਛੰਤ ॥ਜਪਿ ਮਨਾ ਤੂੰ ਰਾਮ ਨਰਾਇਣੁ ਗੋਵਿੰਦਾ ਹਰਿ ਮਾਧੋ ॥ਧਿਆਇ ਮਨਾ ਮੁਰਾਰਿ ਮੁਕੰਦੇ ਕਟੀਐ ਕਾਲ ਦੁਖ ਫਾਧੋ ॥ਦੁਖਹਰਣ ਦੀਨ ਸਰਣ ਸ੍ਰੀਧਰ ਚਰਨ ਕਮਲ ਅਰਾਧੀਐ ॥ਜਮ ਪੰਥੁ ਬਿਖੜਾ ਅਗਨਿ ਸਾਗਰੁ ਨਿਮਖ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਸਾਧੀਐ ॥ਕਲਿਮਲਹ ਦਹਤਾ ਸੁਧੁ ਕਰਤਾ ਦਿਨਸੁ ਰੈਣਿ ਅਰਾਧੋ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਕਰਹੁ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਗੋਪਾਲ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਮਾਧੋ ॥੧॥ਸਿਮਰਿ ਮਨਾ ਦਾਮੋਦਰੁ ਦੁਖਹਰੁ ਭੈ ਭੰਜਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਇਆ ॥ਸ੍ਰੀਰੰਗੋ ਦਇਆਲ ਮਨੋਹਰੁ ਭਗਤਿ ਵਛਲੁ ਬਿਰਦਾਇਆ ॥ਭਗਤਿ ਵਛਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਪੂਰਨ ਮਨਹਿ ਚਿੰਦਿਆ ਪਾਈਐ ॥ਤਮ ਅੰਧ ਕੂਪ ਤੇ ਉਧਾਰੈ ਨਾਮੁ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਈਐ ॥ਸੁਰ ਸਿਧ ਗਣ ਗੰਧਰਬ ਮੁਨਿ ਜਨ ਗੁਣ ਅਨਿਕ ਭਗਤੀ ਗਾਇਆ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਕਰਹੁ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਇਆ ॥੨॥ਚੇਤਿ ਮਨਾ ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮੁ ਪਰਮੇਸਰੁ ਸਰਬ ਕਲਾ ਜਿਨਿ ਧਾਰੀ ॥ਕਰੁਣਾ ਮੈ ਸਮਰਥੁ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਘਟ ਘਟ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਅਧਾਰੀ ॥ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਮਨ ਤਨ ਜੀਅ ਦਾਤਾ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਅਗਮ ਅਪਾਰੋ ॥ਸਰਣਿ ਜੋਗੁ ਸਮਰਥੁ ਮੋਹਨੁ ਸਰਬ ਦੋਖ ਬਿਦਾਰੋ ॥ਰੋਗ ਸੋਗ ਸਭਿ ਦੋਖ ਬਿਨਸਹਿ ਜਪਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਮੁਰਾਰੀ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਕਰਹੁ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਸਮਰਥ ਸਭ ਕਲ ਧਾਰੀ ॥੩॥ਗੁਣ ਗਾਉ ਮਨਾ ਅਚੁਤ ਅਬਿਨਾਸੀ ਸਭ ਤੇ ਊਚ ਦਇਆਲਾ ॥ਬਿਸੰਭਰੁ ਦੇਵਨ ਕਉ ਏਕੈ ਸਰਬ ਕਰੈ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਪਾਲਾ ॥ਪ੍ਰਤਿਪਾਲ ਮਹਾ ਦਇਆਲ ਦਾਨਾ ਦਇਆ ਧਾਰੇ ਸਭ ਕਿਸੈ ॥ਕਾਲੁ ਕੰਟਕੁ ਲੋਭੁ ਮੋਹੁ ਨਾਸੈ ਜੀਅ ਜਾ ਕੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਬਸੈ ॥ਸੁਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਦੇਵਾ ਸਫਲ ਸੇਵਾ ਭਈ ਪੂਰਨ ਘਾਲਾ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤ ਨਾਨਕ ਇਛ ਪੁਨੀ ਜਪਤ ਦੀਨ ਦੈਆਲਾ ॥੪॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 248 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ! ਤੂੰ ਰਾਮ ਨਾਰਾਇਣ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਹਰੀ ਮਾਧੋ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਨੂੰ ਜਪ । ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ! ਤੂੰ ਮੁਕੰਦ ਮੁਰਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਆਰਾਧਨ ਕਰ । (ਇਸ ਆਰਾਧਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਮੌਤ ਤੇ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੀ ਫਾਹੀ ਕੱਟੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਮਨ!) ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਰਾਧਨ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਗ਼ਰੀਬਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਲੱਖਮੀ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਜਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਔਖਾ ਰਸਤਾ, ਤੇ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ (ਨਾਲ ਭਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੰਸਾਰ-) ਸਮੰੁਦਰ ਰਤਾ ਭਰ ਸਮੇ ਲਈ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣਾ ਲਈਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ!) ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਉਸ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹੁ, ਜੋ ਪਾਪਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾੜਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜੋ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਹੇ ਗੋਪਾਲ! ਹੇ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ! ਹੇ ਮਾਧੋ! ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ (ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ) ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ! ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾਮੋਦਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰ, ਜੋ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਡਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ਼ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਲੱਖਮੀ ਦਾ ਖਸਮ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਦਇਆ ਦਾ ਸੋਮਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਨਾ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਢ-ਕਦੀਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੁਭਾਉ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪੂਰਨ ਪੁਰਖ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਲਈਏ, ਤਾਂ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਚਿਤਵਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹਰੇਕ ਮਨੋਰਥ ਪਾ ਲਈਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਅੰਨ੍ਹੇ ਖੂਹ ਦੇ ਹਨੇਰੇ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੱਢ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ!) ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਕਰਾਮਾਤੀ ਜੋਗੀ, ਸ਼ਿਵ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਦਾਸ-ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਦੇਵਤਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਗਵਈਏ, ਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਲੋਕ ਤੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਹੀ ਭਗਤ ਉਸੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ।ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ! ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ (ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਭੀ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ) ।੨।ਹੇ (ਮੇਰੇ) ਮਨ! ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਪਰਮੇਸਰ ਨੂੰ ਚੇਤੇ ਰੱਖ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਸਭਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੱਤਾ ਟਿਕਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਤਰਸ-ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਜੋ ਹਰੇਕ ਸਰੀਰ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਦੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ,ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਮਨ ਤਨ ਤੇ ਜਿੰਦ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ, ਅਪਹੁੰਚ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਅਪਾਰ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਸਰਨ ਪਏ ਦੀ ਸਹੈਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਜੋਗਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਸਭ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਮਨ! ਮੁਰਾਰੀ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਿਆਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਐਬ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਹੇ ਸਭ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ! ਹੇ ਸਭਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੱਤਾ ਟਿਕਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! (ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ) ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ (ਮੈਂ ਭੀ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ) ।੩।ਹੇ (ਮੇਰੇ) ਮਨ! ਤੂੰ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾ, ਜੋ ਸਦਾ ਅਟੱਲ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਦੇ ਨਾਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ, ਜੋ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦਇਆ ਦਾ ਘਰ ਹੈ,ਜੋ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਲਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਦੇਣ ਜੋਗਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਸਭ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ!) ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਉਤੇ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹਰੇਕ ਦੇ ਦਿਲ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ । ਬੜਾ ਹੀ ਦਇਆਲ ਤੇ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮੋਹ ਲੋਭ ਤੇ ਦੁਖਦਾਈ (ਕੰਡੇ ਵਾਂਗ ਚੁੱਭਦਾ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ) ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਸਹਮ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਮਨ!) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੱੁਖ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਨੂੰ ਫਲ ਲੱਗ ਪਂੈਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਸਿਰੇ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਗ਼ਰੀਬਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆਂ ਹਰੇਕ ਇੱਛਾ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।੪।੩।\\""},{"question":"කෙළ සුවහස් කියන්නේ කොපමණක්ද?","answer":"අසන්ඛ්යය කියන්නෙ දහයෙ 133 බලය.කෙළක් කියන්නෙ කෝටියක්.සුවහසක් කියන්නෙ සහශ්‍ර හතරක්.බුදුන් වහන්සේගේ ආඥා ක්ෂේත‍්‍රය කෝටි ලක්ෂයක් සක්වළ ( මහ සහ ශ්‍රී ලෝක ධාතුව / ත්‍රි සහ ශ්‍රී ලෝක ධාතුව ) දක්වා පැතිරෙනවා... 10 හි 12 වන බලය... අමතර කරුණක්"},{"question":"Mitkä ovat kryptosporidioosin oireet?","answer":"Oireet alkavat yleensä viikon kuluttua tartunnasta. Itämisajan vaihteluväli on 1‒22 vuorokautta. Yleisin oire on itsestään rajoittuva, vaikeusasteeltaan ja kestoltaan vaihteleva vesiripuli. Muita oireita voivat olla vatsakipu, lievä kuume, pahoinvointi, oksentelu ja ruokahaluttomuus.Yleensä oireet kestävät 2–4 vuorokautta, mutta ne voivat jatkua jopa neljä viikkoa. Tartunta voi olla myös oireeton. Vastustuskyvyltään heikentyneillä henkilöillä, kuten HIV- ja elinsiirtopotilailla tauti voi olla vakava, jopa henkeä uhkaava."},{"question":"Qual a categoria da pergunta a seguir: Qual ator atuou como James Bond e nasceu na Escócia?.","answer":"A categoria da pergunta é Cinema"},{"question":"முன்னே என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள் ___________எதிரேபின்னேஉயரேகீழே","answer":"விடை : பின்னே"},{"question":"Кыргыз эли отурукташкан аймак","answer":"Орто Азия"},{"question":"Салыштырмалуулук теориясы деген эмне жана аны ким чыгарган?","answer":"Альберт Эйнштейн тарабынан формулировкаланган салыштырмалуулук теориясы Салыштырмалуулуктун атайын теориясын (1905) жана Салыштырмалуулуктун жалпы теориясын (1915) камтыйт жана биздин мейкиндик, убакыт жана тартылуу жөнүндөгү түшүнүгүбүздө төңкөрүш жасады."},{"question":"Lat joor (Dior)  kañ la faatu ?","answer":"26 Oktoobar 1886."},{"question":"प्रतिक्रियालाई बेवास्ता गर्ने बानीले व्यक्तिगत र व्यावसायिक विकासलाई कसरी बाधा पुर्‍याउँछ?","answer":"प्रतिक्रियालाई बानीको रूपमा बेवास्ता गर्दा सुधारका अवसरहरू रोकेर व्यक्तिगत र व्यावसायिक वृद्धिमा बाधा पुग्छ। निरन्तर विकासको लागि रचनात्मक प्रतिक्रियालाई अंगाल्नु आवश्यक छ।"},{"question":"Хто такий Фурман? ","answer":"Марк Фурман (народився 5 лютого 1952) - колишній детектив Департаменту поліції Лос-Анджелеса (LAPD). Він, в першу чергу, відомий своєю участю у розслідуванні вбивств Ніколь Браун Сімпсон і Рона Голдмана у голосній справі О. Дж. Сімпсона"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"_ milevina amoron-dalana ka mahatantesa valin-kitsaka\\"","answer":"\\"Mpamosavy milevina amoron-dalana ka mahatantesa valin-kitsaka\\""},{"question":"Quantos girassóis havia na terceira versão de Van Gogh da pintura 'Girassóis'?","answer":"12"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ ኮርቬት የተዋወቀችው በየትኛው ዓመት ነው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"1953"},{"question":"Suponha que você esteja no Brasil e, de acordo com as regras do Código de Defesa do Consumidor (CDC), qual o prazo máximo para solicitação de reparação de danos por produtos ou serviços com vício?","answer":"O prazo máximo é de 5 anos."},{"question":"翻译下面的古文：予观弈于友人所，一客数败，嗤其失算，辄欲易置之，以为不逮己也。顷之，客请与予对局，予颇易之。甫下数子，客已先得手。局将半，予思益苦，而客之智尚有余。竟局数之，客胜予十三子。予赧甚，不能出一言。后有招予观弈者，终日默坐而已。","answer":"我在朋友家里看一棋。一位客人屡次输掉，（我）讥笑他计算失误，总是想替他改放棋子，认为他赶不上自己。过一会儿，客人请求和我下棋，我颇为轻视他。刚刚下了几个棋子，客人已经取得主动的形势。棋局快到中盘的时候，我思考得更加艰苦，而客人却轻松有余。终局计算双方棋子，客人赢我十三子。我很惭愧，不能说出一句话。以后有人邀请我观看下棋，我整天默默地坐着看而已。"},{"question":"दोलखा भीमसेन","answer":"दोलखा भीमसेन भगवान भीमेश्वरको वासस्थान मानिन्छ, यो दोलखा जिल्लामा रहेको नेपालको प्रसिद्ध हिन्दू मन्दिर हो जसमा व्यापारीहरूबीच बलियो सम्बन्ध छ। जिल्लाको अर्को मन्दिर कालिञ्चोक भगवती हो, बलियो आध्यात्मिक शक्ति भएको शक्तिशाली देवी मन्दिरको रूपमा पूजनीय छ। अग्लो पहाड (३८४२ मिटर) मा अवस्थित यो तीर्थस्थलको रूपमा गौरीशंकर संरक्षण क्षेत्रमा अवस्थित छ।"},{"question":"د آرچدوک فرانز فرډینانډ وژنه د لومړۍ نړیوالې جګړې په پیل کې څنګه مرسته وکړه؟","answer":"د ۱۹۱۴ کال د جون په ۲۸ مه په سراجیوو کې د ارچدوک فرانز فرډینند وژنه په اروپا کې د مخکینۍ کړکېچن سیاسي چاپیریال لپاره د کتلست په توګه کار وکړ. د فرډینند وژنې د اتریش- هنګري او سربیا تر منځ تاوتریخوالی زیات کړ، چې اتریش- هنګري یې د سربیا لپاره الټیمیټم صادر کړ. د سربیا ځواب د قناعت وړ نه و، د اتریش- هنګري هڅول چې د جګړې اعلان وکړي. د اتحادونو پیچلي سیسټم، په ځانګړې توګه درې اړخیزه انټینټ او درې اړخیز اتحاد، په عمل کې پیل شو کله چې ملتونه په شخړو کې ښکیل شول. روسیه، فرانسه، جرمني او برتانیه د هغو سترو قدرتونو له جملې څخه وو چې ځانونه یې په هغه څه کې ښکیل کړل چې په پیل کې سیمه ایزه شخړه وه او په دې توګه یې په نړیواله شخړه بدله کړه."},{"question":"Tessa Thompson","answer":"Tessa Lynne Thompson (tí a bí ní ọjọ́ kẹta oṣù kẹsàn-án ọdún 1983) jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Amerika. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré pẹ̀lú ilé isé Los Angeles Women's Shakespeare nígbà tí ó ń kàwé ní ilé ìwé Santa Monica College. Ó wà nínú eré The Tempest àti Romeo and Juliet, ipa rẹ̀ nínú eré Romeo and Julie sì mú kí wọ́n yàn fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ NAACP Theatre Award. Ó gbajúmọ̀ nígbà tí ó ṣeré nínú fíìmù tí Tina Mabry ṣàgbéjáde; Mississippi Damned (2009) àti fíìmù Tyler Perry tí àpèlé rẹ̀ jẹ́ For Colored Girls (2010)."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko kirolak: Zer da herri kirola?","answer":"Herri kirolak euskal kirol tradizionalak dira, indar eta trebetasuna probatzen dituztenak."},{"question":" Iza no filozofa lehibe nanoratra ny \\"The Social Contract\\" ary heverina ho iray amin'ireo mpandinika lehibe indrindra momba ny Fahazavana Frantsay?","answer":"Jean-Jacques Rousseau, filozofa frantsay, dia nanoratra ny \\"The Social Contract\\" ary heverina ho iray amin'ireo mpandinika lehibe indrindra momba ny Fahazavana frantsay."},{"question":"Explain the difference between \\"there,\\" \\"their,\\" and \\"they're.\\"","answer":"\\"There\\" refers to a place, \\"their\\" indicates possession, and \\"they're\\" is a contraction for \\"they are.\\""},{"question":"Antara berikut, yang manakah benar tentang antibiotik?A. Dapat membunuh virusB. Sejenis hormon buatanC. Diperolehi dariapada sel haiwanD. Merawat penyakit disebabkan oleh bakteria","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D. Merawat penyakit disebabkan oleh bakteria"},{"question":"Trần Nhật Duật là danh tướng giỏi ngoại ngữ, mê âm nhạc. Nhận định này có đúng không?","answer":"Đúng, Trần Nhật Duật rất giỏi ngoại ngữ và cũng mê âm nhạcTrần Nhật Duật sinh năm 1255, là con thứ sáu của vua Trần Thái Tông. Sách Danh tướng Việt Nam viết: \\"Trần Nhật Duật nổi tiếng hiểu nhiều biết rộng. Ngoài việc thông thạo nhiều ngoại ngữ, ông còn hiểu biết sâu rộng các nước láng giềng. Học tiếng Tống, tiếng Chiêm Thành, Nhật Duật chẳng những sử dụng thông thạo các ngôn ngữ ấy mà còn tìm hiểu nhiều mặt của các nước đó. Đối với các dân tộc trong nước, Nhật Duật không những hiểu tiếng mà còn hiểu cả tâm tư người khác\\"."},{"question":"හිස්හොරි ,හිස් සොරි මෙයට කියන නිවරදි වචනය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"හිසේ/ඉසේ හැදෙන හොරි = හිස් හොරි > ඉස් හොරි > ඉස්සොරි (උච්චාරණ පහසුව සඳහා)"},{"question":"Apakah prosedur rawatan veneer gigi?","answer":"Selalunya prosedur yang melibatkan veneer porselin ini memerlukan 3 kali lawatan pergigian. Pada lawatan pertama, doktor akan merancang rawatan dan menentukan saiz, bentuk dan jenis veneer yang bersesuaian dengan senyuman, bentuk muka dan ciri-ciri estetik indiividu.Pada lawatan kedua pula, akan dilakukan prosedur penyediaan gigi di mana sedikit pengurangan pada lapisan enamel akan dilakukan untuk proses pemasangan veneer. Pemasangan veneer sementara akan dilakukan jika proses pengurangan lapisan ini telah melibatkan lapisan dentin.Proses pemasangan sementara ini dilakukan untuk melindungi gigi sementara menunggu prosedur veneer porselin oleh makmal perubatan. Setelah veneer porselin telah siap, doktor akan memanggil kembali individu yang ingin melakukan prosedur ini untuk proses simen veneer gigi."},{"question":"Waa maxey sababta uu Ismaciil Mire u tiriyey gabeyga orod xoogso?","answer":"Waxa uu utiriyey wuxuu waaninaayey wiil uu dhaley oo la odhan jirey cali ismaaciil ,waxa uu dooneyey inuu ku tarbiyeeyo nolosha"},{"question":"Zer da pedagogian konstruktibismoa, eta nola ulertzen du ikasleen ikasketa-prozesua?","answer":"Konstruktibismoa da pedagogiaren ikuspegia non ikasleak aktiboki parte hartzen duen bere ikasketa-prozesuan. Ikasleak bere aurreko jakintzan oinarrituta informazio berria eraikitzen du."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - I Skid-VM 2007","answer":"i Sapporo i Japan tävlade Pettersen uteslutande i den individuella tävlingen i stora backen. Han blev nummer 27. I lagtävlingen blev Norge silvermedaljörer, utan Sigurd Pettersen i laget. Det blev det sista Skid-VM Pettersen tävlade i."},{"question":"තරංගයක වේගය පහත සමීකරණයෙන් දැක්විය හැකිය. එම සමීකරණයෙන් අර්ථදැක්වෙන්නේ කුමක්ද?v = fλ","answer":"තරංගයක් එක් ආවර්ත කාලයක් තුළ දී තරංග ආයාමයට සමාන දුරක් ගමන් කරන නිසා, එහි වේගය v = λ/T නැතහොත් v = fλ ලෙස දැක්විය හැක. "},{"question":"கேள்வி: கி.பி. 1451 வரை இந்தியாவை ஆண்ட அரசர்கள் எந்த இனத்தை சார்ந்தவர்கள்?","answer":"பதில்:துருக்கியர். துருக்கிய மக்கள் அல்லது துருக்கர் என்போர், ஒரு துர்க்கிக் இனக்குழுவினரும் நாட்டினமும் ஆவர். இவர்களை அனத்தோலியத் துருக்கியர் எனவும் அழைப்பதுண்டு. இவர்கள் பெரும்பாலும் தற்காலத் துருக்கியில் வாழ்கின்றனர். அதிக அளவில் பேசப்படும் துர்க்கிக் மொழியான துருக்கிய மொழியைப் பேசுகின்றனர். துருக்கியின் மிகப் பெரிய இனக்குழுவாக இருக்கும் இவர்கள், துர்க்கிக் மொழிகளைப் பேசுவோரில் பெரும்பான்மையாகவும் உள்ளனர். முன்னைய ஓட்டோமான் பேரரசின் கீழிருந்த சில பகுதிகளில் இவர்கள் இன்னும் சிறுபான்மையினராக வாழ்கின்றனர். அத்துடன், தற்காலப் புலப்பெயர்வுகளினூடாகவும் துருக்கிய மக்கள் பலர் ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளில், குறிப்பாக மேற்கு ஐரோப்பிய நாடுகளில் குடியேறியுள்ளனர்."},{"question":"این جمله را کامل کن.با انتخاب حسن روحانی به سمت ریاست‌جمهور و شکل‌گیری دولت یازدهم، برنامه نجات دریاچه ارومیه مورد تأکید قرار گرفت و کارگروه","answer":" ملی نجات دریاچه ارومیه به مدیریت معاون اول رئیس‌جمهور تشکیل شد. این کارگروه موضوعاتی همچون مقابله با ریزگردها، وضعیت کشاورزی، الگوی کشت در منطقه و تعداد زیاد چاه‌های آب را مورد بررسی قرار داد. برخی کارشناسان اعتقاد دارند فعالیت‌های ترمیمی انجام شده در این دوره در کنار حمایت‌های مردمی، موجب کاهش روند تخریب دریاچه ارومیه و در برخی بخش‌ها باعث بهبود شرایط شده‌ است.به رغم برنامه‌ریزی‌های صورت گرفته، وضعیت دریاچه ارومیه وخیم‌تر شده است. در ۲۹ مهر ۱۳۹۶ خورشیدی، تراز سطح آب این دریاچه ۱۲۷۰٫۲۵ متر اعلام شد. این تراز نسبت به روز مشابه در سال ۱۳۹۵ خورشیدی، ۲۳ سانتی‌متر و نسبت به میانگین دراز مدت ۴٫۵ متر کاهش نشان می‌داد. مساحت این دریاچه نیز در ۲۹ مهر ۱۳۹۶ خورشیدی، ۱۶۹۸٫۶۴ کیلومتر مربع اعلام شد که نسبت به روز مشابه در سال ۱۳۹۵ خورشیدی، ۲۷۸٫۷۴ کیلومتر مربع و نسبت به میانگین دراز مدت، ۲۸۲۸٫۰۹ کیلومتر مربع کاهش یافته‌بود. حجم آب موجود در این دریاچه نیز در ۲۹ مهر ۱۳۹۶ خورشیدی، ۱٫۰۱ میلیارد متر مکعب اعلام شد که نسبت به روز مشابه در سال ۱۳۹۵ خورشیدی، ۰٫۴۳ میلیارد متر مکعب کاهش را نشان می‌داد. در نیمه اول آبان ۱۳۹۶ خورشیدی نیز اعلام شد که سطح تراز آب دریاچه ارومیه به ۱۲۷۰٫۱۹ متر رسیده‌است. همچنین اعلام شد که وسعت این دریاچه به ۱۵۹۴ کیلومتر مربع رسیده‌است. با توجه به بارندگی‌های بهار سال ۱۳۹۸ این دریاچه نیز از آب‌های سر ریز سدها و سیلاب‌ها تغذیه شده‌است به طوری که طبق گفته مدیر ستاد احیای دریاچه میزان تراز دریاچه بیش از ۱۱۸ سانتی‌متر افزایش داشته و به ۱۲۷۱/۱۹ رسیده‌است."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berbaur pangkal perceraian\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang bersaudara itu kalau bercampur selalu timbul perselisihan."},{"question":"හැරී පොටර් පොත් රචනා කළේ කවුද?","answer":"ජේ. කේ. රෝලින්"},{"question":"Inona no fihetseham-po mifandray matetika amin'ny loko mavokely?a) Fahatezeranab) Fifalianad) Malaheloe) Tahotra","answer":"b) Fifaliana no fihetseham-po mifandray matetika amin'ny loko mavokely"},{"question":"સૂર્યના પ્રકાશમાં: પ્રેમ અને હરિદ્રાથી ભરેલો જીવન.","answer":"સૂર્યકિરણો ચમકે, આસમાન આલોયે,ફૂલો ખિલાય, વરસાદ આવે ખૂબસૂરત ફરે.પ્રેમમાં સુંદરતા છે, મિઠાસ ભરે વાત,દિલથી દિલ મિલાવો, સખીઓને હાસ્ય ભરે રાત.પર્વોનો આગમન, હર્ષથી ભરો મન,આશાઓનો દીપ, જીવનમાં લાવે પ્રખર જોરાવર.સપનાઓના રંગીન, સજીવ કરે ખ્યાલ,હરિદ્રાના રંગમાં, મિલાવે સુખ-શાંતિનો ખ્યાલ.જીવનનો સફર, સાથે રહે પ્રેમ,હસો, રમો, જીવન બનાવો ખૂબસૂરત એવામેવ."},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, ọkada meji fori sọ tirela l’Abẹokuta, lo ba tẹ wọn pa","answer":"Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ kọja iṣẹju mẹẹẹdọgbọn alẹ ọjọ Ẹti, ọgbọnjọ, oṣu kẹrin, ni awọn ọlọkada meji kan ku iku ojiji lagbegbe Kotopo, l’Abẹokuta. Niṣe ni wọn fori sọ tirela to n bọ jẹẹjẹ lodikeji ọna, ẹsẹkẹsẹ naa ni wọn dagbere faye.Ohun ti Alukoro TRACE, Babatunde Akinbiyi, ṣalaye nipa iṣẹlẹ naa ni pe awọn ọkada meji yii lo n sare, ti wọn n wa iwakuwa to jẹ ki ijamba ṣẹlẹ.O ni ladojukọ ileepo Forte Oil, to wa ni Kotopo, loju ọna Abẹokuta s’Ibadan, lawọn ọlọkada meji naa ti pade iku ojiji yii.Akinbiyi ṣalaye pe Bajaj lawọn ọkada mejeeji, ọkan ni nọmba SGM 006 VG, ikeji ko ni rara. Nọmba tirela to tẹ wọn pa si ni AAB 969XV.‘‘Iwakuwa ati aile ni suuru awọn ọlọkada yẹn lo fa asidẹnti yii, awọn ni wọn lọọ fori sọ tirela to n bọ lodikeji ọna jẹẹjẹ. A ti gbe ọkada mejeeji lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa Arẹgbẹ,  l’Abẹokuta, kan naa.’’ Bẹẹ ni Akinbiyi wi.O tẹsiwaju pe oku ọkan ninu awọn ọlọkada naa ti wa ni mọṣuari, n’Idi-Aba, ẹbi ọkan yooku si ti gbe e lọ lati sin in."},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây.Câu hỏi: Tỉnh Bình Phước có biên giới với quốc gia nào?A. LàoB. CampuchiaC. Thái Lan","answer":"Đáp án: B. CampuchiaGiải thích: Bình Phước là một tỉnh biên giới, giáp Campuchia về phía Tây Bắc. Tổng chiều dài đường biên giới của tỉnh này với Campuchia là gần 260 km, thuộc các huyện Bù Gia Mập, Bù Đốp, Lộc Ninh. Tỉnh Bình Phước đang quản lý bốn cửa khẩu (Hoa Lư, Hoàng Diệu, Lộc Thịnh, Tân tiến) và một lối mở."},{"question":"Idi ti Tinubu ko fi le di aarẹ Naijiria ni 2023 ree o","answer":"Wọn ti n pana ọrọ naa bọ lati bii ọdun meji sẹyin, ṣugbọn ni bayii, ọrọ naa ti burẹkẹ, bi Aṣiwaju Bọla Ahmed Tinubu ko ba si mura daadaa, ọrọ naa yoo fa a lẹwu ya. Ohun ti awọn eeyan wa n sọ ni pe ṣe ki i ṣe nitori ọrọ ibo aarẹ ọdun 2023 lawọn eeyan kan ṣe dide ti wọn fẹẹ koba Tinubu bayii, ṣugbọn awọn ti wọn mọ ipilẹ ọrọ naa ni kinni naa ki i ṣe bẹẹ, pe ohun ti Tinubu funra ẹ ti ṣe sẹyin tẹlẹ lo fẹẹ pada di wahala si i lọrun, bi ko ba si fẹsọ ṣe e, ọrọ naa yoo mu un lomi. Alaye mi-in tawọn eeyan n ṣe ni pe Tinubu wa lara awọn ti wọn tori ẹ le Ibrahim Magu, alaga EFCC tẹlẹ, lọ, nitori wọn ni Tinubu funra rẹ ti sọ pe bi Magu ba wa nipo rẹ, ko si mimi kan ti yoo mi oun. Koda ki awọn kan sopanpa ju bẹẹ lọ, ki wọn mura lati ran oun lẹwọn tabi tu aṣiri awọn ohun ti oun ṣe, ko si ohun ti wọn yoo le fi oun ṣe.Bi ibo ọdun 2023 yii ṣe n sun mọle lawọn kan n wa ọna ti Tinubu o fi ni i jade, tabi ti wọn yoo ti di i lọwọ rẹpẹtẹ ko too di ọjọ naa, ohun tawọn ti wọn sun mọ ọkunrin oloṣelu naa si n wi ni pe iru iyẹn ko ni i ṣee ṣe. Ṣugbọn pẹlu ẹjọ buruku ti wọn hu jade bayii, ti ọrọ naa si ti di ti ile-ẹjọ, ti wọn si ti paṣẹ pe afi ki Tinubu yọju si ile-ẹjọ naa ko waa wi tẹnu ẹ, ko si bi ọrọ naa ko ṣe ni i di ariwo, bẹẹ ni ko si bi ẹjọ naa ko ṣe ni i ko ba Tinubu. Ọkunrin kan lo ti ọpa bọ isa ejo, oun lo ja ejo naa loju, o si ni ọrọ naa ti kọja ohun ti awọn le pari ni kọrọ, gbangba loju aye lawọn yoo ti yanju ẹ. Ẹni to ba mọ Tinubu ko sọ fun un ko maa mura silẹ ni, nitori ẹjọ ti yoo mi gbogbo ilu titi ni. Ọkunrin naa ti pẹjọ o, o pe Tinubu ati ileeṣẹ rẹ kan ti wọn n pe ni Alpha Beta lẹjọ, o ni ileeṣẹ naa ni Tinubu lo lati ko owo buruku, owo awọn ara Eko jẹ.Ọrọ ti eegun ba sọ ni, ara ọrun lo sọ ọ. Ẹni to fi ẹsun kan Tinubu yii, ẹni to mọ ọn deledele ni, awọn ẹsun to si fi kan an yii, ẹsun to lagbara pupọ ni. Bi ijọba kan tabi ile-ẹjọ ba tẹra mọ ẹjọ yii, ohun ti wọn yoo kan nidii rẹ ko le dara fun aṣaaju APC naa, ati ilakaka rẹ lati di aarẹ. Dapọ Apara ni orukọ ọkunrin naa, oun si ni olori ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta fun odidi ọdun mejila gbako. Alpha Beta yii ki i ṣe ileeṣẹ kekere kan, ileeṣẹ to n ba ijọba ipinlẹ Eko gba owo-ori lati ọdun 2002, ọdun mejidinlogun sẹyin, titi di asiko ti a wa yii ni. Ṣugbọn titi di asiko ti ede-aiyede de laarin Tinubu ati Apara, ko sẹni to mọ pe Tinubu lọwọ si ileeṣẹ naa rara, ohun ti wọn n ro ni pe awọn oyinbo lo ni Alpha Beta, ati pe ijọba Eko gbe ileeṣẹ naa wa lati oke-okun lati maa waa ba awọn gba owo-ori. Owo ti wọn gba laarin asiko yii, owo nla ni.Nigba ti ileeṣe naa kọkọ bẹrẹ, bii biliọnu mẹwaa Naira (N10billion) ni ileeeṣẹ naa n ba ijọba Eko gba wọle lọdọọdun, ṣugbọn nigba ti yoo fi di ọdun 2018, owo ti Alpha Beta n ba ijọba Eko pa le ni ọọdunrun biliọnu Naira (N300billion) laarin ọdun kan. Iye yoowu ti Alpha Beta ba waa pa bayii, ida mẹwaa ni tiwọn ninu owo naa. Eyi ni pe bi wọn ba pa ọgọrun-un biliọnu fun ijọba, biliọnu mẹwaa ni tiwọn nibẹ, owo naa si maa n le ju bẹẹ lọ nigba mi-in; bi wọn ba pa ọọdunrun biliọnu, awọn yoo mu ọgbọn biliọnu nibẹ lai duro de ẹnikẹni, owo naa si le ju bẹẹ lọ. Nidii eyi, ọkan ninu awọn ileeṣẹ to n ṣowo, to n jere, julọ ni Naijiria, ti owo naa ko si bajẹ lati bii ọdun mejidinlogun bayii ni Alpha Beta n ṣe.Bi ileeṣẹ yii ti waa n pa owo to yii, awọn iwa kan wa ti ileeṣẹ naa n hu ti ko dara. Akọkọ ni pe ileeṣẹ naa ki i san owo-ori to yẹ ki wọn san pada si apo ijọba, bakan naa ni wọn n lo ileeṣẹ naa lati ko owo buruku lọ si oke-okun, ileeṣẹ yii si tun n lu ijọba ni jibiti owo to pọ gan-an. Ko si ẹni meji to tu aṣiri eyi ju Apara funra ẹ lọ, nitori ko sẹni to le mọ aṣiri ileeṣẹ naa ju Apara yii lọ. Idi ni pe gẹgẹ bi akọsilẹ ti wi, ki i ṣe pe ileeṣẹ naa deede lalẹ hu, Apara ni oun funra oun loun ronu nipa ileeṣẹ naa, ti oun gẹgẹ bii oluṣiro-owo ati agbowoka agba ro o lọkan ara oun pe o ṣee ṣe ki ijọba Eko maa fi ẹrọ ayara-bi-aṣa gba owo-ori awọn eeyan ipinlẹ wọn, lẹyin ti oun si ti ro ọrọ naa ni arogun ni oun gbe e lọ sọdọ ijọba Eko lọdun 2000 pe ki wọn jẹ ki oun waa maa ba wọn ṣiṣẹ naa, ki wọn si maa fun oun ni ohun to ba tọ soun.Apara ni orukọ ileeṣẹ oun ti oun fẹẹ maa fi ṣiṣẹ yii nigba naa ni ‘Infiniti Systems Enterprise’, orukọ yii loun si fi gbe iṣẹ naa lọ sọdọ awọn Tinubu. O ni nigba ti Tinubu ri iwe iṣẹ ti oun kọ lọ, o ranṣẹ soun, nitori oun ni gomina Eko nigba naa. Nibi ipade awọn ni Tinubu ti sọ pe bi oun Apara ba fẹ ki ijọba Eko gbe iṣẹ naa foun, a jẹ pe awọn yoo tun iwe naa ṣe lorukọ ileeṣẹ mi-in ni o, pe awọn yoo da ileeṣẹ tuntun silẹ, ileeṣẹ ti awọn ba si da silẹ yii ni yoo maa gbe iṣẹ naa jade lati ọdọ ijọba ipinlẹ Eko. Ṣugbọn ki i ṣe Apara nikan ni yoo da ni ileeṣẹ naa, oun ati Tinubu funra ẹ ni. Tinubu ni ninu ipin-okoowo (Shares) ọgorun-un ti ileeṣẹ naa ba ni, Apara yoo mu iko ọgbọn (30 per cent), oun Tinubu yoo si ni aadọrin (70 per cent) to ku. Ṣugbọn oun Tinubu ko ni i fi orukọ oun si ileeṣẹ naa, orukọ awọn aṣoju kan loun yoo fi si i.Apara ni Tinubu fẹnu ara rẹ sọ foun pe oun ko le fi orukọ oun si i, ki ajọ to n tọpinpin owo awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba ma le maa le oun kiri, tabi ki wọn maa tudii oun wo to ba ya. Apara gba ọrọ ti Tinubu sọ gẹgẹ bii gomina, inu rẹ si dun pe oun ri eeyan nla ba ṣe, ati pe iṣẹ ti oun mọ lọkan lati ṣe fun ijọba ipinlẹ Eko yoo ṣee ṣe. Bayii ni wọn fi orukọ ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta silẹ ninu iwe ijọba, wọn si pe orukọ ileeṣẹ naa ni Alpha Beta Consulting Company Limited. Ninu ipin idokoowo naa, gẹgẹ bi adehun ti wọn ti ṣe tẹlẹ,  Dapọ Apara ni ọgbọn, Tinubu si ni aadọrin. ṢugbọnTinubu ko fi orukọ ara rẹ si i, o mu ọkunrin kan, Olumide Ogunmọla, wa, bo si tilẹ jẹ pe Apara ko mọ tọhun tẹlẹ, lẹyin ti Tinubu ti mu wọn mọ ara wọn, oun ni Tinubu ni ki wọn fun ni ipin ogoji (40 per cent), bẹẹ ni ki Apara fun Adegboyega Oyetọla, ẹni to jẹ gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun bayii, to si jẹ ibatan Tinubu, ni ipin ọgbọn.Bayii ni ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta bẹrẹ iṣẹ. Ko pẹ ti iṣẹ naa n lọ ti Tinubu paṣẹ fun Apara pe ko lọọ yọ orukọ Adegboyega Oyetọla kuro ninu iwe naa, ko si fi ti Tunde Badejọ rọpo rẹ, Apara si ṣe bi Tinubu ti wi gan-an. Bayii lo jẹ lati igba naa, orukọ awọn mẹta ti wọn ni ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta yii ni Dapọ Apara, Olumide Ogunmọla ati Tunde Badejọ, ṣugbọnTinubu lawọn mejeeji ti wọn gbẹyin yii n ṣiṣẹ fun.  Bi ẹni meji yoo ba fi ọwọ si owo ti wọn ba fẹẹ gba jade lati banki, Dapọ Apara ati ẹni kan ninu awọn meji to ku yii ni, bi Dapọ Apara ko si fi ọwọ si iwe owo naa, yoo ṣoro ki owo too jade, nitori oun gan-an ni oludari agba fun ileeṣeẹ wọn. Lẹyin ti wọn ti fi ọdun mẹwaa ṣiṣẹ naa, nnkan bẹrẹ si i yipada, ko jọ pe awọn Tinubu fẹ Apara nipo ọga mọ. Igbesẹ akọkọ ni pe ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ṣe ofin kan, ofin naa si ni Tinubu lo lati pe ki wọn sọ ileeṣẹ naa di ti ọlọpọ eeyan, ṣugbọn pẹlu ẹ naa, ko sẹni kan ti wọn gba orukọ ẹ wọle ju tawọn to ti wa tẹlẹ lọ.Ohun ti Tinubu lo eto naa fun ni lati fi Ogunmọla ṣe olori ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta, iyẹn lati dọgbọn gba ipo olori naa kuro lọwọ Apara. O ni ki Ogunmọla jẹ olori, nigba to jẹ aṣoju oun Tinubu ni, to si jẹ oun Tinubu ni oun ni ipin-idokoowo to pọ ju lọ nileeṣẹ ọhun, ki Apara si jẹ igbakeji rẹ. Nigba to tun di ọdun 2014, nnkan tun fẹẹ daru laarin Ogunmọla ati Tinubu, Tinubu si tun paṣẹ pe ki Ogunmọla fi ipo olori ileeṣẹ naa silẹ, ki oun jẹ igbakeji, ki Apara si tun pada si ipo gẹgẹ bii ọga agba pata. Bi nnkan ṣe wa niyi titi ti ijọba Ambọde fi de ni 2015, ti nnkan si bẹrẹ si yipada, o da bii pe Ambọde fẹẹ tọwọ bọ iṣẹ Alpha Beta, o fẹẹ mọ ohun to n lọ nibẹ gan-an. Idi ni pe owo ti ijọba Eko n san fun Alpa Beta pọ pupọ ni ọdun kan, to si jẹ bi owo ti n wọle fun ijọba Eko, bẹẹ ni owo Alpha Beta n pọ si i, eyi si jẹ ohun tijọba tuntun yii fẹẹ yẹwo.Ṣe oluṣiro owo agba ni Ambọde nileeṣẹ ijọba Eko ko too fẹyinti, o si mọ nipa Alpha Beta yii ati owo buruku ti wọn n gba lọwọ ijọba wọn. Nidii eyi, o jọ pe o fẹẹ gba iṣẹ naa kuro lọwọ Tinubu ati Alpha Beta rẹ, ki eleyii ma si ṣe ri bẹẹ ni Apara fi rin mọ Ambọde, to si mura lati ṣe ohun ti ọkunrin gomina tuntun naa ba ni ki wọn ṣe, ki wọn ma le gba iṣẹ ti wọn n ṣe naa lọwọ wọn, nigba to jẹ oun Apara ni olori ati oludasilẹ ileeṣẹ yii gan-an. Ko jọ pe irin ti Apara rin sun mọ awọn Ambọde yii tẹ Tinubu lọrun rara, o si mura lati igba naa lati gba gbogbo agbara ti Apara ni kuro lọwọ rẹ, o fẹẹ yọ ọ nipo ọga, bo ba si ṣee ṣe, ko yọ orukọ rẹ kuro ninu iwe ileeṣẹ naa, ṣugbọn eleyii ṣoro pupọ lati ṣe, nigba to jẹ Apara lo fi orukọ ileeṣẹ naa silẹ ninu iwe ijọba,ko si si ẹni to le ṣe ohunkohun lẹyin rẹ nibẹ, ṣe akauntanti loun naa.Nigba naa ni Tinubu kede fun Apara pe yoo fi ipo oga silẹ, oun si n gbe ẹlomi-in bọ ti yoo waa jẹ olori pata fun ileeṣẹ naa, ẹni ti yoo jẹ olori fun ileeṣẹ yii ni Akin Doherty. Ni gbogbo igba ti Tinubu n ṣe gomina, ọkan ninu awọn kọmiṣanna rẹ ni Doherty yii n ṣe, koda, oun ni kọmiṣanna fun eto inawo ninu ijọba Tinubu titi di ọdun 2007 ti wọn gbejọba silẹ. Ojulowo ọmọ Tinubu ni. Oun ni Tinubu mu wa pe ko waa gba ipo olori ati ọga agba ileeṣẹ naa, pe Apara yoo si jẹ igbakeji rẹ, ti wọn yoo jọ maa ṣe. Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan Apara nigba naa ni pe o n tọwọ bọ iwe owo, o n wadii awọn owo ti ileeṣẹ naa ti pa lati ẹyin ati bi wọn ti na awọn owo yii si, iyẹn ni gbogbo asiko to fi jẹ oun kọ ni ọga agba fun ileeṣẹ wọn. Wọn ni o fẹẹ lo iwe naa lati fi tu aṣiri owo ti ileeṣẹ naa na fun ijọba Ambọde ni. Bẹẹ, wọn si mọ laarin ara wọn pe Ambọde naa fẹẹ da ileeṣẹ bii ti Alpha Beta silẹ, ko le maa gba iru owo ti Tinubu n gba ni.Ọrọ yii bi Apara ninu wayi, pe bawo ni ẹni ti ko mọ igba ti awọn da ileeṣẹ silẹ yoo ṣe wa maa sẹ ọga le oun lori, ti wọn si tun waa paṣẹ pe oun ko gbọdọ mọ bi wọn ti nawo ileeṣẹ naa, oun ko si gbọdọ wadii bi owo ba ti ṣe n jade. Eyi lo sọ loju awọn eeyan, ti awọn yẹn si gbe ọrọ naa lọọ ba Tinubu, ti Tinubu fi ranṣẹ si i, to si sọ loju rẹ pe bi oun ti ṣe fẹẹ ṣe ileeṣẹ oun loun n ṣe e yẹn, nitori ileeṣẹ naa ki  i ṣe tirẹ, oun loun ni ipin idokoowo to pọ ju lọ. Nigba naa ni Apara sọ pe Tinubu sọ foun pe boun ba ro pe oun le tu aṣiri oun, ti oun gbe ọrọ naa lọ si ọdọ awọn EFCC, oun kan n daamu ara oun lasan ni o, nitori ẹni to wa ni EFCC to jẹ olori wọn nibẹ, Ibrahim Magu, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ oun ni, ko si ni i jẹ ki iru ọrọ bẹẹ jade laelae. Sibẹ naa, Apara taku, o ni oun ko ni i ṣe igbakeji fun Akin Doherty nile iṣẹ ti awọn jọ da silẹ.Pẹlu ẹ naa, Tunde Badejọ, ọkan ninu awọn ti wọn jọ da ileeṣẹ naa silẹ, mu Akin Doherty lọ si ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta, o si fi i han awọn oṣiṣẹ ibẹ gẹgẹ bii olori ileeṣẹ wọn tuntun. Lọjọ naa, Apara ni Badejọ kilọ fun oun pe ti oun ba fi tun fẹsẹ rin wa si ọfiisi awọn yii, oun yoo pa oun danu ni. Bi Apara ṣe kuro ni ileeṣẹ naa niyi, ti wọn si le e pe ko gbọdọ wa sibẹ mọ laelae. Ni 2018 leleyii ṣẹlẹ, Apara si sare ko gbogbo iwe to ni jọ, o jọ pe pẹlu atilẹyin Ambọde ti i ṣe gomina nigba naa ni, o si kọ ẹsun oriṣiiriṣii, bẹẹ lo tu aṣiri awọn ohun to ni Tinubu ṣe, bo ti n ko owo ileeṣẹ naa si apo ara rẹ, to n paṣẹ ki wọn maa ko owo wọn lo si oke-okun, to si n fi ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta lu ijọba Eko ni jibiti. Ọkunrin yii pa gbogbo rẹ pọ, o si kọwe naa si EFCC ninu oṣu keje, ọdun 2018, o ni ki won wadii ọrọ naa bo ba jẹ irọ loun n pa.Ṣugbọn EFCC gba iwe naa, wọn ju u si ẹgbẹ kan, gẹgẹ bi Tinubu ti ṣe leri ni, ko sẹni kan to pe Apara tabi awọn lọọya rẹ lati waa ṣe alaye ohun kan fun wọn lori ọrọ naa, wọn ṣe bii ẹni pe awọn ko ri i. Nigba ti ọrọ naa fẹẹ maa di ariwo, ti awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si i sọ pe ki lo de ti EFCC ko wadii Tinubu lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an, awọn EFCC yii jade ni ọjọ keje, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun 2018, wọn ni loootọ lawọn ti gba iwe ti Apara kọ, awọn si ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ iwadii lori rẹ, araalu yoo gbọ esi kia. Ṣugbọn titi ti ọdun 2018 fi kọja lọ, ti 2019 tẹle e, ti 2020 si fẹẹ pari bayii, ko ṣẹni to gbọ kinni kan lẹnu EFCC. Wọn tẹ ọrọ naa mọlẹ loootọ ni. Ohun to jẹ ki Apara ṣẹṣẹ waa gba ile-ẹjọ lọ bayii niyi, to ni ki awọn adajọ ba oun da a pe ki Tinubu ati ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta san owo-oṣu ati owo to kan oun gẹgẹ bii oludasilẹ ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta foun, ki ileeṣẹ si paṣẹ fun EFCC lati wadii ẹsun ti oun fi kan Tinubu ninu iwe ti oun kọ ranṣẹ si wọn.Ile-ẹjọ giga Eko kan ni Apara ti pe ẹjọ naa, o si ti yẹ ki ẹjọ bẹrẹ, ṣugbọn gbogbo ibi ti wọn wa Tinubu de lati fun un niwee ipẹjọ ni wọn ko ti ri i. Wọn wa a de Eko, wọn lo ti jade niluu, wọn wa a de Abuja, wọn lo ti jade niluu, wọn si de ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta, ko sẹni kan to ṣetan lati gba iwe ipẹjọ naa lọwọ wọn. Lọọya ti Apara gba, Tade Ipadeọla, ti ni ko si ohun ti awọn fẹẹ ṣe bayii ju ki awọn lọọ ba ile-ẹjọ sọrọ, ki wọn le jẹ ki awọn gbe iwe ipẹjọ naa sinu beba ati awọn ibi ti awọn eeyan naa yoo ti ri i, nitori laarin ọjọ mejilelogoji ni wọn gbọdọ pade nile-ẹjọ. Ohun to han ni pe ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta ati Tinubu paapaa ko fẹ ki ọrọ naa de ile-ẹjọ, nitori ileeṣẹ naa ti jade sita pe ki i ṣe Tinubu lo kowo jẹ, tabi lo dari owo si apo ara rẹ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe Apara ko awọn iwe ati ẹri oriṣiiriṣii silẹ lati sọ ibi ti Tinubu dari owo ileeṣẹ naa si, ati awọn akaunti tirẹ ti wọn n sanwo si.Wọn ni Apara lo kowo jẹ, iyẹn lawọn ṣe le e. Ṣugbọn lọna keji, wọn ni awọn tilẹ ti n wa a tipẹ pe ko waa jokoo ki awọn jọ sọrọ naa ni asoye, iye to ba si jẹ owo tirẹ nileeṣẹ yii, ki awọn san an fun un ko maa ba tirẹ lọ. Ṣugbọn ko jọ pe ọrọ naa yoo lọ bẹẹ, nitori ko jọ pe Apara ṣetan lati fi ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta yii silẹ fun Tinubu, o si ti sọ pe ogun biliọnu lowo oun to ti wa nilẹ bayii,ki wọn tete ba oun ko o. Ṣugbọn awọn to mọ nipa oṣelu ni ọrọ naa le ju bi awọn eeyan ti n foju wo o lọ, wọn ni idi ti yoo fi ṣoro fun Tinubu lati jade pe oun yoo di aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii niyi, nitori ọrọ to jade sita yii, bi Tinubu ko ba jawọ ninu ilakaka rẹ lati di aarẹ, afaimọ ni ko ni i wa latimọle tabi lọgba ẹwọn lasiko ti wọn yoo fi maa dibo naa, nitori ẹjọ naa yoo burẹkẹ mọ ọn lọwọ. Akọkọ ni pe bi Tinubu ba fi le jade pe oun loun ni ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta, tabi ti wọn ba ri owo kan to wọ inu akaunti rẹ lati ileeṣẹ yii, ko si ki ọrọ naa ma gbe e de ọgba ẹwọn.Idi ni pe o lodi sofin lati wa ninu ijọba gẹgẹ bii gomina, ki tọhun si lọọ da ileeṣẹ silẹ, ko si maa fi orukọ ileeṣẹ naa gba iṣẹ lọdọ ijọba to ti n ṣe olori. Ohun ti Tinubu si fi Alpha Beta ṣe ree, nitori lati ọdun 2002 ni wọn ti n gba iṣẹ lọwọ ijọba. Lọna keji, Tinubu ko ṣalaye fun ileeṣẹ to n ṣe akọsilẹ ohun-ini awọn oloṣelu to fẹẹ ṣejọba ki wọn too bẹrẹ iṣẹ, ati lẹyin ti wọn ba pari iṣẹ naa tan, pe oun ni oun ni ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta tabi pe oun gba owo kan lọwọ wọn. Ẹsun buruku leleyii naa ninu iwe ofin ijọba, ọna ti Tinubu si fi le bọ ninu rẹ ni ko jawọ ninu pe oun fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ, bi bẹẹ kọ, ọna ti awọn ọta rẹ yoo gba fi mu un niyi. Awọn ti wọn n woye ọrọ yii ni bi ko si ohun ti ajanaku jẹ tẹlẹ ikun, ko le ṣe ikun gbentọ si ọlọdẹ, bi ko ba jẹ Apara ni awọn alatilẹyin kan ni, ko le gbe iru ẹjọ yii jade, nigba to mọ pe o ṣee ṣe ki ẹjọ naa ko ba oun gan-an alara.Awọn Tinubu naa n wa ọkunrin yii karakara, ṣugbọn o ti sa mọ wọn lọwọ, ko si sẹni to mọ ibi to sa si, o jọ pe nigba ti ẹjọ naa ba de oju rẹ ni yoo too jade. Afaimọ ko ma jẹ ibi yii ni awọn alatako Jaganban yoo gba yọ si i, ti yoo si ṣoro fun un lati jade pe oun yoo du ipo aarẹ lọdun 2023. Bi ko ba si du ipo aarẹ, ko si bi yoo ti ṣe di aarẹ Naijiria ni 2023."},{"question":"Quais países da América do Sul não fazem fronteira com o Brasil?","answer":"Chile e Equador."},{"question":"Quem é \\"Jano\\" na Mitologia Romana?","answer":"Na Mitologia Romana, \\"Jano\\" é o Deus da Luz, que possui dois rostos (um atrás e outro na frente)."},{"question":"Zer da artea, eta nola ulertzen da gizartearen ikuspegitik?","answer":"Artea da gizakiak sortutako edozein sormen ekspresibo, estetiko edo komunikatibo. Gizartearen ikuspegitik, artea kultura, tradizio, sentimendu eta ideien isla da."},{"question":"பதினெட்டாவது அட்சக்கோடுநூலின் ஆசிரியர்  யார்?   ","answer":"விடை: அசோகமித்ரன்"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: തിമിംഗലത്തെ കൊല്ലുന്നതിൽ എന്തെങ്കിലും വിജയഗാഥകൾ ഉണ്ടോ?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: തിമിംഗലത്തെ കൊല്ലുന്നതിനെ ചെറുക്കാനുള്ള ശ്രമങ്ങൾ ഒരു പരിധിവരെ വിജയം കണ്ടിട്ടുണ്ട്. വാണിജ്യ തിമിംഗലവേട്ടയ്‌ക്കെതിരായ മൊറട്ടോറിയം ചില തിമിംഗലങ്ങളെ വീണ്ടെടുക്കാൻ സഹായിച്ചു, ചില ജീവിവർഗങ്ങളെ സംരക്ഷിക്കുന്നതിൽ സംരക്ഷണ നടപടികൾ ഫലപ്രദമാണ്. എന്നിരുന്നാലും, നിയമവിരുദ്ധമായ തിമിംഗലവേട്ടയും ചട്ടങ്ങളിലെ പഴുതുകളും വെല്ലുവിളികൾ ഉയർത്തുന്നത് തുടരുന്നു."},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: 1540-ൽ ഹെർണാണ്ടോ ഡി അലാർകോണിന്റെയും മെൽച്ചിയോർ ഡയസിന്റെയും കീഴിലുള്ള സ്പാനിഷ് കൊളോണിയൽ പര്യവേഷകർ ഈ പ്രദേശം സന്ദർശിക്കുകയും കൊളറാഡോ നദി മുറിച്ചു പ്രകൃത്യാ കടക്കാൻ പറ്റിയ ഈ പ്രദേശം ഒരു നഗരത്തിന് അനുയോജ്യമാണെന്ന് തിരിച്ചറിയുകയും ചെയ്തു. കൊളറാഡോ നദി ഒരു പ്രദേശത്ത് 1,000 അടിയിൽ താഴെ വീതിയുള്ളതായി ചുരുങ്ങുന്നു. യുമ ക്രോസിംഗിലൂടെ കൊളറാഡോ നദി മുറിച്ചുകടന്ന സൈനിക പര്യവേഷണങ്ങളിൽ ജുവാൻ ബൂട്ടിസ്റ്റ ഡി അൻസയുടെ സംഘം (1774), മോർമൻ ബറ്റാലിയൻ (1848), കാലിഫോർണിയ കോളം (1862) എന്നിവ ഉൾപ്പെടുന്നു. 1870 കളുടെ അവസാനം കാലിഫോർണിയ ഗോൾഡ് റഷിന്റെ കാലത്തും അതിനുശേഷവും, സതേൺ എമിഗ്രന്റ് പാതയിലേയ്ക്കുള്ള കടത്ത് മാർഗ്ഗത്തിന്റെ പേരിലും യുമ ക്രോസിംഗ് അറിയപ്പെട്ടിരുന്നു. കാരണം യാത്രക്കാർക്ക് വളരെ വിശാലമായ കൊളറാഡോ നദി മുറിച്ചുകടക്കാൻ കഴിയുന്ന ചുരുക്കം പ്രകൃതിദത്ത സ്ഥലങ്ങളിൽ ഒന്നായിരുന്ന ഇത് അക്കാലത്ത് കാലിഫോർണിയയിലേക്കുള്ള ഒരു കവാടമായി കണക്കാക്കപ്പെട്ടു.","answer":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡിക കൊളറാഡോ നദിയെയും കാലിഫോർണിയ സ്വർണ്ണ തിരക്കിനെയും കുറിച്ച് സംസാരിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Onye bụ Noko Matlou?","answer":"Noko Alice Matlou (amụrụ n'abalị iri atọ n'ọnwa Septemba n'afọ 1985) bụ onye na-agba bọọlụ na South Afrika nke na-agba bọọlụ dị ka onye na-eme egwuregwu maka ndị otu Spanish Segunda División Pro SD Eibar. Ọ nọchitere anya ndị otu ụmụ nwanyị nke mba South Africa ma dị ka onye na-agba ọsọ ma onye na-eche nche. N'afọ 2008, Matlou ghọrọ onye South Africa mbụ a kpọrọ African Women's Footballer of the Year."},{"question":"Kuih keria adalah manisan pencuci mulut yang popular, enak dinikmati untuk minum petang atau untuk berbuka puasa. Kuih keria merujuk kepada kuih keria yang disira dengan gula pasi. Tunjukkan resipi untuk kuih keria dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan Untuk Doh: ½ kg ubi keledek oren atau putih, 1 cawan tepung gandum, 1 sudu besar tepung beras, 1 sudu kecil garamBahan-bahan Untuk Sira: ½ cawan gula pasir, 1 cawan airCara penyediaan: 1. Campurkan tepung gandum dan tepung beras dalam satu bekasCara memasak:1. Kupas keledek, potong, bersihkan dan rebus bersama garam sehingga empuk. Tuskan kemudianlecekkan panas-panas dalam mangkuk adunan sehingga lumat.2. Masukkan campuran tepung sedikit demi sedikit dan uli sehingga menjadi doh. Jangan terlebih tepung, nanti keras.3. Ambil sedikit doh, bulatkan, kemudian leperkan sedikit dan seterusnya buat lubang di tengah. Letak atas dulang beralas plastik atau tepung supaya tak melekat. Ulangi sehingga habis doh.4. Goreng kuih di dalam minyak banyak (deep fry) sehingga keperangan. Kemudian angkat dan tuskan.5. Untuk menyira, didihkan air dalam kuali besar. Kemudian masukkan gula pasir. Masak dengan api kecil sehingga air gula berbuih dan likat berkilat.6. Masukkan kuih keria yang telah digoreng dan gaulkan rata sampai semua kuih bersalut air gula.7. Kecilkan api dan teruskan mengacau air gula berhalwa.8. Tutup api, angkat dan ceraikan kuih yang melekat.9. Biarkan sejuk sedikit sebelum hidang"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Claire Morgan (lahir 18 Mei 1980 di London, England) adalah seorang pemahat dan artis yang terdedah di peringkat antarabangsa yang tinggal dan bekerja di Belfast, Ireland Utara. Ayat 2: Claire Morgan (lahir 18 Mei 1980 di London, England) adalah seorang pemahat dan artis yang dipamerkan di peringkat antarabangsa yang tinggal dan bekerja di Belfast, Ireland Utara. Soalan: Apakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو  الفريق الأول فالسعودية من حيث عدد البطولات المحلية؟","answer":"الإجابة: نادي الهلال السعودي"},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال التالي كم عدد أرجل العنكبوت ؟","answer":"بالتأكيد، الإجابة هي 8 أرجل."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko gastronomia: Nola eragin du Euskal Herria mundu osoko sukaldaritzan?","answer":"Euskal gastronomia nazioartean ospetsua da, bere produktu kalitatezkoen eta sukaldari ospetsuenengatik, hala nola Juan Mari Arzak edo Martín Berasategui. Euskal sukaldaritzak, avantgardia eta tradizioaren nahasketa batean, mundu osoko sukaldaritza-tailerrak eragin ditu, eta \\"pintxos\\" kultura globala bihurtu da."},{"question":"Mínigh an greann seo a leanas? Cad a dúirt an bácálaí nuair a fuair sé a chuid airgid caillte? A: Is é sin díreach an méid a rinne mé!","answer":"Míniú: Is éard is ciall leis an bpócán a phéist ná é a bhrú agus a tharraingt; is é sin a dhéanann tú leis an bpócán sula ligfidh tú dó ardú. 'To knead' is cosúil le 'to need'. Tá an greann seo ag imirt ar na frásaí seo a bhfuil an fuaim chéanna acu. An bhfuil níos mó míniú agat? Níl, ach b'fhéidir go dteastaíonn níos mó míniú uait."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும் - auxiliary storage","answer":"துணை தேக்கம்"},{"question":"जीवनमा सबैभन्दा महत्वपूर्ण कुरा के हो?","answer":"यो व्यक्तित्वको आधारमा परिवर्तन हुन सक्छ। तर सामान्यतया, स्वास्थ्य, प्रेम, खुशी र सन्तुष्टि जीवनका सबैभन्दा महत्वपूर्ण कुरा हुन सक्छन्।"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?එලොව ","answer":"මෙලොව"},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jaki napastnik w 2022 roku był reprezentantem Polski w piłce nożnej, oraz graczem FC Barcelony?","answer":"Reprezentantem Polski w piłce nożnej, oraz graczem FC Barcelony w 2022 roku był Robert Lewandowski."},{"question":"Fisaka ve ny tany ? Valio eny na tsia.","answer":"Tsia, tsy fisaka ny tany fa boribory."},{"question":"E-Commerce හෙවත් ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික වානිජ්‍යය වල වාසි නම් කරන්න.","answer":"E-Commerce හෙවත් ඉලෙක්ට්‍රොනික වානිජ්‍යය වල වාසි පහත දැක්වේ.·         ඉතා ඉක්මනින් භාණ්ඩ හා සේවාවන් අලෙවි කර ගැනීමටත් මිලට ගැනීමටත් හැකි වනවා·         වෙළෙන්දාගේ මෙන්ම පාරිභෝගිකයාගේත් කාලය ඉතිරි වනවා·         වේලාවක් රහිතව දවසේ පැය 24 පුරාම වූවද ගනුදෙණු කල හැකිවනවා·         වෙළෙන්දා හා පාරිභෝගිකයා අතර මුණ ගැසීමක් සිදුවීම අනවශ්‍ය වනවා·         ලෝකයේ ඕනෑම රටක පුද්ගලයකුට ගණුදෙනු කළ හැකි වනවා·         කිසියම් පාරිභෝගිකයකුට ලොව ඕනෑම රටක අලුත් නිෂ්පාදනයක් වූවත් රටට ආනයනය කිරීමට පෙර ලබාගත හැකි වනවා"},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Azerbaijão?","answer":"Bacu."},{"question":"అన్నారుల పాలిట .అపర అన్నపూర్ణగా డొక్కా సీతమ్మను ఎందుకు పిలుస్తారు?","answer":"డొక్కా సీతమ్మగారు .నిరంతరం అన్నదానం చేసేది. ఒకసారి ఆమె అంతర్వేది వెళుతుంటే ఒక పెళ్లి బృందం కనిపించింది. వారు ఆకలితో మాట్లాడుకొనే మాటలను వింది. వారు డొక్కా సీతమ్మగారింటికి వెడితే అన్నం పెడతారు. చంటి పిల్లలకు పాలిస్తారు. అప్పటిదాకా ఓర్చుకోండి. అని ఒక పెద్దావిడ చెప్పడం వింది. వెంటనే తన – ప్రయాణం విరమించుకొంది. డొక్కా సీతమ్మగారు వారి కంటే ముందుగా, తన ఇంటికి వెళ్లింది. చక్కగా వంట చేసింది. వాళ్లు రాగానే తృప్తిగా భోజనాలు పెట్టింది. ఒకసారి ఒక తహసీల్దారుకు గరిక వేళ్లతో పచ్చడి చేసి భోజనం పెట్టింది.ఈ విధంగా అన్నార్తుల పాలిట అపర అన్నపూర్ణగా డొక్కా సీతమ్మగారు ప్రసిద్ధి పొందింది."},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Apakah tindakan yang harus diambil apabila kenderaan anda sedang dipotong oleh kenderaan lain?A. Menambahkan kelajuanB. Mengurangkan kelajuanC. Membunyikan hon","answer":"Jawapannya ialah B. Mengurangkan kelajuan"},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் எதிர்காலம் எந்த வகையில் உறுதியானது?","answer":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் எதிர்காலம் மிகவும் உறுதியானது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் திறமையான மக்கள், உயர் கல்வி நிலை, நல்ல தொழில் வளம் ஆகியவை உள்ளன. தமிழ்நாடு இந்தியாவின் முன்னணி மாநிலங்களில் ஒன்றாக இருக்கும்."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي أول دولة ديموقراطية فالتاريخ؟","answer":"الإجابة: مصطلح الديمقراطيه بان لاول مره فبلاد اليونان القديمة."},{"question":"जीवनशैलीले हाम्रो पोषण सेवनलाई कसरी असर गर्छ?","answer":"जीवनशैली छनोटले पोषण सेवनलाई धेरै असर गर्छ। व्यस्त तालिका,फास्ट फूड र प्रशोधित खानाहरूमा निर्भरता जस्ता कारकहरूले अपर्याप्त पोषण निम्त्याउन सक्छ, जसले समग्र स्वास्थ्य असर गर्छ।"},{"question":"Describe el evento más importante del texto : Además, se alzó con el Campeonato Sudamericano Sub-20 de 2009 totalizando 2 goles. Tiempo más tarde brillo en la Copa Mundial de Fútbol Sub-20 de 2009 siendo elegido como Balón de Bronce. En este torneo fue el capitán de Brasil, jugó 6 partidos y anotó 1 gol.","answer":"Fue la Copa Mundial de Fútbol Sub-20 del 2009. "},{"question":"O jakim wydarzeniu mówi ten tekst?\\"Zwycięzcami zorganizowanej w 2012 24. edycji zawodów zostali Czesi, którzy w finale pokonali reprezentację Francji 2:0. Do najbardziej utytułowanych narodów w Pucharze Hopmana należą Amerykanie (6 tytułów) oraz Hiszpanie i Słowacy – po 3 wygrane edycje zawodów.\\"","answer":"O Pucharze Hopmana z 2012 roku. Była to 24. edycja tenisowego turnieju, uznawanego za nieoficjalne mistrzostwa drużyn mieszanych. Zawody odbyły się w australijskim Perth w dniach od 31 grudnia 2011 do 7 stycznia 2012.W dwudziestej czwartej edycji imprezy udział wzięło osiem zespołów podzielonych na dwie grupy po cztery zespoły w każdej. Zwycięzcy grup awansowali do finału. Najwyżej rozstawionym zespołem była drużyna Czech. Pula nagród wyniosła 1 000 000 dolarów amerykańskich. W finale spotkały się reprezentacje Francji oraz Czech. Zwycięzcą zostały Czechy po konfrontacji wygranej stosunkiem 2:0."},{"question":"Hur många öar finns det i Sverige?","answer":"Sverige har nästan 270 000 öar enligt SCB (Statistiska Centralbyrån). Allra flest hittar man i Norrbottens län. 38% av Sveriges öar är så kallade havsöar, varav den största andelen havsöar finns i Stockholms län, bland annat i Skärgården."},{"question":"ਗਰਮ ਖੁਸ਼ਕ ਦਿਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੂਲਰ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਠੰਡ ਕਿਉਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਗਰਮ ਖੁਸ਼ਕ ਦਿਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ਵੱਧ ਜਾਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਕਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗਤਿਜ ਊਰਜਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ । ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ਕ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਹਵਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਜਲ ਵਾਸ਼ਪ ਘੱਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਹਵਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਲ ਕਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਘੱਟ ਹੋਣ ‘ਤੇ ਵਾਸ਼ਪੀਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਦਰ ਵੱਧ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਵਾਸ਼ਪੀਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਠੰਡਕ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Yaushe aka kafa Jami'ar Usmanu Danfodiyo?","answer":"A shekarar 1975."},{"question":"Siapakah Noraniza Idris? Huraikan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 170 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Nor Aniza binti Idris (lahir di Kluang, Johor, Malaysia, 27 Ogos 1968), lebih dikenali sebagai nama pentasnya, Noraniza Idris merupakan seorang penyanyi, pelakon, penerbit rakaman, penulis lagu di Malaysia. Noraniza merupakan salah seorang penyanyi Malaysia terbaik yang berjaya melahirkan album solo di setiap 4 dekad berturut selain M. Nasir, Anita Sarawak, Sharifah Aini, Khadijah Ibrahim, Jamal Abdillah dan Ramlah Ram. Memulakan kerjaya nyanyian sejak 1985, Noraniza lebih mesra disapa Kak Ani cukup sinonim dengan lagu-lagu yang berentak irama Malaysia dan etnik kreatif sehingga beliau mendapat jolokan Ratu Irama Malaysia.Sepanjang kerjaya muziknya, beliau telah menerbitkan 13 buah album solo, beberapa buah album kompilasi dan duet. Pada masa yang sama, Noraniza telah banyak meraih kejayaan di anugerah-anugerah besar muzik tanah air melalui albumnya, lagu dan persembahan pentas. Sehingga kini beliau masih kukuh di persada seni memperjuangkan irama budaya. Semangatnya tidak pernah mati memperjuangkan muzik tradisional dan lebih suku abad, Noraniza belum mahu berhenti malah melajukan gerakan bagi memastikan elemen kebanggaan Melayu ini terus bernafas di alaf digital."},{"question":"सूत्र A = (1/2) * (आधारहरूको योग) * उचाइ प्रयोग गरेर 8 इन्च र 12 इन्च, र 6 इन्चको उचाइ भएको ट्रापेजोइडको क्षेत्रफल गणना गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ट्रापेजोइडको क्षेत्रफल A = (1/2) * (8 इन्च + 12 इन्च) * 6 इन्च = 60 वर्ग इन्च हो।"},{"question":"In hoeveel landen in de wereld wordt er Frans gesproken? 11, 21, 31, 69?","answer":"In 31 landen, waardoor het een echte wereldtaal genoemd kan worden."},{"question":"ซูชิมีต้นกำเนิดมาจากประเทศอะไร","answer":"จากประเทศญี่ปุ่น"},{"question":"धवलयति समग्रं चन्द्रमा जीवलोकं किमिति निजकलङ्कं नात्मसंस्थं प्रमार्ष्टि |भवति विदितमेतत्प्रायशः सज्जनानां परहितनिरतानामादरो नाSSत्मकार्ये ||सुभाषित रत्नाकर (शार्ङ्गधर)","answer":"सर्व जगाला उजेडाने उजळणारा चंद्र स्वतःवरचा डाग का बरे पुसून टाकत नाही? परोपकारामध्ये मग्न असणाऱ्या सत्पुरुषांना बहुधा स्वतःकडे लक्ष देणे एवढे महत्वाचे वाटत नाही."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රථම පාර්ලිමේන්තු මැතිවරණය පැවති වසර","answer":"1947"},{"question":"Sokolaa","answer":"Brown\\t"},{"question":"1 haftalık gebelikte kese görünür mü?","answer":"Kesenin hamileliğin ilk haftalarında boş görünmesinin sebebi, embriyonun henüz ultrason cihazlarında net bir şekilde görünmeyecek kadar küçük olmasıdır. Embriyonun henüz son derece küçük olduğu süreçte gebelik kesesi de aynı oranda küçüktür ancak karından ya da vajinadan yapılan ultrason muayenelerinde yine de görünür."},{"question":"Inona no niavian’ny anarana hoe “Madagascar”?","answer":"Ny anarana hoe \\"Madagascar\\" dia avy amin'ilay mpikaroka portogey Diego Diaz, izay niantso ny nosy \\"Ilha de São Lourenço\\" tamin'ny taona 1500, saingy nivoatra ny anarana ka lasa \\"Madagascar\\".Araky ny fanazavan'i Avoko (olona mpandinika ny tontolo tsy hita maso) manokana anefa dia avy amin'ny anarana oe Dama,Sikarara sy i Gada izay ao amin'ny baiboly ka natambatambatra ary lasa Madagasikara satria zareo arabo dia mamaky teny avy any aoriana ka Dama lasa mada ary ny Gada lasa daga ary ny Sikara farateny kosa tsy nokitihana ka nahazo oe madadagasikara ary niafara tamin'ny hoe Madagasikara. "},{"question":"\\"Адамдын көркү баш болот, кабактын көркү каш болот\\" деген макалды түшүндүрүп берчи.","answer":"\\"Адамдын көркү баш болот, кабактын көркү каш болот\\" деген макалды мындайча түшүндүрсө болот: адамдын кадыр баркы бул ошол адамдын даанышмандыгында, акылмандуулугунда, адамдык жеке сапатында, жана адамдын сулуулугунун бир белгиси болуп адамдын бетиндеги каш болуп саналат."},{"question":"شهر میبد در کجای ایران قرار دارد؟","answer":"میبد یکی از شهرهای استان یزد است که یکی از مهم‌ترین جاذبه‌های گردشگری این استان نیز به حساب می‌آید. میبد در شمال یزد قرار دارد و از شرق و شمال با اردکان و از جنوب و غرب هم به شهرستان صدوق همسایه است.اگر قصد سفر از تهران به میبد با ماشین شخصی دارید، در حدود ۶ ساعت بدون توقف باید رانندگی کنید. البته از تهران، قم، کاشان، اصفهان و کرمان به میبد با قطار نیز امکان سفر وجود دارد."},{"question":"如何開啟並讀取 DAT 檔?","answer":"DAT 並沒有限定使用的應用程式，如果需要以某方式來開啟或讀取 DAT 檔，必須先了解該檔案是文字、影音或 Email 附件，還是其他格式檔案。"},{"question":"ආවර්ථිතා වගුව සොයාගත්තේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ආවර්ථිතා වගුව සොයාගත්තේ දිමිත්‍රි මෙන්ඩලීප්‌ මහතාය."},{"question":"ප්‍රබල අම්ල සඳහා උදාහරණ මොනවාද?","answer":"ප්‍රබල අම්ල සඳහා උදාහරණ ලෙස HCl,HNO3 හා H2SO4 දැක්විය හැකිය."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn tun ji akẹkọọ-binrin rẹpẹtẹ gbe nileewe ijọba ni Kebbi","answer":"Afi bii atẹgun to ja kiri ilu, bẹẹ lọrọ awọn janduku afẹmiṣofo agbebọn to n ṣoro bii agbọn nilẹ wa lasiko yii, wọn tun ti gbe wahala wọn de ipinlẹ Kebbi, awọn akẹkọọ-binrin ileewe ijọba tẹnikẹni ko ti i mọ iye wọn ni wọn lọọ ji gbe lafẹmọju Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, yii.Gẹgẹ bi iroyin to tẹ wa lọwọ, wọn ni niṣe lawọn agbebọn naa ya bo ọgba ileewe kọlẹẹji tijọba apapọ, Federal Government Girls College, to wa niluu Birnin Yauri, nijọba ibilẹ Yauri, nipinlẹ Kebbi, ni nnkan bii aago meji kọja iṣẹju diẹ lọganjọ oru.Kidaa awọn akẹkọọ-binrin ni wọn n kawe nileewe naa, inu ọgba ileewe ọhun si ni wọn n gbe pẹlu awọn olukọ wọn ti wọn n gbe ile ijọba.Ọkan ninu awọn ẹṣọ to raaye sa lọ ṣalaye pe ọkada rẹpẹtẹ lawọn janduku naa gun wa, ki ẹnikẹni too mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ, wọn ti bẹrẹ si i yinbọn lakọlakọ, o ni wọn ṣina ibọn bolẹ to fi jẹ pe oju oogun leeyan maa ro pe oun wa ni, o ni ibọn ni wọn fi ja geeti ileewe naa, ti wọn si rọ wọle.O lawọn kan lara wọn wọ aṣọ ọlọpaa, ti wọn mura bii agbofinro. O ni niṣe ni wọn dẹnu ibọn kọ ekeji oun tawọn jọ n ṣe sikiọriti, ti wọn si fipa mu un pe ko mu awọn lọ sibi tawọn akẹkọọ-binrin naa n sun si.Ọkunrin naa ni laarin ọgbọn iṣẹju, wọn ti ji ọpọ awọn akẹkọọ-binrin gbe, wọn ko wọn sori ọkada, wọn si gbe wọn wọgbo lọ.Iroyin mi-in sọ pe awọn agbebọn naa yinbọn ba agbofinro kan to n ṣọ ọgba ileewe naa ki wọn too raaye wọle lọọ ṣiṣẹẹbi wọn, ṣugbọn wọn lọlọọpa naa ko ku.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kebbi, DSP Nafiu Abubakar, sọ fawọn oniroyin lori foonu pe awọn ṣi n wadii ọrọ ọhun lọwọ, oun o ti i le sọrọ nipa ẹ bo tilẹ jẹ pe iroyin iṣẹlẹ naa ti to awọn leti."},{"question":"Türkiye'deki 2023 seçimleri ne zaman yapıldı?","answer":"Cumhurbaşkanı Recep Tayyip Erdoğan tarafından 10 Mart 2023'te imzalanan bir kararnameyle seçimlerin yenilenmesine karar verildi. Aynı gün Yüksek Seçim Kurulu genel seçimlerin ve cumhurbaşkanlığı seçiminin ilk turunun 14 Mayıs'ta ve cumhurbaşkanlığı seçiminin ikinci turunun da 28 Mayıs'ta yapılmasına karar verdi. Seçimler bu tarihlerde yapıldı. "},{"question":"วันนี้ยิ้มแล้วหรือยัง","answer":"ยังเลย วันนี้ไม่มีอารมณ์น่ะ"},{"question":"A wace shekara aka kashe tsohon shugan Nigeria Tafawa Balewa?","answer":"A shekarar 1966"},{"question":"Wọn sọ oṣiṣẹ ijọba to gba riba miliọnu marun-un sẹwọn ọdun mejila ni Kwara","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ to ga ju lọ lorileede yii ti ju alaga igbimọ alaṣẹ tẹlẹ ri ni ile ẹkọ gbogbonise (Poly) ti ipinlẹ Kwara, Ọmọwe Saadu Alanamu, si ẹwọn ọdun mejila, fẹsun pe o gba riba miliọnu marun-un naira lọwọ agbaṣẹṣe ni ile ẹkọ ọhun.Nibi igbẹjọ ti awọn igbimọ adajọ ẹlẹni marun-un jokoo rẹ ni ile-ẹjọ to ga ju lọ lorile-ede yii ti fidi ẹwọn ọdun mejila ọhun mulẹ, ti wọn si ni ko si idi ti wọn yoo fi da Alanamu silẹ, lẹyin to jẹbi ẹsun ti ajọ ICPC fi kan an lori iwa ibajẹ, ti ile-ẹjọ meji ọtọọtọ si ti ni ko lọọ fi aṣọ penpe roko ọba fun ọdun mejila gbako.Ni ọdun (2017) ni wọn fi orukọ Alanamu sọwọ gẹgẹ bii ẹni ti yoo jẹ ọkan lara igbimọ ajọ ICPC, ṣugbọn nigba ti wọn ṣe iwadii rẹ ni wọn ri i pe o lẹbọ lẹru, wọn lo gba miliọnu marun-un owo riba lọwọ agbaṣẹṣe kan to fẹẹ gba iṣẹ akanṣe kan ni ile ẹkọ poli ipinlẹ Kwara to wa ni ilu Ilọrin.Mahmud Abdulgafar lo ṣe idajọ Alanamu ni ile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Kwara, to si ju ọmọwe naa si ẹwọn ọdun mejila, sugbọn o gba ile-ẹjọ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun lọ. Ile-ẹjọ ko-tẹmi-lọrun tun fidi ẹwọn ọdun mejila naa mulẹ, o ba tun gba ile-ẹjọ to ga ju lọ (Supreme) lọ.Agbẹjọro rẹ, Ọjọgbọn Arẹmu Kannike, gbiyanju gbogbo agbara rẹ, ki Alanamu ma baa lọ ṣẹwọn, sugbọn pabo lo ja si, nitori ṣe ni adajọ ni ki Alanamu lọọ fi ẹwọn ọdun mejila jura."},{"question":"அரசனின் வெற்றியையும் வீரத்தையும் கூறுவன எது?","answer":"அரசனின் வெற்றியையும் வீரத்தையும் கூறுவன மெய்க்கீர்த்திகள். மெய்க்கீர்த்தி என்பது கல்வெட்டு ஒன்று எழுதப்படும் காலத்தில் ஆட்சியில் உள்ள அரசனின் உண்மையான புகழுக்குரிய செயல்களைக்கூறும் கல்வெட்டின் பகுதியாகும். கல்வெட்டுக்கள் முன்னரே தமிழ்நாட்டு மன்னர்களால் ஆக்கப்பட்டாலும் அவற்றில் விரிவான மெய்க்கீர்த்திகள் இருக்கவில்லை."},{"question":"Anu-anong mga bansa ang kasapi ng Association of Southeast Asian Nations o ASEAN?","answer":"Ang mga bansang bahagi ng ASEAN ay Brunei, Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand at Vietnam. Unang nagsumite ng aplikasyon upang maging miyembro noong 2011 ang East Timor, ang huling bansa sa Timog-Silangang Asya na hindi pa bahagi ng ASEAN. Bagama't hindi pa itinuturing na opisyal na kasapi ang East Timor, pinapayagan na itong dumalo sa mga pulong ng organisasyon."},{"question":"10 xog oo aan xaqiiq ahen","answer":"10 XOG OO AAN XAQIIQ AHAYN! BEENTA LA RUMAYSTAY!1.Waxaad isticmaashaa kaliya 10% maskaxdaada. 2.5G waxa uu keenaa kansar.  3.waad ku bukoon cunista cunto dhulka ku dhacday 4.Waligaa waa inaadan toosin qof hurda.  5.Dhiiggu waa buluug gudaha jidhkaaga.  6.Waa inaadan waligaa siin ilmo malab.  7.Carrabku waa muruqa ugu xoogga badan jirka. 8.Waa inaadan waligaa cabbin kafee ka hor intaadan seexan.9.Waa inaad cabtaa siddeed koob oo biyo ah maalintii.  10.Waa inaadan waligaa ku seexan timo qoyan. "},{"question":"Що таке дільник?","answer":"Дільником називають будь-яке натуральне число, на яке ділиться дане натуральне число.Наприклад, 18 ділиться на 6, отже 6 це дільник для числа 18."},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Ọ̀yọ́?","answer":"Ọlọ́lájùlọ Ṣèyì Mákindé ni."},{"question":"Helsinki moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Helsinki moy péeyu réwum Finlande"},{"question":"Korona: Ọjọgbọn Ibrahim ṣatilẹyin fun ẹkọ ayelujara","answer":"Ọga-agba Fasiti Al-Hikmah niluu Ilọrin tẹlẹ, Ọjọgbọn Mohammed Taofeek Ibrahim, ti rọ ijọba apapọ lati ma ṣi awọn ileewe bayii, ṣugbọn kawọn akẹkọọ maa kọ ẹkọ wọn lori ẹrọ ayelujara.Ibrahim to kawe gboye ninu eto ilera araalu (Public Health) sọrọ naa lonii, Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lasiko to n bawọn oniroyin sọrọ niluu Ilọrin.Ọjọgbọn to ti figba kan ṣiṣẹ pẹlu ajọ to n mojuto eto ilera lagbaaye, WHO, ni ẹmi awọn akẹkọọ atawọn olukọ ṣe pataki, fun idi eyi, ijọba gbọdọ ri i pe arun Korona din ku ki wọn too pada sileewe.O ṣalaye pe arun naa ko figba kan da iṣẹ tabi ẹkọ duro nileewe Al-Hikmah nitori pe ṣaaju ki kinni ọhun too dohun to n tan kaakiri lawọn ti n kọ awọn akẹkọọ awọn lati ori ẹrọ ayẹlujara.Nigba to n sọrọ lori ipa to ti ko laarin ọdun 2015 si asiko to fipo silẹ gẹgẹ bii ọga-agba fasiti naa, o ni Ọlọrun ti ran oun lọwọ lati mu igbega ba ileewe ọhun ju boun ṣe ba a.O dupẹ lọwọ oludasilẹ Fasiti Al-Hikmah, Jagunmolu tilẹ Igbomina to tun jẹ Arogundade tiluu Eko, Alhaji Abdur-Raheem Ọladimeji, fun anfaani lati ṣe akoso ileewe giga naa."},{"question":"Qual evento importante este texto fala sobre: Ele jogou 43 partidas pela seleção da tchecoslovaca, marcando 22 gols, e foi um dos participantes na Copa do Mundo de 1934, onde jogou em três partidas e marcou um gol no jogo contra a Suíça, em 31 de maio de 1934.","answer":"Copa do Mundo de 1934"},{"question":"Tôi bị cận thị đã mổ Lazer được 10 năm, nay lại bị cận lại và có xu hướng phát triển nhanh hơn lúc chưa mổ. Vậy cho hỏi cách phòng tránh để đảm bảo mắt không bị tăng số kính nhanh?","answer":"Với trường hợp của bạn, cần đến khám để xác định xem bạn còn cận bao nhiêu, chiều dày giác mạc còn bao nhiêu và tình trạng đáy mắt ra sao. Việc đó sẽ giúp tư vấn chính xác cho bạn là nên mổ bổ sung hoặc nên sử dụng kính thêm cho hợp lý."},{"question":"මල්ගුඩි දවස කෘතිය රචනා කරන ලද්දේ කවුරුන් විසින්ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියානු නවකතාකරුවෙක් වන ආර් කේ නාරායන් විසින් මල්ගුඩි දවස කෘතිය රචනා කර ඇත. ඉන්දියානු චින්තන ප්‍රකාශන මගින් 1943 දී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද කෙටිකතා එකතුවක් වන මෙම පොත 1982 දී පෙන්ගුයින් ක්ලැසික්ස් විසින් ඉන්දියාවෙන් පිටත නැවත ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. මෙම පොතට කථා 32 ක් ඇතුළත් වන අතර, ඒවා සියල්ලම දකුණු ඉන්දියාවේ පිහිටා ඇති මල්ගුඩි නම් ප්‍රබන්ධ නගරය හා සම්බන්ධ වේ."},{"question":"¿Son las macbooks buenas computadoras para desarrolladores de software?","answer":"Si. En 2020 Apple estrenó su propia línea de procesadores ARM llamada Apple Silicon. Con estos procesadores, se obtienen altas velocidades. Además, estos procesadores contienen memoria unificada, que es como una mezcla de RAM y GPU al mismo tiempo, lo cual quiere decir que poseen acelaración gráfica. En efecto, frameworks de Machine Learning como Pytorch y Tensorflow soportan acelaración con el hardware de Apple Silicon. Estos procesadores son también muy eficientes en cuanto al consumo energético, haciendo que las macbooks tengan una autonomía muy superior a la de computadoras gaming. Por otro lado, el sistema operativo es MacOS, basado en UNIX, así que soporta BASH y otros sublenguajes.En general, las macbooks pueden ser recomendadas a desarrolladores frontend, backend, móviles, de machine learning, etc."},{"question":"ما هي جنسية كارل ماركس ؟","answer":"ألماني"},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து செட்டிநாடு சிக்கன் கிரேவி செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:1 கிலோ சிக்கன்15 அல்லது 20 சின்ன வெங்காயம்2 தக்காளி2 பச்சை மிளகாய்¼ கப் துருவிய தேங்காய்4 காஞ்ச மிளகாய்3 பூண்டு புல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி தயிர்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோம்பு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரகம்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மிளகு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மல்லி½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மஞ்சள் தூள்1 பட்டை துண்டு1 பிரியாணி இலை1 நட்சத்திர சோம்பு4 கிராம்பு3 ஏலக்காய்1 ஜாவித்திரிதேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லிசிறிதளவு கருவேப்பிலை","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் வெங்காயம், தக்காளி, பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி, இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி, தேங்காயை துருவி, மற்றும் சிக்கனை நன்கு கழுவி சுத்தம் செய்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நாம் சுத்தம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கனை போட்டு அதனுடன் தயிர், மஞ்சள் தூள், மற்றும் சிறிதளவு உப்பை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு ஒரு மூடி போட்டு சுமார் அரை மணி நேரம் வரை ஊற விடவும்.3. பின்பு ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் காய்ந்த மிளகாயை போட்டு அதை நன்கு அரைத்து எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.5. எண்ணெய் சுட்டதும் அதில் பிரியாணி இலை, பட்டை, நட்சத்திர சோம்பு, கிராம்பு, ஏலக்காய், ஜாவித்திரி, சோம்பு, சீரகம், மற்றும் மிளகை போட்டு சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை அதை வறுக்கவும்.6. ஒரு நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் மல்லி மற்றும் நாம் அரைத்து எடுத்து வைத்திருக்கும் காய்ந்த மிளகாய்யை சேர்த்து நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு அதை சுமார் 2 நிமிடம் வரை வறுத்து எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விடவும்.7. பிறகு அதே பாத்திரத்தில் நாம் துருவி வைத்திருக்கும் தேங்காயை போட்டு தேங்காய் பொன் நிறம் வரும் வரை வறுத்து அதையும் நாம் வறுத்து எடுத்து வைத்திருக்கும் பொருட்களோடு சேர்த்து ஆற விடவும்.8. அது ஆறியதும் அதை ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாருக்கு மாற்றி அதில் தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு அரைத்து எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.9. பின்பு ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி எண்ணெய்யை சுட வைக்கவும்.10. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயத்தை போட்டு வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வரும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.11. வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வந்ததும் அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பச்சை மிளகாய், இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட், மற்றும் கருவேப்பிலையை சேர்த்து நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டின் பச்சை வாசம் போகும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.12. இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டின் பச்சை வாசம் போனதும் அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் தக்காளி மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு சேர்த்து நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு தக்காளியை நன்கு வதங்கும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.13. தக்காளி நன்கு வதங்கியவுடன் அதில் நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் சிக்கனை எடுத்து அதில் சேர்த்து சிக்கன் நன்கு மசாலாவுடன் ஓட்டுமாறு அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.14. பின்பு அதில் தேவைப்பட்டால் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீர் தெளித்து ஒரு மூடி போட்டு சுமார் 8 லிருந்து 10 நிமிடம் வரை அதை வேக விடவும்.15. 10 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு மூடியை திறந்து ஒரு கிளறு கிளறி அதில் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் மசாலாவை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு மீண்டும் மூடியை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 12 லிருந்து 15 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும். (உப்பை சரி பார்த்து தேவைப்பட்டால் சேர்த்து கொள்ளவும்.)16. 15 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு மூடியை திறந்து அதில் சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லியை தூவி ஒரு கிளறு கிளறி அடுப்பிலிருந்து கீழே இறக்கி சாதத்தில் ஊற்றி சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.17. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் சுவையான செட்டிநாடு சிக்கன் கிரேவி தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து சுவைத்து மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Waa imisa faralada waysadu?","answer":"Waa lix:1. in niyo lala imaado 2. wajiga in la maydho 3. gacmaha oo la maydho yadoo la gaadhsiinyo ilaa suxulada 4. madaxa oo badh ka mida la masaxo 5. lugaha oo la maydho ilaa kuraamaha 6. in la tartiibiyo"},{"question":"شحال من سنة عاش سيدنا إسحاق ؟","answer":"147 سنة"},{"question":"பாரதியாரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"இறவாத புகழுடைய புது நூல்கள் தமிழ் மொழியில் இயற்றல் வேண்டும் மறைவாக நமக்குள்ளே பழங்கதைகள் சொல்வதிலோர் மகிமை இல்லை."},{"question":"Een sausbasis bestaande uit azijn, witte wijn, sjalotten, dragonstengels, bouquet garni en peperbolletjes en is uitgevonden door de Brusselaar Vedy. Hoe noemt deze basissaus welke gebruikt wordt voor veel botersausen?","answer":"Het antwoord is Gastrique "},{"question":"\\"ഒരിക്കൽ ഒരു മുയൽ ആമയുമായി ചങ്ങാത്തത്തിലായി. ഒരു ദിവസം, അവൻ ആമയെ മത്സരത്തിന് വെല്ലുവിളിച്ചു. ആമ എത്ര സാവധാനത്തിലാണ് പോകുന്നതെന്ന് കണ്ട മുയൽ, താൻ ഇതിൽ എളുപ്പത്തിൽ വിജയിക്കുമെന്ന് കരുതി. അങ്ങനെ ആമ തുടരുന്നതിനിടയിൽ അവൻ ഒരു മയക്കം എടുത്തു.\\" മുകളിലെ കഥ പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക. ","answer":"മുയൽ ഉണർന്നപ്പോൾ, ആമ ഇതിനകം ഫിനിഷിംഗ് ലൈനിൽ എത്തിയതായി കണ്ടു. ഉറക്കത്തിന്റെ തിരക്കിലായിരിക്കെ, അമാ മത്സരത്തിൽ വിജയിച്ചു."},{"question":"De Franse wis- en natuurkundige die we zoeken bouwde in 1642 de eerste mechanische rekenmachine. Hij legde de grondslag voor de waarschijnlijkheidsrekening en bedacht de eerste vaste koetslijn voor openbaar vervoer in Parijs. Wie was deze Fransman?","answer":"Het antwoord is Blaise Pascal."},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk ‘Peranan Ibu Bapa Mendidik Anak-Anak’.","answer":"Pernyataan ‘keluarga bahagia tunjang kemakmuran negara’ jelas menunjukkan bahawa keluarga memang memainkan peranan yang penting dalam membentuk keperibadian mulia kanak-kanak. Remaja kini sering melibatkan diri dalam masalah sosial yang telah mencetuskan isu polemik dalam kalangan media massa yang saban hari meniti dari bibir ke bibir. Siapakah yang harus dipersalahkan dalam hal ini? Sudah tentu, sesuatu perkara berlaku tentu ada sebab-sebab yang mendorongnya kerana pepohon pokok tidak akan berliuk-lintuk jika tidak ditiup angin. Pembentukan keperibadian mulia anak-anak bermula daripada institusi keluarga. Sesebuah keluarga dibentuk dengan peranan ibu bapa masing-masing.Ibu bapa seharusnya mementingkan zuriat mereka sendiri daripada kerjaya. Malangnya, kebanyakan ibu bapa kini yang terlalu mementingkan kerjaya sehingga menyebabkan anak-anak mereka di rumah berasa tersisih seperti anak kera di hutan disusukan, anak di rumah mati kelaparan. Oleh hal yang demikian, ibu bapa haruslah mengimbangkan kerjaya dan kehidupan seharian mereka agar anak-anak dapat mendapat didikan yang baik dari segi fizikal dan mental. Ibu bapa sewajarnya tahu bahawa mujtamak yang kaya dalam kebendaan tetapi muflis dari segi keperibadian akan secara tidak langsung mendampakkan kesan negatif terhadap anak-anak mereka. Oleh itu, keluarga terutamanya ibu bapa memainkan peranan yang penting untuk membentuk keperibadian anak-anak.Selain itu, ibu bapa haruslah memberi didikan dan asuhan yang baik sejak kecil lagi kerana melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Anak-anak tentunya dapat mengimplimentasikan nilai-nilai murni dan sikap positif ini dalam kehidupan seharian, seterusnya membentuk sanubari yang baik. Ibu bapa merupakan uswah hasanah kepada anak-anak di rumah, oleh hal yang demikian, mereka mestilah sentiasa bersikap penyayang dan berbudi pekerti mulia dan jangan sesekali menjadi seperti ketam mengajar anaknya berjalan lurus, sedangkan diri sendiri berjalan mengiring. Sudah terang lagi bersuluh bahawa jati diri anak-anak dapat dibentuk melalui institusi keluarga khususnya ibu bapa yang memainkan peranan yang penting.Di samping itu, anak-anak yang berfikiran suci akan sentiasa mencontohi kelakuan ibu bapa mereka kerana bapa borek, anak rintik. Ibu bapa merupakan tempat luahan isi hati dan penyimpan rahsia yang paling dipercayai anak-anak. Lantaran itu, ibu bapa sewajarnya mengindoktrinasikan pucuk-pucuk hijau dengan nilai-nilai murni ini bagai menatang minyak yang penuh kerana anak-anak remaja kini sering melibatkan diri dalam kebejatan sosial dan budaya hedonisme yang begitu cepat merebak bagai virus epidemik. Melalui nasihat dan ajaran yang baik, sudah tentu anak-anak akan tahu cara-cara untuk membezakan antara intan dengan kaca kerana sesal dahulu pendapatan, sesal kemudian tidak berguna lagi. Institusi keluarga memang merupakan salah satu langkah yang signifikan dalam membentuk keperibadian anak-anak. Dalam nada yang berbeza, keluarga yang marem dan sakinah turut merupakan tempat yang paling baik agar proses pengajaran dan pembelajaran dilakukan dalam kalangan anak-anak. Sikap-sikap yang positif haruslah disemai dalam jiwa anak masing-masing bentuk menjamin kesejahteraan hidup dan pembentukan keperibadian mulia mereka. Anak-anak yang berusia setahun jagung, berdarah setampuk pinang ini mesti diberi penekanan dari segi mental dan fizikal supaya kelak dapat menjadi tunggak negara.Intihanya, keluarga merupakan mercu tanda kemakmuran negara dan menggalas tanggungjawab yang berat untuk mendidik anak-anak. Ibu bapa mestilah menjalankan obligasi masing-masing dengan tidak melepaskan batuk di tangga. Jikalau anak-anak kini berjaya membentuk keperibadian yang mulia, sudah tentu anak remaja yang merupakan pemuda harapan bangsa, pemudi tiang negara ini dapat menjadi pemimpin yang berkaliber kelak. Impian mantan bekas Perdana Menteri kita iaitu Pak Lah untuk membentuk sebuah negara yang cemerlang, gemilang dan terbilang dapat dimakbulkan, sekali gus menjadikan negara Malaysia berdiri gah di persada dunia."},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 法律が変わって、今年4月から18歳以上が成人になりました。成人になると、親の許可がなくても1人で契約ができます。 国民生活センターは、新しく成人になった18歳と19歳からのトラブルの相談について調べました。4月から9月にいちばん多かったのは、腕や足などの毛を少なくする「脱毛エステ」の相談で、541ありました。去年の同じときの7倍に増えました。","answer":"相談した人は「広告と違う高いプランのほうがいいと言われて、契約してしまった」とか「1回だけのつもりだったが、契約するように強く言われた」などと言っています。 国民生活センターは「成人になると、契約は自分の責任です。契約についてしっかり聞いて、よく考えることが必要です」と言っています。"},{"question":"Qual foi o primeiro rei de Portugal?","answer":"O primeiro rei de Portugal foi D. Afonso Henriques."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'perang saudara'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud perang antara orang sebangsa. Contoh ayat: Perang saudara yang berlaku di Afghanistan menyebabkan kerugian besar kepada negara itu."},{"question":"क्षेत्रफलको हिसाबले नेपालको सबैभन्दा सानो प्रदेश कुन हो ?","answer":"क्षेत्रफलको हिसाबले नेपालको सबैभन्दा सानो प्रदेश प्रदेश नम्बर २ (५६६१ वर्ग किलोमिटर) हो।"},{"question":"දකුණුලක අගනුවර ලෙස සලකන්නේ කුමන නගරයද?","answer":"දකුනුලක අගනුවර ලෙස සලකනු ලබන්නේ ගාල්ල නගරයයි."},{"question":"ફેસબુક વિશે જણાવો:","answer":" શરૂઆત 2004 માં માર્ક ઝકરબર્ગ દ્વારા હાર્વર્ડ યુનિવર્સિટીમાં તેમના રૂમમેટ્સ ડસ્ટીન મોસ્કોવિટ્ઝ, એડ્યુઆર્ડો સેવરિન અને ક્રિસ હ્યુજીસ સાથે મળીને કરવામાં આવી હતી. તે મૂળરૂપે \\"Thefacebook\\" તરીકે લોન્ચ કરવામાં આવી હતી અને તેનો ઉદ્દેશ્ય હાર્વર્ડ યુનિવર્સિટીના વિદ્યાર્થીઓને જોડવાનો હતો.જો કે, પ્લેટફોર્મ ઝડપથી લોકપ્રિય બન્યું અને ટૂંક સમયમાં અન્ય યુનિવર્સિટીઓ અને હાઇસ્કૂલોમાં વિસ્તર્યું. 2006 સુધીમાં, ફેસબુક સાર્વજનિક બીટા તરીકે ઉપલબ્ધ હતું અને કોઈપણ તેને જોડાઈ શકતું હતું.શરૂઆતમાં, ફેસબુક મુખ્યત્વે લોકોને પ્રોફાઇલ્સ બનાવવા, મિત્રો સાથે જોડાવા અને સંદેશા મોકલવાની મંજૂરી આપવા પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરતું હતું. જો કે, વર્ષોથી, પ્લેટફોર્મે ઘણી નવી સુવિધાઓ ઉમેરી છે, જેમ કે:ન્યૂઝ ફીડ:  જે વપરાશકર્તાઓને તેમના મિત્રો અને પસંદ કરેલા પૃષ્ઠોથી અપડેટ્સ જોવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે.ફોટો શેરિંગ: જે વપરાશકર્તાઓને તેમના મિત્રો સાથે ફોટા શેર કરવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે.વિડિઓ શેરિંગ: જે વપરાશકર્તાઓને તેમના મિત્રો સાથે વિડિઓઝ શેર કરવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે.ગ્રુપ્સ : જે વપરાશકર્તાઓને તેમના રસોને આધારે જૂથો બનાવવા અને જોડાવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે.પેજીસ: જે વ્યવસાયો અને સંગઠનોને તેમના ઑડિયન્સ સાથે જોડાવાની મંજૂરી આપે છે.આજે, ફેસબુક વિશ્વની સૌથી લોકપ્રિય સોશિયલ મીડિયા સાઇટ છે, જેમાં બિલિયનથી વધુ સક્રિય વપરાશકર્તાઓ છે. તે લોકોને જોડાવા, સંદેશા મોકલવા, માહિતી શેર કરવા અને સમાચાર વાંચવા માટે એક મહત્વપૂર્ણ પ્લેટફોર્મ બની ગયું છે."},{"question":"\\"බලය යනු වහල් බවෙකි . මම එහි වහලෙකි.\\"මෙම සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ප්‍රකාශය සිදුකල අසහාය දේශපාලඥයා කවුද?","answer":"ෆිදෙල් කැස්ත්‍රෝ ( කියුබාව )"},{"question":"విసర్గసంధి గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"విసర్గసంధి :i) హస్వ అకారము మీది విసర్గకు వర్గ ప్రథమ, ద్వితీయాక్షరములు గాని, శ, ష, సలు తప్ప మిగిలిన హల్లులు గాని పరమైనచో విసర్గకు ముందున్న అకారమునకు “ఓ”కారమాదేశ మగును.ఉదా :మనః + గతి – మనోగతితపః + ధనము – తపోధనముమనః + రథము – మనోరథముశిరః + రత్నము – శిరోరత్నముii) విసర్గాంత శబ్దములకు అచ్చులు గాని, వర్గ తృతీయ, చతుర్ధ, పంచమాక్షరములు గాని, హ, య, వ, రలు గాని పరమైనపుడు విసర్గకు రేఫము ఆదేశమగును.ఉదా :చతుః + ఆత్మ – చతురాత్మచతుః + భుజుడు – చతుర్భుజుడుధనుః + వేదము – ధనుర్వేదముపునః + దర్శనము – పునర్దర్శనముiii) విసర్గకు క, ఖ, ప, ఫలు పరమైనపుడు విసర్గకు మార్పురాదు.ఉదా :యశః + కాయము – యశఃకాయముతపః + ఫలము – తపఃఫలము"},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන  ලහුතා රූපය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ආහාර නො වැළඳීම ය, පමණට වඩා ආහාර වැළඳීමය, නො මනා ආහාර වැළඳීමය, ශීතෝෂ්ණ දෙකින් පෙළීමය, විෂ ශරීරගත වීමය, වෙහෙසීමය, නිදි නො ලැබීමය, සිත තැවීමය යනාදි කරුණු වලින් ශරීරයේ ධාතූහු කිපෙති. එයින් ක්‍රියා කිරීමෙහි අලස බවක් ඉක්මනින් ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ නො සමත් බවක් ශරීරයෙහි ඇති වේ. එයින් ශරීරය බරක් සේ දැනෙන්නට වන්නේය. විශේෂයෙන් පඨවි ආපෝ ධාතු දෙක උත්සන්න වීමෙන් ශරීරය බර වූවක් සේ දැනෙන ස්වභාවය ඇති වේ. එකල්හි ඒ ධාතු කෝපය දුරු කරන්නා වූ බෙහෙත් ආහාරාදිය සේවනය කළ හොත් ඒ ස්වභාවය දුරු වේ. ක්‍රියා කිරීමේ අනලස ස්වභාවය ද වහා ක්‍රියා කළ හැකි ස්වභාවය ද නැවත ඇතිවී ශරීරය සැහැල්ලු වූවක් මෙන් දැනෙන්නට වන්නේ ය. එය සිදුවන්නේ ශරීරයේ පළමු පැවති නො මනා රූප නිරුද්ධ වී ලහුතා රූපයෙන් යුක්ත වූ අභිනව රූප කලාප පහළ වීමෙනි. පසුව දැනෙන්නා වූ ඒ අනලස ස්වභාවය ලැහැල්ලු බව ලහුතා රූපය ය. මුදුතා, කම්මඤ්ඤතා රූප දෙක ද එය හා සමග ඇති මුත් ඒ අවස්ථාවේ දී ප්‍ර‍කටව පෙනෙන්නේ ලහුතා රූපයාගේ ලක්ෂණය ය.ශාරීරික මහා භූතයන්හි ඇත්තා වූ ඒවා ඉක්මනින් හා පහසුවෙන් ක්‍රියාවෙහි යෙදවිය හැකි බව වූ නො බර ගතිය ලහුතා රූපයාගේ ලක්ෂණය ය."},{"question":"Nitori owo atunṣe oju-ọna, kọmiṣanna Arẹgbẹṣọla ati ti Oyetọla gbena woju ara wọn l’Ọṣun","answer":"Owo tijọba apapọ san pada funjọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun lori atunṣe awọn ojupopo to jẹ tijọba apapọ ti da ariyanjiyan silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ-ẹyin gomina ana, Ọgbẹni Rauf Arẹgbẹṣọla, ati ti Gomina Gboyega Oyetọla bayii.Nibi eto kan ni kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ idile (Home Affairs) laye ijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla, Ọmọọba Sikiru Ayedun, ti sọ laipẹ yii pe biliọnu mejidinlaadọta naira (#48bn) ni Gomina Oyetọla ti gba pada latọdọ ijọba apapọ lori awọn oju-ọna ti wọn ti ṣe.Ayedun ṣalaye pe owo yii, eleyii to ni Arẹgbẹṣọla ṣiṣẹ rẹ silẹ fun un, ni Oyetọla n lo lati fi san ẹkunrẹrẹ owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ, to si pa aṣiri yii mọ fun awọn araalu.Ṣugbọn Kọmiṣanna feto iṣuna lọwọlọwọ bayii, Ọmọọba Bọla Oyebamiji, ko jẹ ki ọrọ naa tutu rara, o ni aturọta bii elubọ ni Ayedun, nitori ohun ti ko ridi lo n sọ fun awọn araalu.O ni irọ to jinna soootọ ni ọrọ ti Ayedun sọ ọhun, eleyii to si le ṣi awọn araalu lọna, to si tun le da wahala ati iyapa silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC.Oyebamiji ṣalaye pe biliọnu lọna mejidinlogoji naira (#38bn) gan-an ni gbogbo owo awọn oju-ọna ijọba apapọ tijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla ṣe, bawo waa ni ijọba Ọṣun yoo ṣe gba ju owo iṣẹ to ba ijọba apapọ ṣe lọ?O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe, lọwọlọwọ bayii, ẹẹmẹta ọtọọtọ nijọba apapọ ti fi lara owo naa ranṣẹ sijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun, apapọ mẹtẹẹta si jẹ biliọnu mejila o din miliọnu kan naira (#11.9bn), eyi to si jẹ owo awọn iṣẹ ti awọn kọngila ti ṣe yọri.O ni ori awọn oju-ọna mẹrin ọtọọtọ tijọba Oyetọla jogun latọdọ ijọba Arẹgbẹṣọla ni awọn na owo ọhun le lori yatọ si owo-oṣu ti Ayedun sọ.Oyebamiji waa ke si gbogbo awọn araalu lati maa wadii ohun gbogbo dajudaju, ko too di pe wọn aa di eyi to jẹ otitọ mu, ti wọn aa si maa polongo rẹ kaakiri ki alaafia le tubọ maa jọba nipinlẹ Ọṣun."},{"question":"Bi ẹnikẹni ba kọlu yin, ẹyin naa ẹ kọlu wọn – Ọga ọlọpaa patapata","answer":"Nitori bi awọn janduku kan ṣe pa awọn ọlọpaa nipakupa lasiko rogbodiyan SARS, Ọga ọlọpaa orilẹ-ede yii, Mohammed Adamu, ti paṣẹ fawọn agbofinro pe ki awọn naa kọlu wọn lati daabo bo ara wọn lọwọ awọn tọọgi to ba doju ija kọ wọn.Adamu sọrọ yii nigba to lọọ ṣabẹwo lori eto aabo kaakiri ilu Abuja. O ni, “Araalu ni ẹyin ọlọpaa naa, bẹẹ lẹyin naa ni ẹtọ, fun idi eyi, ko yẹ ki ẹnikẹni fi ẹtọ tiyin naa du yin.”Ọga ọlọpaa ti fun awọn ọlọpaa laṣẹ lati koju ija sẹnikẹni to ba kọlu wọn, nitori awọn ọlọpaa naa lẹtọọ daadaa, ko si yẹ ki tọọgi tabi janduku kankan maa fi ẹmi tiwọn naa wewu.O fi kun un pe ọrọ ti oun sọ yii, oun fẹẹ fi da araalu loju pe awọn ọlọpaa naa lẹtọọ labẹ ofin, awọn naa  si gbọdọ daabo bo ara wọn daadaa.Bakan naa lo sọ pe, “Ti a ba ri janduku kan to kọlu yin, gbogbo ọna ni ki ẹyin naa gba fi daabo bo ara yin, paapaa ti ko ba si ọna abayọ mọ rara.”"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਊਚੇ ਮੰਦਰ ਮਹਲ ਅਪਾਰਾ ॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਸੋਹਨਿ ਦੁਆਰ ਜੀਉ ਸੰਤ ਧਰਮ ਸਾਲਾ ॥ਧਰਮ ਸਾਲ ਅਪਾਰ ਦੈਆਰ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਸਦਾ ਕੀਰਤਨੁ ਗਾਵਹੇ ॥ਜਹ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਤ ਇਕਤ੍ਰ ਹੋਵਹਿ ਤਹਾ ਤੁਝਹਿ ਧਿਆਵਹੇ ॥ਕਰਿ ਦਇਆ ਮਇਆ ਦਇਆਲ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਹੋਹੁ ਦੀਨ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾਰਾ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਦਰਸ ਪਿਆਸੇ ਮਿਲਿ ਦਰਸਨ ਸੁਖੁ ਸਾਰਾ ॥੧॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਬਚਨ ਅਨੂਪ ਚਾਲ ਨਿਰਾਲੀ ॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੂੰ ਮਾਨਹਿ ਏਕੁ ਜੀ ਅਵਰ ਸਭ ਰਾਲੀ ॥ਮਾਨਹਿ ਤ ਏਕੁ ਅਲੇਖੁ ਠਾਕੁਰੁ ਜਿਨਹਿ ਸਭ ਕਲ ਧਾਰੀਆ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਬਚਨਿ ਗੁਰ ਕੈ ਵਸਿ ਕੀਆ ਆਦਿ ਪੁਰਖੁ ਬਨਵਾਰੀਆ ॥ਤੂੰ ਆਪਿ ਚਲਿਆ ਆਪਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਆਪਿ ਸਭ ਕਲ ਧਾਰੀਆ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਪੈਜ ਰਾਖਹੁ ਸਭ ਸੇਵਕ ਸਰਨਿ ਤੁਮਾਰੀਆ ॥੨॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੁਧੁ ਸਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਧਿਆਵੈ ਦਰਸ ਧਿਆਨਾ ॥ਮੋਹਨ ਜਮੁ ਨੇੜਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਤੁਧੁ ਜਪਹਿ ਨਿਦਾਨਾ ॥ਜਮਕਾਲੁ ਤਿਨ ਕਉ ਲਗੈ ਨਾਹੀ ਜੋ ਇਕ ਮਨਿ ਧਿਆਵਹੇ ॥ਮਨਿ ਬਚਨਿ ਕਰਮਿ ਜਿ ਤੁਧੁ ਅਰਾਧਹਿ ਸੇ ਸਭੇ ਫਲ ਪਾਵਹੇ ॥ਮਲ ਮੂਤ ਮੂੜ ਜਿ ਮੁਗਧ ਹੋਤੇ ਸਿ ਦੇਖਿ ਦਰਸੁ ਸੁਗਿਆਨਾ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਰਾਜੁ ਨਿਹਚਲੁ ਪੂਰਨ ਪੁਰਖ ਭਗਵਾਨਾ ॥੩॥ਮੋਹਨ ਤੂੰ ਸੁਫਲੁ ਫਲਿਆ ਸਣੁ ਪਰਵਾਰੇ ॥ਮੋਹਨ ਪੁਤ੍ਰ ਮੀਤ ਭਾਈ ਕੁਟੰਬ ਸਭਿ ਤਾਰੇ ॥ਤਾਰਿਆ ਜਹਾਨੁ ਲਹਿਆ ਅਭਿਮਾਨੁ ਜਿਨੀ ਦਰਸਨੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਤੁਧਨੋ ਧੰਨੁ ਕਹਿਆ ਤਿਨ ਜਮੁ ਨੇੜਿ ਨ ਆਇਆ ॥ਬੇਅੰਤ ਗੁਣ ਤੇਰੇ ਕਥੇ ਨ ਜਾਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪੁਰਖ ਮੁਰਾਰੇ ॥ਬਿਨਵੰਤਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਟੇਕ ਰਾਖੀ ਜਿਤੁ ਲਗਿ ਤਰਿਆ ਸੰਸਾਰੇ ॥੪॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 248 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਉੱਚੇ ਮੰਦਰ ਹਨ, ਤੇਰੇ ਮਹਲ ਐਸੈ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਾਰਲਾ ਬੰਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਧਰਮ-ਅਸਥਾਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ, ਤੇਰੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨ (ਬੈਠੇ) ਸੋਹਣੇ ਲੱਗ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੇ ਦਇਆਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਹੇ ਠਾਕੁਰ! ਤੇਰੇ ਧਰਮ-ਅਸਥਾਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ, ਤੇਰੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨ ਸਦਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਕੀਰਤਨ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।(ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ!) ਜਿਥੇ ਭੀ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਤ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਥੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਧਿਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਦਇਆ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਮੋਹਨ! ਹੇ ਸਭ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਮੋਹਨ! ਤੂੰ ਦਇਆ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਤਰਸ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਗਰੀਬਾਂ ਅਨਾਥਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਕਿਰਪਾਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈਂ । (ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ!) ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਸੇ (ਤੇਰੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨ) ਤੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰਸਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਖ ਮਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਬਚਨ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੇਰੀ ਚਾਲ (ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਚਾਲ ਨਾਲੋਂ) ਵੱਖਰੀ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ ਜੀ! (ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ) ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਹੀ (ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ) ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ, ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਨਾਸ-ਵੰਤ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਨੂੰ (ਅਸਥਿਰ) ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ—ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਤੈਨੂੰ—ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਸਰੂਪ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ, ਜੋ ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਦਾ ਪਾਲਣਹਾਰ ਹੈਂ, ਤੇ ਜਿਸ ਤੈਂ ਨੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੱਤਾ ਵਰਤਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਤੈਨੂੰ (ਤੇਰੇ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਨੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਬਚਨ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਪਿਆਰ-) ਵੱਸ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਢ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! (ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ) ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਉਮਰ ਭੋਗ ਕੇ ਜਗਤ ਤੋਂ) ਚਲਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਫਿਰ ਭੀ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੱਤਾ ਵਰਤਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ।ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—(ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ) ਲਾਜ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਸਾਰੇ ਸੇਵਕ-ਭਗਤ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਧਿਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰਸਨ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਜੀਵ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਜਪਦੇ ਹਨ, ਅੰਤ ਵੇਲੇ ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਸਹਮ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਦਾ ।ਜੇਹੜੇ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਇਕਾਗਰ ਮਨ ਨਾਲ ਧਿਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਸਹਮ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ (ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਸਕਦੀ) । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਬੋਲ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ, ਆਪਣੇ ਕਰਮ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ (ਮਨ-ਇੱਛਤ) ਫਲ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਹੇ ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕ! ਹੇ ਭਗਵਾਨ! ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਭੀ ਤੇਰਾ ਦਰਸਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਸੂਝ ਵਾਲੇ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ (ਪਹਿਲਾਂ) ਗੰਦੇ-ਕੁਕਰਮੀ ਤੇ ਮਹਾ ਮੂਰਖ ਹੰੁਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਤੇਰਾ ਰਾਜ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੂੰ ਬੜਾ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਫਲਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਬੜੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਪਰਵਾਰ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ । ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਪੁੱਤਰਾਂ ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਮਿੱਤਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਟੱਬਰ ਤੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਤੇਰਾ ਦਰਸਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਤੂੰ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ । ਤੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਹਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਤਾਰਨ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ । ਹੇ ਮੋਹਨ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ (ਵਡ-ਭਾਗੀਆਂ) ਨੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤੀ, ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਦੀ ।ਹੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ! ਸਰਬ-ਵਿਆਪਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹਨ, ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੇ । ਨਾਨਕ ਬੇਨਤੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ—ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਹੀ ਆਸਰਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਆਸਰੇ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ।੪।੨।\\""},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : ఇతిహాసాల యొక్క ప్రాముఖ్యత ఏమిటి?","answer":"రామాయణం, మహాభారతాలు అనేవి రెండు గొప్ప ఇతిహాసాలు, రామాయణాన్ని (ఆది కావ్యం) సంస్కృతంలోకి వాల్మీకి రచించారు. రామాయణంలో శ్రీరాముడిని ఆదర్శపాలకుడిగా, ఆదర్శ సోదరునిగా, ఆదర్శ కుమారునిగా, సీతను ఆదర్శ మహిళగా వర్ణించారు. మహాభారతాన్ని సంస్కృతంలో వేదవ్యాసుడనే ఋషి రచించాడు. అధర్మం పై ధర్మం సాధించిన విజయమే ‘మహాభారతం’గా చెప్పబడింది."},{"question":"kwanini vijana wengi wa kiume huchelewa  au kukosa hamu ya kuingia katika ndoa?","answer":"zipo sababu likuki zinazopelekea vijana wengi kushindwa au kuchelewa kuingia katika mahusiano, sababu hizo ni pamoja na kuumizwa katika mahusiano, kushuhudia vitendo viovu kwa wanandoa waliokwisha kuoana na kukosa uaminifu tendo linalowafanya wasione haja ya kuoa maana kama ni watoto wengine wanao tayari na ni mafundi wa tendo la ndoa ingawaje hawaingia bado katika ndoa."},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Học sinh tốt nghiệp trung học ở trường THPT Nguyễn Thị Minh Khai được cấp bằng gì vào thời Pháp?A. Bằng Tú TàiB. Bằng Thành ChungC. Bằng Sơ Cấp","answer":"Đáp án B. Bằng Thành ChungGiải thích: Khi mới khai giảng, trường Nữ sinh Áo Tím chỉ dạy bậc tiểu học. Đến năm 1918, vì số lượng học sinh gia tăng, trường xây thêm tòa nhà thứ hai với nhiều chức năng, đó cũng là nơi giảng dạy các môn nữ công gia chánh và thêu thùa.Bốn năm sau, trường mở thêm bậc trung học vì được xây thêm dãy nhà phía sau đủ rộng và được gọi là Collège Des Jeunes Filles Indigènes (trường Nữ trung học bản xứ), vẫn chỉ tuyển nữ sinh. Đây là trường nữ công lập duy nhất trong hệ thống các trường Pháp - Việt thời đó có ban trung học. Học sinh được chia thành hai ban: Sư phạm (học ra làm giáo viên) và Phổ thông. Tốt nghiệp trung học, học sinh được cấp bằng Thành chung. Tuy do người Pháp quản lý nhưng phong trào đấu tranh chống thực dân trong học sinh vẫn âm ỉ khi trong thập niên 1920, ít nhất hai lần nữ sinh của trường xuống đường biểu tình."},{"question":"Quel est le dixième élément du tableau périodique ?","answer":"Le dixième élément du tableau périodique est le Néon. Il est représenté par le symbole « Ne » et porte le numéro atomique 10. Le néon est un gaz noble connu pour sa lueur brillante et colorée distinctive lorsqu'il est utilisé dans les enseignes au néon et d'autres applications d'éclairage. Il est chimiquement inerte et ne forme pas facilement de composés avec d’autres éléments."},{"question":"多吃冰淇淋有什麼害處？","answer":"多吃了會使腸胃受冷收縮。腸胃一拱一拱地動得太快，會引起腹瀉，導致其他食物未經過充分消化和吸收，便已排出體外，身體不能吸收足夠的養分，就會影響健康。同時，冰淇淋里加了奶油、朱古力等，含有很高的熱量，容易使人發胖，所以不宜多吃。"},{"question":"¿Qué hace la librería de Python Langchain?","answer":"Langchain es una iniciativa de código abierto que aborda uno de los problemas más acuciantes de los grandes modelos lingüísticos (LLM): la gestión de una conversación. De forma nativa, las APIs LLM funcionan bien para escenarios de un solo turno de diálogo, tipo comando-y-respuesta"},{"question":"Maak de volgende zinnen af: De kansen leken te keren voor de hugenoten toen de protestantse Bourbon Hendrik III van Navarra trouwde met de Franse prinses Margaretha van Valois. Zijn huwelijk liep echter uit op een groot","answer":"bloedbad. Toen in 1589 Hendrik III van Frankrijk vermoord werd was Hendrik van Bourbon volgens de Salische Wet zijn opvolger. Hendrik aanvaardde de Franse kroon (als Hendrik IV) en werd katholiek. Nadat de Spaanse dreiging was geweken in zijn land beloofde Hendrik de hugenoten meer rechten."},{"question":"சிறுவர் இலக்கியத்தில் பாடல்கள் பற்றி எழுதுக.","answer":"சிறுவர்களுக்கான பாடல்கள் மிக முக்கியமான இடத்தினைச் சிறுவர் இலக்கியத்தில் வகிக்கின்றன / வகிக்கவும் செய்யும். சந்த நயத்துடன் பாடப்படும் பாடல் பாடுபவருக்கும் கேட்பவருக்கும் மகிழ்வினைக் கொடுக்கின்றது. பாடுபவருக்கு உற்சாகமும் தொம்பும் அளிக்கின்றது. உலகை மறந்து ரசிக்க வைத்துவிடும். அம்மாவின் தாலாட்டுப் பாடலில் பாடல்கள் துவங்குகின்றது. இசைக்கான ஆரம்பப் புள்ளி அம்மாவின் ஆராரோ பாடல்கள் தான். அதன்வழியே குழந்தை கொஞ்சம் வளர்ந்து அதே போன்ற பாடல்களைக் கேட்க ஆவலாக இருக்கும்.சிறுவர் இலக்கியத்தில் பதிவு செயப்பட்ட முதல் பாடலாகக் கருதுவது HA கிருஷ்ணப் பிள்ளை (1827-1900) இயற்றிய ‘இரட்சன்ய மனோகரம்’. அதனைத் தொடர்வது 1886 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இலங்கை யாழ்பாணத்தில் தம்பி முத்துப்பிள்ளை எழுதிய ‘பாலியக்கும்பி’ என்று வரலாறு கூறுகின்றது. அதன் பின் 1900களின் தொடக்கத்தில் அய்யாசாமி என்பவர் பால இராமாயணம எழுதுகின்றார். ராமரின் பால்ய பருவத்தை மட்டும் பாடல் வடிவில் கொடுத்த நூல்.செய்யுள் மூலம் தான் வரலாறு, மருத்துவம், வாழ்கை முறை, நீதிநெறிகள் நமக்கு வழிவழியாகக் கடத்தப்பட்டது. செய்யுள் வடிவத்தைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்த நோக்கம் அது மறக்கப்படாமல் இருப்பதற்கே. குழந்தைகளுக்கான பாடல்களில் ஒளவை வழியே வந்த பாரதியாரின் பாப்பா பாட்டுக் குறிப்பிடத்தகுந்தது. பாரதியார், கவிமணி, பாரதிதாசன், சுத்தானந்த பாரதி, வாணிதாசன், தமிழ் ஒளி ஆகியோர் சிறுவர் பாடல்களை இயற்றியதில் முதல்வகைக் கவிஞர்கள். இவர்களில் உச்சத்தைத் தொட்டவர் கவிமணி. ஆசியர் பணி மேற்கொண்டு அந்த அனுபவத்தைக் கொண்டே எழுதிய வகையில் கா.நமச்சிவாய முதலியார், மணை திருநாவுக்கரசு மற்றும் மயிலை சிவமுத்து அடங்குவர்.மூன்றாவது வகை கவிஞர்கள் வள்ளியப்பா, எ.ந.கணபதி, திருச்சி பாரதம், தமிழ்முடி, புவனை கலைச்செழியன் மற்றும் லெமன். இவர்கள் பல புதிய முயற்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டனர்."},{"question":"'Akungimangalisi ukuthi awazi lasalaphi leli Bhayibheli ngoba ngelikamama wami,hhayi umama wethu. Eqinisweni thina nawe asikaze sibe yinto eyodwa. Angazi njeukuthi uyaphi lapha ngoba phela lokwehlukana kwethu yinto owawukade uyibumbaPoppie.''Singaba yinto eyodwa kanjani wena ungikhunga kule milando yakininakumaBhayibheli akini? Singaba yinto eyodwa kanjani wena uhlala ngokuduba umakukhona ongakuboni kahle? Nakhu manje awusahlali ekhaya ngoba ngithengeleizingane imoto, uma ungayifuni imoto, buya ekhaya sizokhuluma siyithengiseimoto.''Sihambile isikhathi manje Poppie. Ngisho ungaze uyithengise imoto ngeke iwusule lomonakalo osewenzekile ezinganeni zethu laphaya ekhaya. Zingeke ziphinde zilungelezi zingane zethu.''Manje uthi masenzenjani manje myeni wami?''Ngithi masiyeke zilime ziye etsheni. Phela igeja libanjwe yisiphukuphuku.''Noma ngonile ngathengela izingane imoto, angisona isiphukuphuku Bafana.''Lixhoshwa libhekile Ngubane. Angiboni ukuthi uma mina ngenze iphutha, kufaneleungibize ngesiphukuphuku.''Angizange ngithi wena uyisiphukuphuku. Mina ngithe igeja libanjwe yisiphukuphuku.Uma likulingana leli kepisi, ligqoke Poppie. Uyabona ...'1. Phawula ngempumelelo yombhali ekwethuleni isingeniso sale noveli.","answer":"Umbhali uphumelele kahle ukwethula isingeniso sale noveli. Sitholeumlingiswa omkhulu onguNgubane kanye nesisusa sodweshu. Udweshulususwa ukufika kukaNjini Cele ezocelela izingane zikaLinono indawoyokuhlala emzini kaBafana oseMlazi ko-BA. UBafana utshela uCele ukuthiakabuye esemhlelele isikhathi sokukhuluma naye."},{"question":"“尺蚓穿堤,能漂一邑”这句话是什么意思呢？","answer":"这句话的字面上的意思是指蚯蚓虽小,但它把堤岸穿透了,就能把整个城市淹没。这谚语是用以比喻不注意小的事故,就会引起大祸。"},{"question":"firy kilometatra ny halavirana ofisialy amin'ny marathon?","answer":"Ny halavirana ofisialy amin'ny marathon dia 42.195 kilometatra."},{"question":"Nitori wahala ọrọ ilẹ, ijọba kede konilegbele niluu Ilobu ati Ẹrin-Ọṣun","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti kede konilegbele oniwakati mẹrinlelogun bayii latari wahala to n ṣẹlẹ laaarin ilu Ilobu ati Ẹrin-Ọṣun.Irọlẹ ọj ọ Abamẹta ni wahala ọlọjọ pipẹ naa tun bẹrẹ lasiko ti awọn oṣiṣẹ tijọba ni ki wọn yanju wahala aala ilẹ lagbegbe naa n ṣiṣẹ wọn lọwọ.A gbọ pe agbegbe kan to n jẹ Ahoro Aafin, lo da wahala ọhun silẹ, bi awọn Ilobu ṣe n sọ pe awọn lawọn ni i, lawọn Ẹrin-Ọṣun naa n pariwo pe ori ilẹ awọn ni.Bayii ni wahala yii burẹkẹ, bi wọn ṣe n fa ada yọ, ni wọn n lo aake, ko si pẹ ti wọn fi fa’bọn yọ, ti wọn si doju ẹ kọ ara wọn.A gbọ pe awọn ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun atawọn ọlọpaa ṣiṣẹ pupọ nibẹ loru-mọju, lati pẹtu saawọ naa, ṣugbọn bi ilẹ tun ṣe mọ ni wọn tun bẹrẹ.Lasiko ti a n ko iroyin yii, oku ọdọkunrin kan wa layiika aafin Olobuu, bẹẹ laimọye eeyan si fara pa niluu mejeeji.Idi niyi ti Gomina Gboyega Oyetọla fi kede konilegbele naa. O ni eleyii yoo le jẹ ki alaafia pada siluu mejeeji. O si rọ gbogbo awọn araalu lati pa aṣẹ naa mọ."},{"question":"จงเติมข้อความต่อจากนี้ให้สมบูรณ์:  พิธีเปิดการแข่งขันโอลิมปิกฤดูหนาว 2018 กำหนดจัดขึ้นในวันที่ 9 กุมภาพันธ์ พ.ศ. 2561 เวลา 20.00 น. ตามเวลามาตรฐานเกาหลี ณ สนามกีฬาโอลิมปิกพย็องชัง ซึ่งสร้างเพื่อจัดพิธีการในโอลิมปิกและ","answer":"พาราลิมปิกโดยเฉพาะ และจะรื้อถอนเมื่อการแข่งขันพาราลิมปิกได้เสร็จสิ้น"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bak ajung berat sebelah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud dikatakan terhadap pertimbangan atau keputusan yang tidak adil."},{"question":"Nấm bào ngư tươi gồm protit 4%, gluxit 3,4%, vitamin C, vitamin PP, axit folic, các axit béo không no. Khi nấm bào ngư dưới dạng sinh khối khô, hàm lượng protein chiếm tới 33-43%, bên cạnh các axit amin như glutamic, valin, isoleucin. Kết quả nghiên cứu dược lý cho thấy trong nấm bào ngư có chất pleutorin, công hiệu kháng khuẩn gram dương và kháng cả tế bào ","answer":"ung thư. Bên cạnh khả năng phòng ngừa ung thư, nấm ăn có tác dụng điều tiết công năng tim mạch, làm tăng lưu lượng máu động mạch vành, hạ thấp oxy tiêu thụ và cải thiện thiếu máu cơ tim.Các loại nấm như ngân nhĩ (mộc nhĩ trắng), mộc nhĩ đen, nấm đầu khỉ, nấm hương, đông trùng hạ thảo, giúp điều chỉnh rối loạn lipid máu, hạ cholesterol, triglycerid và beta-lipoprotein trong huyết thanh. Ngoài ra, nấm linh chi, mỡ, rơm, kim châm, ngân nhĩ, mộc nhĩ đen còn có tác dụng làm hạ huyết áp."},{"question":"આ \\"મા! મને છમ વડું\\" બાળવાર્તાની શરૂઆત આપેલી છે.\\"એક હતો બ્રાહ્મણ ને એક હતી બ્રાહ્મણી. એમને હતી સાત છોડીઓ.બ્રાહ્મણ ઘરનો બહુ જ ગરીબ. રોજ બિચારો સાત ગામ માગે ત્યારે માંડ માંડ પેટનું પૂરું થાય.એક દિવસ બ્રાહ્મણને વડાં ખાવાનું મન થયું. એણે બ્રાહ્મણીને કહ્યું - આજ તો વડાં ખાવાનું મન થયું છે.બ્રાહ્મણીએ કહે - પણ બધાંયને થાય એટલો લોટ ઘરમાં નથી. પાંચ-સાત વડાં થાય એટલો લોટ માંડ માંડ નીકળે તો પણ ઘણું.બ્રાહ્મણ કહે - ત્યારે કંઈ નહિ; વાત માંડી વાળો.\\"આગળની બાળવાર્તા પૂરી કરો.","answer":"બ્રાહ્મણી કહે - સારું.રાત પડી ને છોડીઓ સૂઈ ગઈ પછી બ્રાહ્મણીએ હળવેથી ઊઠીને ચૂલો સળગાવ્યો. પછી ચૂલા ઉપર લોઢી મૂકીને ઉપર ટીપૂંક તેલ મૂક્યું. પછી વડાંનો લોટ ડોઈને વડાં કરવા બેઠી. જ્યાં પહેલું વડું લોઢીમાં મૂક્યું ત્યાં ‘છમ, છમ’ થયું. આ ‘છમ છમ’નો અવાજ સાંભળી એક છોડી જાગી ને કહે - મા! મને છમ વડું.મા કહે - સૂઈ જા, સૂઈ જા, આ લે એક વડું. જોજે બીજી જાગે નહીં. પહેલી છોડી તો એક વડું ખાઈને પાણી પીને સૂતી.માએ તો બીજું વડું મૂક્યું. ત્યાં તો પાછું ‘છમ છમ’ થયું. બીજી છોડી જાગી ને કહે - મા! મને છમ વડું.મા કહે - લે સૂઈ જા, સૂઈ જા. જોજે બીજી બહેન જાગશે. બીજી છોડી વડું ખાઈને સૂઈ ગઈ.બ્રાહ્મણીએ બ્રાહ્મણની સામે જોયું. બ્રાહ્મણ કહે - હશે, એ તો છોકરાં છે ને!પછી માએ ત્રીજું વડું મૂક્યું; પણ ત્યાં તો પાછું છમ, છમ, છમ! ‘છમ છમ’ સાંભળી વળી એક છોડી જાગી ને કહે - મા! મને છમ વડું.મા કહે - લે. વળી તું ક્યાં જાગી! લે આ વડું; ખાઈને સૂઈ જજે. જોજે બીજીને જગાડતી નહિ.ત્રણ વડાં તો ખવાઈ ગયાં. હવે ચાર વડાંનો લોટ રહ્યો. બ્રાહ્મણીએ ચોથું વડું મૂક્યું. વળી પાછું વડું તો ‘છમ છમ છમ’ બોલ્યું. ‘છમ છમ’ થતું સાંભળી ચોથી છોડી જાગી ને એનેય વડું આપીને માએ સુવાડી દીધી. પછી તો પાંચમી છોડી જાગી ને પાંચમું વડું એને આપવું પડ્યું. તે પછી વળી છઠ્ઠી છોડી જાગી ને છઠ્ઠું વડું એના ભાગે ગયું. ને છેવટે સાતમું વડું સાતમી છોકરીએ ખાધું. ત્યાં તો બધો લોટ ખલાસ થઈ ગયો!બ્રાહ્મણ-બ્રાહ્મણીએ વડાં ન ખાધાં ને પાણી પીને સૂઈ ગયાં."},{"question":"Ilang taon nagtagal ang pananakop ng Espanya sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Nagtagal ng 333 na taon ang pananakop ng Espanya sa Pilipinas. Nagsimula ito noong Pebrero 13, 1565 nang matagumpay na sinakop ng mga Kastila ang isla ng Cebu sa pamumuno ni Miguel Lopez de Legaspi. Noong 1570 naman sinakop ng mga Kastila ang Maynila sa pamumuno ni Martin de Goiti. Nagtapos ang pananakop ng Espanya sa Pilipinas dahil sa rebolusyong pinamunuan ng kilusang Katipunan at dahil sa Spanish-American War. Ipinahayag ni Emilio Aguinaldo ang kasarinlan ng Pilipinas mula sa Espanya noong Hunyo 12, 1988. Gayunpaman, tuluyan lamang na nagtapos ang pamumuno ng mga Kastila sa bansa nang pinirmahan nila ang Treaty of Paris, na nagsasabing ibinebenta ng Espanya sa Estados Unidos ang Pilipinas sa halagang 20 milyong dolyar."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: ","answer":"Hiện trường xe bán tải tông hai phụ nữ tử vong ở TP.HCM"},{"question":"Босого деген эмне ?","answer":"Босого-дарыя нугундагы аска таштуу тайыз жер.Кээ бир дарыя өрөөндөрүндө аскалуу кууш жерин да босого деп аташат."},{"question":"*ما أول سورة نزلت في المدينة المنورة؟","answer":"البقرة"},{"question":"Aalo ìrókò àti Olúróhunbí","answer":"Àlọ́ oo ,Àlọ́ ọọ,Àlọ́ yìí dá lórí Olurohunbi àti OlúwéréNí ayé àtijó, obìnrin kan wà tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Olúróhunbí. Obìnrin yìí kò sì fi inú soyún, bẹ́ẹ̀ ni kò fẹ̀yin gbọ́mọ pọ̀n, èyí jásí pé ó yàgàn. Ó wá ọmọ títí ṣùgbọ́n pàbó ló ń já sí. Dípò kí ó dúró de iṣẹ́ Olódùmarè, ó gba ọ̀dọ̀ olúwéré lọ. Ó ṣe eléyìí nígbà tí ó rí àwọn tí wọ́n jọ wà nínú ipò báyìí tí wọ́n ń gbọ́mọ pọ̀n. Olúróhunbí gbéra ó lọ sí ọ̀dọ̀ olúwéré. Pẹ̀lú ìtara ni Olúróhunbí fi jẹ́ ẹ̀jẹ́ pé bí olúwéré bá fún òun lómọ, òun yíò sì fún un ní ọmọ náà. Ẹ̀jẹ́ yìí jẹ́ ọ̀tun nítorí pé, ewúrẹ́ àgùntàn ni àwọn obìnrin ń padà wá fún olúwéré gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀jẹ́.Lóòótọ́, Olúróhunbí lóyún, ó sì bí ọmọbìnrin kan tí ó sọ orúkọ rẹ̀ ní Apọ́nbiepo. Apọ́nbiepo ń dàgbà, ìyá rẹ̀ kò sì rántí ẹ̀jẹ́ tí ó bá olúwéré dá.Nígbà tí olúwéré retí Olúróhunbí kí ó wá mú ẹ̀jẹ́ rẹ̀ ṣe tí kò ríi ni òun gan-an bá gbéra ni ọjọ́ kan ó gba ilé Olúróhunbí lọ. Bí ó ṣe dé'bẹ̀ tí ó f'ojú kan Apọ́nbiepo ni ó bá lé lọ́wọ́ mú tí ó sì bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí mú lọ. Ọmọ yìí bẹ̀rẹ̀ si sunkún títí tí ìyá rẹ̀ Olúróhunbí bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí sáré tẹ́lẹ̀ olúwéré títí olúwéré fi padà wọ inú igi lọ pẹ̀lú Apọ́nbiepo.Olúróhunbí bẹ̀rẹ̀ si bẹ olúwéré pẹ̀lú omijé lójú, ṣùgbọ́n dípò kí olúwéré dá ọmọ padà, orin ni ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí fi dáa lóhùn báyìí pé:Olúwéré                  oníkálukú ń jẹ̀jẹ́ ewúrẹ́,                               Ewúré ewúrẹ́,                               oníkálukú ń jẹ̀jẹ́ àgùntàn,                                Àgùntàn bọ̀lọ̀jọ̀,                               Olúróhunbí ń jẹ̀jẹ́ ọmọ rẹ̀,                               ọmọ rẹ Apọ́nbiepo                                           Olúróhunbí ooAgbeorin              janin-janin, ìrókò janin-janinOlúwéré :              Olúróhunbí ooAgbeorin               janin-janin, ìrókò janin-janinBáyìí ni Olúróhunbí ṣe pàdánù ọmọ rẹ̀.Ẹ̀kọ́ tí Àlọ́ yìí kọ́ wa wípé bí a bá jẹ́jẹ̀ẹ́ kí á rí wí pé ẹ̀jẹ́ tí a lè san ni a jẹ́, kí á má máa fi ìwànwara jẹ́ ẹ̀jẹ́. Ní èkejì ó yẹ kí á máa kó gbogbo àníyàn wà tí Olódùmarè. Kí á má máa fi ìwànwara wá nǹkan torí ọba ọ̀kẹ́ t'óṣe fún Táyé kò gbàgbé Kẹ́hìndé, ẹ jẹ́ kí á sọ́ra."},{"question":"Apakah yang terjadi kepada Eye on Malaysia? Jelaskan tempat tarikan ini dalam zaman kegemilangannya. ","answer":"Eye on Malaysia ialah gelaran kepada sebuah roda pemerhatian raksasa setinggi 60 meter dengan 42 buah buaian atau gondola yang boleh berputar 360 darjah di Kuala Lumpur.Berharga RM30 juta, buaian raksasa berhawa dingin yang didirikan di Taman Tasik Titiwangsa, Kuala Lumpur ini telah dirasmikan oleh Perdana Menteri Malaysia, Datuk Seri Abdullah Ahmad Badawi pada 6 Januari 2007. Pada 8 November 2008, Eye on Malaysia telah dipindah ke negeri Melaka, iaitu di Kota Laksamana berdekatan Sungai Melaka.Pada 30 September 2010, Eye on Malaysia akhirnya ditanggalkan untuk dijual kepada pembeli luar. Antara yang menarik pada Eye on Malaysia ini ialah apabila berada di atas sekali, seseorang dapat melihat pemandangan ibu kota dalam lingkungan 20 km. Eye on Malaysia merupakan roda pemerhatian yang terbesar di Asia Tenggara (sebelum diatasi Singapore Flyer) dan juga buaian roda mudah alih terbesar di dunia. Buaian ini setinggi 60 meter dan mampu menanggung beban seberat 25 tan. Buaian ini istimewa kerana ia didirikan khas sempena Tahun Melawat Malaysia 2007.Pada tahun 2007, Eye on Malaysia menyajikan pelbagai acara menarik seperti teater air, pancaran laser diikuti dengan muzik yang menarik, pertunjukan bunga api (hingga 3 Februari) dan pertunjukan air (hingga bulan Mac 2007).Harga tiket bagi kanak-kanak ialah RM8, manakala dewasa RM15 untuk 6 kali pusingan yang mengambil masa lebih kurang 15 minit. Eye on Malaysia dibuka setiap hari dari pukul 10 pagi hingga 10 malam. Dengan pemilikan MyKad, harga akan dipotong sebanyak 50%."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--चोरांच्या हातची लंगोटी","answer":"ज्याच्याकडून काही मिळण्याची आशा नसते त्याच्याकडून थोडेतरी मिळणे."},{"question":"س260- ما الإسم الحقيقي لنبي الله إسرائيل عليه السلام ؟","answer":"ج260- سيدنا يعقوب عليه السلام"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي السورة القرانية اللي كايبكي فيها الشيطان فاش كايسمعها؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة السجدة."},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um médico?","answer":"Os médicos são responsáveis por cuidar da saúde dos pacientes. Eles atuam tanto de forma preventiva, antevendo a possíveis doenças e indicando caminhos para se preveni-las de forma ativa no diagnóstico, o que passa principalmente pelo cuidado das enfermidades encontradas. Os médicos desempenham um papel crítico no diagnóstico e tratamento de doenças."},{"question":"வினா:செஸ் விளையாட்டு தோன்றிய நாடு எது.?","answer":"விடை : இந்தியா"},{"question":"මුදවාපු මීකිරි යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"මුදවාපු මීකිරි, ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ දකුණු පළාත ආශ්‍රිතව බහුලව දැකිය හැකි කිරි නිෂ්පාදනයකි. මෙම කිරි ආහාරය පෝෂ්‍ය පදාර්ථ රැසකින් යුක්ත වූවකි."},{"question":"PDP fa ibinu yọ l’Ondo, wọn ni INEC ti gbabọde","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣèyí Makinde, tí ṣiwaju awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP l’Ondo lati ta ko iyansipo Ọjọgbọn Eyitọpẹ Ogungbenro Ogunbọdẹde gẹgẹ bii olori ajọ INEC ti yoo dari eto idibo to maa waye ni Satide, ọjọ Abamẹta, yii.Ohun ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP sọ ni pe olori awọn oṣiṣẹ eleto idibo tí yoo mojuto bi idibo ṣe maa waye, to tun duro gẹgẹ bii ẹni to maa kede ẹni to jawe olubori, ọmọ ilu kan naa loun ati Rotimi Akeredolu.Ṣeyi Makinde to jẹ alaga fun ipolongo ibo Eyitayọ Jẹgẹdẹ to n dije labẹ asia ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ti sọ pe awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo ko le ri esi ibo gidi ti ọga agba Yunifasiti Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ yii, Ọjọgbọn Ogunbọdẹde, ba fi le dari eto idibo ọhun.Ilu Akurẹ lawọn Ṣeyi Makinde ti sọrọ yii, bẹẹ ni inu n bí wọn gidigidi.Wọn ti sọ pe lọdọ ajọ agbaye gan-an lawọn yoo pariwo ojooro buruku ti ajo INEC atawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC fẹẹ ṣe fawọn yìí lọ, bẹẹ lawọn ko si ni i gba ki wọn fi ojooro dun awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo leto ibo gidi.Ẹgbẹ yii ti sọ pe ohun tawọn fẹ bayii ni ki ajọ INEC paarọ ọkunrin naa, ki wọn si wọ yunifasiti mi–in lọ lati lọọ mu ẹni tí ko ni i ni ohun kankan i ṣe pẹlu ipinlẹ Ondo, tabi ẹgbẹ oṣelu kankan.Bakan naa lo rọ awọn ẹsọ agbofinro pe ki wọn ma ṣe lọwọ si madaru lasiko ibo ọhun, bẹẹ lo ke si awọn ajọ agbaye naa lati foju si ibo to maa waye lọjọ Abamẹta yii, paapaa bi ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC ṣe n wa gbogbo ọna lati da nnkan ru mọ awọn lọwọ."},{"question":"Ijọ Ridiimu fẹẹ gba awẹ ọgbọn ọjọ fun alaafia Naijiria","answer":"Ki alaafia le pada si orilẹ-ede Naijiria, Olori ijọ Ridiimu, Pasitọ Enoch Adeboye, ti ke si awọn ọmọ ijọ ẹ lati gba aawẹ ọgbọn ọjọ.Pasitọ Johson Ọdẹṣọla ti i ṣe amugbalẹgbẹẹ fun olori ijọ yii lo sọrọ ọhun niluu Ibadan, lọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.O ni Alagba Adeboye ti sọ pe ọjọ ki-in-ni, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun yii, ni gbogbo Kristẹni ti wọn jẹ ọmọ ijọ Ridiimu gbọdọ bẹrẹ aawẹ ati adura ọhun fun Naijiria.O fi kun un pe laarin ọjọ kin-in-ni, si ikẹrinla, ni aawẹ agbayipo yoo waye fawọn ti wọn ba lanfaani lati gba a, ti eto bi ohun gbogbo yoo ṣe lọ yoo tẹ wọn lọwọ laipẹ yii.Bakan naa lo rọ awọn ọmọ ijọ ọhun lati wa fun ipade adura, ati pe gbogbo eto ati ilana ti ijọba la kalẹ lori iparamọ lati dena itankalẹ arun koronafairọọsi lawọn yoo tẹle.Pasitọ Johnson Ọdẹṣọla tun sọ pe Alagba Adeboye ti ni ki awọn sọ fun gbogbo awọn ọmọ ijọ naa ki wọn gbiyanju lati fadura ati aawẹ ọlọgbọn-ọjọ yii jagun fun alaafia Naijiria."},{"question":"Ni bayii, ọrọ ile Oṣodi yii lo wa lọkan gbogbo wa","answer":"Mo mọ nnkan temi, mo mo bo ṣe maa n ri. Ti mo ba ti fẹẹ ṣe nnkan, to ba ti n ri bo ṣe n ri yii, mo ti mọ pe kinni naa maa bọ si i ni. Ohun to tun maa n ṣe mi lara bakan ni pe ko si ohun ti mo ni mo fẹẹ ṣe ti awọn eeyan maa ro pe n ko ni owo ti mo le fi ṣe e lọwọ. Ẹ ẹ gbọdọ ri i bi Sẹki ṣe ṣe, niṣe lo n ṣe bii pe owo yẹn ti wa lọwọ mi, to n jo silẹ, to n pariwo, o ti ṣee ṣe. Bẹẹ ni temi, ko si ohun to fẹẹ mu mi ra ile naa gan-an ju ọrọ ti Safu sọ lọ, pe ibẹ ba mi lọwọ mu, ati pe ti ẹlomi-in ba ra a, o le le wa jade nibẹ, ki oluwa ẹ ṣẹṣẹ maa wa ṣọọbu mi-in kiri.Ohun kan ti mo maa n sa fun bi ọrọ ba ti da bayii ni ija, ori mi ki i pariwo rara. Nitori ẹ lo ṣe jẹ igba ti Aunti Sikira tun fẹẹ ba Safu ja, ti mo si mọ pe tọrọ naa ba ṣẹlẹ, yoo kan mi, mo yaa kilọ fun iyẹn pe ti mo ba gbọ ariwo kan lẹnu ẹ, mo maa fọ ọ leti ni. Niyẹn ba yaa sinmi. Gbogbo bi Aunti Sikira ṣe n leri, to n pariwo pe oun fẹẹ fi han an pe fada ni baba jẹ fọmọ, ọmọ yẹn o gbin o, o n wo ni tiẹ ni. Ohun to dun mi ni pe Alaaji to yẹ ko da Aunti Sikira nibẹẹnu, ko kilọ fun un ko yee fira ẹ wọlẹ, niṣe loun tilẹkun mọri, ṣugbọn mo mọ pe ti mo ba sọrọ, ọrọ le di temi.Iwọ lo sọ fun ọmọ pe ko jẹ ko o ba oun sun, pe o n gbe idi sa fun ọ. O tun ni emi ni mo n kọ ọ, pe ko ma fara we emi, nitori ọrọ temi yatọ gedengbe. Gbogbo ẹ lọmọ yii kuku wa n sọ femi. Mo si sọ fọmọ pe eeyan ki i fi ibasun du ọkọ ẹ o, to ba ti jẹ ohun to fẹ ree, ko tete yaa fun un. Niyẹn ba si ni oun ti gbọ, lo ba ni ni ọjọ meji loun maa fun un, ọjo Ileya ati ọjọ keji ẹ. Oun ko ni i lọ sibi kan, oun naa ko ni i jẹ ki baba jade, Lẹyin ta a ba ti kirun ọdun tan, oun maa de e mọle ni, gbogbo nnkan to ba fẹẹ ṣe, gbogbo ere to ba fẹẹ ṣe, ko waa ṣe e foun.Ni gbogbo igba ti mo n wi yii, Safu ti ra firisa kekere kan bayii sinu ile, ati maikroweefu to fi n gbe ounjẹ kana ninu ile wọn nibẹ. Nitori bẹẹ, o le ma de kiṣinni yẹn laarin ọsẹ kan, ọbẹ nikan lo n lọọ se nibẹ. O tun ni firiiji kekere to fi n ko ọti si fun Alaaji, ti oun naa si n ra miniraasi si i to ba fẹẹ mu. Gbogbo ile ẹ lo ti ṣe pe. Bẹẹ lo ṣe jẹ pe lọjọ ọdun ati ọjọ keji ẹ, ko jẹ ki Alaaji bọ sita. Ṣe wọn kuku ti ni ka ma ̀lọọ kirun, kaluku kirun nile ẹ ni. Bọmọ ṣe mu Alaaji mabẹ ninu ile niyẹn o. Alaaji naa to si laiki nnkan bii ifa bii ifa bẹẹ, bi iyẹn ṣe n fun un ni miliiki mu, to n fun un lẹran dindin, to n fun un ni sitaotu, to si n jẹ ko ba oun sun laimọye igba, niṣe ni inu ẹ n dun, to n ṣe faaji ẹ ninu ile.Bi ẹnikẹni ba ti waa wa Alaaji wa, Safu lo maa dahun, o maa ni wọn n sun lọwọ. O jọ pe Aunti Sikira naa ti mura silẹ, o ti ro pe Safu maa lọ si ṣọọbu nijọ keji ọdun, nitori iyẹn naa, tiẹ wa lara ẹ, ko sigba ti ki i lọ si ṣọọbu, o le ni ki loun n ṣe nile, bo ba si lọ loootọ, yoo pa iye kan wale. Ohun ti Aunti Sikira ti fọkan si niyi, afi b’ọmọ o ṣe lọọ ṣọọbu, to tilẹkun mọ baba. Igba  temi n lọ ọdọ awọn Sẹki, mo ri aunti yẹn to ti wẹ, to wọ buresia to fi maa n ko ọmu soke bii tọmọde yẹn kiri ile, mo ti mọ pe baba lo pọn gbogbo ẹ fun, b’Alaaji ba ti le ri i, iṣẹ ọjọ naa pari niyẹn.Ṣugbọn Safu ko jẹ ki baba yọju sita. Emi si ti jade, ọrọ rederede ki i ba ikun nile. Wọn waa ni bi Aunti Sikira ti n paara ẹnu ọna Alaaji lọ, bẹẹ lo n paara ẹ bọ. Igba mi-in, yoo maa rin kiri iwaju ibẹ, igba mi-in, yoo kan ilẹkun pe ṣe wọn ko ti i too ji naa ni, igba kan si wa to ni oun ni ọrọ pataki kan ti oun fẹẹ ba wọn sọ. Igba naa ni Safu sọ fun mi pe Alaaji da a lohun pe gbogbo ohun to ba fẹẹ sọ foun, o di ọjọ keji, nitori oun fẹẹ sinmi ni. Baba buruku. Isinmi wo lo fẹẹ sinmi, ẹni ti Safu n koṣẹ fun. Aunti Sikira naa si mọ iru ẹ, nigba to jẹ ohun toun naa n ṣe niyẹn, ohun to jẹ ki inu bi i si Safu ree.Lọrọ kan, ko ṣẹni to foju kan Alaaji ninu ile yẹn ni Sannde, Safu jẹwọ fun gbogbo wọn pe oun niyawo kekere, oun ṣi wa loju ẹ. Amọ bi ilẹ ṣe n mọ lọjọ Mọnde, Safu ti mura ibi iṣẹ tiẹ, o kan wa soke lati waa sọ fun mi ni pe awọn ara banki ti mo ni wọn le wa mi wa laaarọ ọjọ yẹn ki n too de, ko le mọ ohun to maa sọ fun wọn bi wọn ba ṣaaju mi de. Afi bii pe Aunti Sikira ti n duro de e, o tiẹ ti n duro de e ni. Bo ṣe fo jade niyẹn, to n bi i ni kuẹṣan awọn oniwee mẹwaa, pe ki lo de to tilẹkun mọ Alaaji lanaa, ṣe o ro pe oun nikan loun ni ọkọ ni, ki i lo fẹ ki awọn to ku maa ṣe nigba ti oun mu baba to tilẹkun mọ ọn.‘O ṣaarọ Mọnde, ẹ fi mi silẹ o, Ọlọrun o ni i di yin lọwọ o!’ Ohun ti Safu sọ niyẹn. Ohun tiẹ ti mo si gbọ ni mo fi jade, ni mo ba pariwo mọ ọn pe ti mo ba tun gbọ ohun ẹ nibẹ yẹn, mo maa fọ  ọ leti ni. Lo ba sare wa soke lọdọ mi, bo si ti ṣalaye ọrọ naa tan ni mo ni ko yaa maa lọ. Mo sọ fun un pe ẹni a ba na lara n ta, pe ṣe ko mọ ohun to n dun iyaale ẹ ni. Mo ni ko ma dahun o, ko yaa maa lọ si ṣọọbu kiakia, ko ma jẹ ki ẹnikẹni di i lọwọ iṣẹ aje ẹ. N lọmọ ba yaa n lọ. Ṣugbọn bo ṣe n lọ naa nkọ, lọjọ naa ni mo mọ pe aunti yẹn ko lojuti rara, ọmọọta kan bayii ni.Orukọ tobinrin yẹn ko pe Safu tan lo n lọ yẹn, “Ruutu! Abọkọku! Ja-kinni-jẹ! ṣe o fẹẹ gbe e lọ ni! Wọn aa fi su ẹ! O jẹ di i mẹru lọ si ṣọọbu, Ṣaa ma pa baba fun wa o, ranti pe baba ti dagba o, nitori ki i ṣe bi awa to ku ṣe n jẹ ẹ ree o. Bo ba jẹ bi a ṣe n jẹ ẹ niyẹn, o o ni ba nnkan kan nibẹ mọ o. Ṣebi wọn ni iṣẹ lo laiki, bayii naa lo tun laiki kinni to ni!” Mo kan wa lori bankoni ti mo n rẹrin-in ni, mo mọ pe ka ni mo tu Safu silẹ fun un ni, yoo gba ṣẹnji ẹ. Ṣugbọn ohun to wa niwaju mi ko le jẹ ki n ṣe bẹẹ, kẹnikan ma ba mi fariwo le oriire mi lọ. Safu naa si mọ, nitori mo sọ fun un.Mo ni ṣe o mọ pe awa la fẹẹ ṣe nnkan rere, bi eeyan ba fẹẹ ṣe nnkan rere, ki i pariwo o. N lọmọ yẹn ba lọ. Alaaji to yẹ ko jade ko gbeja ẹ, gbaga ni mo gbọ to tilẹkun lati igba ti Safu ti kọkọ jade lakọọkọ, gbogbo bi iyawo ẹ si ti n gbo bii aja to nibẹ yẹn, ko jade ko waa gba ọmọ yẹn silẹ lọwọ ẹ, oun si leku ẹda to da a silẹ. Emi naa ko pẹ ti mo fi yaa jade, ki wọn ma ko ba mi, nitori mo mọ pe ohun ti Safu ṣe fun Alaaji yẹn, ọjọ mẹta, ko ni i ba ẹlomi-in sun, ọmọ yẹn ti leri bẹẹ fun mi. Ohun to jẹ ko tilẹkun gbaga niyẹn. Inu temi dun pe Ọlọrun ti ba mi le eṣu lọ, nitori ohun rere kan ki i fẹ ka ṣe ohun, eeyan ni yoo mọ iwọn ara ẹ, ọrọ ile Oṣodi yii lo wa lọkan gbogbo wa."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: ఇల","answer":"బుధుని భార్య, ఆవు, మాట, భూమి "},{"question":"英語ではハーキュリーズという、ゼウスとアルクメネの子であるギリシャ神話の英雄といえば誰でしょう？","answer":"ヘラクレスです。"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: UBND tỉnh Lạng Sơn đã chỉ đạo UBND TP Lạng Sơn làm rõ trách nhiệm, tổ chức kiểm điểm và có hình thức xử lý kỷ luật đối với tập thể, cá nhân liên quan đến các vi phạm, sai sót tại dự án khu đô thị mới Mai Pha, xã Mai Pha, TP Lạng Sơn. Cận cảnh dự án khu đô thị mới Mai Pha dính nhiều lình xình  Dự án khu đô thị mới Mai Pha với diện tích 91,73 ha, tổng vốn đầu tư là 3.135 tỉ đồng, trong đó sơ bộ chi phí thực hiện dự án không bao gồm chi phí bồi thường, giải phóng mặt bằng là 2.651 tỉ đồng, chi phí bồi thường, giải phóng mặt bằng đã bao gồm chi phí hỗ trợ, tái định cư: 484 tỉ đồng.  Dự án có quy mô dân số là 9.621 người, tổng số hộ là 2.721, trong đó nhà ở liền kề 2.457 hộ, nhà ở biệt thự 264 hộ, nhà tái định cư 119 hộ, nhà ở xã hội 152 hộ thấp tầng theo kiểu chia lô và khoảng 2.100 căn hộ nhà ở xã hội cao tầng. Nhà đầu tư trúng thầu là liên danh Công ty CP Đầu tư Hải Phát và Công ty TNHH Hà Sơn.  Để thực hiện dự án này có tới 603 hộ dân và 3 tổ chức bị ảnh hưởng do thu hồi đất.  Dự án vấp phải sự phản đối quyết liệt đến từ người dân khi giá đền bù quá rẻ khiến nhiều người dân không chấp nhận. Nhiều người dân bức xúc trước cách xử lý của chính quyền sở tại.  \\"Nếu lấy đất để xây trường học, bệnh viện, đất quốc phòng an ninh hay nhà ở xã hội thì chúng tôi đồng thuận. Tuy nhiên, đây là dự án khu đô thị. Chúng tôi mất hết đất sản xuất mà chỉ được đền bù có vài chục, vài trăm ngàn đồng mỗi mét vuông thì sao có thể chấp nhận\\" - ông N.T.Q. (một người dân bị thu hồi đất ở xã Mai Pha) bày tỏ.  Bức xúc không được giải đáp thỏa đáng khi thực hiện dự án, nhiều người dân xã Mai Pha đã khiếu kiện vượt cấp. Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Lạng Sơn Hồ Tiến Thiệu sau đó liên tục đối thoại với người dân kèm những lời hứa sẽ điều tra lại việc thống kê diện tích đất lúa, xem xét quy trình cưỡng chế.  Ông Nguyễn Văn Hạnh, Chủ tịch UBND TP Lạng Sơn, cho hay UBND TP Lạng Sơn đã phát hiện có sai sót trong quá trình tham mưu, thực hiện dự án này.  Kết quả rà soát sổ địa chính và hồ sơ biến động cho thấy tổng diện tích đất lúa bị thu hồi, chuyển đổi trong dự án là 18,39 ha, không phải 8,38 ha như số liệu thống kê trước đó.  Nhiều diện tích đất lúa đã bị thống kê sai, khiến tổng diện tích đất lúa trong dự án được TP Lạng Sơn trình lên tỉnh chỉ còn hơn 8 ha. Do diện tích đất lúa dưới 10 ha nên thẩm quyền quyết định phê duyệt dự án do tỉnh Lạng Sơn quyết, không phải trình lên Thủ tướng chính phủ. HĐND tỉnh Lạng Sơn cũng đã thông qua nghị quyết thu hồi đất liên quan đến dự án này.  Hiện tại, theo ghi nhận của Báo Người Lao Động, nhiều diện tích đất tại đây vẫn được người dân thực hiện canh tác, trồng hoa màu. Nguồn: https://nld.com.vn/thoi-su/clip-can-canh-du-an-hon-3000-ti-dong-co-10-ha-dat-trong-lua-bi-ho-bie...Nguồn: https://nld.com.vn/thoi-su/clip-can-canh-du-an-hon-3000-ti-dong-co-10-ha-dat-trong-lua-bi-ho-bien-2022073110175351.htm ","answer":"CLIP: Cận cảnh dự án hơn 3.000 tỉ đồng có 10 ha đất trồng lúa bị \\"hô biến\\""},{"question":"Em qual cidade surgiu a banda The Beatles?","answer":"A banda surgiu em Liverpool, na Inglaterra.  A cidade é muito conhecida como o local de origem da banda. John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison e Ringo Starr eram todos originários de Liverpool."},{"question":"مضمون جو خلاصو:  بوگوٽا ، ڪولمبيا (سي اين اين) - ڪولمبيا جي پوليس هڪ منشيات جو واپاري ماريو آهي جنهن کي حڪومت چيو آهي ته ملڪ جي باغي اڳواڻن کان ٻاهر سڀ کان وڌيڪ گهربل فرار آهي. ويڪٽر مانوئل ميجيا مونيرا هڪ منشيات وارو بادشاهه هو جنهن جا نيم فوجي گروهن سان لاڳاپا هئا ، ڪولمبيا جي حڪومت چوي ٿي. وڪٽر منويل ميجيا مونيرا ۽ ٻن محافظن کي ا Tuesdayاري تي ماريو ويو جڏهن پوليس انهن کي شمال مغربي صوبي انٽيوڪيا جي هڪ فارم تي ڳولهيو ، ڪولمبيا جي صدارتي ويب سائيٽ تي هڪ بيان موجب. بيان موجب ٽن ماڻهن کي به گرفتار ڪيو ويو. ميجيا منيرا آمريڪي طرز جو لباس پائي رهيو هو ، صحرا جي نقاب پوش يونيفارم جڏهن هو ماريو ويو ، ڪولمبيا جي دفاع واري وزير جوآن منويل سانتوس چيو. ميجيا منيرا وٽ پڻ مختصر ۽ ڊگهي رينج وارا هٿيار هئا جن ۾ گوليون به هيون، صدارتي بيان ۾ چيو ويو آهي. \\"هي عوامي فورس جي ملڪ جي مجرمانه اڏاوتن جي خلاف هڪ عظيم هڙتال آهي ،\\" سانتوس چيو ، خبردار ڪيو ته منشيات جا واپاري جيڪي پاڻ کي حڪومت جي حوالي نه ڪندا آهن \\"جيل ۾ ختم ٿي ويندا يا قبر ۾\\". بيان ۾ چيو ويو آهي ته ملڪ جي سڀ کان وڌيڪ گهربل فهرست جي لحاظ کان ، ميجيا منيرا ڪولمبيا جي سڀ کان وڌيڪ گهربل ڏوهارين مان هڪ هو ۽ ڪولمبيا جي انقلابي هٿياربند فوج جي اڳواڻن کان هيٺ هو. کاٻي ڌر جي گوريلا گروپ، جيڪو اسپيني مخفف فارڪ جي نالي سان سڃاتو وڃي ٿو، ڪولمبيا جي جهنگلن ۾ تقريبن 750 ماڻهن کي يرغمال بڻائي ٿو ۽ هن يرغمال بڻائڻ کي هڪ جائز فوجي حڪمت عملي جي طور تي ثابت ڪيو آهي. ميجيا مونيرا تي FARC سان تعلق نه هجڻ جو الزام آهي ، پر هو هڪ سا ساڄي ونگ جي نيم فوجي گروپ سان ملوث هو جيڪو ڪولمبيا جي گڏيل خودمختيار فورسز جي نالي سان مشهور آهي ، يو ايس اسٽيٽ ڊپارٽمينٽ جي مطابق. ميجيا منيرا ۽ سندس ڀاءُ، ميگل اينجل ميجيا منيرا، \\"لوس ميليزوس\\" يا \\"ٽوئنز\\" جي نالي سان مشهور آهن، انهن تي ڪولمبيا ۾ وڏي منشيات جي رينگ هلائڻ جو الزام آهي. ڀائرن کي گڏيل قومن ۾ منشيات جي اسمگلنگ جي الزامن سان به منهن ڏيڻو پيو آهي. سانتوس شروعاتي طور تي صحافين کي ٻڌايو ته پوليس مائيڪل اينجل ميجيا منيرا کي قتل ڪيو هو. ... جي","answer":"نيو: ڪولمبيا جي حڪومت جو چوڻ آهي ته مارجي ويل منشيات جي مالڪ وٽ هٿيار ۽ بارود مليا آهن. نئون: دفاعي وزير خبردار ڪري ٿو ته منشيات وڪرو ڪندڙ \\"جيل ۾ يا قبر ۾ ختم ٿي ويندا\\" ويڪٽر منويل ميجيا مونيرا جو تعلق پاراميليٽريز سان آهي، هن کي به آمريڪا ۾ گهربل آهي مقتول شخص اصل ۾ ڀاءُ ميگل اينجل ميجيا سمجهيو ويندو هو."},{"question":"展覧会を開催する前日に、招待者を呼んで行う内覧会のことを「ニスを塗る」という意味のフランス語で何というでしょう？","answer":"ベルニサージュ"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo toerana fizahan-tany malaza indrindra eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Anisan’ny toerana fizahan-tany malaza indrindra eto Madagasikara ny lalan’ny Baobab, ny Nosy Be, ny valan-javaboahary Isalo, ary ny tahiry Tsingy de Bemaraha."},{"question":"புதிர்:  மணல் வெளியில் ஓடுது தண்ணீர் கேட்காத கப்பல் அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை: ஒட்டகம்"},{"question":"唐詩\\"但願人長久\\"的下一句是? ","answer":"千里共嬋娟"},{"question":"కింది పదాలను కలిపి రాయండి.ఉదా : కప్ప + అమ్మ = కప్పమ్మ1. కప్పలు + ఎగిరే2. పండుతాయి + అమ్మ3. వాడలు + అన్నీ4. చేసినారు + ఏ","answer":"1. కప్పలు + ఎగిరే = కప్పలెగిరే2. పండుతాయి + అమ్మ = పండుతాయమ్మ3. వాడలు + అన్నీ = వాడలన్నీ4. చేసినారు + ఏ = చేసినారే"},{"question":"Văn bản và đoạn văn là gì?","answer":"- Văn bản là đơn vị ngôn ngữ trình bày trọn vẹn một vấn đề giao tiếp, có các bộ phận thống nhất về chủ đề, liên kết bằng những từ ngữ nhất định và được sắp xếp theo trình tự hợp lí.- Văn bản có thể gồm một hoặc nhiều đoạn văn.- Mỗi đoạn văn thể hiện một chủ đề nhỏ; hết đoạn văn, phải xuống dòng. Ở dạng điển hình, đoạn văn thường có một câu nêu chủ đề của đoạn văn (câu chủ đề) và một số câu phát triển chủ đề (câu phát triển)."},{"question":"Àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀","answer":"Àwọn àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀, jẹ́ àwọn àjẹsára tí à ń lò láti dènà àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ (polio). À ń lo kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí a ti pa  láti fi ṣe oríṣi kan, a sì má a ń fún ni ní èyí bíi abẹ́rẹ́ (IPV), a sì tún ń lo kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí kò lágbára mọ́ láti fi ṣe oríṣi kejì, a sì ń gba ẹnu lo èyí (OPV). Àjọ Ìlera Àgbáyé gba ni níyànjú pé kí gbogbo ọmọdé má a gba àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀. Àwọn àjẹsára méjèèjì náà ti dẹ́kun àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ ní ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ orílẹ̀-èdè àgbáyé, wọ́n sì ti dín iye ènìyàn tó ń ní àrùn náà lọ́dọọdún kù láti iye tí a ṣírò sí 350,000 ní ọdún 1988 sí 359 ní ọdún 2014.Àwọn àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí a fi kòkòrò tí a ti pa ṣe náà kò léwu rárá. Pípọ́n yòò ibi ojú abẹ́rẹ́ náà àti ìrora díẹ̀ lè wáyé. Àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí à ń gba ẹnu lò a má a ṣe òkùnfa àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìmúlò àjẹsára náà nínú ìwọ̀n egbògi náà tó tó mẹ́ẹ̀ta nínú mílíọ̀nù kan. A lè lo oríṣi àjẹsára méjèèjì náà láìséwu bí ènìyàn bá ní oyún àti bí ènìyàn bá ní àrùn kògbóògùn HIV/AIDS ṣùgbọ́n tí ara rẹ̀ ṣì dá ṣáká.Àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ àkọ́kọ́ ni àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí a fi kòkòrò tí a ti pa ṣe. Ẹnití ó ṣe àgbéjáde rẹ̀ ni Jonas Salk , a sì bẹ̀rẹ̀ síí lòó ní ọdún 1955. Ẹnití ó ṣe àgbéjáde àjẹsára àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí à ń gba ẹnu lò ni Albert Sabin, a sì bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí tàá fún lílò ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ènìyàn ní ọdún 1961. Wọ́n wà lórí Àkójọ Àwọn Egbògi Kòṣeémáàní ti Àjọ Ìlera Àgbáyé, àwọn òògùn tó ṣe pàtàkì jùlọ tí a nílò fún ètò ìlera ìbẹ̀rẹ̀pẹ̀pẹ̀ yòówù. Iye owó rẹ̀ lójú pálí jẹ́ bíi 0.25 USD fún ìwọ̀n egbògi náà kanṣoṣo fún oríṣi tí à n gba ẹnu lò ní ọdún 2014. Ní ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríkà iye owó rẹ̀ jẹ́ 25 sí 50 USD fún oríṣi tí a fi kòkòrò tí a ti pa ṣe."},{"question":"အောက်ဖော်ပြပါ အနှစ်ချုပ်ကို အခြေခံ၍ ဆောင်းပါး / အကျယ်ချဲ့ ရေးသားပါ။အခြေခံအုတ်မြစ်ချခြင်းနဲ့ စလိုက်ပါ။ နံရံရဲ့ မြင်သာတဲ့ အစွန်းကနေ စလိုက်ပါ။ လိုအပ်ရင် အောက်ခြေကျောက်ရဲ့ အပေါ်ပိုင်း လျှာကို ဖြတ်ပစ်ပါ။ လိုအပ်ပါက ပထမအလွှာကို ပြီးစီးရန် သီးခြား အတုံးတွေကို ဖြတ်ရပါမယ်။ ကျောက်တုံးများရဲ့ ပထမအလွှာကို ပြန်ဖြည့်ရန် ကြိတ်ချေထားသော ကျောက်တုံးများ သို့မဟုတ် မြေဖြူများကို သုံးပါ။ နောက်ပြန်ဖြည့်တဲ့အပေါ်မှာ စိမ့်ဝင်တဲ့ အထည်တစ်ခု ထည့်လိုက်ပါ။ ပထမဆုံးအလွှာကို ဖုန်မှုန့်နဲ့သုတ်လိုက်ပါ။  ဆောင်းပါး ","answer":"အကျယ်ချဲ့ ရေးသားခြင်း (သို့) ဆောင်းပါး နံရံပေါ်က အရေးပါဆုံး အစိတ်အပိုင်းတွေပါ။ ၎င်းတို့ဟာ အထက်ရှိ အလွှာကို မထောက်ပံ့နိုင်ရင်၊ ဒါမှမဟုတ် မမှီခိုနိုင်ရင်၊ ပရိုဂျက်ဟာ ကျွမ်းကျင်မှု နည်းနေမှာပါ။ လိုအပ်ပါက ကျောက်တုံးကို ပြားချပ်စေရန် မြေဖြူ သို့မဟုတ် ကျောက်ချပ်များကို ထည့်ပါ။ ပထမဦးဆုံး ကျောက်တုံးကို ထောင့်ကျောက်နဲ့ ဆောက်ပေးပါ။ ရှေ့နောက်နဲ့ ဘေးချင်းယှဉ်ပြီး တစ်ထပ်တည်းကျအောင် လုပ်ပေးပါ။ ဒါမှမဟုတ် နံရံတစ်ခုရဲ့ အစွန်းက အခြားတစ်ခုထက် ပိုမမြင်သာဘူးဆိုရင် အခြားတစ်ခုနဲ့ (ပုံမှန်တော့ အိမ်တစ်လုံး) အနီးဆုံးမှာရှိတဲ့ အစွန်းကနေ စလိုက်ပါ။ သင်ဟာ ဖြောင့်တန်းတဲ့ (သို့) စတုဂံပုံ ပံ့ပိုးပေးတဲ့ နံရံတစ်ခု ဆောက်နေတယ်ဆိုရင် ဘလောက်တွေရဲ့နောက်ဘက်တွေ တစ်ခုနဲ့တစ်ခု လုံးဝကို ကိုက်ညီတာ သေချာအောင်လုပ်ပါ။ သင်ဟာ ကွေးနေတဲ့ ပံ့ပိုးပေးတဲ့ နံရံတစ်ခု ဆောက်နေတယ်ဆိုရင် ဘလောက်တွေရဲ့ရှေ့ဘက်တွေ တစ်ခုနဲ့တစ်ခု လုံးဝကို ကိုက်ညီတာ သေချာအောင်လုပ်ပါ။ စစ်ဆေးပြီး လိုအပ်ရင် တူနဲ့ ကတ်ကြေးနဲ့ လျှာကို ထိုးပါ။ လျှာများပါ ကွေးနေတဲ့ ထောက်ခံ နံရံများဟာ ချိတ်ဆက်ထားတဲ့ အပေါက်များရဲ့ အကျိုးကို မခံစားနိုင်ကြပါ။ ဒီဂေါက်ပေါက်တွေကို တူနဲ့တူပြီး ခုတ်ရပါသည် အကယ်၍ ဒီပုံစံက ဂေါက်ပေါက်တွေရဲ့ ဦးတည်ချက်နဲ့ မကိုက်ဘူးဆိုရင်ပေါ့။ ဒါက အခြေခံအုတ်မြစ် တစ်ခုလုံးကို ပြီးမြောက်စေပါလိမ့်မည်။ သင်ဟာ အိပ်ရာပေါ်ကို အိကျဖို့ အချိန်ယူခဲ့ရင် ပထမ အတန်းကို နေရာချတာ လွယ်ပါလိမ့်မယ်။ ရော်ဘာတုံးနဲ့ ကျောက်တုံးတွေကို ရိုက်ချိုးလိုက်ပါ။ ဖြတ်တောက်ရာမှာ အမြဲတမ်း လုံခြုံရေးကို သုံးပါ။ ရေခဲစိုင်က အေးလာပြီး မြေဆီလွှာနဲ့ ရောမသွားအောင် တားဆီးပေးပါသည်။ ခင်ဗျားရဲ့ အကာအရံအမြင့်ကို လိုက်ပြီးတော့ ကတုတ်ကျင်း ဒါမှမဟုတ် အိမ်ရဲ့ နောက်ဘက်ခြမ်းကို ဖုံးအုပ်လိုက်ပါ ကတုတ်ကို ဖုံးအုပ်ထားတဲ့ နေရာမှာ ဖုံးအုပ်လိုက်ပါ။ နောက်ပြီး ဖုံးအုပ်ထားတဲ့ နေရာမှာ ဖုံးအုပ်လိုက်ပါ။ ဒါက ညစ်ပတ်မှု (သို့) ဖုန်မှုန့်တွေကို ဖယ်ရှားပေးပါလိမ့်မည်။"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Anh dùng dao đâm chết em trai vì... tắt nhạc","answer":"Chiều 31/7, lãnh đạo xã Hiệp Cát (huyện Nam Sách, tỉnh Hải Dương) cho biết, đêm hôm trước (30/7) trên địa bàn xảy ra vụ việc anh đâm chết em trai - theo Báo Hải Dương. Theo thông tin ban đầu, sự việc xảy ra vào khoảng 21 giờ 15 phút ngày 30/7, anh Ph.V.H. (SN 1987) đi sinh nhật bạn về nhà thì thấy anh trai là Phan Văn Huân (SN 1985) đang mở nhạc to. Thấy đã muộn, Ph.V.H. có nói với anh trai tắt nhạc để mình đi ngủ. Tuy nhiên, khi thấy anh trai không tắt nhạc, H. đã tự mình tắt nhạc thì giữa 2 anh em xảy ra cãi vã, to tiếng. Trong lúc không giữ được bình tĩnh, Phan Văn Huân cầm dao (dạng dao gọt hoa quả) đâm nhiều nhát lên người em trai. Bị anh trai đâm bất ngờ, H. chạy ra ngoài cầu cứu, nhưng do bị thương quá nặng nên khi chạy ra đến cổng thì H. gục xuống, tử vong ngay sau đó. Nhận được tin báo về vụ anh đâm chết em, Công an huyện Nam Sách và các đơn vị nghiệp vụ Công an tỉnh Hải Dương đã khẩn trương có mặt tiến hành công tác khám nghiệm và điều tra nguyên nhân vụ trọng án. Ngay sau đó, cơ quan công an đã tạm giữ hình sự đối với Phan Văn Huân để phục vụ công tác điều tra. Được biết, 2 anh em Huân và H. đều đã xây dựng gia đình và có con. Riêng nạn nhân Ph.V.H. cùng vợ trước đây đi nước ngoài, sau đó anh H. về trước và hiện đang xây nhà, còn vợ vẫn ở nước ngoài. Phan Văn Huân không có tiền án, tiền sự và trong cuộc sống hàng ngày giữa 2 anh em ruột bình thường, không có mâu thuẫn. "},{"question":"Mavi şampuan saç rengini açar mı?","answer":"Mavi şampuan saç rengini açmaz, aksine soğuk, koyu tonların daha belirgin hale gelmesini sağlar."},{"question":"Quantos arquipélagos tem Portugal?","answer":"Portugal tem dois arquipélagos, Madeira (4 ilhas) e Açores (9 ilhas)."},{"question":"Zer da psikologian motibazioa, eta nola ulertzen du pertsonen jokabidearen kausak?","answer":"Motibazioa da pertsonen jokabidearen kausa edo arrazoia. Motibazioak ulertzen ditu gure ekintzen eta erabakiak hartzen ditugun arrazoiak."},{"question":"Paragrafı devam metni yaz: Fiber optik, iletişim ve veri iletimi için kullanılan ince cam veya plastik fiberlerden oluşan bir iletişim teknolojisidir. Fiber optik kablolar, verileri ışık sinyalleri olarak iletmek için tasarlanmıştır. Bu teknoloji, elektrik sinyalleri ile karşılaştırıldığında ","answer":"daha yüksek hızlar, daha uzun mesafeler ve daha düşük gecikme süreleri sunar."},{"question":"Ga ihap ka ug http://www.binisaya.com/cebuano/karneroarnero para maka tulog?","answer":"Usahay maka tabang sya."},{"question":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਸਮਾਜਸ਼ਾਸਤਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਸਤਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"1. ਹਰਬਰਟ ਸਪੈਂਸਰ (Herbert Spencer) ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ – ਹਰਬਰਟ ਸਪੈਂਸਰ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਸਮਾਜਸ਼ਾਸਤਰੀ ਸੀ ਜਿਸਨੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਸਨ । ਪਰ ਉਸਨੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ ।ਉਸਨੇ ਇਕ ਕਿਤਾਬ ਲਿਖੀ Principles of Sociology ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਉਸਨੇ ਜੈਵਿਕ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਅਰਥ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ । ਸਪੈਂਸਰ ਨੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਅਰਥਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ।ਸਪੈਂਸਰ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੀ ਬਣਤਰ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਭਾਗ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਕੰਨ, ਨੱਕ, ਹੱਥ, ਮੂੰਹ, ਲੱਤਾਂ, ਬਾਹਾਂ ਆਦਿ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਸੰਗਠਿਤ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਕਿਰਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਭਾਗ ਅੰਤਰ-ਨਿਰਭਰ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਤਰ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਹੀ ਸਾਡਾ ਸਰੀਰ ਸੁਚਾਰੂ ਰੂਪ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਯੋਗ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ । ਚਾਹੇ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਵਿਚ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਭਾਗ ਇਕੋ-ਜਿਹੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੋਈ ਲੰਬੇ ਕੱਦ ਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਛੋਟੇ ਕੱਦ ਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਮੋਟਾ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਪਤਲਾ ਹੈ ਆਦਿ । ਇਸੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਵੀ ਵੱਖਵੱਖ ਅੰਤਰ-ਨਿਰਭਰ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਤਰ-ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਭਾਗ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸੁਚਾਰੂ ਰੂਪ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਜਾਂ ਇਕਾਈਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਤਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਹੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੂਜੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਖ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹਰਬਰਟ ਸਪੈਂਸਰ ਨੇ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਇਕਾਈਆਂ ਦੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਸੀ । ਪਰ ਕੰਮ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਇਕਾਈਆਂ ਦੀ ਆਪਸੀ ਸੰਬੰਧਤਾ ਵੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ । ਸਪੈਂਸਰ ਨੇ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੇ ਅਰਥ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਆਸਾਨ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਸਨ ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦਾ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਅਰਥ ਨਾ ਦੇ ਸਕੇ ।2. ਐੱਸ. ਐੱਫ਼. ਨੈਡਲ (S.F. Nadal) ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ – ਐੱਸ. ਐੱਫ਼. ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਇਕਾਈਆਂ ਦਾ ਤਰਤੀਬਾਤਮਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਜਾਤਮਕ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਹੀ ਵੱਖ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਬਾਹਰਲੇ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੈ । ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਤੱਤ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਹਨ-ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਮੂਹ, ਸੰਰਚਨਾਤਮਕ ਨਿਯਮ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸਮੂਹ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਸਥਾਤਮਕ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਜਾਂ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ । ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਮੁਰਤ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਇਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਰੋਲ ਨਿਭਾਉਂਦਿਆਂ ਹੋਇਆਂ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੇ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਵਿਵਹਾਰਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਬੰਧਿਤ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਜਾਂ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਅਸੀਂ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ।”ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਸੰਕਲਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਣ ਲਈ ਨੈਡਲ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਦਿੱਤੇ ‘ਇਕ ਸਮਾਜ’ ਦੇ ਸੰਕਲਪ ਦੀ ਵਿਆਖਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ । ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਉਹ ਸਮੂਹ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਸੰਸਥਾਗਤ ਆਧਾਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਇਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਨਿਯਮ, ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਵਹਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਿਤ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਯੰਤਰਿਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੈਡਲ ਦੇ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਤਿੰਨ ਤੱਤ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਹਨ-ਵਿਅਕਤੀ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਅੰਤਰ ਕਿਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਤਰ ਕਿਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਬੰਧ ।ਨੈਡਲ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਵਿਵਸਥਿਤ ਤਰਤੀਬ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਰਚਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਨਾ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਜਾਤਮਕ ਪੱਖ ਨਾਲ । ਨੈਡਲ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸਮਾਜ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਮੂਹ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ, ਸੰਸਥਾਤਮਕ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਨਿਯਮ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਵਹਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਨੈਡਲ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਸਮੂਹ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੋਣੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਬਲਕਿ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਿਤ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਹੋਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ । ਸੋ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਆਪਸੀ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਜਾਂ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਕੁਮਬੱਧਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਨੈਡਲ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਵਸਥਿਤ ਹੋਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਲਕਿ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਵਸਥਿਤ ਹੋਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸੇ ਗੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਧਿਆਨ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਨੈਡਲ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ, “ਮੂਰਤ ਜਨਸੰਖਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਿਵਹਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਅਲੱਗ ਕੱਢ ਕੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਕਰਤਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਏ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਮਾਨ, ਜਾਲ ਜਾਂ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।”3. ਰੈਡਕਲਿਫ਼ ਬਰਾਊਨ (Redcliff Brown) ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਰੈਡਕਲਿਫ਼ ਬਰਾਉਨ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਮਾਨਵ ਵਿਗਿਆਨੀ ਸੀ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਸਮਾਜ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਦੇ ਸੰਰਚਨਾਤਮਕ ਕਾਰਜਾਤਮਕ ਸਕੂਲ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਸੀ । ਬਰਾਊਨ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਤੱਤ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਨ, ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਥਾਤਮਕ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਤੇ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਹੈ ।”ਬਰਾਊਨ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, “ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੇ ਗੁੰਝਲਦਾਰ ਘੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਏ ਗਏ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਦੇ ਘੇਰੇ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਹੈ ।”ਬਰਾਊਨ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸਥਿਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਬਲਕਿ ਇਕ ਗਤੀਸ਼ੀਲ ਨਿਰੰਤਰਤਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਵੇਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਢਾਂਚੇ ਵਿਚ ਬਦਲਾਵ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਬਦਲਾਵ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਮੌਲਿਕ ਤੱਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਦਲਦੇ | ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਬਦਲਾਵ ਤਾਂ ਆ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਮੌਲਿਕ ਤੱਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਬਦਲਾਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੇ । ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਤਾਂ ਬਣੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਈ ਵਾਰੀ ਆਮ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਸਰੂਪ ਵਿਚ ਬਦਲਾਵ ਆ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । 4. ਦਾਲਕਟ ਪਾਰਸਨਜ਼ (Talcot Parsons) ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਰ – ਪਾਰਸਨਜ਼ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਅਮੂਰਤ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ, “ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਸਪਰ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ, ਏਜੰਸੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਮਾਨਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਸਮੁਹ ਵਿਚ ਹਰੇਕ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਪਦਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਰੋਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਤਰਤੀਬ ਜਾਂ ਕੁਮਬੱਧਤਾ ਲਈ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।”ਪਾਰਸਨਜ਼ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਜਿਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਸੀ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਪਰਸਪਰ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਇਕ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਸਥਾਪਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਹਰੇਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਦ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਵੀ ਅਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਅਮੂਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਵੀ ਅਮੂਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਅਸੀਂ ਨਾ ਤਾਂ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਬੰਧਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਾ ਹੀ ਛੂਹ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ, ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ । ਪਾਰਸਨਜ਼ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ, ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਰਿਵਾਜਾਂ, ਪਰੰਪਰਾਵਾਂ, ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸਾਂ ਆਦਿ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਪਦ ਅਤੇ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਪਦਾਂ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੀ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਏਜੰਸੀਆਂ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਜਦੋਂ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਏਜੰਸੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਤਰਤੀਬ ਸਥਾਪਿਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਰਸਪਰ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"கோவலனும் கண்ண கியும்……………….நகருக்குள் சென்றபோது கொடிகள் அசைந்தன.அ) தஞ்சைஆ) புகார்இ) மதுரைஈ) வஞ்சி","answer":"இ) மதுரை"},{"question":"Asmara mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Asmara mooy gëblag réewum Erythrée."},{"question":"கேள்வி: வளரும் நாடுகளில் நகரமயமாக்கல் மற்றும் விரைவான மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சியின் பொருளாதார, சமூக மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழல் தாக்கங்கள் என்ன, மேலும் நிலையான நகர்ப்புற வளர்ச்சியை மேம்படுத்த என்ன உத்திகளைப் பயன்படுத்தலாம்?","answer":"பதில்: வளரும் நாடுகளில் நகரமயமாக்கல் மற்றும் விரைவான மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி வாய்ப்புகள் மற்றும் சவால்கள் இரண்டையும் கொண்டு வருகிறது. ஒருபுறம், நகரங்கள் பொருளாதார வளர்ச்சி மற்றும் புதுமைகளின் மையமாக இருக்கலாம். மறுபுறம், அவர்கள் அடிக்கடி நெரிசல், போதிய உள்கட்டமைப்பு, மாசுபாடு மற்றும் வளங்கள் குறைதல் போன்ற பிரச்சனைகளை எதிர்கொள்கின்றனர். நிலையான நகர்ப்புற மேம்பாட்டு உத்திகள் திறமையான பொதுப் போக்குவரத்து அமைப்புகள், மலிவு விலை வீடுகள், பசுமையான இடங்கள், கழிவு மேலாண்மை மற்றும் நிலையான கட்டிட நடைமுறைகள் உள்ளிட்ட பல்வேறு தீர்வுகளை உள்ளடக்கியது. கூடுதலாக, கலப்பு நிலப் பயன்பாடு, குறைக்கப்பட்ட புகை வண்டிப் பெட்டி பயன்பாடு, மற்றும் வளங்களுக்கான சமமான அணுகல் ஆகியவற்றுக்கு முன்னுரிமை அளிக்கும் நகர்ப்புற திட்டமிடல் எதிர்மறை தாக்கங்களைத் தணிக்கும். கல்வி, சுகாதாரம் மற்றும் சமூக சேவைகளை ஊக்குவிக்கும் சமூகக் கொள்கைகள் நகரமயமாக்கலின் விளைவுகளை சமமான மற்றும் சுற்றுச்சூழலுக்குப் பொறுப்பான விதத்தில் நிர்வகிப்பதற்கு முக்கியமானதாகும்."},{"question":"\\" आग में घी डालना \\" का अर्थ क्या होता हैं ? इस मुहावरे को एक वाक्य में उपयोग करें ।","answer":"\\" आग में घी डालने \\" का अर्थ है किसी के ग़ुस्से को और भड़काना । इस मुहावरे का उदाहरण हैं -तुम उसे पुरानी बातें याद कराकर आग में घी डालने का काम कर रहे हो।"},{"question":"ශ්‍රීමත් වින්ස්ටන් චර්චිල්ගේ \\"දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය\\" වෙළුම් හයේ මාතෘකා මොනවාද?","answer":"ශ්‍රීමත් වින්ස්ටන් චර්චිල්ගේ \\"දෙවන ලෝක යුද්ධය\\" වෙළුම් හය 1948 සහ 1953 අතර ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලදී. ඒවා නම්: 1. එකතු කිරීමේ කුණාටුව 2. ඔවුන්ගේ හොඳම හෝරාව 3. මහා සන්ධානය 4. ද හන්ජ් ඔෆ් ෆේට් 5. ක්ලෝසින් ද රින්ග් 6 ජයග්‍රහණය සහ ඛේදවාචකය"},{"question":"GACAL DOORASHADA!","answer":"GACAL DOORASHADA!Diinteenna Islaamku waxay ina baraysaa in haweeney afar waxyaabood lagu guursado, kuwaasi oo kala ah: qurux, qoys sharaf leh ooy ka dhalatay, maal iyo diin. Haddaba haddaynu mid mid u kala qaadno:1-Qurux: Quruxdu inkastoo ay tahay shabagga ugu horreeya ee ay dumarku ragga u daadiyaan, misana diin iyo akhlaaq haddaanay dugsanayn, intay halleyso ayaa ka badan waxay hagaajiso, waxana weeye wax da' ku xiranoo qofka aan ku daahin. Waxaa la yiri quruxda keligeed ahi waa sida bal cagaaran oo intaad u bogto aa xoolaha ku deysatid, kolkeyse daaqaan ay ku banaan (shubmaan) oo bushi uun ka qaadaan.2-Qoys sharaf leh: Waa wax loo baahan yahay in dad la garanayo 00 magac iyo maamuus leh laga guursado, waana kii uu Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) yiri: U doorta xawadiinna, cirqigu waa uu dusaaye\\". Xadiiska oo uu soo saaray ibnu Maajah, micnihiisu waxa weeye dadnimo wanaagga waa la'iska dhaxlaaye, hubiya qofka aad guursaneysaan amaba u guurineysaan inuu qoys wanaagsan ka dhashay. Ha yeeshee, illayn qoyska dhan guursan maysido0 qof baad ka guursanaysaaye, sideed ku dammaanad qaadaysaa inay qoftaasi noqon doonto tii lagu nastoo lagu nagaado, haddaanad akhlaaq iyo diin ka cegin?.3-Maal: Ninkii gabar maalkeed oo qura\\" u guursadaa, ma uu doonayo gabadhee maalkeeduu doonayaa, ayada lafteeduna waxayu aragtaa nin ay iibsatay. Waxaa hore loo yiri: Ninka waxa wanaagsan inuu gabadha uu guursanayo saddex dheer yahay: da' iyo nasab iyo duunyo, Si aysan u yasin. Gabadhana waxa wanaagsan ninka ay guursanayso inay saddex dheer tahay: samir iyo edeb iyo suurad wanaag, si uusan u yasin.4-Diin: Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis saxiix ah ku yiri: (Naag waxa loo guursadaa maalkeeda, quruxdeeda, sharafteeda iyo dinteeda, ee ta diinta leh gaar gacmaha ciid gashee). Gabadha diinta lihi waa tan garanaysa siday u gudan lahayd xaqa uu ninkeedu ku leeyahay, siday u dhawri lahayd asraarta gurigeeda iyo nafteeda, siday isaga ilaalin lahayd masayr, carruurtana ugu barbaarin lahayd tubta toosan.Haddaba, maadaama ay adagtahay sidii lagu heli lahaa haweeney afarta sifoee aannu soo sheegnay isku darsatay, waxaa habboon in XOogga la saaro qof diin leh, hadday markaasi qurux iyo qoys wanaag ku darsato waa Alxamdu Lil Laahi, hadday maalkeeda sidatana waa Rabbil Caalamiin.Si kastaba arrintu ha ahaatee, waxaad mooddaa in dabeecadda raggu dalkay doonaanba ha u dhasheene tahay inay gabadha bilicsanaanteeda iyo muugaalkabedenkeeda ku daba galaan, intaanay u daadegin diin iyo dabeecad kale.Hadday markaasi diin iyo dabeecadi u dheer yihin, ninka daa'in ka baqayaa waa tuu doonayey, kii kalee damackatiir ahe xoolo daneeyaase quruxda wuxuu ku daraa inay dad magac iyo deeq leh ka dhalatay. "},{"question":"Saako elintarvikkeita markkinoida gmo-vapaina?","answer":"EU:n yhteisen lainsäädännön mukaan muuntogeeniset elintarvikkeet ja ainesosat tulee selkeästi ilmoittaa pakkausmerkinnöissä.Gmo-vapaa -markkinointiväittämän käyttö on sen sijaan vapaaehtoista, ja sen käytölle on laadittu Ruokaviraston toimesta ohjeet. Ohjeen perustana on, että kuluttajia ei saa johtaa harhaan. Markkinointi voidaan katsoa kuluttajia harhaanjohtavaksi, jos kuluttajien annetaan gmo-vapaa -markkinointiväittämän avulla ymmärtää elintarvikkeen poikkeavan muista vastaavista, vaikka näin ei ole.Gmo-vapaa -markkinointiväittämää on mahdollista käyttää vain sellaisille elintarvikkeille tai ainesosille, joista on olemassa EU:ssa hyväksytty muuntogeeninen lajike. Näitä kasveja ovat tällä hetkellä (helmikuu 2022) maissi, rapsi, soija ja sokerijuurikas. Gmo-markkinointiväittämän käytölle näistä kasveista valmistettujen elintarvikkeiden osalta on tarkat ohjeet. Käytännössä toimijan tulee eräkohtaisesti analyysituloksin varmentaa, että käytetty raaka-aine on täysin gmo-vapaata."},{"question":"Which female New Zealand director helmed the films Bright Star (2009), The Water Diary (2006), and In the Cut (2003)?","answer":"These movies were directed by Jane Campion."},{"question":"வினா: நீரில் கரையாத வாயு எது?1.நைட்ரஜன்2.உருகுதல்3.ஸ்டார்ச் மாவு4.அழைப்பு மணி","answer":"விடை:1.நைட்ரஜன்"},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Шотландияда эки эмес, үч соттун өкүмү бар: \\"күнөөлүү\\", \\"күнөөсүз\\" жана \\"далилденбеген\\" . Акыркы өкүм акталды деп эсептелет жана сотто айыпталуучунун күнөөсүн далилдеген жетиштүү далилдер жок болгон учурда чыгарылат, анын күнөөсү бардыгына ачык болуп турса дагы.Бул система 18-кылымдан бери, анын каршылаштарынын аны жок кылууга жасаган көптөгөн аракеттерине карабастан, иштеп келе жатат."},{"question":"\\"БӨУ\\" - кыскартылган сөзүнүн толук түшүндүрмөсү кандай ?","answer":"БӨУ-бейөкмөт уюмдар"},{"question":"132z hangi duraklardan geçiyor?","answer":"SULTANBEYLİ PERONLAR - Pendik.EŞREF BİTLİS BULVARI - Pendik.BULVAR GİRİŞİ - Pendik.ŞEHİT KEREM ÇALIŞKANCI - Sultanbeyli.AKŞEMSETTİN - Sultanbeyli.ÇİÇEKLİ - Sultanbeyli.SANAYİ - Sultanbeyli.MECİDİYE CADDESİ - Sultanbeyli."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਵੇਲਿ ਵਧਾਈ ॥ਫਲ ਲਾਗੇ ਹਰਿ ਰਸਕ ਰਸਾਈ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਿ ਅਨਤ ਤਰੰਗਾ ॥ਜਪਿ ਜਪਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਸਾਲਾਹੀ ਮਾਰਿਆ ਕਾਲੁ ਜਮਕੰਕਰ ਭੁਇਅੰਗਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਰ ਮਹਿ ਭਗਤਿ ਰਖਾਈ ॥ਗੁਰੁ ਤੁਠਾ ਸਿਖ ਦੇਵੈ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥੨॥ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਮ ਕਿਛੁ ਬਿਧਿ ਨਹੀ ਜਾਣੈ ॥ਜਿਉ ਕੁੰਚਰੁ ਨਾਇ ਖਾਕੁ ਸਿਰਿ ਛਾਣੈ ॥੩॥ਜੇ ਵਡ ਭਾਗ ਹੋਵਹਿ ਵਡ ਊਚੇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਹਿ ਸਚਿ ਸੂਚੇ ॥੪॥੭॥੫੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 367 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਵੇਲ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ-ਵੇਲ ਨੂੰ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦਾ ਜਲ ਸਿੰਜ ਸਿੰਜ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਵਡੀ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿਚ ਇਸ ਵੇਲ ਨੂੰ) ਰਸ ਦੇਣ ਵੇਲੇ ਸੁਆਦਲੇ (ਆਤਮਕ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੇ) ਫਲ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜੀਆ-ਜੰਤ-ਰੂਪ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਲਹਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਤੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹੁ । (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਿਆ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕੀਤੀ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮਨ-) ਸੱਪ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਲਿਆ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮੌਤ ਦੇ ਡਰ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਕਾ ਲਿਆ,ਜਮਦੂਤ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਢੁਕਦੇ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ (ਆਪਣੀ) ਭਗਤੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਰੱਖੀ ਹੈ, ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ! ਗੁਰੂ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ (ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ) ਸਿੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨। (ਪਰ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ) ਹਉਮੈ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ (ਆਪਣੇ ਵਲੋਂ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ) ਕੰਮ (ਭੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ) ਭਗਤੀ ਦੀ ਰਤਾ ਭੀ ਸਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣਦਾ (ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਕੰਮ ਇਉਂ ਹਨ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਹਾਥੀ ਨ੍ਹਾ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਰ ਤੇ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। ਜੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਭਾਗ ਹੋਣ, ਜੇ ਬੜੇ ਉਚੇ ਭਾਗ ਹੋਣ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਤਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦੇ ਹਨ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੭।੫੯।\\""},{"question":"Crie um verso contendo a palavra: Felicidade","answer":"Verso: A felicidade é um presente, um tesouro a se guardar,Nas pequenas alegrias da vida, é onde devemos encontrar."},{"question":"Zer da meteorologia, eta nola pronostikatzen du eguraldiaren aldaketak?","answer":"Meteorologia da atmosferaren egonkortasuna, eguraldia eta klima aztertzen duen zientzia. Eguraldiaren aldaketak pronostikatzeko, meteorologiak erakusten du nola atmosferaren datuak erabili eguraldiaren jokabidearen iragarpenak egiteko."},{"question":"एक सूप भरून लाह्यात्यात फक्त एक रुपया=> उत्तर- ","answer":"चंद्र आणि चांदण्या"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Benda ini suka menyorok ke papan, tapi dapat nampak juga kepala besarnya.","answer":"Jawapan: paku. "},{"question":"Ẹgbẹ awọn oṣere ni: Baba Ijẹṣa ba wa loju jẹ, o gbọdọ jiya ẹṣẹ ẹ","answer":"Asiko yii ti kọja awada ṣiṣe fun Baba Ijẹṣa, boya si l’Ọgbẹni Ọlanrewaju James le dẹrin-in pa ara rẹ lọwọ yii pẹlu bi ọpọ awọn ololufẹ rẹ ṣe kọyin si i lori ẹsun ifipa bọmọde lo pọ ti wọn fi kan an, bakan naa si ni ẹgbẹ awọn oṣere tiata ilẹ wa, TAMPAN, ti lawọn o ni i ṣatilẹyin kan fun afurasi ọdaran yii, bo ba jẹ loootọ lo huwa ọhun, ko lọọ maa da iya rẹ jẹ loju paali ni.Ẹgbẹ TAMPAN (Theatre Arts and Motion Pictures Practitioners Association of Nigeria) sọ iduro wọn lori iṣẹlẹ yii lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ninu atẹjade kan ti ọga to wa lẹka iwadii ati akọsilẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Yẹmi Amodu, fi lede. O ni ẹgbẹ awọn o ni i ṣatilẹyin fun ọmọ ẹgbẹ to yọ kẹlẹ huwa ainitiju ati iwa ọdaran eyikeyii, wọn lawọn o laṣọ aṣiri tawọn fẹẹ da bo iru ẹni bẹẹ, kaka bẹẹ, awọn ṣetan lati ṣatilẹyin fun ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ninu igbesẹ rẹ lati fidi idajọ ododo mulẹ lori ọrọ yii.Atẹjade naa to tẹ ALAROYE lọwọ, ka lapa kan pe:“A ri i gẹgẹ bii ojuṣe wa lati kede pe awa o fara mọ ẹsun ti wọn fi kan ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa yii, a si bẹnu atẹ lu iwa ailojuti ati iṣekuṣe ti wọn ni Ọgbẹni Olanrewaju James, ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Baba Ijẹṣa jẹwọ pe oun hu. O ka ẹgbẹ wa, TAMPAN, lara, o si dun wa gan-an pe ọkan lara awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa ni wọn fi iru ẹsun iwa abani-loju-jẹ bayii kan, a da iwa ibajẹ buruku yii lẹbi gidi.“Nitori ọrọ to gbẹgẹ gan-an lọrọ yii, ti ọrọ ọhun ṣi wa labẹ iwadii, a o ni i sọ ohunkohun lati ṣegbe tabi ta ko ẹni tọrọ yii kan, ju pe ka fi ero wa han lodi si iwakiwa ọhun lọ.“Gẹgẹ bii ẹgbẹ kan, a loye pe apẹẹrẹ to daa lawọn eeyan n reti latọdọ wa lawujọ, tori naa, a o ni i kẹrẹ lati ṣatilẹyin fun ijọba ki idajọ ododo le fidi mulẹ lori ọrọ yii.“A ba awọn obi ati mọlẹbi ọmọde tọrọ yii kan kẹdun, a si rọ gbogbo awọn obi lati tubọ wa lojufo si ojuṣe wọn lati maa daabo bo awọn majeṣin wọn lọwọ ewu ati iwa ibajẹ to gbode kan lasiko yii.”"},{"question":"Abíọ́lá Ọdẹ́jídé","answer":"Abíọ́lá Ọdẹ́jídé jẹ́ Ọ̀jọ̀gbọ́n-ágbà nínú ìmọ̀ iṣẹ́-ọ̀nà èdè àti lítíréṣọ̀ láti Yunifásítì Ìbàdàn, (University of Ibadan). Ó ti kọ́kọ́ jẹ Igbákejì ọ̀gá Yunifásítì lábala ètò ẹ̀kọ́ ní University of Ibadan, òun sìn ni obìnrin àkọ́kọ́ tó kọ́kọ́ dé irú ipò bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ́mọ ọdún méjìdínlọ́gọ́ta.Abíọ́lá Ọdẹ́jídé kàwé gboyè dìgírì àkọ́kọ́ pẹ̀lú èsì ìdánwò tó dára nínú ìmọ̀ èdè òyìnbó ní University of Ibadan lọ́dún 1968. Lẹ́yìn náà, ó lọ sí University of Leeds lókè òkun láti kàwé gboyè dìgírì kejì nínú ìmọ̀ ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ti Lìnùngúísítì àti èdè òyìnbó pẹ̀lú èsì tó dára jù lọ lọ́dún. Ó gboyè ọ̀mọ̀wé lọ́dún 1986,ó sìn di ọ̀jọ̀gbọ́n yányán lọ́dún 1991 ní University of Ibadan.Ọdẹ́jídé ni obìnrin àkọ̀kọ̀ tí ó k9kọ́ jẹ Igbákejì ọ̀gá Yunifásítì ní University of Ibadan.[3] A¡ṣáájú àkókò náà, ó ti kọ́kọ́ di oríṣiríṣi ipò mú, lára àwọn ipò tó jẹ ni; Olùdarí ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ òkèèrè. Ó sinmi lẹ́nu iṣẹ́ ní Ìbàdàn lóṣù kọkànlá ọdún 2011. "},{"question":"世界最大のひげクジラはシロナガスクジラですが、世界最大の歯クジラといえば何クジラでしょう？","answer":"マッコウクジラ"},{"question":"దాశరధీ శతకమును ఎవరు రచించారు? అనే దానికి సమాధానం కంచర్ల గోపన్న అని రూమర్ ఉంది.నాకు సందేహం ఉంది. మీరు తెలుగులో గరిష్టంగా 8000 అక్షరాలతో వికీపీడియా తరహా కథనాన్ని రాయడం ద్వారా పై వాటిని నిరూపించగలరా?","answer":"దాశరథీ శతకము శ్రీరాముని ప్రస్తుతిస్తూ కంచర్ల గోపన్న 17వ శతాబ్దంలో రచించిన భక్తి శతకము. ఈ శతకానికి దాశరథీ కరుణాపయోనిధీ అనే మకుటం అన్ని పద్యాలలో చివరగా వస్తుంది. దాశరథీ అనగా దశరథుని పుత్రుడైన శ్రీరాముడు.గోపన్న ఆత్రేయస గోత్రుడు . కాంమాంబ యాతని తల్లి, తండి లింగన మంత్రి. ఈ విషయమును ఇతడు ఈ పద్యమున తెలెపెను."},{"question":"ਕਤੂਰੇ ਨੇ ਗਲੀਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਗੰਦਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮਾਲਕ ਨੇ ਕਤੂਰੇ ਨੂੰ ਝਿੜਕਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮਾਲਕ ਨੇ ਕੁੱਤੇ ਦੀ ਖਾਤਰ ਕੀਤੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮਾਲਕ ਨੇ ਕਤੂਰੇ ਨੂੰ ਝਿੜਕਿਆ।"},{"question":"வினா :பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றைத் தரவும்.","answer":"விடை :நான் சொல்கிறேன் என்பதற்காக எதையும் நீங்கள் ஒப்புக்கொள்ளாதீர்கள். பிறகு, மதவாதிகள் புராணத்தை முன்வைத்து பேசுவதை நீங்கள் ஒப்புக் கொள்வதற்கும், இதற்கும் வித்தியாசம் இல்லாமல் போய்விடும். நான் பேசியதை வைத்து உங்களுக்குள் நிறைய கேள்விகளை எழுப்புங்கள், அதன் பின்னர் நான் சொன்னது சரியென்கும் பட்சம் ஒப்புக் கொள்ளுங்கள்.இன்றைய நிலைக்கு நான் பேசும் கொள்கைகள் சரி ; என் திட்டங்கள் சரி என்றால் எனக்குப் பிறகும், இன்னும் 100, 200, 1000 வருடங்களுக்குப் பிறகும் என் கொள்கைகள் - நான் வகுத்த திட்டங்கள் கொஞ்சம் கூட மாற்றப்படாமல் அப்படியே இருக்க வேண்டும் என்பது என்ன நியாயம்."},{"question":"Hughie Ferguson","answer":"Hugh Ferguson (ojo keji Oṣu Kẹta 1895 - ojo kejo Oṣu Kini ọdun 1930) jẹ agbabọọlu alamọdaju ara ilu Scotland kan. Ti a bi ni Motherwell, o ṣere fun Parkhead ni ipele kekere bi magbowo ati pe o jẹ ọkan ninu awọn oṣere ọdọ ti o wa julọ julọ ni Ilu Scotland ṣaaju ki o to forukọsilẹ fun ẹgbẹ ilu rẹ lati bẹrẹ iṣẹ alamọdaju rẹ. O fi idi ararẹ mulẹ bi olutayo deede ti nṣire bi iwaju aarin, ti o pari bi agba ibi-afẹde oke ni Ajumọṣe bọọlu Ilu Scotland ni awọn iṣẹlẹ mẹta laarin 1918 ati 1921. Awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe igba o le mẹrinlelọgọrin rẹ jẹ igbasilẹ ni agba ati, ni ọdun 1925, o jẹ oṣere ti o gba wọle ga julọ ninu itan-akọọlẹ Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland.Ni ọdun 1925, Ferguson gbe lọ si ilu Welsh Cardiff City fun £ 5,000 ati tẹsiwaju awọn ilokulo igbelewọn rẹ. O jẹ agbabọọlu agba bọọlu fun awọn akoko itẹlera mẹrin ati gba ibi-afẹde ti o bori ni ipari 1927 FA Cup lakoko iṣẹgun okan si odo lori Arsenal . O tun gba wọle ni 1927 FA Charity Shield, lakoko iṣẹgun meji si okan kan lori ẹgbẹ magbowo Korinti . Awọn abajade mejeeji jẹ ki Cardiff jẹ ẹgbẹ ti kii ṣe Gẹẹsi nikan ti o gba FA Cup tabi FA Charity Shield . Pelu igbasilẹ igbelewọn ti o ni agbara, ti o pari iṣẹ rẹ pẹlu aropin ibi-afẹde kan ti 0.855 fun ere kan, ko yan rara lati ṣere fun Scotland, ṣugbọn o ṣe aṣoju Ajumọṣe Scotland XI ni awọn igba mẹta.Ferguson pada si Scotland pẹlu Dundee ni ọdun 1929, ṣugbọn o tiraka lati tun fọọmu ibi-afẹde rẹ ṣe. Oṣu mẹfa lẹhin dide rẹ, o ti padanu aaye rẹ ninu ẹgbẹ o si pa ara rẹ ni ọjọ 8 Oṣu Kini ọdun 1930 ni ọmọ ọdun merin-le-ogbon. O jẹ ọkan ninu awọn ọkunrin meje nikan ni itan-akọọlẹ ti Awọn Ajumọṣe bọọlu Gẹẹsi ati Scotland lati ti gba awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe àádọ́ta-un-un-un wọle.Ṣaaju akoko odun 1915–16, pẹlu bọọlu ilu Scotland ti n tẹsiwaju lakoko Ogun Agbaye akọkọ, Ferguson ṣe awọn ijiroro pẹlu ẹgbẹ ilu rẹ Motherwell ati pe o padanu ibẹrẹ ti ere ṣiṣi Parkhead ti ipolongo naa lẹhin awọn ijiroro lọpọlọpọ pẹlu oluṣakoso Motherwell John Hunter sare pẹ. O wa pẹlu Parkhead ati ni aarin-ojuami ti ipolongo naa, Ferguson jẹ ọkan ninu awọn oṣere ọdọ ti o ṣojukokoro julọ ni orilẹ-ede naa, ti gba diẹ sii ju awọn ibi-afẹde ogbon ni oṣu mẹrin akọkọ ti akoko naa, ati gbigba akiyesi orisirisi awọn ọgọ. O kọ ipese keji lati darapọ mọ Motherwell ni oṣu kanna ati pe o yẹ ki o jade fun Rangers ni ere anfani ni oṣu kan lẹhinna, ṣugbọn o yọkuro lẹhin ti ipalara kan lakoko ti o nṣire fun Parkhead ni idije Junior Scotland, tai ninu eyiti o gba wọle. igba marun. O yan lati ṣe aṣoju Glasgow Junior League XI lodi si ẹgbẹ kan lati Iyoku Scotland fun akoko keji ni Kínní 1916, o si gba ọkan ninu awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ ni iṣẹgun marun si meji. Ifaramu naa ṣiṣẹ bi idanwo fun yiyan ẹgbẹ ọmọ ilu Scotland kan lati mu lori awọn ẹlẹgbẹ Irish wọn ni Oṣu Kẹta, ati pe Ferguson ni a yan daradara. Lodi si ẹgbẹ Irish, o ti samisi ni pẹkipẹki ati padanu ọpọlọpọ awọn aye bi ibanujẹ rẹ lori itọju rẹ ti dagba. O ṣẹgun ijiya kan ni idaji keji ti o yipada lati fi idi iṣẹgun meji si odo fun Ilu Scotland.Ferguson sunmọ lati fowo si fun Celtic, ṣugbọn nikẹhin darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ ilu rẹ Motherwell fun ibẹrẹ ti akoko Ajumọṣe bọọlu Scotland 1916–17 . Lẹhin iṣubu ti gbigbe rẹ si Ilu Manchester, o ti sọ pe Motherwell ni “ẹgbẹ miiran nikan ti yoo ronu nipa rẹ”. O ṣe akọnimọṣẹ alamọdaju fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa ni iyaworan meji si meji pẹlu Raith Rovers ni ọjọ okanlelogun Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 1916, o gba awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ mejeeji wọle. Ọsẹ meji lẹhinna, o gba ijanilaya ijanilaya akọkọ akọkọ rẹ lakoko iṣẹgun merin si meji lori Dundee ati pe o ni idasesile nigbamii ti a ko gba laaye fun aiṣedeede iṣaaju. Motherwell ti tọpa okan si odo ni idaji-akoko ṣaaju ki Ferguson ṣe atilẹyin ipadabọ idaji keji. Idaji akọkọ ti akoko rẹ ni opin nitori awọn ipalara kekere, ṣugbọn o tẹsiwaju lati pari ipolongo akọkọ rẹ pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe marunlelogun, pẹlu ijanilaya-ija keji si Dumbarton ni osu keji odun 1917. Iwọn rẹ jẹ kẹrin ti o ga julọ ni Ajumọṣe ati pe o fẹrẹ to idaji awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ lakoko ipolongo naa. Ni opin akoko naa, o yan ni ẹgbẹ aṣoju Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland fun ere anfani kan lodi si awọn aṣaju Ajumọṣe Celtic; Sheffield Star Green 'Un sọ pe \\"awọn ẹlẹsẹ diẹ ti ṣe orukọ wọn ni kiakia\\".Syd Puddefoot ranti Ferguson ti o nṣire lodi si Shettleston ni idije Junior Cup Scotland kan ti o ti pẹ ati ti o ni ewu ti iwaju ti o padanu ipinnu lati pade; Ferguson tẹsiwaju lati gba awọn akoko mẹjọ fun Parkhead ṣaaju ki o to ṣe ifarapa lati lọ kuro ni ere ni kutukutu pẹlu abajade ko ni iyemeji mọ. Parkhead tẹsiwaju lati ṣẹgun ere naa okankola si okan. Ferguson tun ṣe iranlọwọ fun Parkhead lati de ipari ipari Ife Junior Scotland keji ni itẹlera ni ọdun 1916, ṣugbọn ẹgbẹ rẹ ni a ṣẹgun meji si odo nipasẹ Petershill .Lẹhin ipari 1916, ọpọlọpọ awọn ẹgbẹ Parkhead ti fowo si nipasẹ awọn ẹgbẹ alamọdaju. Ferguson, ti o ti gba diẹ sii ju awọn ibi-afẹde aadọrin ni ọdun to kọja pẹlu ẹgbẹ, da duro ipo magbowo rẹ gun ju awọn ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ lọ bi o ti nireti fun ipese lati ẹgbẹ orisun Lancashire ni Ajumọṣe Bọọlu afẹsẹgba . Sporting Chronicle ṣapejuwe Ferguson gẹgẹbi “oṣere agba ti o ni ariyanjiyan julọ julọ ni akoko rẹ”, diẹ ninu awọn ti n sọ ọ gẹgẹbi “oluyanṣẹ ibi-afẹde lasan”, ṣugbọn fi kun pe “ko si ẹgbẹ agba kan ni Ilu Scotland ti kii yoo fun £ 10, ni ọpọlọpọ igba pupọ. lati gba Ferguson.\\" Ferguson pada si Parkhead fun ibẹrẹ akoko 1916–17 o si gba wọle lẹẹmeji fun ẹgbẹ naa ni iṣẹgun meta si okan lori Strathclyde .Ferguson bẹrẹ iṣẹ rẹ pẹlu awọn ẹgbẹ ọdọ agbegbe ni ilu abinibi rẹ ti Motherwell o si ṣe aṣoju ẹgbẹ ile-iwe Dalziel bi idaji sẹhin . O tẹsiwaju si ẹka Motherwell ti Ẹgbẹ Ọmọkunrin Ọmọkunrin ati nigbamii Motherwell Hearts bi iwaju iwaju, ṣe iranlọwọ fun ẹgbẹ naa lati de ipari idije Awọn ọdọ ti Ilu Scotland. O darapọ mọ Glasgow -orisun Parkhead ni 1914, nigbati o yipada si ere bi aarin siwaju . O farahan fun ẹgbẹ ni iṣẹgun wọn 1914 – 15 Scottish Junior Cup ipari lori Port Glasgow Athletic Juniors . Ferguson ṣii igbelewọn lẹhin awọn iṣẹju ogun nipa lilu ikọlu akoko akọkọ ti o kọja goli atako, eyiti The Sunday Post ṣe apejuwe bi “ ibi-afẹde olu kan”. Parkhead tẹsiwaju lati ṣẹgun ere-idaraya meji si odo. Ni ipari akoko akọkọ rẹ pẹlu Parkhead, o yan ni Glasgow Junior League XI lodi si Iyoku ti Scotland XI ati gba wọle mẹta ti awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ ni iṣẹgun marun si okan kan. Iwe akọọlẹ Midlothian sọ pe Ferguson wa “ninu kilasi funrararẹ”. O wọ inu awọn ifọrọwerọ adehun pẹlu Ilu Manchester ati pe o wa ni etibebe lati fowo si ẹgbẹ agba nigbati Ogun Agbaye akọkọ ti pọ si. Pẹlu idaduro bọọlu ni England, gbigbe naa ti fagile.Ninu ere ṣiṣi ti akoko 1917–18, Ferguson ṣii akọọlẹ rẹ fun ipolongo tuntun nipa gbigbe gbogbo awọn ibi-afẹde Motherwell mẹrin lakoko iṣẹgun merin si meji lori Kẹta Lanark . Lakoko ere Ajumọṣe kan lodi si St Mirren ni Oṣu Kẹwa, o ti lu daku lẹhin ti o jẹ aṣiṣe ni agbegbe ijiya alatako. Adari agbabọọlu naa fun un ni ifẹsẹwọnsẹ fun aiṣedeede naa, eyi ti wọn gba ami ayo ti o bori wọle. Ferguson na kuro ni papa ko si ṣere fun ọsẹ mẹta miiran. Siwaju ijanilaya-ẹtan tẹle nigba ti akoko; akọkọ, lodi si Ayr United ni Kejìlá, gbe Ferguson bi awọn ga-igbelewọn player ni Scotland ni opin ti 1917 pẹlu ibi-afede mejilelogun. Awọn keji wá osu kan nigbamii, lodi si Queen ká Park ni January 1918. O pari akoko naa bi agba ibi-afẹde oke ti Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland pẹlu merinlelogbon, mẹta ṣaaju David McLean ti Kẹta Lanark. Awọn ibi-afẹde rẹ ṣe iranlọwọ fun Motherwell lati ṣe igbasilẹ ipari ti o wa ni ipo karun ati di ẹgbẹ ti o gba wọle julọ ni liigi, Ferguson tun gba wọle ni ayika idaji awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ.Siwaju oke marun pariMotherwell bẹrẹ akoko 1918 – 19 ni ọna ti ko dara, ti o gba wọle lẹẹmeji ni ṣiṣi awọn ere-kere marun wọn, ọkan ninu eyiti Ferguson sọ. Aisan akoko rẹ ni ipa lẹhin ti o ni akoran ọfun eyiti o fi agbara mu lati padanu pupọ julọ oṣu meji ti o kẹhin ti 1918. Motherwell gba pada lati tun ipo karun wọn pari ni ọdun to nbọ, ṣugbọn o gba awọn ibi-afẹde ti o dinku pupọ, Ferguson funrararẹ ṣe igbasilẹ iye rẹ ti o kere julọ fun ẹgbẹ ni akoko kikun lẹhin ti o gba wọle ni awọn akoko okandilogun ni Ajumọṣe lati awọn ifarahan merindinlogbon, botilẹjẹpe o wa ti ẹgbẹ naa oke ibi-afede. Ferguson gba awọn ibi-afẹde akọkọ rẹ ti akoko 1919 – 20 nipa gbigbe ijanilaya kan ni iṣẹgun ere ṣiṣi lori Dundee. O gba ijanilaya-ija keji si Hamilton Academical ni ọsẹ mẹta lẹhinna, fun eyiti o gba aago goolu lati ọdọ oniṣowo agbegbe TB Hill. Ferguson tẹle eyi pẹlu àmúró kan si Raith Rovers ni ere ti Motherwell ti o tẹle, ti o gbe e si gegebi agbaboolu oke ti Ajumọṣe Scotland, ti o ti gba awọn akoko mọkanla ni awọn ifarahan mẹfa akọkọ rẹ, mẹta siwaju si orogun ti o sunmọ julọ. Ferguson tun gba wọle ni gbogbo awọn ifarahan Ajumọṣe rẹ titi di 6 Oṣu Kẹwa, nigbati ẹgbẹ rẹ ti lu nipasẹ Dundee. Fọọmu akoko ibẹrẹ rẹ yori si yiyan rẹ ni Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland kan lati koju XI Ajumọṣe Irish kan, ṣugbọn o yọkuro kuro ninu ere naa lẹhin mimu ipalara kan ninu idije liigi kan lodi si Heart of Midlothian ni ọsẹ ṣaaju. Ipalara naa pa Ferguson jade fun ọsẹ marun ṣaaju ṣiṣe ipadabọ rẹ lodi si Partick Thistle ni aarin Oṣu kejila.Laibikita isansa rẹ, ni opin Oṣu Kini ọdun 1920, Ferguson wa ni isomọ pẹlu James Williamson ti Hibernian gẹgẹbi agbaboolu oke ti Ajumọṣe pẹlu okanlelogun. Ferguson gbe siwaju orogun rẹ lẹhin ti o ti gba ijanilaya ijanilaya lakoko iṣẹgun marun si okan lori Clyde ni ibẹrẹ Kínní. O yan fun Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland XI fun akoko keji ati ṣere ni ijatil merin si odo si awọn ẹlẹgbẹ Ajumọṣe Gẹẹsi wọn ni Oṣu Kẹta Ọjọ ogun. Iṣẹ rẹ ti ṣofintoto ni The Sunday Post lẹhin ti o padanu ọpọlọpọ awọn aye lati Dimegilio. Ferguson pari akoko naa gẹgẹbi agbaboolu oke ti Ajumọṣe Scotland pẹlu metalelogbon. Awọn ibi-afẹde rẹ ṣe iranlọwọ fun Motherwell lati beere ipo kẹta ni Ajumọṣe, ipari wọn ti o ga julọ ni ipele oke ni akoko yẹn.Akoko igbasilẹ igbasilẹFerguson tẹsiwaju fọọmu ti o dara rẹ si akoko 1920–21 o si gba mẹrin ti awọn ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ lakoko iṣẹgun mefa si odo lori Queen's Park ni kutukutu ipolongo naa. O tẹle eyi pẹlu ijanilaya ijanilaya siwaju si Falkirk ni ọsẹ meji lẹhinna o pari Oṣu Kẹwa gẹgẹbi agbabobo apapọ ti o ga julọ ni Ajumọṣe. Fọọmu ibi-afẹde rẹ ṣe ifamọra akiyesi lati awọn ẹgbẹ ni Ajumọṣe Bọọlu England ati mejeeji Everton ati Huddersfield Town ṣe awọn ibeere si Motherwell lori gbigbe ṣugbọn wọn kọ silẹ. O gba awọn ibi-afẹde mẹrin siwaju sii lakoko iṣẹgun mejo si meji lori ẹgbẹ ti o wa ni isalẹ Dumbarton ni Oṣu kọkanla, ti o de awọn ibi-afẹde okanlelogun fun akoko naa ati di oṣere ti o ga julọ ni Ilu Scotland ati England ni akoko yẹn.Oṣu kan lẹhinna, Ferguson gba awọn ibi-afẹde mẹrin wọle ni ere ẹyọkan fun igba kẹta ni akoko yii, ni akoko yii ni mefa si okan ṣẹgun Ayr United. Ni Oṣu Kẹrin Ọjọ merindinlogun, o tun ṣe aṣeyọri ibi-afẹde mẹrin rẹ fun akoko kẹrin lakoko akoko ni iṣẹgun lori Aberdeen . Ni ṣiṣe bẹ, o kọja igbasilẹ Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland fun awọn ibi-afẹde ni akoko kan ti okandinlogoji ṣeto nipasẹ Rangers Willie Reid ṣaaju Ogun Agbaye akọkọ. Awọn ibi-afẹde mẹrin ti Ferguson gba iye rẹ si ogoji fun akoko naa. O pari ipolongo naa pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde mejilelogoji lati pari bi agba ibi-afẹde ti Ajumọṣe fun akoko kẹta ni awọn akoko mẹrin. Igbasilẹ awọn ibi-afẹde rẹ yoo ṣiṣe titi di ọdun to nbọ, nigbati Duncan Walker gba awọn ibi-afẹde aagoji wọle fun St Mirren.Lakoko awọn oṣu ṣiṣi ti akoko 1921–22, Ferguson gba ijanilaya ijanilaya akọkọ rẹ ti ipolongo lodi si Dumbarton, nipasẹ akoko wo o jẹ ibi-afẹde kan kukuru ti Walker. Ni ọsẹ meji lẹhinna, o gba fila keji rẹ fun Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland XI ni Oṣu Kẹwa ati gba wọle fun ẹgbẹ bi wọn ti ṣẹgun awọn ẹlẹgbẹ Irish wọn meta si odo. Ni Oṣu Kejila, o gba gbogbo awọn ibi-afẹde Motherwell ni maarun si meji iṣẹgun lori Clydebank, mẹrin ninu eyiti o wa ni idaji akọkọ. Ferguson nigbagbogbo ni asopọ pẹlu gbigbe si awọn ẹgbẹ Gẹẹsi, ṣugbọn Sunday Post royin ni Oṣu Kini ọdun 1922 pe ko ni ifẹ lati jade kuro ni Ilu Scotland ati pe ko gbadun aṣa bọọlu Gẹẹsi. Ferguson ṣubu mẹwa kukuru ti Walker ni akoko ipari igbasilẹ ti igbehin, ti o pari bi agba agba keji ti o ga julọ ni Ajumọṣe pẹlu aadogbon.Nitosi gbigbe ati nigbamii odunNi ipari akoko 1921-22 Ferguson ni a gbe sori atokọ gbigbe nipasẹ Motherwell ni aṣẹ tirẹ; eyi fa awọn ọna lati ọpọlọpọ awọn ọgọ. Ni Oṣu Karun ọdun 1922, Ilu Ilu Manchester ṣe ifilọlẹ £ 3,500 (ni ayika £ 215,000 ni ọdun 2021) eyiti Motherwell kọ, ẹniti o ni idiyele Ferguson ni ayika £4,000. Ilu pada pẹlu ipese ti £ 3,900 eyiti Igbimọ Motherwell gba ṣugbọn gbigbe naa ṣubu nigbati Ferguson kọ gbigbe naa silẹ. O tun ṣe awọn ijiroro pẹlu Bọọlu Ajumọṣe Ẹgbẹ Kẹta South ẹgbẹ Bournemouth &amp; Boscombe Athletic lori ipa kan bi oluṣakoso ẹrọ orin, eyiti awọn iwe iroyin kan royin bi o ti pari. Nigbeyin ko si iṣipopada wa si imuse; Ferguson ro pe ko tọ si pe ko gba apakan ti owo gbigbe ti o pọju ati pe o joko ni awọn ọsẹ ibẹrẹ ti akoko 1922–23. Nikẹhin o tun fowo si fun Motherwell o si pada si ẹgbẹ ni meji si okan ijatil lodi si Aberdeen ni Oṣu Kẹsan ọjọ 2, o gba ibi-afẹde ẹgbẹ rẹ wọle. Lehin ti o gba wọle ni igba mẹfa ni aarin Oṣu Kẹwa, Ferguson ni a pe si Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland XI fun idije kan si Ireland nigbati George French yọkuro nitori ipalara. O gba àmúró kan fun ẹgbẹ bi wọn ti ṣẹgun meta si odo. Awọn ẹtan ijanilaya fun Motherwell lodi si Kilmarnock ati Clyde ni Oṣu kọkanla ti ilọpo meji tally rẹ fun akoko si mejila ni opin oṣu. Ferguson tẹsiwaju ṣiṣan ti ijanilaya-ẹtan, fifi awọn iṣẹlẹ siwaju sii ni Oṣu Kejila, Oṣu Kini ati Kínní lati mu tally ti awọn ẹtan ijanilaya si marun fun akoko naa. O tun ṣe awọn ijanilaya netiwọki ni awọn iṣẹgun lori Falkirk ati Bo'ness ni Ife Scotland. Iṣẹgun ti o kẹhin ni iyipo kẹrin jẹ ki Motherwell de opin-ipari idije naa fun igba akọkọ ninu itan-akọọlẹ ẹgbẹ naa. Ferguson pari akoko naa bi ẹlẹẹkeji ti o ga julọ ni Ilu Scotland pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe okanlelogbon, laibikita awọn ere 9 ti o padanu jakejado ipolongo naa, ṣubu ni kukuru ti Hearts ' Jock White .Ninu ooru ti 1923, Kẹta Lanark seto kan ajo ti South America, sugbon ri ara wọn kukuru ti awọn ẹrọ orin. Ẹgbẹ naa lẹhinna pe awọn oṣere lati awọn ẹgbẹ Scotland miiran lati rin irin-ajo, pẹlu Ferguson gba lati kopa. O gba ami ayo mẹjọ wọle ni ọpọlọpọ awọn ere-kere si awọn alatako pẹlu Independiente, Peñarol ati Urugue XI kan. Ṣaaju irin-ajo naa, Awọn iroyin Ere- ije kowe pe Ferguson ti jẹ “aarin-iwaju ti o munadoko julọ ni Ilu Gẹẹsi nla” ni ibẹrẹ awọn ọdun 1920. Lakoko akoko atẹle, o tun wa laarin awọn agbabọọlu oke ni kutukutu ọdun ati, ni opin Oṣu Kẹwa, o ti gba awọn ibi-afẹde mejilati o jẹ ki o tọpa Tom Jennings ti Raith Rovers nikan. Ni ọsẹ meji lẹhinna, Ferguson ti yọ kuro ni iṣẹgun meji si okan lori Queen's Park lẹhin ijiyan pẹlu olugbeja ti o tako nigbati o gbẹsan lodi si ere inira kan. Lẹhinna o gba ibawi kan lati ọdọ Ẹgbẹ Bọọlu afẹsẹgba Ilu Scotland ṣugbọn yago fun ijiya siwaju. Ferguson pari ipo kẹta ni ipo awọn olubori, lẹhin Dundee siwaju Dave Halliday ati Jennings, forukọsilẹ awọn ibi-afẹde metadinlogbon ni awọn ifarahan metalelogbon liigi.Pelu igbasilẹ igbelewọn ti o ni agbara, ni ibẹrẹ akoko 1924–25, Motherwell ṣe idanwo nipasẹ gbigbe Ferguson si inu ọtun dipo ipo aringbungbun deede rẹ. Botilẹjẹpe o loorekoore awọn ipo mejeeji, Ferguson ṣetọju aitasera igbelewọn rẹ ati pe o jẹ ibi-afẹde kan ni pipa ti o jẹ agba ibi-afẹde ti o ga julọ ni ipari Oṣu Kẹwa. Ni January 1925, Ferguson sunmọ lati ṣe ere ni Amẹrika, ṣugbọn kọ ipese naa. Nigbamii oṣu kanna, o gba wọle ni igba marun ni mefa si meta iṣẹgun lodi si Galston ni ipele akọkọ ti Ife Scotland. Motherwell pari akoko naa ni ipo ejidinlogun, ipo wọn ti o kere julọ lati igba Ogun Agbaye akọkọ. Ferguson sibẹsibẹ jẹ apapọ agbabọọlu kẹrin-giga julọ ni Ajumọṣe, ṣugbọn o wa lori atokọ gbigbe bi ẹgbẹ naa ṣe n wo lati gba owo.Pelu atokọ rẹ, Ferguson wa pẹlu Motherwell fun ibẹrẹ akoko 1925 – 26 o si bẹrẹ ipolongo naa nipa fifi aami àmúró kan ni iṣẹgun lori Clydebank ni ọjọ ṣiṣi. Ni akoko ipari rẹ pẹlu ẹgbẹ agba, Ferguson gba wọle ni awọn akoko mejila ni awọn ifarahan mejila, nlọ fun u ni ibi-afẹde kan lẹhin David McCrae gẹgẹbi oṣere igbelewọn keji ti o ga julọ ni liigi Scotland ni akoko yẹn. Awọn ibi-afẹde rẹ ti o kẹhin fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa wa ni iṣẹgun meji si odo ti Hamilton ninu eyiti o gba awọn ibi-afẹde mejeeji ti ẹgbẹ rẹ.Ilu CardiffNi Oṣu kọkanla ọdun 1925, awọn alaṣẹ lati ẹgbẹ Welsh Cardiff City fi ipese silẹ fun Ferguson. Idiyele wọn ni a kọ ṣugbọn wọn pada lati pade idiyele ibeere Motherwell laipẹ lẹhin; Ferguson fowo si fun owo kan ti £ 5,000, o kan £ 1,000 kere ju idiyele gbigbe igbasilẹ ni akoko naa. [101] Iru olokiki rẹ ni ẹgbẹ ilu Scotland ti awọn iṣẹ irin agbegbe ti pa fun idaji wakati kan bi awọn oṣiṣẹ ṣe laini opopona lati gbe Ferguson kuro. Ogunlọgọ nla tun pejọ si ibudo ọkọ oju irin bi o ti nlọ ati ikini ti awọn ami kurukuru okanlelogun ti a fun ni lati ọdọ David Colville &amp; Sons ṣiṣẹ bi o ti n kọja. Oluṣakoso Cardiff Fred Stewart, ẹniti o tẹle e, sọ pe \\"ko tii ri ẹrọ orin kan ti a fun ni iru ifiranšẹ bẹ tẹlẹ\\". Ferguson jẹ ọkan ninu awọn Scots mẹta ti Cardiff fowo si ni igba diẹ, Joe Cassidy ati George McLachlan mejeeji de fun iru idiyele £5,000 ni idapo. Ferguson ṣe akọbi ibi-afẹde kan fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa ni Bọọlu League First Division [nb 1] ni ọjọ keje Oṣu kọkanla ọdun 1925 ni marun si meji ṣẹgun Leicester City, ere kan ninu eyiti Cassidy gba ijanilaya kan.Lẹhin ti o ti gba wọle lẹẹkan ni awọn ifarahan mẹta akọkọ rẹ, Ferguson bẹrẹ si ṣiṣe ibi-afẹde kan. O ṣe netiwọki ni igba meje ni awọn ere marun ti n bọ, pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde ti o bori ni awọn ibaamu lodi si Bolton Wanderers, Notts County ati West Bromwich Albion . Ni akoko akọkọ rẹ, Ferguson pari bi agbaboolu ti o ga julọ ti ẹgbẹ pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde liigi okandinlogun, botilẹjẹpe o ti ṣe ni idaji nikan awọn ere Cardiff. Tally rẹ tun pẹlu ijanilaya akọkọ rẹ ni Ajumọṣe bọọlu lakoko iṣẹgun marin si meji kan lori Notts County ni Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 1926. Cardiff pari ipolongo naa ni ipo erindinlogun, yago fun ifasilẹ . Ilọsiwaju ni agbara ikọlu ẹgbẹ ti o tẹle awọn ibuwọlu tuntun wọn ni a ka fun fọọmu ti o ni ilọsiwaju lakoko idaji akoko ti o kẹhin, awọn ibi-afẹde Ferguson jẹ itọkasi bi ifosiwewe pataki.O tun jẹ agbaboolu oke ti ẹgbẹ ni akoko 1926 – 27, ti n ṣe awọn akoko merindinlogbon ni awọn ere Ajumọṣe okandinlogoji, laibikita nigbagbogbo nṣere ni inu ọtun bi ẹgbẹ naa ṣe n wo lati baamu mejeeji Ferguson ati Len Davies sinu tito sile. Lakoko ipolongo naa, Ferguson jẹ ohun elo fun ilọsiwaju Cardiff si ipari FA Cup. O gba ami ayo meji wọle ni awọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ mẹrin akọkọ wọn ṣaaju ki o to gba ibi - afẹde ti o bori ni ipele kẹrin si Chelsea nipa yiyipada ifẹsẹwọnsẹ kan. Niwaju ti wọn kẹrin-yika tai pẹlu ijọba Cup holders Bolton Wanderers, Ferguson gba a \\"orire\\" dudu ologbo ti a npè ni Trixie ti o ti woye rin kakiri ni Royal Birkdale Golf Club ni Southport, ibi ti awọn Cardiff egbe ti a duro. Ologbo naa ti n tẹle awọn oṣere naa ati pe o ṣe akiyesi pe o ti “ṣafihan ojusaju ọtọtọ fun Hughie”. Ferguson tọpa awọn oniwun ẹranko naa o si rọ wọn lati fun ologbo naa ni paṣipaarọ fun awọn tikẹti si ipari ti Cardiff ba ni ilọsiwaju. Ni ologbele-ipari, o gba àmúró kan lodisi Kika bi Cardiff ṣe bori meta si odo lati de Ipari 1927 FA Cup .Lehin ifihan ni inu ọtun ni gbogbo awọn iyipo ti o yori si ipari, Ferguson ti yipada si aarin-siwaju fun idije ipinnu. Ni iṣẹju ãdọrin mẹrin ti ere naa, gbigba jiju lati apa ọtun, Ferguson yara kan tame shot si goolu Arsenal. Dan Lewis, olutọju Arsenal, farahan lati gba rogodo ṣugbọn, labẹ titẹ lati ilọsiwaju Len Davies, gba bọọlu laaye lati yiyi nipasẹ imudani rẹ; ni igbiyanju aibikita lati gba bọọlu pada, Lewis nikan ṣaṣeyọri ni lilu bọọlu pẹlu igbonwo rẹ sinu apapọ tirẹ. Ernie Curtis, ọmọ ẹgbẹ ẹlẹgbẹ omo ọdun kandinlogun ti Ferguson, sọ nipa ibi-afẹde naa:“Mo wa ni ila pẹlu eti agbegbe ifẹsẹwọnsẹ ni apa ọtun nigba ti Hughie Ferguson kọlu ibọn ti agbabọọlu Arsenal ti tẹ lulẹ fun igba diẹ ni kutukutu. Bọọlu naa yiyi bi o ti n rin si ọdọ rẹ, ti o ti ya iyipada diẹ nitoribẹẹ o ti wa ni die-die ni ila pẹlu rẹ. Len Davies n tẹle shot ni ati pe Mo ro pe Dan gbọdọ ti ni oju kan lori rẹ. Abajade ni pe ko mu ni mimọ ati pe o rọ labẹ rẹ ati lori laini. Len be lori rẹ ati sinu awọn àwọn, ṣugbọn kò fi ọwọ kàn o. \\"Goolu Ferguson jẹ ki Cardiff di ẹgbẹ kanṣoṣo lati ita England ti o bori ninu idije naa bi wọn ṣe bori ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ naa okan si odo. Awọn ibi-afẹde liigi merindinlogbon rẹ ati 6 ni idije FA Cup ẹgbẹ naa ṣeto igbasilẹ ẹgbẹ tuntun fun awọn ibi-afẹde ni akoko kan pẹlu mejilelogbon. Igbasilẹ naa duro titi di ọdun 2003 nigbati Robert Earnshaw gba aadogbon wọle ni akoko kan. Ni akoko ti o tẹle, Ferguson gba wọle ni igba meje ni awọn ere Ajumọṣe mẹwa akọkọ rẹ ati pe o tun gba wọle ni iṣẹgun meji si okan kan lori ẹgbẹ Korinti magbowo ni 1927 FA Charity Shield ni Oṣu Kẹwa ọjọ kejila. Cardiff pari akoko naa ni ipo kẹfa ṣugbọn awọn osu ti Ferguson ni ipalara nipasẹ awọn ipalara; ko ṣe ere diẹ sii ju awọn ere Ajumọṣe itẹlera mẹta lẹhin akoko Keresimesi. Bi o ti lẹ jẹ pe eyi, o tun jẹ akọbi ibi-afẹde giga ti Cardiff, ti n ṣe awọn akoko mejidinlogun ni Ajumọṣe. Ni Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 1928, o gba awọn ibi-afẹde mejeeji wọle ni ipari ti Welsh Cup bi Cardiff ti ṣẹgun Bangor meji si odo.Ferguson gba ijiya kan ni ọjọ ibẹrẹ ti akoko 1928–29 lati fun ẹgbẹ rẹ ni iyaworan okan si okan lodi si Newcastle United . Ninu idije keji ẹgbẹ naa, o ṣeto igbasilẹ ẹgbẹ kan fun awọn ibi-afẹde ni ere liigi kan lẹhin ti o ti gba wọle ni igba marun si Burnley ni ọjọ 1 Oṣu Kẹsan ọdun 1928 bi Cardiff ti pari awọn olubori meje si odo Lẹhin awọn ere-kere mẹjọ, o ṣe itọsọna Pipin Akọkọ bi akọni ibi-afẹde ti o ga julọ pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde mẹwa. Ifimaaki rẹ rii pe o kọja Steve Bloomer bi oṣere ti o gba wọle julọ ni Ilu Scotland ati bọọlu Gẹẹsi lori awọn ibi-afẹde àádọ́rùn-ún méjìlá, ṣiṣe bẹ ni akoko diẹ. Lẹhinna o bẹrẹ si jiya lati awọn iṣoro ipalara ti o tẹsiwaju ati, lẹhin ti o ṣiṣẹ ni ijatil okan si odo si Aston Villa ni opin Oṣu Kẹsan, o ṣe awọn ifarahan mẹta nikan ṣaaju Keresimesi. Eyi ṣe deede pẹlu idinku ninu fọọmu fun Cardiff, ẹniti o gba wọle ni awọn akoko keje nikan ni awọn ere metala ti o tẹle, lakoko eyiti Western Mail ṣe kerora isansa Ferguson. O ṣe ifarahan Ajumọṣe ikẹhin rẹ fun Cardiff ni ọjọ ketalelogun Kínní 1929, ti o gba wọle ni iyaworan meji si mejisi Manchester United . Pẹlu Cardiff n tiraka lati yago fun ifasilẹlẹ ati ijiya awọn iṣoro inawo, Ferguson ni orukọ bi ọkan ninu awọn oṣere mejila ti ẹgbẹ n wa lati gba awọn ipese. Ipo rẹ tun jẹ alailagbara nipasẹ wíwọlé ti aarin-iwaju miiran, Jimmy Munro . Bi o tile jẹ pe ogun nikan ni awọn ere liigi mejilelogoji ti ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa, Ferguson pari bi agba agbabọọlu Cardiff fun akoko kẹrin ni itẹlera pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde merinla liigi. Eyi tun jẹ akoko itẹlera merinla rẹ bi agba ibi-afẹde ti ẹgbẹ rẹ, ni mejeeji Motherwell ati Cardiff. Ifarahan rẹ kẹhin fun ẹgbẹ naa wa ni Oṣu Karun ọjọ 1, nigbati o ṣere ni ijatil meta si odo si Connah's Quay &amp; Shotton ni ipari Welsh Cup.DundeeFerguson pada si Scotland pẹlu Dundee ni Oṣu Karun ọdun 1929. Cardiff ti nireti lati san pada £1,000 fun u ṣugbọn gbigbe naa ti pari nikẹhin fun ayika £800. Ferguson ti ṣe afihan ifẹ rẹ ni gbangba lati pada si Motherwell, aṣayan ti ẹgbẹ naa gbero, ṣugbọn gbigbe naa ko de imuse. O si ṣe rẹ Uncomfortable fun Dundee lori awọn šiši ọjọ ti awọn akoko lodi si Falkirk, o si bẹrẹ awọn ipolongo ni aarin-siwaju sugbon tiraka lati gbe soke si rẹ ibi-oruko. Ibi-afẹde akọkọ fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa wa ni Oṣu Kẹwa, nigbati o gba ibi-afẹde kanṣoṣo ti ere naa lodi si Queen’s Park. Dundee Courier nigbamii royin pe ko “ni igbadun ilera ti o dara julọ” ni akoko yẹn ṣugbọn ṣere lori. Lẹhinna o gbe lọ si ita ọtun ṣaaju ki o to lọ silẹ lati ẹgbẹ patapata. Ere ikẹhin rẹ fun ẹgbẹ naa jẹ iṣẹgun meta si odo lori Heart of Midlotian ni ọjọ kerinla Oṣu kejila ọdun 1929. Iṣe rẹ ninu ere naa ti ṣofintoto ati pe lẹhinna o lọ silẹ lati ẹgbẹ akọkọ. Nigbamii ti a royin pe o ti jiya irora nla ni awọn ẹsẹ rẹ ti o jẹ ki o tiraka lati sare.Ferguson ṣubu sinu ibanujẹ ati pe o ṣe afihan “iwa ibajẹ ati ijiya ti ara ti o han gbangba” ni ibẹrẹ Oṣu Kini ọdun 1930 nipasẹ awọn ẹlẹgbẹ ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ tẹlẹ ni Motherwell. Ó ti ń jìyà àìsùn oorun fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ oṣù ní òpin 1929 ó sì ti ṣàníyàn nípa ìlera rẹ̀. Ni ọjọ kejo Oṣu Kini, o ṣe igbẹmi ara ẹni, ti n gbe ara rẹ gasi ni ilẹ Dundee's Dens Park lẹhin ti o ku lẹhin igba ikẹkọ kan. Ara rẹ ti ṣe awari ni owurọ ọjọ keji nipasẹ awọn oluyaworan ti n ṣiṣẹ ni ilẹ. Ó wà lẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ òrùka gáàsì kan tí wọ́n ti tan, àwọ̀tẹ́lẹ̀ kan sì bo orí rẹ̀. Won sare gbe e lo si Dundee Royal Infirmary sugbon o ti ku. Iku rẹ nigbagbogbo ni a tọka si bi o ti ni ipa nipasẹ ibuduro ogunlọgọ bi o ti kuna lati ṣe agbekalẹ fọọmu ti a reti lati ọdọ rẹ ni ipadabọ rẹ si Ilu Scotland. Ninu ere to kẹhin fun Dundee, o gba ibawi pupọ lati ọdọ ogunlọgọ bi o ti n tiraka pẹlu cramp. Dundee Evening Teligirafu sọ pe, fun Ferguson, “iriri ti ọsan yẹn jẹ irora nla.” William McIntosh, oludari Dundee, ṣalaye pe “(Ferguson) ṣe ohun ti o dara julọ fun Dundee ati pe o mu ikuna rẹ si ọkan. Aini aṣeyọri rẹ dajudaju kii ṣe nitori aini igbiyanju ... laipẹ o di ifẹ afẹju pẹlu imọran pe iwulo rẹ bi bọọlu afẹsẹgba ti de opin.”Ti o jẹ ọdun omo merinlelogbon, Ferguson fi iyawo rẹ Jessie ati awọn ọmọ meji silẹ. Jessie loyun pẹlu ọmọ kẹta ti tọkọtaya ni akoko yẹn. Idile rẹ ti sọ iku rẹ si “aiṣedeede ti eti inu rẹ” ti o kan iwọntunwọnsi rẹ ti o yori si irisi talaka rẹ. Wọn gbagbọ pe eyi jẹ ṣẹlẹ nipasẹ tumọ ọpọlọ ti a ko ṣe ayẹwo. Ara Ferguson ti gbe lati Dundee si Motherwell; mẹ́rin lára àwọn ẹlẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀ Dundee gbé pósí rẹ̀ lọ sí gbọ̀ngàn ìdúróde nígbà tí ìyókù ẹgbẹ́ náà ń wò ó. Iṣẹ́ kékeré kan wáyé nílé rẹ̀ kí wọ́n tó sin ín sí ibi ìsìnkú Airbles ní ìlú ìbílẹ̀ rẹ̀ ní Motherwell.Ferguson ni a bi ni Motherwell ni ojo keji Oṣu Kẹta 1895 o si ni arakunrin mẹfa ati arabinrin kan. Baba rẹ ti pa ninu ijamba colliery nigbati Ferguson jẹ ọdun omo odun merindinlogun. O fẹ Jessie Andrews ni ọjọ kanlelogun Oṣu Kẹta ọdun 1924 ni ilu abinibi rẹ. Arakunrin arakunrin rẹ, ti a tun npè ni Hugh Ferguson, jẹ oloselu kan ati pe o ṣiṣẹ bi Ọmọ ẹgbẹ ti Ile-igbimọ fun Motherwell ati pe o ṣe iranlọwọ nigbakan arakunrin arakunrin rẹ ni awọn apejọ oloselu. Ọmọkunrin Ferguson Jack nigbamii tẹsiwaju lati ṣe aṣoju Ilu Gẹẹsi ni polo omi ni Olimpiiki 1952 ati 1956. Ọmọbinrin rẹ Sadie nigbamii fẹ Dunfermline player James Hogg, arakunrin ti ilu Scotland Bobby Hogg .Ferguson ni a gba bi ẹrọ orin mimọ, o jẹ teetotal, ko mu siga ati lọ si ile ijọsin. O tun nifẹ si ati tọju awọn ẹiyẹ, ti n ṣafihan wọn ni awọn idije ti a ṣeto nipasẹ Ẹgbẹ Ẹyẹ Motherwell ati District Cage. O bori ẹka rẹ lakoko ti o pari olusare-soke ni omiran ni ọdun 1923 pẹlu ibọwọ goolu kan o si gba awọn ami-ẹri pupọ ni ọdun to nbọ.Ohun pataki ti Ferguson ni agbara ipari rẹ; Sporting Chronicle ṣe akiyesi lẹhin iṣafihan agba rẹ fun Motherwell ni ọdun 1916 pe “o ni gbogbo awọn agbara ti ara ti o nilo ni iwaju-aarin, ati laiseaniani jẹ ami-ami itanran”. Ni ipari akoko agba akọkọ rẹ, Daily Record kowe “Hugh le fa atako jade, o le gba iṣẹ deede lori bọọlu ati pe ko gbagbe ibiti ibi-afẹde wa”. Iwe naa tun tọka si ti ara rẹ, ṣe akiyesi pe lakoko ti kii ṣe abala pataki ti ere rẹ “kii ṣe ẹlẹgẹ. O le kan kan, o le da ọkan pada.\\" Nigbati o forukọsilẹ fun Cardiff ni ọdun 1925, Western Mail ṣe apejuwe rẹ gẹgẹbi “kii ṣe eniyan nla ni pataki ṣugbọn o jẹ wiry ati nippy”.O tun jẹ olokiki fun irẹlẹ ati oye ti ere ododo. John Hunter, ti o ṣakoso Ferguson ni Motherwell, ṣapejuwe rẹ gẹgẹbi \\"aibikita ninu iwa, ẹlẹgbẹ ododo ti o dara, o ju gbogbo ohun miiran lọ jẹ ọlọla.\\" Ọkan iru apẹẹrẹ ti eyi wa ninu idije liigi kan lodi si Hibernian lakoko ti o nṣere fun Motherwell. Bọọlu alatako Bill Harper ti ṣe ipalara kan ati pe anfani wa si Ferguson lati lo anfani yii nigbati o tiraka lati gba bọọlu lati ori agbelebu. Dipo ki o lo aburu Harper, Ferguson gba olutọju laaye lati gba pada ki o da ibi-afẹde kan duro.Awọn igbasilẹ igbelewọnPelu awọn iṣe rẹ fun Motherwell, Ferguson ko yan rara fun ẹgbẹ orilẹ-ede Scotland. Ni akoko ilọkuro rẹ lati ọgba ni 1925, Ferguson jẹ oṣere ti o gba igbelewọn ti o ga julọ ninu itan-akọọlẹ ti Ajumọṣe Ilu Scotland. Lẹhinna o kọja nipasẹ Jimmy McGrory ati Bob McPhail . O jẹ ọkan ninu awọn oṣere meje nikan ti o ti gba diẹ sii ju awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe àádọ́ta-un-un-un ninu itan-akọọlẹ bọọlu afẹsẹgba Scotland ati Gẹẹsi, pari iṣẹ rẹ pẹlu ipin ibi-afẹde fun ere kan ti 0.855.Fun ọpọlọpọ ọdun Ferguson ṣe igbasilẹ igbasilẹ ẹgbẹ Motherwell fun awọn ibi-afẹde ni awọn ere itẹlera, titi ti Kevin van Veen fi fọ ni ọdun 2023."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:సీ॥ కాళిదాసాది సత్కవి పుంగవుల గాంచివిద్యావతి యన నేవెలది యొప్పె ?రణశూరులగు కృష్ణరాయాదులను గనివీరమాత యన నేనారి తనరె?నతుల కాశ్యాది పుణ్యక్షేత్రములు గల్గిపుణ్యవతియన నేపొలతి నెగడె ?కొహినూరు మొదలగు మహిత మణులనీనిరత్నగర్భయన నేరామ వెలసె ?తే॥గీ|| నట్టి సద్గుణసంఘాత యఘ విదూరసన్నుతవ్రాత విపుల తేజస్సమేతబహుళ విఖ్యాత యాచక పారిజాతభద్రముల మీకొసగుగాత భరతమాత.","answer":"సకల సద్గుణ రాశి మన భరతమాత. ఈమె అందరి పాపాలను దూరం చేస్తుంది. అందరూ పొగడ దగినది. గొప్ప తేజస్సు కలది. అనేక విధాలుగా కీర్తి కలది. కోరిన వరాలనిచ్చే పారిజాత వృక్షం వంటిది. కాళిదాసు మొదలైన గొప్ప కవులను కన్న విద్యావతి. కృష్ణదేవరాయలు వంటి వీరులను కన్న వీరమాత. కాశీ వంటి పుణ్యక్షేత్రాలు ఉన్న పుణ్యభూమి. కోహినూరు వజ్రం వంటి మణులను కన్న రత్నగర్భ మన భరతభూమి. అటువంటి భరతమాత మీకు భద్రతను కల్గిస్తోంది."},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：滕文公问曰：“滕，小国也，间于齐、楚。事齐乎？事楚乎？”孟子对曰：“是谋非吾所能及也。无已，则有一焉：凿斯池也，筑斯城也，与民守之，效死而民弗去，则是可为也。”","answer":"滕文公问道：“滕国是个小国，夹在齐国和楚国的中间，侍奉齐国呢，还是侍奉楚国呢？”孟子回答道：“谋划这个问题不是我力所能及的。一定要我说，就只有一个办法：深挖护城河，筑牢城墙，与百姓共同守卫，百姓宁可献出生命也不逃离，这样就好办了。”"},{"question":"Apakah silinder licin dalam enjin? Berdasarkan soalan sebelumnya, tulis konteks yang mengandungi jawapannya. Ia boleh menjadi 1 - 20 ayat. Konteks:","answer":"Kebiasaannya, motor synchronous hysteresis biasanya (pada dasarnya) motor dua fasa dengan kapasitor peralihan fasa untuk satu fasa. Ia bermula seperti motor induksi, tetapi apabila kadar geseran menurun cukup, rotor (silinder licin) menjadi magnet sementara. Kutubnya yang diedarkan menjadikannya bertindak seperti PMSM. Bahan rotor, seperti paku biasa, akan kekal magnet, tetapi juga boleh dimagnetkan dengan sedikit kesukaran. Sebaik sahaja berjalan, tiang rotor tetap di tempatnya; mereka tidak hanyut."},{"question":"Có trọng lượng tới 4-5 kg, giá đắt đỏ, song không phải lúc nào tôm hùm bông thiên nhiên Australia cũng có hàng để nhập về Việt Nam.Vốn là loại hải sản cao cấp đắt đỏ nhất trong dòng tôm, tôm hùm bông trọng lượng 4-5 kg một con khai thác ngoài tự nhiên có số lượng ít. Tại Việt Nam, loại này đa phần là tôm nuôi ở các vùng biển Nha Trang hoặc Phú Yên nhưng số lượng cũng không nhiều.Mới đây một công ty ở TP HCM đã nhập lô tôm hùm bông thiên nhiên Australia gần 100 con.Tôm hùm bông thiên nhiên Australia có trọng lượng 4 kg tại cửa hàng hải sản ở TP HCM. Ảnh: Linh ĐanTôm hùm có trọng lượng 4 kg tại cửa hàng hải sản ở TP HCM. Ảnh: Linh ĐanÔng Trần Văn Trường, CEO chuỗi Hải sản Hoàng Gia, cho biết lần đầu tiên ông nhập được lô tôm hùm bông có kích cỡ khủng trước dịp lễ. Các năm trước, loại này cả năm mới có một lần hoặc 2-3 tháng khách mới báo có hàng. Trong 100 con tôm cập cảng TP HCM hồi đầu tuần có khoảng 10 con trọng lượng 4-5 kg nhưng đều được khách đặt mua dịp lễ 2/9. \\"Chúng tôi chỉ còn loại có trọng lượng 1-3kg\\", ông Trường nói.Theo ông, giá bán lên tới gần 3,5 triệu một kg. Loại 2 kg một con có giá 7 triệu đồng, con 4-5 kg có giá 14-17 triệu đồng. Những con tôm này có chiều dài 40 cm và chiều ngang 18 cm, không tính phần chân và râu.Cũng từng bán 20 con tôm hùm bông nhập khẩu, anh Toàn, chủ vựa hải sản trên đường Phạm Văn Đồng (TP Thủ Đức) cho biết, tôm hùm bông thiên nhiên loại 2 kg một con số lượng ít, con 4-5 kg là \\"cực hiếm\\". Đặc biệt, với loại đánh bắt ở vùng biển sạch, được bảo vệ nghiêm ngặt như Australia lại càng đắt đỏ. Do đó, anh Toàn thường phải gom đơn và đề nghị khách đặt cọc trước 50% mới dám nhập hàng.Đưa ra một tiêu đề cho đoạn văn bản trên. ","answer":"Tôm hùm bông Australia giá 15 triệu đồng một con"},{"question":"Inona no teny filamatry ny oniversite an' Antananarivo ?","answer":"Ny teny filamatry ny oniversite an' Antananarivo dia: \\"Izay adala no toa an-drainy\\"."},{"question":"Yumurtalık kisti ameliyatsız geçer mi?","answer":"Yumurtalık kistlerinin çoğu 'skleroterapi' yöntemiyle ameliyatsız olarak tedavi edilebilir. Skleroterapi yönteminde, önce ultrason rehberliğinde cilt uyuşturularak bir iğne ile kiste girilir ve kist sıvısı enjektörle dışarı alınır."},{"question":"Por quanto tempo esteve Macau sob Influência Portuguesa?","answer":"Macau foi ocupada, colonizada e administrada por Portugal, durante mais de 400 anos (1557 - 1999) e é considerada o primeiro Entreposto, bem como a última Colónia Europeia, na Ásia."},{"question":"Chọn một trong hai vấn đề sau để thảo luận, tìm và lập dàn ý cho chủ đề đã chọn:- Nguyên nhân nào làm cho nước sạch ngày càng khan hiếm?- Vì sao cuối học kì I, lớp em được tuyên dương là lớp đứng đầu khối 6?","answer":"- Tìm ý:+ Kết quả của sự khan hiếm nước sạch: con người không thể sinh sống mà thiếu đi nước.+ Nguyên nhân dẫn đến sự khan hiếm nước sạch: Số nước ngọt không phải là vô tận và đang ngày càng bị nhiễm bẩn bởi chính con người gây ra. Số lượng nước ngọt được sử dụng trong sinh hoạt hàng ngày ngày càng tăng do nhu cầu của con người và dân số tăng. Ý thức sử dụng của con người còn phung phí nước ngọt, chưa khai thác hợp lí.+ Nguyên nhân quan trọng là do ý thức sử dụng của con người.- Lập dàn ý:+ Mở đầu: Hiện nay nước sạch ngày càng khan hiếm, cuộc sống của con người bị ảnh hưởng.+ Nội dung chính:  Số nước sạch không phải là vô tận và đang ngày càng bị nhiễm bẩn bởi chính con người gây ra. Số lượng nước sạch được sử dụng trong sinh hoạt hàng ngày ngày càng tăng do nhu cầu của con người và dân số tăng. Ý thức sử dụng của con người còn phung phí nước sạch, chưa khai thác hợp lí. Con người không thể sinh sống mà thiếu đi nước.+ Kết thúc: Có rất nhiều nguyên nhân, nếu chúng ta không ý thức hơn trong việc sử dụng nước ngọt thì sự sống của loài người sẽ bị hủy diệt."},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-community portal","answer":"சமுதாய வலைவாசல்"},{"question":"විකිපීඩියාවට ප්‍රවේශ වන උපාංග මොනවාද, සහ ඩෙස්ක්ටොප් සහ ජංගම දුරකථන වලින් දිනකට කොපමන පිරිසක් පිවිසේද?","answer":"විකිපීඩියාවට දිනපතා උපාංග මිලියන 67කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවකින් ප්‍රවේශ වන අතර, මිලියන 45කට අධික පරිශීලකයන් ජංගම උපාංගවලින් සහ මිලියන 22කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවක් ඩෙස්ක්ටොප්වලින් ප්‍රවේශ වේ."},{"question":"Ajụjụ:Gwa ihe gbara aka pụọ ije ma  chiri ụmụ lọta? ","answer":"Azịza:EdeNke a bụ maka ọ n'abụ etinye naanị isi ede n'ala, o puo, ọ nwee ọtụtụ aka. "},{"question":"అజంతా గుహలు ఎక్కడ ఉన్నాయి ? వాటి విశిష్టతను తెలపండి.","answer":"అజంతా గుహలు జల్గామ్ కు దక్షిణంగా 35 మైళ్ళ దూరంలో, ఔరంగాబాదు ఉత్తరంగా 55 మైళ్ళ దూరాన ఉన్నాయి. అజంతా గుహలలోని భారతీయ చిత్రకళ, అంతకు ముందుగాని, ఆ తర్వాత గాని అందుకోనంతటి మహోన్నత శిఖరాలను అందుకొంది. వాఘోరా నది పుట్టిన చోటుననే అజంతా గుహలున్నాయి. బౌద్ధభిక్షువులు అక్కడ చిత్రాలను చిత్రించారు. అజంతా గుహలు మనల్ని స్వాప్నిక జగత్తులోకి తీసుకొని వెడతాయని చెప్పి నెహ్రూ గారు అజంతా చిత్రకళను మెచ్చుకోవడం వాటి విశిష్టతను వెల్లడిస్తోంది."},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚Манас кайсы уруунун өкүлү катары сүрөттөлөт?а) нойгут б) ногойв) кыпчак г) кыргыз","answer":"Манас эпосу 📚б) ногой"},{"question":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡികയ്ക്ക് ഒരു തുടർച്ച എഴുതുക: 1919 ഏപ്രിൽ 13-ന് നിയമത്തിനെതിരെ പ്രതിഷേധിച്ചുകൊണ്ട് അമൃത്സറിലെ ജാലിയൻ വാലാബാഗ് എന്ന സ്ഥലത്ത് ജനങ്ങൾ ഒത്തുകൂടി. എന്നാൽ ഇവിടെവച്ച് അന്നത്തെ ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് മിലിറ്ററി കമാൻഡറായിരുന്ന റെജിനാൾഡ് ഡയർ, ജാലിയൻ വാലാബാഗിന്റെ മുൻഭാഗത്തുള്ള പ്രവേശനകവാടം അടയ്ക്കാനും തുടർന്ന് 5,000 ഓളം വരുന്ന ജനക്കൂട്ടത്തിനുനേരേ പട്ടാളക്കാരോട് വെടിവയ്ക്കാനും ഉത്തരവിട്ടു. ജാലിയൻ വാലാബാഗ് കൂട്ടക്കൊലയിൽ","answer":"കൊല്ലപ്പെട്ടവരുടെ എണ്ണമായി ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് കമ്മീഷന്റെ രേഖകളിൽ പറയുന്നത് 379 പേർ എന്നാണെങ്കിലും 1,500 ലധികം പേർ കൊല്ലപ്പെട്ടിരുന്നുവെന്ന് ഇന്ത്യയിലെ കണക്കുകൾ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"تعلیمی دورے پر مضمون","answer":"ایک تعلیمی دورہ زیادہ تر اسکولوں اور کالجوں میں تعلیمی تجربے کا حصہ ہے۔ اس طرح کے دورے طلباء کو مختلف مضامین کے بارے میں خود کو سمجھنے میں مدد کرتے ہیں۔مثال کے طور پر، اسکول طلباء کو تعلیمی دوروں پر چڑیا گھروں اور پارکوں میں لے جا سکتے ہیں تاکہ انہیں نباتات اور حیوانات سے آشنا کیا جا سکے۔ کتاب میں کسی جانور یا پودے کی تصویر دیکھنا ایک چیز ہے اور اسے آمنے سامنے دیکھنا دوسری بات ہے۔اسی طرح فلکیات کو سمجھنے کے لیے سیاروں کا دورہ بہت مفید ہے۔ کالجوں میں بھی ایسے ٹور کرائے جاتے ہیں۔ تاریخ کے طلباء کو تاریخی اہمیت کے حامل مقامات یا عجائب گھروں میں لے جایا جا سکتا ہے جہاں قدیم نمونے محفوظ ہیں۔ پرانے قلعوں اور محلات یا قدیم سلطنتوں کے کھنڈرات کا دورہ ہماری آنکھوں کے سامنے تاریخ کو زندہ کر سکتا ہے۔ اس سے ہمیں اندازہ ہوتا ہے کہ پرانے زمانے میں لوگ کیسے رہتے تھے۔ سائنس کے طلباء کو سائنسی اہمیت کے حامل مقامات جیسے ریسرچ لیبز میں لے جایا جا سکتا ہے۔ آثار قدیمہ کے طلباء کو کھدائی کے مقامات پر لے جایا جاتا ہے۔تعلیمی دورہ ایک تفریحی تجربہ ہے۔ چونکہ یہ دورہ بہت دور کی جگہوں پر ہو سکتا ہے، اس لیے یہ طلباء کے لیے ایک ساتھ خوشگوار وقت گزارنے کا موقع ہے۔ کچھ دنوں کے لیے وہ کلاسز، ہوم ورک اور امتحانات کو بھول سکتے ہیں۔ بس یا ٹرین کا سفر، طالب علموں کے ساتھ گیت گاتے ہوئے اور خوش مزاج اساتذہ کے ساتھ خوشیاں منانا، ایک ناقابل فراموش تجربہ ہے۔یہاں تک کہ تماشائیوں کو بھی ایک متعدی جوش و خروش محسوس ہوتا ہے جب وہ طالب علموں کے ایک بس کے بوجھ کو ہم جنس پرستوں کو چھوڑ کر گاتے ہوئے اور خوشی سے ان کی طرف ہلاتے ہوئے دیکھتے ہیں۔ دوستوں کی قربت اور والدین کی عدم موجودگی خوشامد اور فساد کی دعوت ہے۔ اس عرصے کے دوران کچھ قریبی دوستیاں قائم ہو سکتی ہیں کیونکہ جب ہم کچھ دنوں تک ان کے ساتھ رہتے ہیں تو ہم لوگوں کے بارے میں زیادہ سمجھتے ہیں۔ سب سے افسوسناک حصہ اسی پرانے معمول پر گھر واپس آ رہا ہے۔"},{"question":"What is the title of the first ever Carry On film made and released in 1958?","answer":" the first ever Carry On film made and released in 1958 is Carry on Sergeant"},{"question":"Wọn ba oku Ṣalewa lẹyin ileewe kan ni Badagry","answer":"Agbẹnusọ fawọn ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Eko, Muyiwa Adejọbi, ti rọ awọn obi Ṣalewa Adebọwale ti wọn pa, ki wọn tete fi ọrọ ọhun to ọlọpaa leti ki iwadii to peye le bẹrẹ ni kiakia.Lẹyin ileewe kan ni wọn sọ pe wọn ti ba oku ọmọ ọdun mọkandinlogun ọhun lẹyin ti wọn ti n wa a lati ọjọ kọkanla oṣu kẹwaa ọdun yii.Adugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Igando, l’Ekoo, ni wọn sọ pe ọmọ yii ti n bọ to fi dawati laarin ibẹ sile wọn.Ẹgbọn ẹ to ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ, Feyikẹmi, ṣalaye wi pe ọmọleewe Poli l’Ekoo ni Ṣalewa n ṣe, ati pe idanwo si ileewe awọn nọọsi lo lọọ ṣe lọjọ to kuro nile, ko too pade iku ojiji ọhun.O ni bo to ṣe pari idanwo ẹ lo ti pe awọn nile wi pe oun ko ni i le wa sile mọ lọjọ yẹn nitori pe oun ko tete pari idanwo naa. Ọdọ ibatan ẹ to wa n’Igando ni wọn sọ pe o pada sun lọjọ naa.Iya Ṣalewa ni tiẹ ti sọ fawọn oniroyin pe lẹyin ileewe kan ni Badagry lawọn ti ri oku ọmọ naa lẹyin tawọn ti wa a titi.Lati fidi ọrọ ọhun mulẹ lọdọ awọn ọlọpaa, ohun ti agbẹnusọ wọn sọ ni pe ki awọn mọlebi ̀ọmọ ti wọn pa a yii lọọ fọrọ naa to teṣan ọlọpaa to wa laduugbo wọn leti, ki iwadii le bẹrẹ lori iṣẹlẹ naa kiakia."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Ba mu matee sëkk te ñor xomm, [Muusaa] jox Na nu ko àtte ya ak xàm-xàm.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Ba mu matee sëkk te ñor xomm, [Muusaa] jox Na nu ko àtte ya ak xàm-xàm.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Ba: SCONJmu: PRONmatee: ADJsëkk: ADVte: CCONJñor: ADJxomm: ADV,: PUNCT[: PUNCTMuusaa: PROPN]: PUNCTjox: VERBNa: AUXnu: PRONko: PRONàtte: NOUNya: DETak: CCONJxàm-xàm: NOUN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Y a-t-il de la vie sur Mars ?","answer":"Les sondes envoyées sur Mars n'ont encore rien trouvé... Or l'eau a bien coulé sur la planète rouge ! Mais..., malheureusement, durant une très courte période et il y a vraiment très longtemps ! Il y a vraiment peu de chance (environ 0 chance) que la vie existe aujourd'hui à la surface de Mars. Reste la possibilité que des formes de vie primitives se cachent dans le sous-sol martien. Aussi, il est bien probable que les nombreuses missions d'exploration de la surface martienne aient emmené sur la planète rouge des bactéries terrestres."},{"question":"खिर भनेको के हो?","answer":"\\"खिर\\" एक नेपाली  खाद्य पदार्थ हो। यसमा दुध, चामल, चिनी, घिउ, बदाम, र अन्य सुगन्धिक मसलाहरू मिसाइएका हुन्छन् र साधारणत: विशेष पर्वका दिनमा बनाइन्छ र सेवन गरिन्छ। "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'diseluduki bawah rumah orang berluluk kepala'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kalau tinggal di tempat orang tentu diisi adat lembaganya atau kalau beristeri ke sebuah rumah, tentu ditanggung susah senang dan lain-lain di rumah itu"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Công thức làm món cánh gà chiên kiểu Hàn Quốc thơm ngon, hấp dẫn","answer":"Nguyên liệu 900g – 1kg cánh gà nguyên chiếc 1/2 thìa cà phê muối 3 thìa súp đường nâu 1 thìa súp gochujang (tương ớt ngọt Hàn Quốc) 1 thìa nước mắm 1/3 chén rượu soju 3 củ tỏi lớn, bóc vỏ đập giập 1 thìa cà phê dầu vừng Gochugaru (ớt bột Hàn Quốc) tuỳ khẩu vị 1 thìa súp bột khoai tây Dầu thực vật 1 thìa cà phê hạt vừng rang để trang trí Cách làm Rắc muối lên cánh gà, đậy bằng nylon bọc thức ăn và cho vào tủ lạnh 24 tiếng. Làm như vậy gà sẽ đậm đà hơn, và còn rút bớt nước trên bề mặt, giúp gà dễ rán hơn. Để làm nước sốt, trộn đường nâu, nước mắm, gochujang, soju, tỏi, gừng và dầu vừng vào một cái chảo, nấu sôi cho đến khi sền sệt dạng siro. Nếm nước sốt và cho thêm gochugaru cho đến khi đủ độ cay. Lọc nước sốt qua một cái rây mắt nhỏ để loại bỏ hết cặn. Điều này quan trọng vì cặn sẽ có xu hướng bám trên bề mặt làm xấu thịt gà. Cho dầu vào chảo sao cho dầu ngập cánh gà, đun sôi ở khoảng 160 độ C. Lấy thịt gà ra khỏi tủ lạnh, dùng khăn giấy thấm càng nhiều nước trên bề mặt thịt gà càng tốt. Điều này sẽ làm miếng thịt khô và không gây nổ hay bắn dầu ra ngoài khi cho vào chảo, đồng thời da gà cũng nhanh vàng và đẹp hơn. Rắc bột khoai tây đều lên cả 2 mặt từng miếng cánh gà. Rán cánh gà trong vòng 10 phút, theo từng lô một, sao cho cánh gà ngập trong dầu rán, cho lô cánh gà hoàn thành sang đĩa và tiếp tục lô khác. Tăng nhiệt độ dầu lên khoảng 190 độ C. Rán lại cánh gà cho đến khi 2 mặt vàng ruộm (khoảng 2-3 phút). Cho ngay cánh gà sang bát nước xốt, đảo thật nhanh để nước xốt bám đều rồi cho ra đĩa. Khâu này bạn cần nhanh tay để nước ít ngầm vào cánh gà nhất mà vẫn bám được xung quanh. Rắc hạt vừng rang lên và thưởng thức."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"O ótimo é inimigo do bom\\"?","answer":"De tanto tentar fazer algo perfeito, acabamos por não fazer. Ou seja, acabamos mais prejudicamos ainda.Exemplo: “Entregue assim mesmo o relatório, já passou do prazo e o ótimo é inimigo do bom.”"},{"question":"Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"ada gaya\\".","answer":"Osman ada gaya menjadi pelakon filem kerana dia tinggi dan tampan."},{"question":"السؤال: من هم المغضوب عليهم عند الله تعالى؟","answer":"الإجابة:  اليهود."},{"question":"「おみずとり」で知られる二月堂のあるお寺と言えばどこ？","answer":"東大寺です。"},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:\\" Any atsimo andrefana, tsy lavitra an’i Toliara no misy ny tanàna kely antsoina hoe Tanambe Manirisoa , izay faritra maina, voahodidina raketa. Ny faharatsian’ny kalitaon’ny tany sy ny tsy fikojakojana ny lava-drano fatsakana misy eo an-toerana no nahatonga olona manodidina ny 250 eo ho eo mampiasa rano ambanin’ny tany ho an’ny filàn’izy reo andavanandro, indrindra ho an’ny fidiovana, fandrahoan-tsakafo, fanasan-damba ary hatramin’ny rano ho an’ny biby fiompy, ny fambolena nandritra ny 7 taona mahery. \\"Inona no mahatonga ny rano fampiasa ho rano avy any ambanin'ny tany raha ny voalazan'ny lahatsoratra?","answer":"Araka io lahatsoratra io, dia rano avy any ambanin'ny tany no fampiasa noho ny tsy fisian'ny rano izay vokatry ny faharatsian'ny kalitaon'ny tany sy ny tsy fikojakojana ny lava-drano."},{"question":"ஏறு தழுவுதல் குறித்துக் கூறும் ஒரே சங்க நூல் எது?","answer":"ஏறு தழுவுதல் குறித்துக் கூறும் ஒரே சங்க நூல் கலித்தொகை. கலித்தொகை சங்க காலத் தமிழிலக்கியத் தொகுதியான எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களுள் ஆறாவது நூலாகும். பல புலவர்களின் பாடல்கள் அடங்கிய தொகுப்பு நூலான கலித்தொகையில் ஓசை இனிமையும், தரவு, தாழிசை, தனிச்சொல், சுரிதகம் என்னும் சிறப்பான அமைப்புகளால் அமைந்த கலிப்பாவினால் சிவனைப் பற்றிய கடவுள் வாழ்த்துப் பாடல் ஒன்று உட்பட பாடப்பட்ட 150 பாடல்கள் உள்ளன. அப்பாடல்களை அடி எல்லை நோக்கில் ஆராயும் போது குறைந்த அடி எல்லையாக 11 அடிகள் கொண்ட பாடல்களும் உயர்ந்த அடி எல்லையாக 80 அடிகள் கொண்ட பாடல்களும் காணப்படுகின்றன."},{"question":"請回答下列問題：世界上最高的山峰是哪一座?","answer":"答案：珠穆朗瑪峰"},{"question":"1° frase: Adamsville está rodeada al oeste por Coleman, al este de Sumterville, al norte por Wildwood y al sur por Lake County.2° frase: Adamsville está rodeado al oeste por Coleman, al este por Lake County, al norte por Wildwood y al sur por Sumterville.Pregunta: ¿La frase 1 y la 2 expresan el mismo significado? ¿Sí o No?","answer":"No."},{"question":" बलरामाच्या वडिलांचे नाव काय होते?उत्तर -","answer":"वासुदेव"},{"question":"'කකුල් පුපුරනකම් ගුටි කා' නැටුම් ඉගෙනගත් 'නර්තන රැජිණ'","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ කලා ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ උන්නතියට දායක වූ තවත් විශිෂ්ට කලාකාරියක දැයට අහිමි වී තිබේ.ඒ, ප්‍රවීණ නර්තන ආචාර්යවරියක වූ කලාශූරී, විශ්ව කලා කීර්ති රැජිණි සෙල්වනායගම් ය.සිකුරාදා (ඔක්. 20) රාත්‍රියේ ඇය අභාවප්‍රාප්ත වන විට 71 වන වියේ පසු වූ අතර ඇය දීර්ඝ කාලයක් තිස්සේ අසනීප තත්ත්වයෙන් පසු විය.'නර්තන රැජිණ' යන විරුදාවලියෙන් ද හැඳින්වූ ඇය රාජගිරිය, කලපළුවාව ප්‍රදේශයේ පදංචි වී සිටියා ය.ළමා අවධියරැජිණි සෙල්වනායගම්ගේ මව බලංගොඩ පදිංචිව සිටි කාන්තාවක වූ අතර, පියා යාපනයේ උපත ලැබූ ද්‍රවිඩ ජාතිකයෙකු විය.ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාට දාව රැජිණි ඇතුළු දූවරුන් 9 දෙනෙක් සහ එක් පුත්‍රයෙක් උපත ලැබූහ. ඒ අනුව, රැජිණිට සහෝදර සහෝදරියන් 9 දෙනෙක් සිටියහ.පියා වාරිමාර්ග දෙපාර්තමේන්තුවේ ප්‍රධාන ලිපිකරුවෙකු ලෙස සේවය කළ අතර ඔහුට ලැබෙන ස්ථාන මාරු වීම් නිසා පාසල් කිහිපයක ම ඉගෙනුම ලැබීමට රැජිණිට සිදු විය.ඒ අනුව, ඇයගේ පළමු පාසල වූයේ, කොළඹ බෞද්ධ බාලිකා විද්‍යාලය යි.පසුව පියාට ලැබුණු ස්ථාන මාරුවක් හේතුවෙන් පැල්මඩුල්ල ගන්කන්ද මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලයට ඇතුළු වීමට ඇයට සිදු විය.ජීවිතයේ හැරවුම් ලක්ෂයරැජිණි සෙල්වනායගම් පවසා ඇති පරිදි ඇයගේ නර්තන ජීවිතයේ හැරවුම් ලක්ෂය වූයේ, ගන්කන්ද මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලයට ඇතුළත් වීම ය.\\"මට පොඩි කාලේ ඉඳන් මට හීනෙන් වගේ හැම තිස්සෙ ම පෙනුණා, නැටුම. මම හැම තිස්සෙ ම ඒ කාලේ අතපය නටවනවා. ගන්කන්ද මධ්‍ය මහා විද්‍යාලයේදී මගේ වාසනාවට මගේ ගුරු සරත් ලාල් පනාවල මහත්මයා මට මුණ ගැසුණා. එතුමා තමයි මට මේ තරම් ලොකු ගමනක් යන්න මග පෙන්නුවේ,\\" රූපවාහිනී සාකච්ඡාවකදී වරක් ඇය පැවසුවා ය.පසු කලෙක ශ්‍රී ලංකා කලා කෙතෙහි විශිෂ්ටයින් බවට පත්වූ නිශ්ශංක දිද්දෙණිය සහ සුමනා රත්නපාල යන කලාකරුවන් ද රැජිණි සෙල්වනායගම් සමග සරත් ලාල් පනාවල නර්තන ගුරුවරයාගෙන් ඉගෙනුම ලැබූ සමකාලීනයින් දෙදෙනෙකි.\\"අම්මා කකුල් පුපුරනකම් ගැහුවා\\"රැජිණි ඇතුළු සිය දූවරුන් ගුරුවරියන් බවට පත්වනු දැකීමට කැමැත්තෙන් සිටි ඇගේ මව රැජිණි නර්තනය හැදෑරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කිසිදු කැමැත්තක් නොදැක්වූවා පමණක් නොව, එය නතර කිරීමට බොහෝසෙයින් උත්සහ කළා ය.\\"අම්මා සම්පූර්ණයෙන් ම විරුද්ධ වුණා. අම්මා ගහලා තියෙනවා මගේ කකුල් පුපුරන්න. අම්මා කිව්වෙ ම නටන්න එපා කියලා. අම්මා කිව්වේ ගෑණු ළමයින්ට නැටුම් සුදුසු දෙයක් නෙවෙයි කියලා. අක්කලාත් විරුද්ධ වුණා. ඉස්කෝලෙ නැටුවා ම අක්කලා ගෙදර ඇවිත් අම්මාට කේලම් කිව්වා. අම්මා ඉතින් ඒවා අහලා මට කකුල් පුපුරන්න ගහනවා,\\" ඇය පවසා තිබිණි.කෙසේ වෙතත්, ඇය සිය සිහිනය වූ නර්තන ශිල්පිනියක වීමේ අරමුණ අත්හැරියේ නැත.වැඩිදුර අධ්‍යාපනයපාසල් අධ්‍යාපනය නිම කිරීමෙන් පසු රැජිණි, කොළඹ සෞන්දර්ය විද්‍යා පීඨයට ඇතුළු වී එවකට පැවති නර්තන ඩිප්ලෝමාව නිම කළා ය. ඒ, වසර 5ක අධ්‍යයන කටයුතුවලින් පසුව ය.ඊට අමතරව, ඇය භරත නාට්‍යම් විෂය සම්බන්ධයෙන් ද ඩිප්ලෝමාවක් ලබා ගත්තා ය.ඇයට තමන් ආශාවෙන් උගත් ශිල්පය දරුවන්ට ඉගැන්වීමට අවශ්‍ය වූයේ, ඉන් පසුව ය.ඒ අනුව ඇය 1975 වසරේ පෙබරවාරි මස 5 වන දා 'චාමර කලායතනය' නමින් නර්තන කලායතනයක් ආරම්භ කළා ය.එම වකවානුවේදී ඇයට නර්තන ගුරුවරියක ලෙස රජයේ ගුරු පත්වීමක් ද ලැබිණි.නර්තන ගුරුවරියක ලෙස මුල්ම පත්වීම ලබා ඇය සේවය කළේ, හලාවත මාදම්පේ සේනානායක ජාතික පාසලේ ය.ඇය පාසල් නර්තන ගුරුවරියක ලෙස වසර 18ක් සේවයේ නිරත විය.පාසල් ගුරුවරියක ලෙස සහ සිය කලායතනය හරහා ඇය දරුවන් ලක්ෂයකට වැඩි පිරිසකට නර්තනය උගන්වා ඇතැයි ඇය පවසයි.ඇයගේ සැමියා වූයේ, හරීන්ද්‍ර රොද්‍රිගු නමැත්තෙකි. විවාහයෙන් ඇයට දරුවන් නොසිටිය ද ඇය ඒ සම්බන්ධයෙන් කම්පාවට පත්වූයේ නැත.ඇය වරක් මෙසේ කීවා ය.\\"මට අම්මා කෙනෙක් වෙන්න බැරි වුණාට දෙවියන් වහන්සේ මට දරුවෝ ගොඩක් දීලා තියෙනවා. මම උගන්වපු හැම දරුවෙක් ම මට මගේ ම දරුවෙක් කියලායි හිතෙන්නේ. දෙවියන් වහන්සේ මට දරුවන් දුන්නා නම් සමහර විට මට මේ වගේ විශාල දරුවන් පිරිසකට අම්මා වෙන්න බැරි වෙයි. ඒ නිසා මම ගොඩක් සතුටු වෙනවා මට ලැබුණු ජීවිතය ගැන.\\""},{"question":"Qual è la differenza tra PIL e PNL?","answer":"Il PIL calcola il prodotto interno lordo mentre il PNL il prodotto nazionale lordo. Entrambi calcolano la quantità di beni e servizi prodotti nell’arco di un anno solare, al lordo degli ammortamenti. Con il PIL si calcolano tutti i beni e servizi prodotti da fattori produttivi di ogni nazionalità sul terreno di un determinato paese; quindi tutti i beni e servizi prodotti da imprese anche straniere ma sul territorio nazionale. Il PNL invece calcola tutti i beni e servizi prodotti da imprese di un’unica nazione in qualsiasi parte del mondo. Per determinare se in un paese è più grande il PIL o il PNL bisogna analizzare il sistema economico di quel paese, quindi se ha maggiormente imprese straniere sul suolo nazionale oppure maggiormente imprese nazionali in terra straniera. In Italia per esempio è più grande il PIL."},{"question":"Qual famosa banda americana era chamada originalmente de “Kara’s Flowers”?","answer":"Maroon 5"},{"question":"तुर्कांनी कॉन्स्टॅन्टिनोपल केव्हा जिंकून घेतले ?","answer":"तुर्कांनी कॉन्स्टॅन्टिनोपल इ.स. 1453 मध्ये जिंकून घेतले."},{"question":"以下の段落に関連する内容を記入しなさい： 日本のいろいろな所で起こった強盗事件について、警察は、フィリピンにいた日本人4人が中心になって事件を起こしたと考えています。9日、フィリピンの入国管理局の施設から、2人が日本に戻されました。7日にはほかの2人も戻されていて、4人全員が日本に戻されました。","answer":"警察は、4人が別の詐欺事件に関係している疑いで逮捕しました。この詐欺事件では60億円以上の被害が出ていて、警察は4人を詳しく調べます。強盗事件についても、4人がフィリピンから、日本にいるグループに強盗の命令を出していたと考えて、調べることにしています。"},{"question":"问题：YC的投资策略是什么？","answer":"答案：YC的投资策略主要是在初创公司的早期阶段提供种子资金和指导。"},{"question":"సౌరకుటుంబంలో గ్రహాల క్రమం ఏమిటి?","answer":"సౌరకుటుంబంలో గ్రహాల క్రమం సూర్యుని నుండి దూరం ప్రకారం ఇలా ఉంది: మొదటగా బుధుడు, తరువాత శుక్రుడు, ఆ తరువాత భూమి, తరువాత అంగారకుడు, ఆ తరువాత బృహస్పతి, ఆ తరువాత శని, తరువాత యురేనస్, మరియు చివరగా నెప్చ్యూన్. ఈ గ్రహాలు వాటి గురుత్వ బలం, ఆకారం, మరియు వాతావరణ లక్షణాలలో భిన్నంగా ఉన్నాయి."},{"question":"Amayi ku Malawi","answer":"Mkhalidwe wa amayi padziko lonse lapansi, kuphatikizirapo dziko la Malawi, umayesedwa pogwiritsa ntchito zilolezo zosiyanasiyana zomwe zimafotokoza za chikhalidwe, chuma, ndi ndale. Kuyang'ana kwambiri za nthawi yapakati pa 2010 ndi masiku ano, momwe amayi m'Malawi muno adzaunikiridwa pogwiritsa ntchito ziwerengero zosiyanasiyana.Mkhalidwe wa amayi m'Malawi muno umawerengedwera bwino kudzera m'mabuku monga mwayi wa amayi kusukulu, chiwerengero cha imfa za amayi oyembekezera, ndi zaka zoyembekezeka za moyo wa amayi kuyambira kubadwa. Zizindikirozi zimapereka chidziwitso chambiri chaufulu wa amayi ndi moyo m'Malawi. Kupeza mwayi kwa amayi kupita kusukulu ku Malawi ngati chilolezo chikuwonetsa momwe m'boma, chiŵerengero cha ophunzira achimuna ndi aakazi m'magulu azaka zambiri komanso kwa ophunzira onse kutengera jenda zikuwonetsa mwayi wamaphunziro wa amayi kusukulu ukukulirakulira ndi mwayi wa amuna. Ophunzira achikazi ku Malawi, komabe, akuwona kuchepa kwanthawi zonse pamene zaka zikuchulukirachulukira, zomwe zikusonyeza kulephera kwa maphunziro okakamiza kwa ophunzira achikazi ku Malawi. Zaka khumi zapitazi zakhala zikukula kwambiri kwa amayi kuyambira kubadwa m’Malawi muno pamene zaka zoyembekezeka za moyo wa amayi m’chaka cha 2010 zinali pafupifupi zaka 58 pamene kafukufuku waposachedwapa wa 2017 wasonyeza kuti moyo wa amayi m’Malawi wakula kufika pa zaka 66. Chiwopsezo cha kufa kwa amayi oyembekezera m'Malawi muno ndichotsika kwambiri poyerekeza ndi mayiko omwe ali m'malo omwe ali pachitukuko.Mkhalidwe wa chuma cha amayi m’Malawi muno ukuwunikiridwa pogwiritsa ntchito zilolezo monga ufulu wa cholowa cha amayi, kusowa ntchito, kutengapo gawo kwa akazi, komanso kukula kwa kusiyana kwa malipiro komwe kulipo pakati pa abambo ndi amai pa chuma cha Malawi. Mlozera waufulu wa cholowa umayesa kuthekera kwa amayi kukhala ndi katundu ndi kusamalira bwino katunduyo poyerekeza ndi anzawo achimuna. Ufulu wa cholowa m'Malawi muno ukupezeka kuti ndi wofanana pakubalalika kwawo pakati pa ana aamuna ndi aakazi ndi amuna ndi akazi omwe atsala. Mosiyana ndi kufanana komwe kumapezeka pa ufulu wa cholowa m'Malawi, kutenga nawo mbali kwa ogwira ntchito ndi kusowa kwa ntchito kumawonetsa zovuta zomwe akazi amakumana nazo m'bomalo. Zomwe zikuchitika panopo za akazi omwe akutenga nawo gawo pantchito yogwira ntchito zimafotokoza momwe kuchuluka kwa amuna kumagwirira ntchito pakadali pano ngakhale kuti azimayi ali ndi anthu ambiri olembedwa ntchito komanso ulova wofanana kwambiri. Kusiyanaku kukupitirirabe ndi malipiro a Malawi pamene boma likupitirirabe kufika pamunsi pamndandandawu poyerekeza ndi mayiko padziko lonse lapansi. Pogwirizana ndi kusachita bwino kwawo m'mayiko osiyanasiyana, boma silinachite bwino poyerekezera ndi mayiko ena a kum'mwera kwa chipululu cha Sahara pomwe dziko la Rwanda lomwe lili pamwamba pa chigawo cha kum'mwera kwa chipululu cha Sahara, linapeza 0.791 pa sikelo ya 0-1 pomwe Malawi yapeza 0.664.Zizindikiro zomwe zimagwiritsidwa ntchito poyesa momwe amayi alili pa ndale ndi monga kutenga nawo mbali pa ndale pakati pa amayi, mwayi wopita ku ndale, ndi mipando ya amayi mu nyumba yamalamulo ya dziko. Kutenga nawo mbali pa ndale kwa amayi m'Malawi monga chilolezo chafotokozedwa bwino m'magwero ambirimbiri; Magwerowa afika pamalingaliro ofananawo pankhani yotenga nawo mbali pazandale za amayi. Kutenga nawo mbali kwa amayi mu ndale za dziko kwawoneka kukhala kofooka kusiyana ndi amuna awo chifukwa cha kukhazikika kwa malingaliro oipa omwe amayi sayembekezera kuti azichita ndale monga amuna. Kutenga nawo mbali pa ndale kwa amayi kumaletsedwanso ku mabungwe a ndale a dziko chifukwa cha kupezeka kwa alonda a pakhomo omwe amapereka mwayi wopeza zofunikira kuti apambane zisankho ndi kusunga mipando yanyumba yamalamulo. Kutengapo mbali kochepaku kumakhudzana mwachindunji ndi malo ochepa omwe amayi amakhala nawo pakukhazikitsa dziko. Kukhazikitsa kumeneku, ngakhale kudzipereka kwawo kuti akhale paudindo wofanana pakati pa abambo ndi amai, kwalephera kulimbikitsa njira za ndale zachikazi kuti asunge mipando yawo ku Nyumba ya Malamulo ndipo chifukwa cha ndondomeko zomwe zanenedwazo, amayi m’Malawi muno atsala opanda dongosolo ndi zipangizo zoyendetsera udindo wawo. mu dongosolo la dziko. Ngakhale kuti andale achikaziwa ali ndi chuma chochepa, nyumba yamalamulo ya dziko la Malawi yapeza bwino posankha aphungu achikazi kuti akhale pamipando ya bungweli popeza 20% ya mipando yanyumba yamalamulo imakhala ya amayi. Ngakhale kuti andale achikazi ali ndi mwayi wochepa komanso chuma chomwe chilipo kwa andale achikazi m’Malawi muno, boma likupeza chipambano pokweza ndale zachikazi pa dziko lonse lapansi zomwe zimagwira ntchito mogwirizana ndi ndondomeko yabwino ya chikhalidwe ndi zachuma kuti dziko la Malawi liyembekezere kukula kwachuma. za kufanana pakati pa amuna ndi akazi."},{"question":"If n(A) = 37, n(B) = x, n(A ∪ B) = 52, n(A ∩ B) = 8, then x =A) 23B) 15C) 29D) 44","answer":"A) 23"},{"question":"కొన్ని దత్తాంశములలోని అంత్య విలువలు క్రింది దేనిపై ఎక్కువ ప్రభావము చూపును ?A) అంకమధ్యమముB) మధ్యగతం లోC) బాహుళకముD) వ్యాప్తి","answer":"A) అంకమధ్యమము"},{"question":"ਉਸ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਪਤੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅਣ-ਵਿਆਹੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ?(a) ਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ(b) ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ(c) ਵਿਸਤ੍ਰਿਤ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ(d) ਨਵਸਥਾਨੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ।","answer":"(a) ਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ।"},{"question":"Qual a capital do Canadá?","answer":"A capital do Canadá é Ottawa."},{"question":" செடல்  நூலின் ஆசிரியர்  யார்?   ","answer":"           விடை:இமையம்"},{"question":"Ndeipi emoji inomiririra nzvimbo isina chinhu kana isina chinhu?","answer":" ⬜"},{"question":" Sheeg Magaca Qaaradda Aan Laheyn Dhul Lama Degaan Ah","answer":" Waa Qaaradda Yurub."},{"question":"Berikan resipi untuk peria goreng telur dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 1 biji peria saiz sederhana, 4 ulas bawang putih, 2 biji bawang merah, 2 sudu besar udang kering atau ikan bilis, 1 biji telur ayam, 1 biji cili merah, 1 sudu besar sos tiram, garam dan gula secukup rasa, 2 sudu besar minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Potong dua buah peria, buang biji dan isi dalaman, potong nipis secara menyerong, dan rendam dalam air garam selama 15 minit untuk mengurangkan pahitnya. Kemudian tuskan dan bilas.2. Tumbuk bawang putih, bawang merah dan udang kering atau ikan bilis.3. Potong cili merah secara menyerong.Cara memasak:1. Panaskan minyak dalam kuali, kemudian tumiskan bawang putih, bawang merah dan udang kering sehingga kekuningan.2. Masukkan peria dan cili merah. Kacau sekejap untuk sebatikan dengan tumisan.3. Masukkan sos tiram dan perasakan dengan garam dan gula. Kacau sehingga peria sedikit layu.4. Masukkan telur yang telah dipukul dan kacau sehingga telur mengeras dan peria masak.5. Matikan api dan angkat segera.6. Hidangkan panas-panas"},{"question":"من هو صقر يوم أحد ؟","answer":"طلحة بن عبيد الله"},{"question":"NumPy අරා දෙකක් element-wise එකතු කරන්න. ","answer":"import numpy as nparray1 = np.array([1, 2, 3])array2 = np.array([4, 5, 6])sum_array = array1 + array2"},{"question":"तारतारतरैरेतैरुत्तरोत्तरतो रुतैः |रतार्ता तित्तिरी रौति तीरे तीरे तरौ तरौ ||","answer":"अर्थ : कामविव्हल झालेली टिटवी ह्या अशा अधिकाधिक वाढत जाणाऱ्या कर्कश आवाजात सगळ्या काठावर प्रत्येक झाडावर ओरडत आहे.चित्रकाव्यामध्ये हा द्वयक्षर श्लोक रसपूर्ण आणि अर्थाची ओढाताण न करता सुंदर रचना केली आहे."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්තමානයේ පවතින වනගහනය කීයද ?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ වර්තමානයේ පවතින වනගහනය  29% කි."},{"question":"රන්වන් පැහැයෙන් බබලන සිරුර නිසා \\" කංචන මානව \\" ලෙස , ගිහි ජීවිතයේදී හැඳින්වූ මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ කවුද ?","answer":"මහා කච්චායන මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ"},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kas buvo pirmasis Rusijos caras?","answer":"Atsakymas: Pirmasis Rusijos caras buvo Ivanas IV, žinomas kaip Ivanas Siaubūnas. Jis pradėjo valdyti 1547 m. ir buvo pirmasis Rusijos monarchas, kuris priėmė caro titulą."},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع سنغافورة؟","answer":"تقع سنغافورة في قارة آسيا."},{"question":" काष्ठमण्डप बनाउँदा प्रयोग गरिएको कल्पबृक्षको नाम के हो ?","answer":"सुरतरु"},{"question":"C++ හි \\"නාම-අවකාශයන්\\"(namespaces) භාවිතා  කිරීම නිරූපණයට  කේතයක් ලියන්න.","answer":"#include <iostream>using namespace std;namespace first {    void func() {        cout << \\"Inside first namespace\\" << endl;    }}namespace second {    void func() {        cout << \\"Inside second namespace\\" << endl;    }}int main() {    first::func();    second::func();    return 0;}"},{"question":"یادگیری چه سازی آسان است؟","answer":"بطور قطع نمی توان گفت که یادگیری چه سازی آسان تر از ساز های دیگر است !هر سازی در مقایسه با ساز دیگر دارای سختی ها و آسانی هایی نسبت به یکدیگر هستند. ولی یادگیری و جا افتادن تکنیک برخی از سازها در ذهن و دست نوازنده به مراتب ساده تر از سازهای دیگر است. بطور مثال تکنیک های ساز ویولن مقداری سخت تر از سازی مثل پیانو می باشد یا تعداد تکنیک های ساز دف کمتر از ساز تمبک می باشد.راحت ترین ساز برای یادگیری، می‌تواند برای افراد مختلف بنا بر شرایطی مانند سن، سبک موسیقی مورد علاقه، وضعیت جسمانی، بودجه، فضای خانه (محلی که در آن تمرین می‌کنید) و شرایط محیط زندگی و… متفاوت باشد.به عنوان مثال ساز هارمونیکا (ساز دهنی) یکی از سازهای موسیقی است که می‌توان راحت تر و زودتر از باقی سازها به آن مسلط شد. اما اگر شما فردی مبتلا به عارضه‌های تنفسی هستید، اصلا نباید به طرف سازهای بادی بروید چرا که این موضوع می‌تواند برای شما تبدیل به یک کابوس شود. در این شرایط نه تنها نمی‌توانید به آن ساز مسلط شوید بلکه احتمالا از همۀ سازهای موسیقی هم زده خواهید شد.یا اگر شما علاقه مند به یادگیری ساز درامز هستید اما فضایی در خانه (یا هرجای دیگری) برای قرار دادن ساز وجود ندارد، بنابراین شاید یادگیری این ساز را باید به زمان دیگری موکول کنید.اما فرض کنیم که شما از هیچ لحاظ محدودیتی برای تهیه، نگهداری و یادگیری ساز نخواهید داشت. در این صورت می‌توان چند ساز را نام برد که راحت ترین ساز برای یادگیری هستند.توجه داشته باشید که اگر سازی را، راحت ترین ساز برای یادگیری می‌نامیم به این معنی نخواهد بود که آن ساز از سایر سازها کم ارزش تر است یا از محبوبیت کمتری برخوردار است. بلکه تمرکز ما در این قسمت معضلات کمتر در روند یادگیری ساز است. همچنین بهتر است این مورد را همیشه در ذهن خود داشته باشیم که تبدیل شدن به نوازنده‌ای حرفه‌‌ای در هر ساز، نیازمند تلاش و پشتکاری مثال زدنیست.در بین سازهای خارجی ای که راحت تر از سایر سازها هستند به این ها می شود اشاره کرد:هارمونیکا(سازدهنی)،  کالیمبا، یوکوللی، کاخُن، ملودیکا و حتا پیانو!در بین سازهای ایرانی ای که راحت تر از سایر سازها هستند به این ها می شود اشاره کرد:تنبک، دف، سه تار، سنتور"},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:પર્યાવરણમાં જીવસૃષ્ટિ માટે હાનિકારક ફેરફાર","answer":"પ્રદૂષણ "},{"question":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 12","answer":"MOTHER'S CURSEChapter 12I'm pregnant for Izunna; he got me pregnant before leaving. She liedOkay, Izunna, how come? You told us you were no longer with her; how come she's now pregnant for you? His elder sister askedAdanne, I don't know what this imposter here is talking about; after she gave birth to Light, she never allowed me to touch her again. She knows who the father of the unborn child is. Izunna defendedThis pregnancy belongs to you, Izunna; I have never cheated on you,she said, crying.Crocodile tears,your plans will never work. Izunna's mum Anthonia screamed at herEven if that child is mine like you claimed, I can never take you back because you frustrated my life, and I'm filled. Izunna told herMama I know you hate me so much, but it's well, I'll go since you all decided to push me off,and you, Izunna, will regret ever knowing me.I'm done with my regrets; you're cursed; we ain't meant for each other; go and meet your martins.Cassandra's phone rang, and she frowned as she picked up the call.Please come back home; your grandmother wants to talk to you. Her mom saidWhat does she want to tell me? Please, nobody should disturb me because I'm trying to fix things with my husband. She replied and ended the call.Who's your husband, young lady? When you were starving me and your children, collecting money from men, and doing all sorts of nonsense, you didn't remember that I'm your husband, Cassy. What do you want from me?I want you back, please... She said this as everyone laughed.He is married, Cassandra, love... Maris smirked Ogbanje... Anthonia shouted and went in.Cassandra felt defeated. She turned her back and left the compound, crying loudly.Where's grandma? She asked as soon as she got home.My daughter came inside. Her grandma said from insideCassandra went in and sat beside her, sniffing.Please, I'm sorry for everything. I'm sorry for laying a curse on you. She coughed.Cassy stared at her mom, and their eyes met.What's she saying, mom? She askedCan't you just pay attention and listen? Her mom bellowedThe curse has destroyed your marriage. I'm really sorry, my grandchild; your mother is the cause of everything. She coughed again.                                    THROWBACKStop visiting that boy, Chinelo; he is not good for you. Leave Onaka alone."},{"question":"Bana şarkıcı ve şarkı sözü yazarı Barry White'ın en bilinen 10 şarkısını listeler misin?","answer":"Elbette. İşte Barry White'ın en bilinen 10 şarkısı:1. Just The Way You Are2. Never Gonna Give You Up3. Practice What You Preach4. Let The Play5. Come On6. Can't Get Enough Of Your Love Babe7. You're The One I Need8. Baby We Better Try To Get It Together9. Walkin' In The Rain With The One I Love10. You See The Trouble With Me"},{"question":"Ашкабактын пайдалуулугу тууралуу айтып бер.","answer":"Ашкабакты, тамакка кабыгы менен кошуу керек. Анткени, кабыгынын курамында сулулуулуктун булагы болгон, тери менен тырмакты жакшырта турган цинк бар. Ошондой эле, жүрөктүн коргоочусу, онкологиялык ооруулардын пайда болуу коркунучун азайтуучу каротин сыяктуу пайдалуу элементтерге бай."},{"question":"لدينا الجملتان 'متعة للكبار والاطفال .' و 'متعة للاطفال فقط .'. هل تدل الجملتان على نفس المعنى؟","answer":"لا, الجملتان مختلفتان لان الاولى تضم متعه الفئتين فئه الكبار وفئه الاطفال بينما الجمله الثانيه فهي تتكلم فقط عن متعه الاطفال فقط"},{"question":"اكتب كمالة للفقرة دي: ولد في فريدريكتون، نيو برونزويك وترعرع في تورونتو، وينيبيج وساسكاتون، ساسكاتشوان. خدم في الخارج مع فوج ساسكاتشوان الجنوبي خلال الحرب العالمية الثانية وجرح في دييب","answer":". بعد الحرب، واصل كوهالي دراسته في جامعة ساسكاتشوان، وحصل على درجة في القانون في عام 1950. هو عمل في استيفان. انتخب كوهالي في مجلس المحافظات في انتخابات 1953 بعد وفاة جون إدوارد ماكورماك. بعد هزيمته عندما ترشح لإعادة انتخابه في عام 1956، عاد إلى ممارسة القانون. شغل كوهالي منصب رئيس فرع ساسكاتشوان وكذلك منصب رئيس وطني للجيش الملكي الكندي."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Tailândia?","answer":"Banguecoque."},{"question":"من هو أول أئمة الإسلام الأربع؟\\t","answer":"\\tالإمام أبو حنيفة رحمه الله."},{"question":"Inona ireo tara-kevitra nampiavaka ny vanim-potoana ankehitriny?","answer":"Ireto avy ireo tara-kevitra nampiavaka ny vanim-potoana ankehitriny:\\t-fampitahana ny rafi-pitondrana\\t-fampisehoana ireo zava-misy iainana izay niteraka ny fahadisoam-panantenana,\\t-fahantrana ara-batana sy ara-tsaina,\\t-fahasarotan’ny fiainana sy fitadiavana asa,\\t-tsy fahamarinana amin’ny lafiny maro,\\t-fitaomana ny olona mba hitolona hanova rafitra, ny TTF (Tanindrazana Tolom-piavotana Fahafahana),\\t-fiantsoana ny olona hiverina ho eny ambanivohitra,\\t-fanoherana ny fanavakavaham-bolonkoditra-Fampisehoana ireo zava-misy iainana izay niteraka ny fahadisoam-panantenana,\\t-fahantrana ara-batana sy ara-tsaina,\\t-fahasarotan’ny fiainana sy fitadiavana asa,\\t-tsy fahamarinana amin’ny lafiny maro,\\t-fitaomana ny olona mba hitolona hanova rafitra, ny TTF (Tanindrazana-Tolom-piavotana-Fahafahana),\\t-fiantsoana ny olona hiverina ho eny ambanivohitra,\\t-fanoherana ny fanavakavaham-bolon-koditra."},{"question":"မြန်မာနိုင်ငံရဲ့ စီးပွားရေးအရ အရေးပါဆုံးမြို့က ဘယ်မြို့လဲ","answer":"မြန်မာနိုင်ငံ၏အကြီးဆုံးမြို့တော်ဖြစ်သောရန်ကုန်မြို့သည်စီးပွါးရေးအရအရေးပါဆုံးမြို့ဖြစ်သည်။ "},{"question":"Xikmad","answer":"“Waayaha nololeed waxay I bareen in abeesadu ay hoos jiifsato ubaxyada soo jiidashada leh, muuqaalka guudna Uu yahay marin habaabiye.”! DOSTOEVSKY."},{"question":"Ano ang dapat kong gawin kapag nakakita ako ng galit na aso sa daan?","answer":"Ito ang iyong dapat gawin para manatili kang ligtas kapag may asong galit sa daan:1. Manatiling nakatayo at maging kalmado para kumalma rin ang aso.2. Kung ang aso ay hindi aatras at ito ay nagsimulang umatake, magkulubot na parang bola sa lupa.3. Huwag makipag-eye contact sa hayop.4. Huwag ipakita ang iyong mga ngipin. 5. Kung sakaling kagat ka ng aso, huwag subukang tumakas o kumalas."},{"question":"වනයේ රජු ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ කුමන සත්වයාද?","answer":"සිංහයා හඳුන්වන්නේ කැලේ රජු ලෙසයි."},{"question":"\\"Азыркы учурда “аялдардын эркек сымал, эркектердин аял сымал жүрүшү” үй-бүлөлөрдө берекенин кетүүсүн  ....\\"-окуяны кандай улантсак болот ? ( 2-4 сүйлөм болушу мүмкүн )","answer":"Окуянын мындайча өнүгүшү мүмкүн :\\"Азыркы учурда “аялдардын эркек сымал,эркектердин аял сымал жүрүшү” үй-бүлөлөрдө берекенин кетүүсүнө жана бузулуусуна себеп болгон эң маанилүү маселе катары каралып келет.Алла Таала аялзатын өзүнчө, эркекти да өзүнчө өзгөчөлүктөрү менен жараткан. Ал өзгөчөлүктөрү аялдын да эркектин да коомдогу ордуна ылайык жаратылган. Дене түзүлүшүнөн тартып ички дүйнөсүнө чейин бардык өзгөчөлүктөрүаларга жүктөлгөн жоопкерчиликтерге жараша ыйгарылган. \\""},{"question":"一个卡车司机撞倒一个骑摩托车的人,卡车司机受重伤,摩托车骑士却没事,为什么","answer":"答案：卡车司机在走路"},{"question":"Apakah jenis karangan dalam UPSR di Malaysia?","answer":"Terdapat dua jenis karangan dalam UPSR di Malaysia, iaitu karangan berformat dan karangan tidak berformat.1. Karangan berformat seperti surat kiriman rasmi, surat kiriman tidak rasmi, laporan, ucapan, syarahan, ceramah, catatan, berita dan dialog.2. Karangan tidak berformat sperti fakta, keperihalan, autobiografi, biografi, peribahasa, perbincangan, cerita (Reka), menyudahkan cerita, menulis permulaan atau isi cerita"},{"question":"Sheeg hal ka mid ah dhaqanka soomaalida?","answer":"Soomaalida dhaqankeeda waxa ka mid ah waa dad Reer-guura ah."},{"question":"Apakah maksud cacing hendak menjadi naga?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah orang kecil mahu menjadi orang yang hebat."},{"question":"Iza avy ireo dimy  mana- karena indrindra ao @ nosy Maurice?","answer":"Raymond Ah-chuen, fianakavian'ny Bashir Currimjee, Arnaud Dalais, Nundun Gopee ary Michel de Spéville."},{"question":"Victor Ndoma-Egba","answer":"Victor Ndoma-Egba (bíi ní ọjọ́ kẹjọ oṣù kẹta ọdún 1956) jẹ́ olóṣèlú ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà tí wọ́n dìbò yàn wọlé gẹ́gẹ́ bí aṣojú ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin àgbà ti ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà láti ọdún 2003.Wọ́n bí Victor Ndoma-Egba ní ọjọ́ kẹjọ oṣù kẹta ọdún 1956 ní ilù Ikom, Ìpínlẹ̀ Cross River. Ó gba ìwé ẹ̀rí àkọ́kọ́ nínú ìmọ̀ òfin láti University of Lagos. Wọ́n pèé sí àwùjọ amòfin gẹ́gẹ́ bí agbẹjọ́rò ní ọdún 1978 tí ó si di Senior Advocate of Nigeria (SAN) ní ọdún 2004. Ó ti fi ìgbàkan jẹ́ alága Nigerian Bar Association ti ẹ̀ka Calabar."},{"question":"එංගලන්තයට එරෙහිව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවට කඩුලු 08ක විශිෂ්ට ජයක්","answer":"ලෝක කුසලාන එක්දින ක්‍රිකට් තරගාවලියේ එංගලන්තය සමග පැවති තරගයෙන් කඩුලු 08ක ජයක් ලැබීමට ශ්‍රී ලංකාව අද (ඔක් 26 වෙනිදා) සමත් විය.තරගය පැවැත්වුනේ බැංගලෝර් එම්. චීන්නස්වාමි ක්‍රිඩාංගණයේදීයි.කාසියේ වාසිය දිනු එංගලන්ත නායක ජොස් බට්ලර් පළමුවෙන් පන්දුවට පහර දීමට තීරණය කරන ලදී. අද එංගලන්ත තරගය සඳහා ශ්‍රී ලංකා කණ්ඩායමේ වෙනස්කම් දෙකක් සිදුකර තිබීම විශේෂත්වයක් විය.ඒ අනුව ඉකුත් දා නෙදර්ලන්ත කණ්ඩායම සමග පැවැති තරගයට ක්‍රීඩා කළ චාමික කරුණාරත්න සහ දුෂාන් හේමන්ත වෙනුවට ඇන්ජලෝ මැතිව්ස් සහ ලහිරු කුමාර කණ්ඩායමට කැඳවා තිබුණි."},{"question":"问题：三星的旗舰产品是什么？","answer":"答案：三星的旗舰产品包括Galaxy S系列智能手机、Galaxy Note系列和QLED电视等。"},{"question":"'Ngithe ngiseMkhobeni izolo kusihlwa, imoto yakhunyukelwa ngushafu, yagijima phansinge-enkapleti. Cishe yangibulala. Ngenhlanhla enkulu ngikwazile ukuyibamba, yama.Ngihlale lapho-ke kwaze kwasa ngikhanda.' Kwavele kwala kuMaNzimande ukubaaqhubeke nokulalela leyo mbude.'Bewuyaphi eMkhobeni yise kaMpisendlini?''EMkhobeni phela kusendleleni ebheke eMzimkhulu. Bengihambisa uDumazile kubonjengesicelo sakho. Ngiyethemba ukuthi usakhumbula ukuthi wathi angimphindiselelapho ngamthatha khona. Ingozi-ke ingehlele ngisohambweni olunjalo.''Pho bewukhanda kanjani ukilini kanjena?' Aphinde asikhihle futhi isililo uMaNzimande.USithole wezwa ecikeka nje ukutetenyelwa ngumuntu omdala kangaka, futhi olokhuembuza ipasi nesipesheli. Wadumisa imoto, watshela umkakhe ukuthi sebeyobonanantambama, wakhala wemuka.UMaNzimande wasala nentshidi wasala nesidanga sevondwe. Wazibuza, ezifunangaphakathi:'Nkosi yami, lesi sichitho esingaka sivela kuphi phakathi komuzi wami? USitholeubengenje! Selokhu ngakhuluma noLizy angibange ngisakuthola ukuthula phakathikomuzi wami. Ukuba uLizy akangifikelanga nezindaba, ngabe ngisahlezi kahlenomyeni wami. Mh ..., ngaze ngazibhidlizela umendo wami! Kuzofanela ngifundemanje ukuba ngingaqophisani noyise kaMpisendlini. Kuzothi uma ebuya ntambama,angifice sengiwumama omuhle wekhaya onesizotha. Ngeke ngisamqulisa amacalaumyeni wami. Ngizomphekela ukudla okuhle, akuthandayo ngimenzele netiye, aphuze.Ehhe, kusukela namhlanjena ngizomphatha kahle umyeni wami.'USithole wafika esitolo abantu sebazi ukuthi ubekade engalalanga ekhaya ngayizolo.1. Chaza kafushane ukuthi lesi siqeshana siyigqamisa kanjani indikimbayesimilo esingesihle kule noveli.","answer":"Indikimba yale noveli/isimilo esingesihle/esixegayo. USithole ushiyauMaNzimande akamtsheli ukuthi uyaphi, ugcina eselale kwaDumazile.Utshela uMaNzimande ukuthi ubehambise uDumazile, uma uMaNzimandeeqhubeka nemibuzo unquma ukumshiya uMaNzimande ebe eyinkosikaziyakhe uyohlala noDumazile yize bengashadile."},{"question":"Doorashadii dhacday qiyaamana ma dhicin","answer":"\\"Doorashadii dhacday, qiyaamana ma dhicin\\" Juxaa.Hal-ku-dheg macno badan xambaarsan ...Madaxda Dawladda Federal-ka waxay geed dheer iyo mid gaabanba u fuuleen sidii ay u fashilin lahaayeen, ama u curyaamin lahaayeen doorashada Q&C ee Puntland. Waxay qeyb ahaan ku guuleysteen in ay hakiyaan doorashada 3 degmo, halka 30 degmo ay si nabad ah uga dhacday .. 91% success rate.Su'aashu waxay tahay waa maxa dareenka taban ee madaxda Dawladda Federal-ka ah ay ka qabaan horumarka siyaasadeed ee Puntland? Waa la fahmi karaa isqabadka Puntland iyo Federal-ka ee awood qeybsiga, xiriirka dibedda iyo dastuurka qabyada ah. Waxaanse la fahmi karin in ay si aan qarsoodi ahayn uga soo horjeedo hor u kaca bulsho iyo deegaan \\"State\\" ka tirsan Dawladda ay madaxda ka yihiin.  Sida muuqata ilaa iminka ma bogaadin qabsoomidda doorashooyinka!Malaha in shacabka Puntland si cod dheer sidii hore u wajahaan siyaasadda Dawladda Dhexe ee Federal-ka ay u baahan yihiin."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kuih bangkit yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 3 cawan rata tepung ubi kayu, ½ cawan tepung gandum, 1 cawan atau lebih pati santan dari sebiji kelapa (jangan campur air) / santan kotak, 1 cawan rata gula aising (untuk manis sederhana), atau gula halus / gula kisar (manis biasa), 2 biji kuning telur gred B, Sehelai daun pandan (disiat & disimpul)Cara-cara:1. Campur kedua-dua jenis tepung bersama daun pandan.2. Goreng tanpa minyak (sangrai) dalam kuali hingga ringan. Kemudian, ayak dan sejukkan.3. Masukkan gula ke dalam mangkuk. Campurkan telur dan dikacau hingga sebati & kembang.4. Masukkan tepung, santan sedikit demi sedikit sambil diuli hingga menjadi doh sehingga tidak melekat ditangan.5. Ambil seketul doh, gelek dengan penggelek dan tekap menggunakan acuan mengikut bentuk kesukaan anda.6. Panaskan oven.7. Bakar dalam oven menggunakan suhu 160°C selama 30 minit atau hingga masak. Ikut kepanasan oven masing-masing..8. Sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"सकारात्मक सोचले भविष्यमा अझ आशावादी दृष्टिकोणमा कसरी योगदान गर्छ?","answer":"सकारात्मक सोचले आशा र आत्मविश्वास जगाएर भविष्यमा थप आशावादी दृष्टिकोणलाई आकार दिन्छ। सकारात्मक सोच भएका व्यक्तिहरूले सकारात्मक नतिजाको सम्भावना र सम्भाव्यताहरू हेरेर उत्साहका साथ अज्ञातमा पुग्ने सम्भावना बढी हुन्छ।"},{"question":"Wanene Sarkin Kano na fulani na 15?","answer":"Mai martaba Aminu Ado Bayero."},{"question":"Kanti nanihlobene kanjani noSipho?Kwakungumngani wami omkhulu. Mhlawumbe sasiyogcina sithandananje. Uyena owayekwazi ukungiduduza uma ngikhumbule umfowenu.Ngaphatheka kabuhlungu kabi mina ngizwa kuthiwa useshonile.Ngifisa ukuyobeka imbali eyodwa vo ethuneni lakhe. Ngifunanokuvalelisa ngoba washona ngithi ngisazombona.Ngizwa kuthiwa wakubhalela incwadi engakashoni.Edabukisa kakhulu. Sengathi wayebona ukuthi usezofa.Akashongo lutho ngami?1. Chaza lesi simo sokukhuluma esibhalwe ngokugqamile njengobasisetshenzisiwe esiqeshini esingenhla: Nalokho kwafaka isandla kakhulu. ","answer":"Okukodwa kwalokhu: Kwaba nomthelela/kwelekelela/kwasiza/yikhonaokwenza ngishitshe isinqumo sami. "},{"question":"Tôi có thói quen không gọt vỏ một số loại trái cây và rau củ để đỡ mất dưỡng chất, điều này có nên hay không?","answer":"Vỏ trái cây hoặc rau củ thường bị loại bỏ do sở thích hoặc thói quen, nhằm giảm tiếp xúc với thuốc trừ sâu. Tuy nhiên, gọt vỏ đồng nghĩa với việc loại bỏ một trong những bộ phận giàu chất dinh dưỡng nhất.Ví dụ, một quả táo nguyên vỏ chứa nhiều vitamin K hơn tới 332%, 142% vitamin A, 115% vitamin C, 20% canxi và 19% kali so với quả táo gọt vỏ.Tương tự, một củ khoai tây luộc cả vỏ có thể chứa nhiều vitamin C hơn tới 175%, 115% kali, 111% folate, 110% magie và phốt pho so với loại đã gọt vỏ. Hơn nữa, mức độ chống oxy hóa trong vỏ trái cây có thể cao hơn 328 lần so với trong thịt quả, giúp ngăn ngừa một số bệnh.Tuy nhiên, một số loại vỏ trái cây hoặc rau quả khó tiêu thụ hoặc không ăn được. Ví dụ, vỏ quả bơ được coi là không ăn được, bất kể chúng được nấu chín hay sống. Vỏ dứa, dưa, hành tây và cần tây, có thể có kết cấu dai, khó nhai và tiêu hóa. Trái cây họ cam quýt cũng có vỏ dai và đắng nên khó ăn sống.Rửa là một cách tốt để loại bỏ dư lượng thuốc trừ sâu trên bề mặt vỏ. Gọt vỏ là cách tốt nhất để loại bỏ thuốc trừ sâu đã thấm vào vỏ trái cây và rau quả."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai diikat dengan sehasta tali\\"?","answer":"Tidak dapat berbuat sekehendak hati"},{"question":"Everyone is so quick","answer":"Everyone is so quick to demand their needs from God, but have you ever considered what His needs are? Have you ever once yielded yourself to what God wants, even when it is easy? Have you ever gone out of your comfort zone to please God, who owns the breath within you?Many approach His presence only because they have received help from Him or seek help from Him. Why can’t you keep your burdens and desires out of the way and focus alone on God?I beseech you all to take this step as of today; just ask Him what He wants and see to it that it is accomplished. Remember, He can do what He wants at anytime; however, when His creation, those created in His image and after His likeness, go ahead to make their vessels available for His use, He doesn’t just use them and abandon them; he ensures all their needs are met even without them asking.I don’t know those in such positions who have left it all, just like the disciples who left it all and followed Jesus. He is ready to attend to those needs. No man can come to your aid.For as many who are ready to take this step today, just declare unto Him that I am ready to surrender all, am ready to forsake my sinful lifestyle, and am ready to let go of my selfish attitude, which entails just me alone. Say to God, I am ready to do your will and yours alone. "},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదాలకి సమాసాలు తెలుపండి:1. శిథిలవస్త్రంబు2. చక్రపాణి3. గరుగృహం4. దయాపయోనిధి5. దయార్ద్ర దృష్టి","answer":"1. శిథిలవస్త్రంబు : శిధిలమైన వస్త్రము – విశేష పూర్వపద కర్మధారయ సమాసము2. చక్రపాణి : చక్రము పాణియందుకలవాడు – బహువ్రీహి కర్మధారయ సమాసము3. గరుగృహం : గురువుయొక్క గృహం – షష్ఠీతత్పురుష సమాసము4. దయాపయోనిధి : దయా పయోధి – షష్ఠీ తత్పురుష సమాసము5. దయార్ద్ర దృష్టి : దయార్ద్రమైన దృష్టి – విశేష పూర్వపద కర్మధారయ సమాసము"},{"question":"Ọṣun Oṣogbo: Ẹ jokoo sibi ti ẹ ba wa ki ẹ maa wo ayẹyẹ naa","answer":"Kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ aṣa atibudo iṣẹmbaye nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Dokita Ọbawale Adebisi, ti parọwa si gbogbo awọn ti wọn maa n wa sipinlẹ Ọṣun lọdọọdun fun aṣekagba ayẹyẹ ọdun Ọṣun-Oṣogbo lati jọwọ, jokoo sibi ti wọn ba wa, ki wọn si maa wo gbogbo bi eto ba ṣe n lọ lori ẹrọ ayelujara.Nigba to n ba ALAROYE sọrọ lori imurasilẹ wọn fun aṣekagba ayẹyẹ naa ti yoo waye lọla lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii, Ọbawale ṣalaye pe ijọba ko fẹ ki ajakalẹ arun Korona to ṣẹṣẹ de, iyẹn Delta Variant, wọle nipasẹ awọn olubọ Ọṣun.Nitori idi eyi nijọba ṣe gba ileeṣẹ kan ti yoo maa ṣafihan gbogbo bi eto naa ba ṣe n lọ lori ẹrọ ayelujara, ti awọn eeyan yoo si lanfaani lati wo o nibikibi ti wọn ba wa kaakiri agbaye.Bakan naa ni Ọbawale tun rọ awọn ti wọn ba wa layiika lati mọ pe ẹmi ko laarọ, ki wọn tẹle gbogbo alakalẹ lati dena itankalẹ arun Koronafairọọsi lasiko aṣekagba ayẹyẹ naa.O ni ijọba ti ṣeto aabo to nipọn fun ẹmi ati dukia awọn olubọ Ọṣun, oniṣẹmbaye, alejo, awọn oniroyin ati awọn ti ọrọ kan nidii aṣa ati isẹmbaye.O ni ijọba ko ni i faaye gba ẹnikẹni lati fara pamọ sabẹ aṣekagba ayẹyẹ Ọṣun Oṣogbo lati da wahala silẹ tabi lati maa dunkooko mọ ẹmi awọn alejo.Ọbawale ni ki awọn obi ati alagbatọ kilọ fawọn ọmọ wọn lati ma ṣe gba ki ẹnikẹni lo wọn fun iwa-ipa tabi iwa janduku nitori ẹnikẹni ti ọwọ ba tẹ yoo fimu kata ofin.Bakan naa lo rọ awọn ẹlẹsin-jẹsin nipinlẹ Ọṣun lati ṣiṣẹ papọ ni iṣọkan, ki wọn faaye gba awọn ẹlẹsin yooku lati ṣe ẹsin wọn, ki alaafia si jọba lasiko aṣekagba ọdun naa."},{"question":"Sawubona makoti. Kade ngakugcina ngenxa yomsebenzi.(Athi ukukhophoza) Yebo baba omncane.Kodwa usahleli kahle lapha kithi?Ngihleli khona, kodwa nje usizi lusangiphethe.Zama ukukhohlwa mntanomuntu. Ngiyakuzwela kakhulu kabi, ikakhulungoba usemncane. Khohlwa impela makoti.Ngiyawabonga lawo mazwi akho. Okwenza ngingakhohlwa kalulaukuthi ngangimthanda kakhulu umfowenu. Okubi-ke ukuthi asibangesisahlala isikhathi eside njengokufisa kwethu.Angiqonde khona ukukuthunuka amanxeba makoti. Angifuni ukubauhlupheke lapha ekhaya. Umama nobaba sengathi bangahlalabekucabangela njalo. (Abuke izitsha) Lo msebenzi owenzayo njekufanele engabe wenziwa nguThabi uphi yena?(Abuke uDumisani)Wangibukisisa kukhona osafuna ukukusho?Cha ngicabanga indaba kamama nobaba.Ngike ngazama ukubacela ukuba bangidedele ngibuyele ekhaya.Benqabile bangitshela ezamadlozi namasiko.(Athi ukuthula) Yini edala ufune ukubuyela ekhaya?Ukuthi ukuhlala lapha ekhaya kungicabangisa umkhwenyana waminjalo. Ngenye indlela ngizama ukukhohlwa ngokushintsha indawo.Uma ngisekhaya ngibona sengathi ngingakhohlwa kalula.Sengathi usheshe wayeka ukuncenga makoti. Qhubeka uncengeimpela. Beka nezizathu ezisemqoka impela. Uthi abacabangi ukuthiuzohamba unomphela?Angiboni ukuthi ngingahamba unomphela ngoba angisazimiselengokubuye ngigane. Okwesibili ngeke ngilikhohlwe leli khaya. Nomangingahamba kodwa ngiyohlala ngingowalapha ekhaya njalo.1. USipho ungumlingiswa oyindilinga kulo mdlalo. Sekela lesi sitatimendengamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Izenzo zikaSipho ziyaguquguquka zihambisana nesimo azitholaekuso.• Ngesikhathi izinto zisahamba kahle wayegqugquzela uThenjiwe ukuthiangalivumi leli siko lokungenwa waze wagwaza noDumisani evikelauThenjiwe. Kuthe lapho isimo sesisibi evalelwe ejele, washintshaumqondo waxolisa kuDumisani waphinde wacela noThenjiwe ukuthiakalivume isiko lokungenwa.(Nokunye okunembayo okungashiwo ngumfundi)"},{"question":"Жусуп Турусбековдун \\"Энеме\\" поэмасы","answer":"Жусуп Турусбековдун \\"Энеме\\"- поэмасында жаштардын билимге умтулуусу, жаңы замандын илимдүү инсандардын образдарын көрсөтүп арасына энесин (улуу муунду)кошуп аларын көрсөткөн."},{"question":"王思聪在哪些公司担任职务？","answer":"王思聪是普思投资的创始人和董事长，也是电子竞技队伍“IG”的创始人。"},{"question":"من هو مخترع ألاطارات المنفوخه ؟","answer":"جورج دانلوب."},{"question":"Miksi aamulla ja illalla aurinko näyttää punaiselta?","answer":"Auringon noustessa tai laskiessa pilvettömällä taivaalla se näyttää punertavalta. Tämä johtuu siitä, että auringon ollessa matalalla taivaanrannassa auringon säteet joutuvat kulkemaan pisimmän matkan halki ilmakehän, jolloin sininen sirottuu auringon valosta pois ja jäljelle jäävät punertavat värisävyt. Ilmassa leijuvat epäpuhtaudet, savu, utu yms. aiheuttavat samanlaisen sinistä valoa hävittävän ilmiön; savun ja udun läpi aurinko näyttää punertavalta."},{"question":"Inona no fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 05 ora sy sasany  hariva fahiny ? ","answer":"Ny fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 05 ora  sy sasany hariva  fahiny dia : \\"Mena masoandro \\". "},{"question":"I am on my desk","answer":"I am at my desk, and while starting the day, I decide to drop something as led by the Spirit of God. When we refer to glory, it is a measure of the divine revealed through you to the world. Taking that definition into consideration, we can infer that all glory belongs to God. Remember, in His word, He said, There's the glory of the sun, which differs from the moon, and also that of the stars; even stars are of different glories in manifestation. Regardless of what achievement you have incurred or how influential you have become, always have a deep understanding that all glory belongs to God. The issue with mankind is that they quickly forget their source and are carried away by the quest for affluence, fame, and wealth acquisitions. No matter the office attained on earth, always know that you got there only by the grace of God, and therefore ensure that you acknowledge Him (God Almighty) when praised by men. Herod in the scripture failed to attribute the glory that belongs to God alone, but rather was engulfed by the praise of men, leading to His demise. This was also the reason why 'lucifer' was cast out of heaven due to him harboring iniquity in his heart (as he was attributing God's glory unto himself) (Isaiah 14:13). Be mindful of the praise of men, as it can disconnect you from God and lead to eternal damnation. Remember, pride comes before a fall."},{"question":"Saare ti wọn ṣe fun Ajimọbi di ariyanjiyan nla","answer":"Nise ni awọn eeyan n gba ọrọ saare Ajimọbi ti awọn mọlẹbi rẹ ṣe bii aafin ọba bii ẹni gba igba ọti. Niṣe ni wọn ṣe saare ọkunrin naa ringindin. Aga wa nibẹ, ohun amuletutu wa nibẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn fa ina sibẹ to mọlẹ rokoso. Ẹrọ amunawa paapaa wa nibẹ bi ina ijọba ba lọ.Bawọn kan ṣe n sọ pe ohun to daa ni, pe ko si ohun ti mọlẹbi ko le ṣe fun eeyan wọn ti wọn ba fẹran, ṣugbọn to ku.Ṣugbọn awọn kan sọ pe ifowoṣofo gbaa ni. Wọn ni ẹni to ti ku ti ba tiẹ lọ, oku rẹyin. Ati pe wọn ko nilo iru nnkan bẹẹ.Awọn eeyan yii sọ pe wọn le lo awọn owo ti wọn na danu lasan yii fun nnkan daadaa mi-in. Wọn le fun awọn alaini lawujọẸ gbọ, ki lẹyn ri sọ si i."},{"question":"استخرج من المقطع إجابة السؤال: أين تقع مدينة بيدوا؟بَيْدَوَا هي مدينة في وسط جنوب الصومال، تبعد 256كم عن الطريق الشمالي الغربي للعاصمة مقديشو.[1][2][3] وهي ثالث أكبر مدن الصومال، والرابعة أهميةً بعد كيسمايو. ويقدر عدد سكانها أكثر من 800 ألف. تحتل مركزا استراتيجيا هاما بالنسبة لقربها من الحدود المشتركة مع الحبشة وكينيا.","answer":"مدينة بيدوا تقع في وسط جنوب الصومال، على بعد 256 كم إلى الشمال الغربي من العاصمة مقديشو على الحدود المشتركة مع الحبشة وكينيا."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Thượng tá Nguyễn Văn Dũng, Trưởng phòng CSGT Công an tỉnh Tiền Giang, cho biết khuya 30/7 đã phát hiện khoảng 50 người ở Tiền Giang, Bến Tre, Long An hẹn nhau tổ chức đua xe trái phép trên quốc lộ 1. Nhóm \\"quái xế\\" này còn cho người cảnh giới trước trụ sở công an để báo động cho các tay đua khi thấy lực lượng chức năng đi làm nhiệm vụ. Để chặn bắt nhóm này, lãnh đạo Phòng CSGT phân công cán bộ, chiến sĩ phối hợp với cảnh sát cơ động, hình sự lên phương án chốt chặn trên quốc lộ 1 đoạn qua huyện Châu Thành và TP Mỹ","answer":"Tho. Đến hơn 5h ngày 31/7, nhóm người này tưởng không có cảnh sát làm nhiệm vụ nên đã ra quốc lộ 1 ở xã Phước Thạnh, TP Mỹ Tho. Khi nhóm chuẩn bị tổ chức đua xe, các tổ trinh sát mật phục đã cùng lực lượng công khai khép kín khu vực từ ngã 3 Trung Lương, TP Mỹ Tho đến ngã 4 Đồng Tâm, huyện Châu Thành. Các \\"quái xế\\" nhìn thấy cảnh sát đã quay đầu xe tháo chạy, lao vào các con hẻm hòng thoát thân. Tại hiện trường, cảnh sát đã khống chế 24 người liên quan, tạm giữ 18 xe máy các loại. Trong 18 xe máy bị tạm giữ, nhiều phương tiện đã thay đổi kết cấu với mục đích phục vụ việc đua xe. Theo Phòng CSGT, tình trạng tụ tập cổ vũ đua xe trái phép trên địa bàn tỉnh Tiền Giang có dấu hiệu manh nha trở lại. Đầu năm 2022 đến nay, cảnh sát đã phát hiện và bắt giữ 3 nhóm thanh thiếu niên tụ tập đua xe, cổ vũ đua xe trái phép, tạm giữ 46 phương tiện. Cảnh sát khởi tố 2 vụ án, liên quan đến 12 người về hành vi tổ chức đua xe trái phép và gây rối trật tự công cộng."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Burquina Fasso?","answer":"Em 2021, o Índice de Desenvolvimento Humano (IDH) da Burquina Fasso foi 0,449. Este valor é classificado como “baixo” e coloca o país na 184ª posição do ranking do IDH. O Índice de Desenvolvimento Humano é uma medida geral e sintética usada para classificar o grau de desenvolvimento económico e a qualidade de vida dos países. Foi criado em 1990 e vem sendo publicado anualmente desde 1993 pelo Programa das Nações Unidas para o Desenvolvimento (PNUD) da ONU."},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் முதல் சபாநாயகர் யார் ?","answer":"இந்தியாவின் முதல் சபாநாயகர் ஜீ.வீ.மாவ்லங்கர்.ஜி. வி. மாவ்லங்கர்(27 நவம்பர் 1888 – 27 பிப்ரவரி 1956), தாதாசாகிப் என மக்களால் அன்பாக அழைக்கப்பட்ட இவர், இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பு நிர்ணய மன்றத்தின் தலைவராகவும், பின் நாடாளுமன்ற மக்களவையின் முதல் மக்களவைத் தலைவராகவும் பணியாற்றியவர்.5 மே 1952ல் நடைபெற்ற முதல் இந்தியப் பொதுத் தேர்தலில், மாவ்லங்கர், அகமதாபாத் மக்களவைத் தொகுதியிலிருந்து, நாடாளுமன்ற மக்களவைக்குத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். மாவ்லங்கர் இந்திய நாடாளுமன்ற முதல் மக்களவைத் தலைவராகவும் 13 ஜனவரி 1956 முடிய பணியாற்றினார். 27 பிப்ரவரி 1956ல் இருதய நோயினால் அகமதாபாத் நகரத்தில், தமது 67வது வயதில் மறைந்தார்இந்திய மக்களவைத் தலைவர் இந்திய நாடாளுமன்றத்தின் கீழ் அவையான மக்களவையை நடத்தும் தலைவரைக் குறிப்பதாகும். மூன்றாம் உலக நாடுகளில் (வெஸ்ட்மினிஸ்டர் அரசாங்கம்) உள்ள பேரவைகளில் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் சொல்லையே இந்தியாவிலும் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகின்றது.மக்களவைத்தலைவர் 5 ஆண்டுகளுக்கொருமுறை நடத்தப்படுகின்ற தேர்தலில் வெற்றிபெற்ற உறுப்பினர்கள் பங்குபெரும் மக்களவையின் முதல் கூட்டத்தில் உறுப்பினர்களால் ஒருமனதாகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுகின்றார். அதன்பின் அவர் பதவி விலகினாலன்றி வேறு ஒருவரை அப்பதவியில் நியமிக்க முடியாது.மக்களவைத் தலைவரின் அதிகாரங்கள்மக்களவைத் தலைவரே பேரவையே நடத்துபவர், கண்காணிப்பவர் மற்றும் பேரவைகளின் அலுவல்களை கவனிப்பவரும் அவரே.மசோதாமசோதாவின் தன்மைகளை ஆராய்ந்து (பண விடை மசோதா மற்றும் பண விடையில்லா மசோதா) அதன்படி தாக்கல் செய்ய அனுமதிக்கின்றார். பேரவையை அதன் மாண்புக் குறையாமல், இறையாண்மைக் குறையாமல், ஒழுக்கத்துடன் நடைபெறக் கடப்பாடுக் கொண்டுள்ளார்.தீர்மானங்கள்தீர்மானங்களை அவரின் அனுமதியின்றித் தாக்கல் செய்யமுடியாது. நம்பிக்கையில்லாத் தீர்மானம், ஒத்திவைப்புத் தீர்மானம், கண்டனத் தீர்மானம் மற்றும் கவன ஈர்ப்புத் தீர்மானம் போன்றத் தீர்மானங்களை அனுமதிக்கின்றார். அவரின் இசைவினால் விவாதங்கள் ஏற்கப்படுகின்றன மற்றும் தள்ளுபடி செய்யப்படுகின்றன.தேர்தல்மக்களவைத் தலைவரின் தேர்தலை குடியரசுத் தலைவர் தீர்மானிக்கின்றார்."},{"question":"Cecilia Nku","answer":"Cecilia Ngibo Nku (ti a bi ni ọjọ kerindinlogbon Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 1992) jẹ agbabọọlu Naijiria ti o gba fun egbe agbabọọlu Rivers Angels ti idije Awọn obinrin Naijiria .Nku gba bọọlu akọkọ rẹ ni ìdíje agbaye ni ọdun 2010 lakoko ti o nṣere fun Nigeria ni 2010 FIFA U-20 World Cup Women . Arabinrin naa wa lara ikọ agbabọọlu orilẹede Naijiria ti o bori ninu idije idije awọn obinrin ile Afirika ti ọdun 2014 ni orile-ede Namibia . Ni Oṣu Karun ọdun 2015 ni a pe Nku lati gba bọọlu fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu orilẹ-ede Naijiria ninu idije Ife Agbaye Awọn Obirin ti 2015 FIFA ."},{"question":"\\"I Paoly avy any Tarsosy, no mpanoratra ireo epistily maro ao amin'ny Testamenta Vaovao, nosoratana ho an'ireo fiangonana sy olona samihafa.\\"Inona ny fanontaniana azo tsogaina amin'io andian-teny io?","answer":"Fanontaniana: Iza no mpanoratra ireo epistily maro nosoratana ho an'ny fiangonana samihafa ao amin'ny Testamenta Vaovao?"},{"question":"\\"Tichifunga nezvemashoko akanyorwa pamusoro paGennady Petrovich Lyachin, ndiudzei paakapinda muchiuto uye paakadzingwa basa. Gennady Petrovich Lyachin (chiRussian: Геннадий Петрович Лячин; 1 Ndira 1955 - 12 Nyamavhuvhu 2000) aive mukuru weuto reRussia. mukuru mukuru weRussia submarine Kursk apo ngarava yakatambura kuputika kwakatevedzana uye yakanyura musi wa12 Nyamavhuvhu 2000.Lyachin akaberekerwa muSarpinsky muVolgograd Oblast. Akapinda muNavy muna 1972 uye akapedza kudzidza paChikoro Chepamusoro Naval Chikoro cheSubmarine Navigation chakanzi Lenin Komsomol muna 1977 uye akagadzwa semukuru. Akashanda semukuru wezvombo ari mudhiziri-yemagetsi Juliett class cruise missile submarine K-58. Kubva 1984 kusvika 1986, saKaputeni 3rd Chinzvimbo, akashanda semukuru weK-77, zvakare Juliett Kirasi. Muna 1986 akapinda Advanced Special Officers 'Classs panguva yaakakwidziridzwa kuita Captain 2nd Rank.Muna October 1988, Lyachin akagamuchira murairo wake wokutanga, K-304 uyewo kirasi yaJuliett. Akabata chinzvimbo ichi kusvika K-304 yabviswa mushure mekudonha kweSoviet Union muna 1991.Muna Kubvumbi 1991, akagadzwa mukuru mukuru wechikepe chenyukireya, Project 949A Antey class (NATO reporting name Oscar-II) K-119 Voronezh uye akashanda muchikepe kuburikidza ne1996. Iye nevashandi vachangobva kuumbwa vakapedza nguva pakati paGunyana 1991 ne March 1993 achidzidziswa muObninsk.Lyachin akakwidziridzwa kusvika pachinzvimbo cheKaputeni 1st Chinzvimbo muna 1996 uye akapihwa kuraira kwechikepe chehanzvadzi yeVoronezh, iyo yakashata K-141 Kursk, yekupedzisira kwazvo Project 949A ngarava yepasi pemvura kupedzwa, iyo yakanga yatumwa makore maviri chete apfuura. Pakanyura Kursk musi waNyamavhuvhu 12, 2000, Lyachin akaparara pamwe chete nevamwe vese vevashandi 117.","answer":"Gennady Petrovich Lyachin akabatana neNavy muna 1972 uye akabviswa muna 1991 mushure mekudonha kweSoviet Union."},{"question":"வினா :என்னில் என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள்…………………….அ) உனக்குள்ஆ) நமக்குள்இ) உலகுக்குள்ஈ) எனக்குள்","answer":"விடை :ஈ) எனக்குள்"},{"question":"Os ritmos deslumbrantes do interior têm uma geometria complexa. Os ritmos deslumbrantes do interior têm uma geometria complexa. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Sim."},{"question":"Mai wannan jimlar take bayyanawa: Za ayi Kurda kurda kenan... Irin namu na kano😁","answer":"Tana bayyana dai-dai"},{"question":"ਵਿਕਾਸ ।","answer":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਇੱਕ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਕ੍ਰਿਆ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਕਈ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਅਤੇ ਖੱਲੇ ਆਕਾਰ ਵੱਲ ਵੱਧਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਇਹ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ੀਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਵਿਭੇਦੀਕਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਚੀਜ਼ ਜਿਸਦਾ ਅਸੀਂ ਮੁੱਲਾਂਕਣ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਾਂ, ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਉੱਨਤੀ ਵੱਲ ਵੱਧਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Madoda! Namuhla ngithokoze kakhulu ngoba indunaayizukulala esitokisini.Ndabezitha!Yize icala lingaphelile kodwa mina nginethemba ngoba lesisilima esinguMbandlwa asinaye ufakazi. (iqondise kuDlamini)Awuthi qaphuqaphu ngesimo secala khona umkhandlu wamiuzothola sonke isithombe.(asukume uDlamini) Ndabezitha! Ngizoqala ngokubongauNdabezitha ngokungikhokhela ibheyili. Minabengizoyithathaphi inkulungwane yamarandi? Ndabezithanani bandla lenkosi, icala lokushaya ngiyaliphika ngimangentaba. Ngithi, uMbandlwa ngamsikaza ngenduku maqedeyena wagxuma wazishayisa echosheni lobonda lwekilasi.Okuhle kakhulu ngukuthi mina amadoda engangihamba nawoayangifakazela. Yena akanaye ufakazi ngoba ikhanselalalingaphakathi ekilasini kanye nezethameli zomhlangano.Lihlehlile-ke icala. Liyoze lingene emva kwezinyangaezintathu.(kuzwakale ukuhhomuzela kwentokozo abanye behleka)(inkosi yelule isandla sakumhlalisa phansi uDlamini)Hhayi-ke! Siyabonga Mzizi, ungahlala phansi.(ahlale phansi) Ndabezitha!Kunjalo-ke madoda. Mina ngeke ngimsole uDlamini ngoba lelikhansela liyangeyisa. Lake lakubonaphi ukuthi umfokazanaangamane abize umhlangano endaweni yenkosiengadlulanga enkosini?(ahhomuzele)Uyagcwaneka lo!Yisizwe sakho lesi Ndabezitha! Singakufela lokho thina!(eqondise emkhandlwini) Yehlisani umoya madoda! Thulaniumsindo, uNdabezitha usakhuluma!Mina ngiyasola uDuma usabambelele kulokhu okwenzekangesikhathi sodlame. Angithi ngikhuluma nje ungomunyewalaba ababehla benyuka lapha endaweni yami,begqugquzela ngenkani ukufaka leli dungabantu ababelibizangomzabalazo …1. Yini eyayenza inkosi uShandu ibize uMbandlwa ngesilima?","answer":"Wenziwa ukuthi akamhloniphi ubiza imihlangano engamtshelanga."},{"question":"රොනල්ඩ්ස්වේ ගුවන් තොටුපළ පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කුමන දූපතේද?","answer":"අයිල් ඔෆ් මෑන්"},{"question":"ලෝක සෞඛ්‍ය සංවිධානයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා  තිබෙන්නේ?","answer":"ස්විස්ටර්ලන්තයේ ජිනිවා නුවර"},{"question":"We krwi człowieka występują bezjądrowe fragmenty komórek. Ich liczba w 1 mm3 krwi zdrowego człowieka wynosi od 200 do 400 tysięcy. Chronią one organizm przed utratą krwi, zatykają uszkodzone naczynia krwionośne i biorą udział w procesie krzepnięcia krwi.Dokończ zdanie. Wybierz właściwą odpowiedź spośród podanych.Opisane składniki morfotyczne krwi toA. płytki krwi.B. krwinki czerwone.C. krwinki białe – limfocyty B.D. krwinki białe – limfocyty T.","answer":"A, płytek krwi."},{"question":"රූප සැකසීම(Image Processing ) පැහැදිලි කරන්න?","answer":"රූප සැකසීම යනු විවිධ ඇල්ගොරිතම සහ ශිල්පීය ක්‍රම භාවිතා කරමින් ඩිජිටල් රූප හැසිරවීම, විශ්ලේෂණය සහ වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සම්බන්ධයෙන් කටයුතු කරන ඩිජිටල් සංඥා සැකසීමේ ශාඛාවකි. රූප සැකසීමේ පරමාර්ථය වන්නේ රූපවලින් ප්‍රයෝජනවත් තොරතුරු උකහා ගැනීම, රූපයේ ගුණාත්මකභාවය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සහ නිශ්චිත යෙදුම් සඳහා සුදුසු රූප සෑදීමයි."},{"question":"من هي زوجة الرسول التي كانت تلقب بالحميراء ؟","answer":"عائشة بنت أبي بكر"},{"question":"Monna Rosa (Mona Roza) şiirinin şairi kimdir?","answer":"Monna Rosa (Mona Roza) şiirinin şairi Sezai Karakoç ya da kimlikteki adıyla Ahmet Sezai (1933 – 16 Kasım 2021)'dir.  Sezai Karakoç Cumhuriyet Dönemi'nde şiir, çeviri, hikaye, tiyatro, deneme, düşünce yazısı, inceleme ve röportaj gibi türlerde toplam 50'den fazla kitap yazmış Türk şair, hikaye yazarı, düşünür ve siyasetçidir."},{"question":"Escribe una continuación para este párrafo: En marzo de 2011, fue convocado por el selectivo sub-20 para disputar el Campeonato Sub-20 de la Concacaf de 2011. Araújo jugó los 90 minutos de todos los partidos que disputó. México logró el campeonato de manera invicta al ganar sus cinco partidos ante Cuba (0:3), Trinidad y Tobago (5:0), Canadá (3:0), Panamá (4:1) y Costa Rica (3:1). En junio, fue convocado para disputar la Copa Mundial de Fútbol Sub-20 de 2011...","answer":"... que se jugó en Colombia. Participó de titular en todos los encuentros y solo salió de cambio en el partido por el tercer lugar contra la Selección de fútbol de Francia. México terminó como segundo lugar de su grupo, resultado de perder en contra Argentina (1:0), ganarle a Corea del Norte (3:0) y empatar con Inglaterra (0:0). En octavos de final México derrotó a Camerún en penales (0:3), después de empatar a un gol en el tiempo regular; en cuartos de final derrotaron a Colombia (3:1); en semifinales perdieron en contra de Brasil (2:0) y en el partido por el tercer lugar le ganaron a la selección de Francia (3:1)."},{"question":"የበርሊኑ ጉባኤ መች ነበር የፖርቱጋልን የቅኝ ግዛት ድንበር የወሰነው?","answer":"የበርሊኑ ጉባኤ በ1885 እ.ኤ.አ የፖርቱጋልን የቅኝ ግዛት ድንበር ወሰነ።"},{"question":"खलः करोति दुर्वृत्तं नूनं फलति साधुषु ।दशाननो हरेत् सीतां बन्धनं स्याद् महोदधेः ॥","answer":"दुष्ट लोक दुष्कृत्ये करतात पण त्याची फळे सज्जनांना भोगावी लागतात. रावणाने सीतेचे हरण केले आणि समुद्राला सेतूबंधनात पडावे लागले."},{"question":"विश्वको जनसंख्या ७ अर्ब कहिले पुग्यो ?","answer":"२०६८ असोज २४, मंगलवार (सन् २०११ अक्टोबर ११) विश्वको जनसंख्या ७ अर्ब पुग्यो।"},{"question":" ரிச்சர்டு, யார்க் கோமகன் ரிச்சர்டின் மிகவும் இளைய மகனாவார். இவருக்கு மூன்று அண்ணன்கள், எட்வர்டு, எட்மண்டு,ஜார்ஜ் இருந்தனர். இரோசாப்பூப் போர்களின்","answer":"போது இவரது தந்தை ரிச்சர்டும் இரண்டாம் மகன் எட்மண்டும் போரில் கொல்லப்பட்டனர். மூத்தவர், எட்வர்டு, மிகச் சிறந்த போர்வீரராக போராடி இங்கிலாந்தின் அப்போதைய மன்னர் என்றி VIஐ வென்று இங்கிலாந்தின் முடியாட்சியை வென்றார். இங்கிலாந்தின் நான்காம் எட்வர்டு என முடிசூட்டிக் கொண்டார். இதன் பின்னர் இவரது இரு தம்பிகள் ஜார்ஜும் ரிச்சர்டும் செல்வாக்கு மிக்கவர்களாக விளங்கினர்."},{"question":"Кытайда балдарды кантип тарбиялашат?","answer":"Кытайлар ымыркай төрөлгөндөн алты айга чейин эле эненин сүтү менен багышат. Андан кийин наристе балдар бакчасында чоңоёт. Ошол себептен Кытайда бала багуучу деген түшүнүк жок. Кытайда балдарга кичинесинен тарта улууларды сыйлаганды жана тынымсыз эмгектенүүгө, сабырдуу болууга үйрөтөт. Кытай ата-энелери балдар сөзсүз түрдө пайдалуу иш менен алаксышы керектигин айтып, аларга шарттарын түзүп берет."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Sababaha loogu dardaarmo In timirta la cuno maalin Kasta?","answer":"Timirtu waxa ay ka mid tahay khudradaha nafaqada badan u leh jidhka, waxa ay leedahay faa’iidooyin caafimaad oo tiro badan, qormadan oo aynu ka soo xigannay shabakadda Aljazeera waxa ay soo bandhigaysaa sababahaas caafimaad.Timirtu waxa ay hodan ku tahay sonkor, sida oo kale waxaa ku jira maaddooyinka Potasium, Phosphorous iyo Magnesium. Waxa kale oo ku badan Faytamiinnada A iyo B. boqolkii Garaam ee kasta ee timir ah waxaa ku jira 275 Kalooriyo iyo 7.5 Garaam oo ah gal / gan nafaqo leh.Khubarada caafimaadka cuntadu waxa ay ku taliyaan in Timirta lagu daro cuntooyinka maalinlaha ah, maadaama oo la ogyahay in ay caafimaadka qofka aad ugu fiican tahay.Haweenayda qoraaga ah ee Cristina de Las Eras ayaa warbixin ay ku baahisay majaladda Miarevista oo ka soo baxda dalka Spain waxa ay ku sheegtay in muddo hadda laga joogo 6 kun oo sano ay beerista timirtu ka soo bilaabatay Koonfurta-bari ee qaaradda Aasiya iyo woqooyiga Afrika, kaddibna ay ku faaftay dalalka uu heerkulka cimiladoodu sarreeyo.Kaldaawiyiinta (Chaldea) oo ahaa qawmiyad deggenayd konfurta dhulkii loo yaqaannay Mesobotaamiya (Dhulka labada webi oo imika ay dhacaan dalalka Ciraaq, Suuriya iyo Turkigu) muddo lagu qiyaaso qarnigii tobnaad ee dhalashadii nebi Ciise (CS) ka hor, waxa ay timirta u yaqaanneen magaca ah ‘Geedka nolosha’. Midhaha timirta ayaa ay cunto ahaan ugu noolaayeen, caleenteeda iyo dhuuxeeda iyo gankeedana intifaacsan jireen.Timirtu waxa ay leedahay noocyo kala duwan oo tiro badan, kuwaas oo loo isticmaalo siyaabo kala duwan oo xitaa ay ka mid tahay in noocyada qaar lagu daro cajiinka laga sameeyo khubusta iyo keegga."},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kas yra suformuluota Einšteino specialiosios reliatyvumo teorijoje?","answer":"Atsakymas: Tai yra idėja, kad visų stebėtojų, judančių vienas kitam konstantiniais greičiais, laiko ir erdvės matavimai yra vienodi."},{"question":"ലിങ്ക്ഡീന് എന്തിനു വേണ്ടി ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു? വിഷയം ലിങ്ക്ഡിനാണ്.","answer":"തൊഴിൽ ദാതാക്കളായ വ്യവസായങ്ങൾക്കും ഉദ്യോഗാർത്ഥികൾക്കും വേണ്ടിയുള്ള സോഷ്യൽ നെറ്റ് വർക്കിങ് സേവനമാണ് ലിങ്ക്ഡ് ഇൻ. വെബ്‌സൈറ്റ് വഴിയും മൊബൈൽ ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകൾ വഴിയും ലിങ്ക്ഡ് ഇൻ സേവനങ്ങൾ ലഭ്യമാണ്. 2002 ഡിസംബർ 28 നാണ് ലിങ്ക്ഡ് ഇൻ സ്ഥാപിക്കപ്പെടുന്നത്. 2003 മേയ് 5 മുതലാണ് ലിങ്ക്ഡ് ഇൻ പൊതുമധ്യത്തിലേക്കെത്തുന്നത്."},{"question":"سوال ڇا آهي ته: \\"آوڪوڊو يا الگيٽر پيئر پڻ وڻ جي ميون ڏانهن اشارو ڪري ٿو (بٽانياتي طور تي هڪ وڏي بيري جنهن ۾ هڪ واحد ٻج شامل آهي) \\"؟ موضوع آهي آوڪوڊو.","answer":"\\"اُن ٻوٽي جو ڪهڙو حصو اُفڪوڊو آهي؟\\""},{"question":"ඔබ ස්ලැම් ඩන්ක් එකක් කරන්නේ කුමන ක්‍රීඩාවේද?","answer":"පැසිපන්දු"},{"question":"Eeyan mẹrin padanu ẹmi wọn nibi ijamba ọkọ ni Mọniya","answer":"Eeyan mẹrin lo ku loju-ẹsẹ ninu ijamba ọkọ kan to waye ni Mọniya, n’Ibadan, ni nnkan bii aago mejila ọsan ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Nibi ti ọkọ tasin micra kan to n na Sango si Mọniya ti n gbiyanju lati ya ọkọ tirela to wa niwaju ẹ ṣilẹ laduugbo ti wọn n pe ni Funduck, ni Mọniya, nijamba ọhun ti waye, nigba ti ọkọ tasin naa lọọ fori sọ tirela mi-in to n bọ latọna Ijaye wa sigboro Ibadan.Ọgbẹni Fẹmi Ilọri tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju ẹ ṣalaye fun akọroyin wa pe afọwọfa awakọ tasin ọhun lo ṣokunfa ijamba ọhun, o ni ainisuuru lo ko ba a.“Nibi ti gálọ́ọ̀bù wa, to jẹ pe gbogbo ọkọ to n lọ ati eyi to n bọ ni wọn maa n du apa ibi to daa ni onimicra yẹn ti fẹẹ ofatéèkì tirela, o ro pe tirela yẹn maa ni suuru fun oun ni, sugbọn iyẹn ko ni suuru fun un rara. Bo ṣe lọọ kọ lu ọkọ mi-in to bọ niwaju niyẹn.“Eeyan mẹrin lo ku loju-ẹsẹ, ẹni karun-un ko ku, ṣugbọn o fara pa gan-an.”ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn oṣiṣẹ FRSC, iyẹn ajọ to n ri si eto aabo loju popo ni wọn gbe ẹni ti ori ko yọ lọwọ iku oro yii lọ sileewosan ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti wọn si tọju awọn mẹrẹẹrin to padanu ẹmi wọn pamọ si yara ti wọn n ṣe oku lọjọ si nileewosan ọhun."},{"question":"கேள்வி:  தமிழைப்  பிழையின்றி எழுத என்ன செய்யவேண்டும் என்பதைக் கூறவும் அல்லது எழுதவும்? ","answer":"பதில்:         ஒற்றுப் பிழைகள் என்பவை எழுதும்போது ஏற்படும் சந்திப் பிழைகளே ஆகும். அதாவது வலி மிகும் இடங்களில் மிகாமலும் தேவையற்ற இடங்களில் மிகுந்தும் எழுதப்படுவதாகும். இஃது உரைநடையில் ஒரு சில நேரங்களில் தேவையற்ற குழப்பங்களை உண்டாக்கும். எனவே பொதுவாகத் தமிழில் ஒற்றுப் பிழைகள் இன்றி எழுதுவதே சிறப்பு ஆகும்.“\\tஇயல்பினும் விதியினும் நின்ற உயிர்முன்க ச த ப மிகும் விதவாதன மன்னே”என்ற நன்னூல் விதிப்படி, நிலைமொழி ஈற்றில் இயல்பாகவும் விதியின் படியும் உயிரெழுத்து வரும்பொழுது வருமொழி முதலில் வரும் வல்லெழுத்து (சிறப்பு விதிகளால் கூறப்படாத இடங்களைத் தவிர்த்து மற்ற இடங்களில்) மிகும். இஃது உயிரீற்றுப் புணரியலில் (நூற்பா.165) இடம்பெறுகிறது.சான்று :-இயல்பாக உயிரெழுத்து வரல்கரும்புக் கட்டு → இங்கு ப்+உ=பு ; எனவே உயிரெழுத்து இயல்பாக வந்துள்ளது.விதியின்படி உயிரெழுத்து வரல்மரச் சட்டம் = மரம் + சட்டம்“\\tமவ்வீறு ஒற்றொழிந்து உயிரீறு ஒப்பவும்\\t”என்ற நன்னூல் விதிப்படி நிலைமொழியீற்று ம் கெட்டு மர+சட்டம் என்று தொக்கி நின்றது. இதன் பிறகு மேற்குறிப்பிட்ட விதியின்படி வல்லெழுத்து மிகும்.வலிமிகும் இடங்கள்முதன்மைக் கட்டுரை: வல்லெழுத்து மிகும் இடம், மிகா இடம்அப்படி, இப்படி, எப்படி என்னும் சொற்களின் பின் வலிமிகும்:- அப்படி + கூறினான் = அப்படிக் கூறினான்,இப்படி + சொன்னார் = இப்படிச் சொன்னார், எப்படி + சொன்னார் = எப்படிச் சொன்னார்.ஆய், போய் என்னும் வினையெச்சங்களின் பின் வலிமிகும்:- நன்றாய் + பேசினார் = நன்றாய்ப் பேசினார். போய் + பார்த்தான் = போய்ப் பார்த்தேன்அங்கு, இங்கு என்னும் சுட்டுத் திரிபுப் பெயர்களின் பின் வலிமிகும்:- அங்கு + கண்டேன் = அங்குக் கண்டேன். இங்கு + பார்த்தேன் = இங்குப் பார்த்தேன்.இரண்டாம் வேற்றுமை உருபுக்குப் பின்வரும் வலி மிகும்:- பையை + கொடு = பையைக் கொடு.நான்காம் வேற்றுமை உருபிற்குப் பின்வரும் வலிமிகும்:- சென்னைக்கு + சென்றான் = சென்னைக்குச் சென்றான்.ஓரெழுத்து ஒருமொழியின் பின் வலிமிகும்:- தை + திங்கள் = தைத் திங்கள். பூ + பறித்தாள் = பூப் பறித்தாய்.'க்கு', 'ச்சு', 'ட்டு', 'த்து', 'ப்பு', 'ற்று' என முடியும் சொற்களின் (வன்றொடர்க் குற்றியலுகரம்)பின் மிகும்:- எடுத்துக்காட்டு, நச்சுப் புகை, தட்டுப்பாடு, பருப்புக் கூட்டு, மாற்றுச் சேலை.'ங்கு', 'ஞ்சு', 'ண்டு', 'ந்து', 'ம்பு', 'ன்று' என முடியும் சொற்களின் (மென்றொடர்க் குற்றியலுகரம்) பின் பெயர்ச்சொல் வந்தால் மிகும் :- குரங்குத் தலை, பஞ்சுப் பொதி,கூண்டுக் கிளி, மருந்துக் கடை,இரும்புத் திரை கன்றுக் குட்டி, அன்புக் கரங்கள்.(குறிப்பு : வினைமுற்று வந்தால் மிகாது).வலிமிகா இடங்கள்முதன்மைக் கட்டுரை: வல்லெழுத்து மிகும் இடம், மிகா இடம்எழுவாய்த் தொடரில் வலிமிகாது:- குரங்கு + கடித்தது = குரங்கு கடித்தது.வினைத் தொகையில் வலிமிகாது:- விளை + பயிர் = விளைபயிர்உம்மைத் தொகையில் வலிமிகாது:- செடி + கொடி = செடிகொடிஅடுக்குத் தொடரில் வலிமிகாது:- தீ + தீ = தீ தீஇரண்டாம் வேற்றுமைத் தொகையில் வலிமிகாது:- நீர் + குடித்தான் = நீர் குடித்தான்; மாடு + மேய்த்தார் = மாடு மேய்த்தார்நான்காம் வேற்றுமைத் தொகையில் வலிமிகாது:- சென்னை + சென்றான் = சென்னை + சென்றான்'ங்கு', 'ஞ்சு', 'ண்டு', 'ந்து', 'ம்பு', 'ன்று' என முடியும் சொற்களின் (மென்றொடர்க் குற்றியலுகரம்) பின் வினைமுற்று வந்தால் மிகாது :- கரும்பு தின்றான், குரங்கு பார்த்தது."},{"question":"ماهو الحدث المهم الذي يتحدث عنه النص التالي: يُفترض أن أسرة أبيدوس كانت سلالة محلية قصيرة العمر حكمت أجزاء من مصر الوسطى ومصر العليا خلال الفترة الانتقالية الثانية في مصر القديمة. كانت أسرة أبيدوس معاصرة للأسرتين الخامسة عشرة والسادسة عشرة، من حوالي 1650 إلى 1600 قبل الميلاد. كان من الممكن أن يكون مقره في أبيدوس أو حولها وربما كانت مقبرتها الملكية تقع عند سفح جبل أنوبيس، وهو تل يشبه الهرم في صحراء أبيدين، بالقرب من مقبرة منحوتة في الصخر بنيت للملك المصري سنوسرت الثالث.","answer":"يتحدث النص عن أسرة أبيدوس."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta :¿Qué edad tiene George R.R. Martin?. ","answer":"Tiene 74 años. "},{"question":"मगर समुदायको \\"पिठो त्याउँ\\" नृत्य र संगीतको सांस्कृतिक महत्वबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"पिठो त्यौन एक परम्परागत मगर नृत्य र संगीतको रूप हो जुन चाडपर्वहरूमा प्रदर्शन गरिन्छ, सामुदायिक बन्धन र आनन्दको प्रतिनिधित्व गर्दछ।"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Tümgeneral rütbesiyle Polonya Seferi'nde Kempf Panzer Tümeni'ne, Fransa Seferi'nde 6. Panzer Tümeni'ne komuta etmiştir. Korgeneralliğe terfi ederek Fransa Seferindeki rolüyle Şövalye Demir Haç madalyası ile ödüllendirildi. 1942'de 48. Panzer Kolordusu'nun komutanı olarak Stalingrad Muharebesi'nden sonraki Kış Fırtınası Harekâtı'na katılmıştır. 1943'te Kempf Ordu Müfrezesi'ne komuta ederek Kursk Muharebesi'ne katılmıştır. Kursk'ta uğranılan başarısızlık ardından Alman kuvvetleri geri çekilmişti. Ardından başlayan Sovyet Komutan Rumyantsev Harekâtı sırasında Harkov'u savunan General Kempf, Hitler'in emrine karşın 22 Ağustos 1943 tarihinde kenti tahliye etmişti. Bunun üzerine Hitler tarafından görevden alınmıştır.","answer":"Kursk Muharebesi ve Sovyet Komutan Rumyantsev Harekâtı"},{"question":"اشتي اعمل فول يمني. كيف اسويه؟","answer":"المكوّناتعلبة فول (استخدمت مقشور)علبة طماط معلب او حبتين طماطم مفرومة1 بصلة3 فصوص ثومالبهارات: ملح وفلفل اسود وكمونالخطواتالخطوة 1اشوح البصل والزيت دقيقتين بعدين اضيف الثومالخطوة 2اضيف الطاطم مع ملح وفلفل اسود وكمون واخليه يتسبك ١٠ دقايقالخطوة 3اضيف الفول (اذا كان حبوب نصفية من الموية)الخطوة 4اخلط كل شي واعلي النار واخليه عشر دقايقالخطوة 5حطو طحينة وبصل وطماط وقت التقديم وبالعافية"},{"question":"Kannst du mir Vorschläge für eine Themenparty geben? Es handelt sich um eine Geburtstagsfeier.","answer":"Es gibt verschiedenste Ideen für eine Mottoparty. Hier sind ein paar Vorschläge:1. Kostümidee-Überraschungsparty2. Hollywood-Party3. Food-Mottopartys4. Crazy Socks5. Star Wars6. Apres-Ski-Party"},{"question":"வினா:இராணுவ ஆட்சி நடைபெறும் நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை: மியான்மர் "},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து சோன்பப்படி செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:1 கப் கடலை மாவு½ கப் மைதா மாவு1 கப் சர்க்கரை½ கப் நெய்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி பிஸ்தா1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி பாதாம்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி முந்திரி½ எலுமிச்சம் பழம்2 சிட்டிகை உப்புதேவையான அளவு வெண்ணெய்","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் பாதாம், பிஸ்தா, மற்றும் முந்திரியை சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக நறுக்கி மற்றும் எலுமிச்சம் பழத்திலிருந்து சாறை எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் அரை கப் அளவு நெய் ஊற்றி அதை உருக விடவும்.3. நெய் உருகியதும் அதில் கடலை மாவை போட்டு அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.4. பின்பு அதில் மைதா மாவை போட்டு அதையும் நன்கு கலந்து விடவும். (சிறிது வறண்டு தான் இருக்கும் ஆனாலும் நாம் தண்ணீர் எதுவும் ஊற்றி விடக்கூடாது.)5. பின்னர் அடுப்பை முற்றிலுமாக குறைத்து விட்டு அதை சுமார் 6 லிருந்து 8 நிமிடம் வரை வதக்கவும்.6. 8 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு மாவு நன்கு உருகி சிறு சிறு பபிள்ஸ் வந்ததும் அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதை வேறு ஒரு பாத்திரத்திற்கு மாற்றி சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விடவும்.7. அது ஆறுவதற்குள் ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் அரை கப் அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி பின்பு சர்க்கரையை அதில் போட்டு ஒரு கரண்டி மூலம் அதை நன்கு கரைத்து விட்டு அடுப்பை முற்றிலுமாக குறைத்து அதை சுமார் 5 லிருந்து 7 நிமிடம் வரை கொதிக்க விடவும்.8. 5 நிமிடத்திற்குப் பிறகு அதில் நன்கு நுரை வந்ததும் அதில் 2 சிட்டிகை அளவு உப்பை சேர்த்து அதனுடன் நாம் பிழிந்து வைத்திருக்கும் எலுமிச்சை சாறையும் அதில் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.9. பின்பு அதில் சிறிது பெரிய அளவு பபிள்ஸ் வந்ததும் ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீர் எடுத்து அதில் கொதித்து கொண்டிருக்கும் இந்த சிரப்பில் இருந்து ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் சிறிதளவு எடுத்து இந்த கிண்ணத்தில் இருக்கும் தண்ணீரில் ஊற்றவும்.10. 3 வினாடிகளுக்கு பிறகு நாம் கிண்ணத்தில் ஊற்றிய அந்த சிரப்பை எடுத்து உருட்டினால் அது நாம் உருட்டும் வடிவிற்கு வரவேண்டும்.11. அப்படி வந்துவிட்டால் ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை எடுத்து அதில் நெய்யை நன்கு தடவி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.12. பின்பு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு இந்த சிரப்பை எடுத்த அந்த பாத்திரத்தில் ஊற்றி விடவும்.13. அடுத்து அதை ஒரு போர்க் ஸ்பூனின் மூலம் அதை நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு கொண்டே இருக்கவும்.14. பிறகு அது சிறிது கெட்டியானதும் அதை 2 போர்க் ஸ்பூனின் மூலம் அது நன்கு கெட்டியாகும் வரை தூக்கி தூக்கி கிளறி விடவும்.15. அது நன்கு கெட்டியானதும் நம் கைகளில் நன்கு நெய் தடவிக்கொண்டு அது நன்கு வெள்ளை நிறம் வரும் வரை அதை நன்றாக இழுத்து இழுத்து விட வேண்டும். (அது சூடாக இருப்பதால் கவனமாக இருக்க வேண்டும்.)16. எவ்வளவுக்கு எவ்வளவு நன்றாக இழுத்து விடுகிறோமோ அந்த அளவுக்கு நம் சோன்பப்படி மிருதுவாகவும் மற்றும் நன்கு நூல் நூலாக இருக்கும்.17. அது நன்கு வெள்ளை நிறம் வந்ததும் அதை நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் கடலை மாவு கலவையில் போட்டு அதை நன்கு இழுத்து இழுத்தே அதை நன்கு மாவுடன் கலந்து விடவும். (இப்பொழுதும் அது சூடாக தான் இருக்கும் அதனால் நாம் கவனமாக இதை செய்ய வேண்டும்.)18. பின்பு அது ஆறுவதற்குள் ஒரு ட்ரையில் வெண்ணெய்யை தடவி இந்த கலவையை அதில் சூடாக இருக்கும் போதே வைத்து நன்கு பரப்பி விட்டு அதன் மேலே நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் பாதாம், பிஸ்தா, மற்றும் முந்திரியை போடவும்.19. சரியாக 2 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதை ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் அவரவருக்கு பிடித்தமான வடிவில் கோடுகளை போட்டு அதை சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விட்டு பின்பு எடுத்து பரிமாறவும்.20. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் மிருதுவான மற்றும் மிகவும் சுவையான சோன்பப்படி தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து சுவைத்து மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bertumpu dulu barulah melompat'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud membuat persediaan yang cukup sebelum melakukan sesuatu pekerjaan"},{"question":"මනා දෘශ්ටියකට අවශ්‍ය පෝෂක වර්ගය","answer":"විටම්න් A"},{"question":"राणा वंशको उदय हुनु अघि नेपालको सक्रिय राजनीतिमा कुन-कुन कुलीन परिवार संलग्न थिए?","answer":"राणा वंशको उदय हुनु अघि नेपाल अधिराज्यको सक्रिय राजनीतिमा संलग्न हुने चार कुलीन परिवारहरू शाह वंश, बस्न्यात परिवार, पाण्डे वंश र थापा वंश थिए।"},{"question":"جاوب على هذا السؤال: من اكتشف الصفر ؟","answer":"من اكتشف الصفر هو موضوع مثير للجدل، فهناك من ينسب الفضل للهنود، وهناك من يرجعه للبابليين، وهناك من يذكر دور العرب في نقله إلى أوروبا."},{"question":"Qui sont les grands maîtres du ballet chez la jazz moderne?","answer":"La modern jazz dance de concert trouve surtout son expression chez les chorégraphes noirs américains : Donald McKayle et Alvin Ailey, mais aussi Talley Beatty (1918-1995) et George Faison (né en 1945). En Europe, elle a commencé à se répandre dans les années 1970, essentiellement grâce aux disciples de Katherine Dunham (1909-2006) et à Matt Mattox (1921-2013), et elle s'est surtout développée en France, avec Reney Deshauteurs (1935-2014), Anne-Marie Porras (née en 1948), Rheda (né en 1954), Rick Odums et Raza Hammadi (nés en 1955)."},{"question":"Karl Landsteiner akawana kubudirira kupi kwekurapa muna 1901?","answer":"Muna 1901, nyanzvi yekudzivirira zvirwere zvemuAustria Karl Landsteiner akaita kuwanikwa kunoshamisa kwemapoka eropa uye kuenderana kwawo. Landsteiner akaziva chirongwa cheboka reropa reABO, iro rinoisa ropa revanhu mumarudzi akasiyana: A, B, AB, uye O. Kuwanikwa uku kwakachinja kuisirwa ropa uye nzira dzokurapa, sezvo kwakagonesa nyanzvi dzezvokurapa kuona kuwirirana pakati pevanopa nevanorigamuchira, zvichideredza ngozi. yezvakaipira kuita. Basa raLandsteiner rakaisa hwaro hwemiitiro yokuisira ropa yakakotsekana uye inoshanda zvikuru."},{"question":"Everyone knows that the elephant has a very long nose.Apa padanan atau terjemahan kalimat Bahasa Inggris di atas dalam Bahasa Indonesia?","answer":"Terjemahan dari \\"Everyone knows that the elephant has a very long nose.\\" dalam Bahasa Indonesia adalah:Semua orang tahu, hidung gajah sangat panjang."},{"question":" murtida meeqaa loo qaybiyaa ? ","answer":" Waxaa looqaybiyaa saddex qaybood waxayna kala yihi"},{"question":": Waxaad sheegtaan Aayada 118 Suuratu Al- Towba, Sadaxda Saxaabi ay ku soo degtay magacyadooda?","answer":": Waa raggii ka dib dhacay duullaankii Tabuuk, waxayna kala ahaayeen:    Kacab ibnu Maalik,    Muraara ibnu Rabiica iyo    Hilaal ibnu Umaya (RC).    "},{"question":"සාපේක්ෂතා වාදය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සාපේක්ෂතාවාදය ඇල්බට් අයින්ස්ටයින් විසින් සකස් කරන ලද විශේෂ සහ සාමාන්‍ය සාපේක්ෂතාවාදයෙන් සමන්විත වේ. 1905 දී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද විශේෂ සාපේක්‍ෂතාවාදය, කාලය සහ අවකාශය අභ්‍යවකාශ කාලය ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන තනි වස්තුවකට බද්ධ වී ඇත යන අදහස හඳුන්වා දුන්නේය. ආලෝකයේ වේගය ඔවුන්ගේ චලිතය හෝ ආලෝක ප්‍රභවයේ චලිතය කුමක් වුවත්, සියළුම නිරීක්ෂකයින් සඳහා නියත බව ද එය ප්‍රකාශ කළේය. 1915 දී ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කරන ලද සාමාන්‍ය සාපේක්‍ෂතාවාදය, ගුරුත්වාකර්ෂණය ඇතුළත් කිරීම සඳහා මෙම අදහස් දිගු කළ අතර එය ස්කන්ධය හා ශක්තිය නිසා ඇතිවන අවකාශ කාලයේ වක්‍රය ලෙස විස්තර කළේය. මෙම න්‍යායන් මූලික භෞතික විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ අවබෝධයේ විප්ලවීය වෙනසක් ඇති කළ අතර බොහෝ අත්හදා බැලීම් සහ නිරීක්ෂණ මගින් තහවුරු කර ඇත."},{"question":"जपानी पौराणिक कथांमध्ये सुकुनाची कथा काय आहे?","answer":"र्योमेन सुकुना, ज्याला सहसा सुकुना म्हणून संबोधले जाते, ही जपानी लोककथा आणि पौराणिक कथांमधील एक प्रमुख व्यक्ती आहे. तो एक शक्तिशाली आणि द्वेषपूर्ण योकाई (अलौकिक प्राणी) म्हणून ओळखला जातो आणि विविध दंतकथा आणि कथांमधील मध्यवर्ती पात्र आहे. तथापि, हे लक्षात घेणे महत्त्वाचे आहे की कथेची एकच निश्चित आवृत्ती नाही, कारण सुकुनाचे पात्र मौखिक परंपरा, साहित्य आणि पॉप संस्कृतीच्या रूपांतरांद्वारे कालांतराने विकसित झाले आहे.सर्वसाधारणपणे, सुकुना हे दोन चेहरे, प्रत्येक विरुद्ध दिशेने आणि एकच शरीर असलेला एक भयानक राक्षस म्हणून चित्रित केला जातो. \\"र्योमेन सुकुना\\" हे नाव \\"र्योमेन\\" म्हणजे \\"दोन-चेहऱ्याचे\\" यासह आले आहे.सुकुनाचा समावेश असलेल्या सर्वात प्रसिद्ध कथांपैकी एक म्हणजे प्रख्यात भूत आणि अध्यात्मिक माध्यम, अबे नो सेमी यांच्याशी झालेल्या लढाईबद्दल. पौराणिक कथांनुसार, सुकुना एक शक्तिशाली आणि धोकादायक योकाई होता ज्याने लोकांना दहशत दिली. अपवादात्मक आध्यात्मिक शक्ती असलेल्या अबे नो सेमी यांना सुकुनाचा सामना करण्यासाठी आणि त्याच्या द्वेषपूर्ण प्रभावाला वश करण्यासाठी बोलावण्यात आले. भयंकर लढाईनंतर, सेमीने सुकुनाला पराभूत करण्यात आणि त्याच्या शक्तींवर शिक्कामोर्तब केले, ज्यामुळे त्याला आणखी नुकसान होण्यापासून रोखले.संपूर्ण इतिहासात, सुकुनाची कथा पुन्हा सांगितली गेली आहे आणि विविध मार्गांनी त्याचा अर्थ लावला गेला आहे, काहीवेळा ती इतर कथांमध्ये देखील विणली गेली आहे. अलिकडच्या काळात, सुकुनाच्या पात्राला अॅनिमे आणि मांगा सारख्या आधुनिक माध्यमांमध्ये त्याच्या देखाव्यामुळे अतिरिक्त लोकप्रियता मिळाली आहे. सर्वात उल्लेखनीय उदाहरणांपैकी एक म्हणजे अॅनिमे आणि मांगा मालिका \\"जुजुत्सु कैसेन,\\" जिथे सुकुना एक प्रमुख विरोधी आहे. या मालिकेत, सुकुनाला अफाट शक्तीचा एक शापित आत्मा म्हणून चित्रित केले आहे, आणि त्याच्या दंतकथेला शाप, चेटूक आणि भूतविद्या या मोठ्या कथेमध्ये समाविष्ट केले आहे.हे ओळखणे महत्त्वाचे आहे की सुकुनाची कथा स्त्रोत आणि अर्थानुसार तपशीलांमध्ये भिन्न असू शकते, परंतु एक द्वेषपूर्ण योकाई म्हणून त्याची स्थिती आणि अबे नो सेमी सारख्या आध्यात्मिक व्यक्तींशी त्याचा सामना या कथांमध्ये आवर्ती घटक आहेत."},{"question":"Để nhóm một đống lửa lớn làm tín hiệu cầu cứu, yếu tố nào đóng vai trò quan trọng để lửa cháy mạnh?","answer":"các cây gỗ to và bùi nhùi đều cần thiết để giúp bạn có một ngọn lựa mạnh. Nhưng bùi nhùi đóng vao trò then chốt, bởi nếu thêm củi to vào quá sớm, ngọn lửa sẽ tắt. Do đó, cần duy trì lửa bằng bùi nhùi cho đến khi bén tới củi to.Các mẹo để nhóm lửa trong rừng, núi, ngay cả khi môi trường ẩm ướt như sau:- Tìm những que củi và lá thông phủ đầy lớp nhựa để dễ bắt lửa.- Nếu tìm được một khúc củi ẩm, hãy lột bỏ vài lớp vỏ cây bên ngoài, để có phần khô ráo bên trong.- Một khúc củi trơn, nhẵn sẽ không dễ cháy, nên bạn cần chẻ nhỏ củi lớn, làm lộ bề mặt xù xì của chúng.- Bạn cần có nhiên liệu, tia lửa và không khí để đốt một ngọn lửa. Để đảm bảo có nhiều không khí, hãy xếp các khúc củi thành hình tam giác giống chiếc lều vải, hoặc hình lán che để không khí lưu thông trong đó. Một đống củi chồng chất chỉ khiến ngọn lửa bị thiếu không khí và không thể cháy to.- Trước khi bắt đầu chuyến đi, hãy mang theo những chất kích lửa như Vaseline, dung dịch rửa tay hoặc một sản phẩm chuyên dụng. Ngoài ra, bạn cũng có thể chuẩn bị sẵn vụn vải tẩm xăng, dầu và bảo quản trong một túi nhựa mỏng, chắc chắn.- Khi thắp lửa, hãy thắp từ dưới lên và từ phía gió thổi, dùng cơ thể để chặn gió.- Chuẩn bị sẵn nhiều bùi nhủi (lá thông, lá khô, cây bụi), bởi đây là yếu tố quan trọng cho lửa cháy mạnh.- Trong trường hợp gió thổi tắt lửa, hãy đào một cái hố để đốt lửa, nhưng nếu gió không mạnh, bạn nên ưu tiên đốt lửa trên một ụ đất cao."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Fehrbelliner Platz är ett torg i stadsdelen Wilmersdorf i Berlin som är en viktig trafikknutpunkt. Den ligger där Hohenzollerndamm korsar Brandenburgische Strasse. Den har","answer":"fått sitt namn efter staden Fehrbellin och Slaget vid Fehrbellin 1675 då Carl Gustav Wrangels svenska trupper tvingades tillbaka från Mark Brandenburg av kurfürstens trupper."},{"question":"पृथ्वीराज चौहानचा पराभव करून त्याला देहांताची शिक्षा कोणी दिली ?","answer":"पृथ्वीराज चौहानचा पराभव करून त्याला देहांताची शिक्षा मुहम्मद घोरीने दिली "},{"question":"Pourquoi les dinosaures ont-ils disparu ?","answer":"Les scientifiques n'ont pas d'explication précise à la disparition des dinosaures. Ce qui est sûr, c'est que les conditions climatiques auxquelles les dinosaures étaient adaptés ont été modifiées de manière irréversible.Voici quelques hypothèses possibles :- une énorme comète, un météore ou un astéroïde se serait écrasé sur la Terre, formant un panache ardent, puis des nuages se dispersant dans l'atmosphère. En retombant sur la Terre, ces nuages auraient produit des incendies immenses, masquant la lumière du soleil, donc refroidissant le climat et stoppant la photosynthèse.- à l'époque des dinosaures, il y avait beaucoup de volcans à cause de l'activité tectonique qui s'est produite au cours du Crétacé. À l'endroit où il y avait le plus de lave ''sèche'', les dinosaures ont pondu leurs oeufs. La lave s'est alors recouverte de sédiments et les oeufs ont été perdus. De plus, la poussière volcanique véhiculée dans les airs a provoqué le refroidissement du climat de la même manière que le panache ardent provenant de la comète.- les mouvements internes et externes de la Terre tels que le déplacement des continents, les modifications des courants (marins et atmosphériques), le soulèvement des chaînes de montagnes et les séries d'évènements naturels auraient éliminé les climats tropicaux et subtropicaux."},{"question":"வினா : தமிழக – ஆந்திரா எல்லைச் சிக்கல் தீர்க்க அமைக்கப்பட்ட ஆணையம்/குழு எது?A. எஸ்.கே.தார் ஆணையம்B. எச்.வி.படாஸ்கர் குழுC. பாசில் அலி ஆணையம்D. ஜே.வி.பி.குழு","answer":"விடை :  எச்.வி.படாஸ்கர் குழு"},{"question":" sheeg macnah \\"la heed heetiyeen\\"?","answer":" waxay lamid tahay  la ciirciireen"},{"question":"Fale um pouco sobre a origem do queijo coalho","answer":"O Queijo Coalho, tem origem no nordeste brasileiro, não se sabe em que região de origem nem data específica de criação. Mas estudos dizem que ele é produzido há mais de 50 anos, nas primeiras fazendas do sertão nordestino.Era muito comum durante longas jornadas, onde retirantes nordestinos levavam leite em bolsas feitas de estômago de animais, nelas o leite coagulada e dava origem a uma massa, hoje conhecida como Queijo Coalho.Para produzir o queijo so é necessário leite,  o “coalho” renina (enzima digestiva proteolítica) e sal. O processo envolve a fermentação e coagulação do leite, resultando no queijo."},{"question":"I wonder భారతదేశం లో లైంగిక వేధింపుల చట్టం ఎప్పుడు ","answer":"పై పాటలోని భాగం యొక్క అర్థం ఈశ్వరుడే సత్యముసత్యమే శివుడుశివుడే సుందరుడుసత్యం శివం సుందరమంటే ఇదే.'-- లతా మంగేష్కర్ ఆలపించిన, వేకువ ఝామునే శివుని స్తుతిస్తూ, ఆ కుగ్రామంలో శివాలయాన్ని శుభ్రపరచే యువతిగా జీనత్ ఆమన్ నటించిన ఈ గీతం ఏ హిందువు మరువలేనిది. హైందవ ధర్మంలోని భక్తి/ఆధ్యాత్మికతలోనే పురుష లైంగికత శివుని రూపంలో నిగూఢమై ఉన్నదని, అది సత్యమని, అదే సుందరమని ఈ గీతం స్పష్టంగా తెలియజేస్తుంది!!పురుష లైంగికత  (ఆంగ్లం: Human Male Sexuality) అనగా పురుషుల శారీరక/మానసిక/సాంఘిక/సాంస్కృతిక/రాజకీయ లైంగిక స్వభావము, లైంగిక వాంఛలు, లైంగిక చర్యలు, లైంగిక స్పందనలు మరియు వాటి సంబంధిత ప్రక్రియలు. పురుషుల లైంగికతకు సంబంధించిన నీతినియమాలు, మతంలోని పురుష లైంగికతలు కూడా పురుష లైంగికతలో భాగాలే.నేపథ్యంఅనాదిగా పురుష లైంగికత స్త్రీపురుషులిరువురికీ సమానంగా ఆనందోత్సాహాలని ఇచ్చింది. లలిత కళలలో, సంగీతంలో, సాహిత్యంలో అనేకానేకులకు ప్రేరణగా నిలిచింది. జీవరాశి జవసత్వాలతో కొనసాగటానికి భూమిపై జనాభివృద్ధికి కారణభూతమైనది. అయిననూ పురుష లైంగికత సానుకూల అభిప్రాయాన్ని మాత్రం పొందలేకపోయింది.[1]ప్రస్తుత సభ్యసమాజం పురుష లైంగికతను హేయమైనదిగా, మొరటుదనం గలదిగా, మృగతృష్ణగా పొరబడుతోంది. కానీ ఈ దురభిప్రాయానికి విరుద్ధంగా స్త్రీ లైంగికత ఎంత భిన్నమైనదో, క్లిష్టమైనదో, అద్భుతమైనదో పురుష లైంగికత కూడా అంతే భిన్నం, క్లిష్టం, అద్భుతం.హైందవంలో పురుష లైంగికతహిందూమతములో సృష్టి ప్రారంభం నుండే మానవ లైంగికతకు ప్రాధాన్యత ఉంది. దీనిలో భాగంగానే పురుష లైంగికత, స్త్రీ లైంగికతలు అనాదిగా ప్రస్తావించబడినవి.శైవంశివుడి మూర్తీభవించిన రూపమే కాలగతికి చిహ్నం. ఆది పరాశక్తి యొక్క శక్తితో శివుడిలో చలనము కలుగుతుంది. ఈ శక్తితోనే శివుడు విశ్వవినాశనానికి, దాని పునర్నిర్మాణానికి కారకుడౌతాడు. మహాశక్తియే శివుడి భార్య.శివ లింగము, శివుడి పురుషాంగం. శివ లింగము పురుష లైంగికతకు ప్రతీక.లింగ యోని, ఆది పరాశక్తి యొక్క యోని. ఇదే మహాయోని, స్త్రీ సృజనాత్మక శక్తికి ప్రతీక.శివ లింగము యొక్క పరిపూర్ణ రూపం, లింగ యోనిలో అమర్చబడిన లింగము. లింగ యోనుల సంగమం స్త్రీ శక్తియైన నిష్క్రియాత్మక విశ్వం, పురుష శక్తియైన క్రియాత్మక గతుల (కాలాల) అద్వైత ఐక్యతను (ఒకదానితో మరొకటి అల్లుకుపోయి, విడదీయలేనంత బంధాన్ని) సూచిస్తుంది. ఇదే జీవరాశి యొక్క ఉద్భవంగా ఘోషిస్తుందిలింగానికి చేసే ప్రత్యేక పూజలు, భక్తులు..."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la pregunta a: \\"una parcela es una porción de tierra, la cual es parte de un terreno aún mayor, que está delimitada\\"? El tema es terreno.","answer":"\\"¿Qué son las parcelas de tierra?\\""},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"_ no renin'i Jaona Mpanao Batisa sy ny zanaky ny mpiray tampo amin'i Maria Virjiny.\\"","answer":"Valiny: I Elizabeta no renin'i Jaona Mpanao Batisa sady zanaky ny mpiray tampo amin'i Maria Virjiny."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Sêneca para a filosofia?","answer":"Sêneca foi um filósofo estoico romano, conhecido por suas epístolas e ensaios que abordam temas como a virtude, o autocontrole e a aceitação do destino."},{"question":"வினா : ஐரோப்பாவின் விளையாட்டு மைதானம்?","answer":"விடை : சுவிட்சர்லாந்து"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: \\"Covdonga\\" levererades till Spaniens flotta i oktober 1859 och gick som postångare mellan Manilla och Hongkong. År 1863 utbröt krig mellan Spanien och Chile,","answer":"Chinchakriget och \\"Covadonga\\" deltog som ett hjälpfartyg. Hon kapades av den korvetten \\"Esmeralda\\" och överfördes till Chiles flotta. Hösten 1874 gjorde \\"Covadonga\\" forskningsexedition till Desventuradasöarna."},{"question":"ਕੁਹਾੜਾ, 7 ਮਾਰਚਕੁਹਾੜਾ-ਮਾਛੀਵਾੜਾ ਸੜਕ ‘ਤੇ ਸਥਿਤ ਗੁਰੂ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਟੇਡੀਅਮ ਵਿਖੇ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਕਲੱਬ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਬਾਬਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਹਾਦਰ ਦੇ ਫਤਹਿ ਦਿਵਸ ਦੀ ਤੀਜੀ ਸ਼ਤਾਬਦੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਰਪਿਤ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਜਗਜੀਵਨ ਸਿੰਘ  ਖੀਰਨੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਰਪ੍ਰਸਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਲੱਬ ਦੇ ਚੇਅਰਮੈਨ ਜਗਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਪ੍ਰਿਥੀਪੁਰ, ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮਨਮੋਹਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਖੇੜਾ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠ ਕਰਵਾਏ ਇਸ ਕੱਪ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਇਕ ਪਿੰਡ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕਲੱਬ ਦੇ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਕਰਵਾਏ ਗਏ, ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਜੌਹਲਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਨੂੰਪੁਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਹੋਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੌਹਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਡਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਵਧੀਆ ਖੇਡ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਤੇ 41 ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਰੁਪਏ ਦਾ ਇਨਾਮ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ, ਜਦਕਿ ਮਾਨੂੰਪੁਰ ਦੀ ਟੀਮ ਨੇ 31 ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਰੁਪਏ ਦਾ ਇਨਾਮ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਦੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਦਿਨ ਨੌਰਥ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਫੈਡਰੇਸ਼ਨ ਦੀਆਂ 8 ਅਕੈਡਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਹੋਏ, ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਫਾਈਨਲ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਦਸਮੇਸ਼ ਕਲੱਬ ਨਕੋਦਰ ਤੇ ਬੀ.ਸੀ. ਕਲੱਬ ਸਮਰਾਲਾ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਹੋਇਆ। ਦਸਮੇਸ਼ ਕਲੱਬ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਜਿੱਤ ਕੇ 1 ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਏ ਦਾ ਇਨਾਮ ਅਤੇ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ, ਜਦਕਿ ਦੂਜੇ ਨੰਬਰ ‘ਤੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਟੀਮ ਨੂੰ 71 ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਰੁਪਏ ਦਾ ਇਨਾਮ ਮਿਲਿਆ।ਇਸ ਮੌਕੇ ਕੈਬਨਿਟ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਹੀਰਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਗਾਬੜੀਆ, ਪੰਜਾਬ ਮੰਡੀ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਚੇਅਰਮੈਨ ਅਜਮੇਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਲੱਖੋਵਾਲ, ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਡਿਪਟੀ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਚਰਨਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਅਟਵਾਲ, ਪੰਜਾਬ ਐਗਰੋ ਦੇ ਚੇਅਰਮੈਨ ਸ਼ਰਨਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਢਿੱਲੋਂ, ਐਸ.ਐਸ. ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਚੇਅਰਮੈਨ ਸੰਤਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਉਮੈਦਪੁਰੀ, ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਸੁਖਦੇਵ ਸਿੰਘ ਲਿਬੜਾ, ਸ਼ੋ੍ਰਮਣੀ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾਲ ਸਿੰਘ ਖੀਰਨੀਆਂ, ਐਸ.ਓ.ਆਈ. ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਗੁਰਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਰਾਜੂ ਖੰਨਾ, ਹਲਕਾ ਕੂੰਮ ਕਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਈਸ਼ਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਮੇਹਰਬਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਭÇਲੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਭੰਡਾਲ ਨੇ ਹਾਜ਼ਰੀ ਲਗਵਾਈ।ਬਾਬਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਬਹਾਦੁਰ ਫਤਿਹ ਦਿਵਸ ਦੀ ਤੀਸਰੀ ਸ਼ਤਾਬਦੀ ਮੌਕੇ ਕਿਸ ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਕਲੱਬ ਨੇ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ?","answer":"ਇਸ ਕਬੱਡੀ ਕੱਪ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਸ਼੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਸਿੰਘ ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਕਲੱਬ ਨੇ ਕੀਤਾ।"},{"question":"من هو مؤلف كتاب (تاريخ الرسل والملوك)؟","answer":"الطبري"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਭ ਕਰਹਿ ਉਸਤਤਿ ਜਿਨਿ ਫਾਥੇ ਕਾਢਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਤੁਧਨੋ ਕਰਹਿ ਸਭ ਨਮਸਕਾਰੁ ਜਿਨਿ ਪਾਪੈ ਤੇ ਰਾਖਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਿਮਾਣਿਆ ਤੂੰ ਮਾਣੁ ਹਰਿ ਡਾਢੀ ਹੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਡਾਢਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀਆ ਮਾਰਿ ਨਿਵਾਏ ਮਨਮੁਖ ਮੂੜ ਸਾਧਿਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤਾ ਦੇਇ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਗਰੀਬ ਅਨਾਥਿਆ ॥੧੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 90 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਸਭ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੀ (ਹੀ) ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਸ ਤੂੰ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ) ਫਸਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਢਿਆ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਸਭ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਸਿਰ ਨਵਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਸ ਤੂੰ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਪਾਪਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਤੇ ਆਦਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ, ਤੂੰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਣ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵਧੀਕ ਡਾਢਾ ਹੈਂ (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਬਿਪਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਪਾ ਕੇ) ਨਿਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੂਰਖ ਮਨਮੁਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿੱਧੇ ਰਾਹੇ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਹੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਗਰੀਬ ਤੇ ਅਨਾਥ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਦਰ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧੭।\\""},{"question":"Quantos olhos a maior parte das aranhas têm?","answer":"A maior parte das aranhas possuem oito olhos (família Salticidae), porém dois (Dysderidae), quatro (Tetrablemma) ou seis (Caponiidae) deles podem estar ausentes, e, em algumas aranhas de caverna, todos estão ausentes (p. ex. em Sinopoda scurion). Normalmente, os olhos estão dispostos em duas fileiras curvas (às vezes três fileiras), sendo então denominados olhos anteriores laterais, olhos medianos laterais, olhos posteriores laterais e olhos posteriores medianos. Os olhos podem ainda ocorrer agrupados numa elevação denominada cômoro ocular. "},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 空港やホテル　観光に来た外国人などで混んでいる","answer":"成田空港は、観光に来た外国人などで混んでいます。日本に入る人の数は3月下旬から、新型コロナウイルスが広がる前と同じぐらいになっています。空港は6日、3年前から閉めていた入国審査の場所をまた使い始めました。シンガポールから夫婦で来た男性は「コロナでしばらく日本に来ることができませんでした。京都の天橋立を見に行くのが楽しみです」と話していました。東京のホテルも、観光に来た外国人などで混んでいます。東京の浅草にあるホテルは3月からほとんど毎日、全部の部屋に予約が入っています。ホテルの人は「お客さんが増えて、少しずつホテルの値段が上がっています」と話していました。旅行の専門家は4月下旬からの連休に旅行を計画している人に、「人気の場所から電車で30分ぐらい離れたホテルはまだ部屋があって、値段も安くなります」と言っています。"},{"question":"七味唐辛子に入っている「陳皮」といったら、何の皮のことでしょう？","answer":"ミカン"},{"question":"ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਵਾਕ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਨਾਂਵ ਚੁਣਨ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਵੀ ਦੱਸੇ । ਸ਼ੇਰ ਜੰਗਲ਼ ਦਾ ਰਾਜਾ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।","answer":"ਸ਼ੇਰ, ਜੰਗਲ, ਰਾਜਾ ।"},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Avo izy rehefa mipetraka nohon'ny mitsangana.\\"","answer":"Valiny : alika. Ny ahavon'ny alika rehefa mipetraka mbola avo noho izy mitsangana.\\""},{"question":"Immisa madaxwayne ayaa soomaray Somaliland?","answer":"waxaa soomaray shan madaxwayne"},{"question":"Amfanin Makamai a wajan mai farauta?","answer":"Makami shi ne kayan aikin mafarauci. Yana amfani da kayayyakin da suka haɗa da wuƙa, adda, takobi, barandami, tsitaka, gariyo, kwari-da-baka, bindiga, kulki, gora, kokara, ƙaho, kere, ruzu, buzu, da sauransu."},{"question":"لدينا المقال التالي: بعدما تلغاو التراويح وصلاة العيد، قام الملك محمد السادس، مرفوقا بولي العهد الأمير مولاي الحسن، والأمير مولاي رشيد، اليوم الأربعاء 20 ماي 2020، بإحياء ليلة القدر عن بعد. وبهاد المناسبة الدينية، أدى الملك  العشاء والتراويح. كما قام وزير الأوقاف والشؤون الإسلامية بختم صحيح البخاري بين يدي الملك. محمد السادس، اختار إحياء ليلة القدر بهاد الطريقة، في إطار احترام الحجر الصحي، والالتزام بالتدابير الوقائية والاحترازية، اللي اتخذتها بلادنا لمواجهة جائحة فيروس كورونا”. وهادي أول مرة يتم فيها احياء لـ”ليلة 27″ بطريقة التباعد الاجتماعي، منذ تولي الملك العرش.. قم بتلخيصة!","answer":"هذا تلخيص للمقال السابق: بسباب “كورونا”.. الملك احيى ليلة القدر عن بعد لاول مرة منذ توليه العرش."},{"question":"سوال این است که: \\"اگر چه در گذشته فرضیه های مختلفی برای منشأ آن وجود داشته است، در حال حاضر پذیرفته شده ترین توضیح این است که ماه از بقایای باقی مانده پس از یک برخورد عظیم بین زمین و یک جسم به اندازه مریخ شکل گرفته است\\". این متن درباره چه موضوعی است؟","answer":"ماه چگونه بوجود آمد"},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây.Câu hỏi: Đường sắt Việt Nam nối liền với đường sắt của quốc gia nào?A. Trung QuốcB. CampuchiaC. Lào","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: A. Trung QuốcGiải thích: Hiện nay, đường sắt Việt Nam kết nối với đường sắt Trung Quốc và thông qua Trung Quốc sang các nước Trung Á, từ đó đi châu Âu, Trung Đông. Tàu của Việt Nam có thể chạy sang đường sắt Trung Quốc qua hai ga ở cửa khẩu: Ga Lào Cai tuyến Hà Nội - Lào Cai và ga Đồng Đăng tuyến Hà Nội - Đồng Đăng (tỉnh Lạng Sơn).Tuyến đường sắt qua Lào Cai sẽ tới Vân Nam (Trung Quốc), còn qua Lạng Sơn tới Quảng Tây (Trung Quốc)."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\" Sasa-poana manao saha maina, fa _\\"","answer":"\\"Sasa-poana manao saha maina, fa tsy ho tompon-tanàna akory.\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਰੈਣਿ ਸੁਹਾਵੜੀ ਦਿਨਸੁ ਸੁਹੇਲਾ ॥ਜਪਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਸੰਤਸੰਗਿ ਮੇਲਾ ॥ਘੜੀ ਮੂਰਤ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਪਲ ਵੰਞਹਿ ਜੀਵਣੁ ਸਫਲੁ ਤਿਥਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਸਿਮਰਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਦੋਖ ਸਭਿ ਲਾਥੇ ॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਾਥੇ ॥ਭੈ ਭਉ ਭਰਮੁ ਖੋਇਆ ਗੁਰਿ ਪੂਰੈ ਦੇਖਾ ਸਭਨੀ ਜਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਮਰਥੁ ਵਡ ਊਚ ਅਪਾਰਾ ॥ਨਉ ਨਿਧਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਭਰੇ ਭੰਡਾਰਾ ॥ਆਦਿ ਅੰਤਿ ਮਧਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸੋਈ ਦੂਜਾ ਲਵੈ ਨ ਲਾਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਮੇਰੇ ਦੀਨ ਦਇਆਲਾ ॥ਜਾਚਿਕੁ ਜਾਚੈ ਸਾਧ ਰਵਾਲਾ ॥ਦੇਹਿ ਦਾਨੁ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਜਨੁ ਮਾਗੈ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਈ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੩੮॥੪੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 107 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਰਾਤ ਸੁਹਾਵਣੀ ਬੀਤਦੀ ਹੈ, ਦਿਨ ਭੀ ਸੌਖਾ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਜੇ) ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਲ (ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ਤਾਂ ਉਥੇ) ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਜਪੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਉਮਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਘੜੀਆਂ ਦੋ ਘੜੀਆਂ ਪਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਿਆਂ ਬੀਤਣ ਉਥੇ ਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ (ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ) ਸਫਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਿਆਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਾਪ ਲਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ) ਨਾਲ (ਵੱਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਤ) ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਅਦਬ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਾਲਾ ਡਰ ਮੁਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਭ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।੨।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਭ ਤਾਕਤਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਉੱਚਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਮਾਨੋ, ਜਗਤ ਦੇ) ਨੌ ਹੀ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਹੈ, (ਨਾਮ ਧਨ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਭਰੇ ਪਏ ਹਨ । (ਸੰਸਾਰ ਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ) ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਸੀ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ) ਅੰਤ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ (ਹੁਣ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਰਚਨਾ ਦੇ) ਮੱਧ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੈ । ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝ ਸਕਦਾ ।੩।ਹੇ ਦੀਨਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! (ਮੇਰੇ ਉਤੇ) ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ । (ਤੇਰਾ ਇਹ) ਮੰਗਤਾ (ਤੇਰੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਧੂੜ ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਤੇਰਾ) ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ (ਤੈਥੋਂ) ਮੰਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਇਹ) ਦਾਨ ਦੇਹਿ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ, ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ! ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ (ਤੈਨੂੰ) ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ ।੪।੩੮।੪੫।\\""},{"question":"東海道・山陽新幹線の駅で、「小さい」という漢字がつく駅はいくつかありますが、「大きい」という漢字がついている唯一の駅は何でしょう？","answer":"新大阪駅です。"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk hati dan limpa goreng kunyit? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 300 gm hati & limpa, 1 biji bawang besar, 3 ulas bawang putih, 4 batang kacang panjang, 3 biji cili padi, ½ sudu kecil serbuk kunyit, ½ sudu kecil garam, ½ sudu kecil sebuk lada hitam, serbuk perasa, 3 sudu besar minyak masak.Cara penyediaan:1. Potong dadu hati, potong nipis limpa, kerana limpa lebih susah empuk berbanding hati. Rendam sekejap (10 minit) dalam air yang dicampur tepung gandum untuk menghilangkan bau hamis lembu. Kemudian bilas dan tuskan.2. Gaulkan hati dan limpa dengan serbuk kunyit, garam dan serbuk perasa (jika suka).3. Hiris bulat bawang besar dan hiris nipis bawang putih.4. Potong kacang panjang dan cili padi.Cara memasak:1. Masukkan hati dan limpa lembu ke dalam kuali. Masukkan air hingga tenggelam hati & limpa danmasukkan sesudu besar minyak. Rebus dengan api sederhana sehingga empuk.2. Setelah hati dan limpa empuk dan air kering, masukkan minyak selebihnya. Goreng sambil mengacau sehingga hati dan limpa garing mengikut citarasa anda.3. Masukkan kacang panjang, bawang putih dan lada hitam. Kacau sekejap. Kemudian masukkan hirisan bawang besar, cili padi dan kacau sehingga bawang layu.4. Matikan api, angkat dan hidangkan."},{"question":"自動車にかける保険で、加入が義務付けられている「強制保険」に対し、加入が当事者の意志に任せられているものを何というでしょう？","answer":"任意保険です。"},{"question":"Iza moa i Nelson Mandela?","answer":"Nelson Mandela dia mpanao politika, mpanoratra ny tantaran'ny fiainany mizaka ny zom-pirenen'i Afrika Atsimo teraka ny 18 Jolay 1918 ary maty ny 5 Desambra 2013."},{"question":"Asiko wahala awọn oloṣelu West ni 1965 ni Adeyinka Oyekan di ‘Ọba of Lagos’","answer":"Ni ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu keji, ọdun 1965, lasiko ti ija awọn oloṣelu ilẹ Yoruba n gbona gan-an, paapaa ija laarin awọn ọmọlẹyin Awolọwọ ati Akintọla pẹlu awọn eeyan rẹ, ọjọ naa ni wọn kede Adeyinka Oyekan, gẹgẹ bii ọba ilu Eko tuntun.Aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii igba naa, Nnamdi Azikiwe, lo fọwọ si iwe naa, iyẹn iwe to sọ Oyekan di ọba. Lati igba ti Ọba Musẹndiku Adele, si ti waja ninu oṣu keje, ọdun 1964, igba naa ni wahala ti bẹrẹ, ti awọn ọmọọba loriṣiiriṣii si ti dide, ṣugbọn ninu gbogbo awọn ti wọn dide yii, ọpọ lo dide nitori wọn ko fẹ ki Oyekan di “Oba of Lagos”, wọn ni o san ki ẹlomi-in jẹ ẹ ju ko jẹ Oyekan ni yoo di ọba le awọn lori lọ. Ọta pọ fun ọkunrin naa, awọn oloye ilu ti ko si fẹ ko jọba pọ ju awọn ti wọn fẹ ẹ lọba lọ. Ko si si ohun to fa a ju ọrọ oṣelu ati ijọba to ti wa nilẹ tẹlẹ lọ. Ija naa pọ gan-an ni.Ohun to fa a niyi to jẹ nigba ti oniṣẹ de lati ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ abẹle ni Naijiria nigba naa, iyẹn Ọgbẹni I. A. Wemambu, to si mu lẹta naa wa fun Oyekan ni ile rẹ ni Opopona Garba Square, ni bii aago marun-un kọja iṣẹju mẹwaa, ohun to kọkọ ti ẹnu ẹ jade ni, “Ọlọrun doju tẹyin ọlọtẹ!” Ṣe awọn oniroyin ti gbọ tẹlẹ, nigba ti wọn yoo si fun un ni lẹta, oju wọn lo ṣe. Bo ti gba lẹta naa lo doju kọ wọn, ohun to si sọ ni pe, “Iwe ti mo gba yii, Ọlọrun gbe mi bori gbogbo awọn oniṣẹ ibi ni. O gbe mi leke gbogbo awọn ẹni aburu. Ohun ti mo ṣe sọ bẹẹ ni pe ọmọ ọdun mẹrinla ni mo wa ti baba to bi mi ti sọ fun mi pe mo maa jọba Eko, ṣugbọn awọn kan ti wa nibi kan ti wọn ko fẹ ko ṣee ṣe. Ṣugbọn o ti ṣee ṣe loju wọn bayii, nitori iwe ti wọn gbe le mi lọwọ yii, iwe ipesiṣẹ ni, wọn ni ki n waa ṣiṣẹ fun ilu ni, ma a si ṣe e daadaa.“Bi mo ṣe wa yii, mo ti pinnu pe n ko ni i ba oloṣelu tabi ẹgbẹ oṣelu kankan ṣe, mo fẹẹ da duro temi ni. Ṣugbọn ko sẹni to le pa ohun mọ agogo lẹnu, n oo sọ gbogbo ọrọ yoowu to ba wa lọkan mi jade, bi nnkan ba si ṣe ri ni mo ṣe maa sọ ọ. Bi emi ba sọ temi o, ohun to ba wu ijọba lo le ṣe, ṣugbọn mo maa wi tẹnu mi, bo tilẹ jẹ ijọba lo laṣẹ. Ijọba to wa lode bayii, ijọba to ṣe deede, ijọba ti ki i gbe sẹyin ẹnikan ni, o wu mi ko jẹ bi wọn ṣe maa maa ṣe e lọ naa niyẹn. Wọn ti fun mi niwee aṣẹ, wọn ti fun mi ni lẹta, bi ohun gbogbo ba si lọ bo ṣe yẹ ko lọ, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu yii, ni wọn maa de fila fun mi gẹgẹ bii ọba Eko, ko sohun to tun le fa idiwọ mọ. Ọkan pataki ninu iṣẹ ti mo fẹẹ sare ṣe ni lati kọ gbagede nla kan fawọn ọdọ wa, nibi ti wọn aa ti maa ṣere, ti wọn aa maa kọ ẹkọ loriṣiiriṣii, nitori ko ti i si aaye igbafẹ kankan fun wọn laarin Eko.”Igba naa ni Adeyinka Oyekan sọrọ pe ko si irẹpọ laarin awọn ọba Yoruba, lara iṣẹ oun si ni lati ri i pe irẹpọ de saarin awọn ọba ilẹ Yoruba gbogbo. Oyekan ni ọrọ oṣẹlu lo n da wahala awọn ọba yii silẹ, nitori ẹ loun ko ṣe ni i ba wọn da si oṣelu rara. Bi Oyekan ba sọ bayii, tabi to ba n sọrọ si awọn kan to pe ni ọta ara rẹ, o mọ idi to fi n wi bẹẹ o jare. Ori ko pe oun fẹẹ ba ọrun duro, lati di ọba fun Oyekan, irinajo ọjọ pipẹ gbaa ni, o si ni wahala gidi ninu. Ohun to si fa wahala naa ni pe Oyekan naa paapaa ti fi igba kan sun mọ awọn oloṣelu pẹkipẹki. Ọrẹ loun ati Nnamdi Azikiwe, nitori bẹẹ, ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ lo fi si lọdọ, ko too di ọba rara ni o, nigba to fi n ṣe iṣẹ apoogun ni Ọsibitu gbogbogboo (General Hospital). Nitori bẹẹ, oun naa ti gbojule pe ko si igbakigba ti aaye ọba ṣi silẹ, oun loun yoo jẹ ọba naa dandan.Bo ti n ronu niyi nigba ti Ọba Falolu ku ni ọjọ keji, oṣu kẹṣan-an, ọdun 1949. Nigba naa, ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogoji ni Oyekan, o si ti ṣiṣẹ o ti lowo, o si ti ro pe ko si ohun ti ko ni i jẹ ki oun di ọba Eko, paapaa pẹlu atilẹyin ẹgbẹ NCNC, ẹgbẹ to lagbara gan-an nilẹ Yoruba, ati ni Naijiria nigba naa. Awọn aṣaaju NCNC naa ti mura silẹ, wọn si ni ko si wahala fun un, yoo di ọba Eko yii ni. Ṣugbọn ọmọọba kan wa to n jẹ Musẹndiku Adeniji Adele, ọmọ ọdun mẹrindinlọgọta loun ni 1949 yii, iyẹn ni pe o fi ọdun mejidinlogun ju Adeyinka Oyekan lọ. Yatọ si eyi, ọkan pataki ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Oduduwa ti Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ da silẹ ni, bẹẹ naa lo si jẹ alatilẹyin ẹgbẹ ọdọ Naijiria, ‘Nigeria Youth Movement’, ọkan ninu awọn aṣaaju wọn l’Ekoo ni. Yatọ si eyi, oṣiṣẹ ijọba Eko ni, o si lẹsẹ, bẹẹ lo lẹnu daadaa ju Oyekan lọ.Bi a ba ti yọwọ agbara ati atilẹyin ẹgbẹ oṣelu ti Oyekan n reti nigba naa, ko si bo ṣe le duro lẹgbẹẹ Musẹndiku Adele, nitori ẹni ti ọpọ eeyan mọ ni, ẹni to si ti ṣe oriṣiiriṣii nnkan meremere si Eko nigba ti ko tilẹ ti i di ọba wọn ni. Ọpọ ẹgbẹ awọn ara Eko lo jẹ oun ni baba isalẹ fun wọn, awọn mi-in si wa to jẹ oun gan-an lo da wọn silẹ fun ilọsiwaju Eko, lati igba ti oun naa ko ti ju ọmọ ọgbọn ọdun lọ lo ti wa lẹnu akitiyan bẹẹ, to si ṣe e titi to fi n lọ si bii ọgọta ọdun. Nitori bẹẹ, ọpọ eeyan foju si i lara pe oun ni Ọba Eko tọ si. Ṣugbọn boya nitori pe baba tiẹ ti sọ fun un nigba to wa lọmọ ọdun mẹrinla pe yoo jọba Eko, tabi ti awọn olosẹlu ti wọn n ti i lẹyin, Oyekan nigbagbọ pe asiko toun niyẹn, oun si gbọdọ di ọba naa dandan ni. N lo ba bẹrẹ si i ṣa awọn eeyan jọ, kia loun naa si ti lero lẹyin, ti awọn naa n sọ pe oun n 0i ipo ọba tọ si.Awọn NCNC naa n rin si i, wọn o duro rara, ṣugbọn awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ Oduduwa, ati awọn alatilẹyin wọn nigba naa ti wọn jọ jẹ ojulowo ọmọ Yoruba, ti wọn si lagbara gidi niwaju ijọba oyinbo rin si ọrọ Adele naa, lọjọ gan-an ti ọkunrin naa si fẹyinti ninu iṣẹ ijọba ni wọn kede ẹ bii Ọba Eko, wọn si gbe ade le e lori lọjọ keji. Ọgbọnjọ, oṣu kẹsan-an, 1949, nirọlẹ, ni wọn kede rẹ, asiko si ti kọja ti ẹnikẹni le gba ile-ẹjọ lọ, bi ilẹ si ti n mọ ni ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kẹwaa, ni wọn de fila ọba fun un. N lo ba di ọba Eko, ọrọ naa jo ẹgbẹ oṣelu NCNC lara, ati Oyekan ti wọn n ti lẹyin, nitori awọn ko mọ pe ọna ti wọn yoo gba yọ si awọn niyẹn. Wọn ti ro pe bi ọjọ Mọnde kan ni wọn yoo kede orukọ ẹni ti wọn ba fẹẹ fi jọba, wọn si ti mura silẹ pe to ba ti le jẹ Adele ni, awọn n gba ile-ẹjọ lọ lati gbegi dina pe wọn ko gbọdọ sọ ọ dọba Eko rara.Nigba ti ọrọ waa ri bayii, awọn NCNC ati Oyekan ni awọn ko gba, wọn ni awọn ko ni i jẹ ki Adele wọ inu aafin gẹgẹ bii ọba, wọn ni ko ni i de Iga Iduganran nitori ki i ṣe ọmọ Dosunmu, wọn ni ki wọn ma fi i jẹ ọba Eko, ko wa ibomi-in ti yoo ti jọba. Ohun ti wọn tori ẹ gbe e dele-ẹjọ ni pe ki i ṣe ọmọ Dosumu, ko le duro si Iga Iduganran, nibi ti aafin awọn ọba Eko wa. Ohun ti wọn gbojule ni pe bi ile-ẹjọ ba le da awọn lare eyi, ti wọn ni ki Adeniji Adele ma de Iga, wọn yoo ni ko yẹ ni ẹni to gbọdọ jẹ ọba Eko niyẹn, ko yaa gbe ade silẹ fun alade, a ṣe pe Oyekan ni yoo di Ọba Eko niyẹn. Bi ọrọ naa ti di wahala gidi ree, ti Oyekan pe Adele lẹjọ, ti awọn NCNC ti i lẹyin, ti wọn si n sọ pe Musẹndiku Adeniji Adele ti wọn gbe ade fun ko ni i di Ọba Eko, Adeyinka Oyekan ni yo pada di ọba."},{"question":"OECDs tal fra 2018 for dødeligheden af hjerte-kar-sygdomme viser, at den i Danmark ligger på 191 pr. 100.000 indbyggere. Sammenligner vi med de andre nordiske lande, ","answer":"er dødeligheden af hjerte-kar-sygdomme i Finland 270, i Sverige 246, i Norge 204 og i Island 214 pr. 100.000 indbyggere."},{"question":"வினா: ஈசாப் நீதிக் கதைகள் ஏதேனும் ஒன்று கூறுக ","answer":"     விடை:  சேவலும் இரத்தினக் கல்லும் அது ஒரு அழகிய பனிக்காலம். சேவல் ஒன்று வழக்கம் போல் காலையில் எழுந்து அதற்கான உணவைத்தேட தன் நண்பர்களுடன் கிளம்பியது. அந்த சேவல் தொலைவில் ஒரு குப்பைக் கிடங்கை கண்டது.அந்த குப்பைக் கிடங்கில் ஏதாவது உணவு கிடைக்குமா என்ற எண்ணத்துடன் கிளற ஆரம்பித்தது. அப்போது அந்த சேவலுக்கு விலை மதிப்பில்லாத இரத்தினக்கல் ஒன்று கிடைத்தது.அந்த கல்லை சேவல் திருப்பித் திருப்பிப் போட்டது. அதைக் கண்ட மற்றொரு சேவல் வருத்தமுடன் \\"இந்த கல் நமக்கு கிடைத்து என்ன பயன்? ஒரு இரத்தின வியாபாரியின் கையில் இது கிடைத்திருந்தால் அவனுக்கு இதன் மதிப்பு தெரியும். நமக்கோ இந்த கல்லை விட சிறிது தாணியம் கிடைத்திருந்தால் அதுவே விலை மதிப்பில்லாத பொருளாக இருக்கும்\\" இந்த கல் நமக்கு உதவாது என்று கூறியது.நீதி: ஒருவருக்கு பயன்படும் பொருளே அவர்களுக்குச் சிறந்ததாகும்."},{"question":"அறிவியல் செய்திகளை வெளிப்படுத்தும் கவிதைகளைத் தொகுத்து வகுப்பறையில் படித்துக் காட்டுக.","answer":"அ) நீர்நின் றிளகிற் றிதுவேண்டா– சீவகசிந்தாமணி (காந்தருவதத்தை இலம்பகம்)அறிவியல் செய்தி:மரத்தில் செய்யப்படும் வீணையே இன்னிசை எழுப்ப ஏற்றது. மரத்தின் ஈரத்தன்மைக்கு ஏற்ப அதில் மோதும் ஒலி அலைகளின் அதிர்வெண்ணும் வேறுபடும். சீவகன், தத்தை கொடுத்த யாழினை ஆராயும் போது, நீரில் இருந்து ஊறிய மரத்தால் செய்யப்பட்ட யாழில், அதிர்வெண் வேறுபட்டு சமச்சீரற்று காணப்படும் என்பதால் “நீர்நின் றிளகிற் றிதுவேண்டா” என்றான்.ஆ) “அணுவைத் துளைத்து ஏழ்கடலைப் புகட்டி” – ஔவையார்“ஓர் அணுவினைச் சதகூறிட்ட கோணினும் உளன்” – கம்பர்அறிவியல் செய்தி:அணுவைப் பிளக்கவும், சேர்க்கவும் முடியும் என்ற இன்றைய அறிவியலை நம் கவிஞர்கள் அன்றே தம் கவிதைகளில் கூறியுள்ளனர். அணுசேர்ப்பும், அணுப்பிரிப்பும் பற்றிய கருத்துகள் அன்றே அரும்பியுள்ளன.இ) “அகல்வயல் பொழிந்தும்…….உறுமிடத் துதவா உவர்நிலம்…….” – புறநானூறு பரணர்“பயவாக் களரணையர் கல்லாதவர்” – திருவள்ளுவர்அறிவியல் செய்தி:எவ்வளவு மழை பொழிந்தாலும் “களர்நிலம்” என அழைக்கப்படும் உவர்நிலம் எதற்கும் உதவாது என்ற மண்ணியல் அறிவியலைக் கூறுகிறது.இவ்வாறு நம் தமிழ்ப் புலவர்கள் இயற்றிய கவிதைகள் பல, நமக்கு அறிவியல் செய்திகளைக் கூறுவதாக உள்ளன என்பதை மறுக்க இயலாது."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kuih gegatas yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: ½ biji kelapa parut, 2 cawan tepung pulut, 2 senduk tepung gandum, 1 sudu kecil garam, Air secukupnya, GulaCara-cara:1. Campurkan kelapa parut, tepung pulut, tepung gandum dan garam dalam satu bekas.2. Kemudian uli adunan dengan air hingga adunan tak melekat pada tangan.3. Kemudian, bentukkan menjadi adunan.4. Goreng kuih dengan menggunakan api sederhana sehingga kekuningan.5. Sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"Rispondi: Cosa è \\"Korfball\\"?","answer":"Il korfball è uno sport di squadra originario dei Paesi Bassi, ideato da un insegnante di Amsterdam, Nico Broekhuyzen, nel 1902. Questa disciplina atletica si pratica su campo, a forma rettangolare, lungo 60 m e largo 30 m all'aperto o lungo 40 m e largo 20 m al coperto. Il campo è diviso in due zone uguali nelle quali, a inizio partita, si schierano due squadre: ogni squadra è composta da quattro donne e quattro uomini. In ogni metà campo, posizionato ad una distanza pari ad un terzo dal fondo, sono posti due pali alti 3,5 m. che sostengono due canestri in plastica di forma circolare. Ogni canestro realizzato vale un punto e la partita è vinta da chi realizza più punti in 70 minuti, divisi in due tempi di 35, su campo all'aperto o in 60 minuti, divisi in due tempi di 30, su campo al coperto: il riposo tra tempi dura 10 minuti. La palla usata è sferica in gomma e pesa 445-475 g. A parte il palleggio di controllo, non è ammesso palleggiare. Non si può rubare la palla se non su intercettazione nei passaggi. Non è ammesso il contatto fisico. Ogni difensore può difendere solo attaccanti del suo stesso sesso: in caso contrario si procederà con il free-pass. Non si può tirare se marcati; in caso si tirasse marcati il korf viene annullato e si procede con una rimessa a favore della squadra in difesa. Nel caso in cui avvenga un fallo nell'azione di tiro o semplicemente l'attaccante venga ostacolato da un difensore di sesso diverso dal suo si procederà con il penalty, a meno che non venga realizzato il korf. Il difensore si considera in atteggiamento non difensivo se tiene le braccia basse dietro la schiena. Ogni 2 korf totali i 4 giocatori in attacco vanno in difesa e viceversa."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ॥ਹਉ ਪੰਥੁ ਦਸਾਈ ਨਿਤ ਖੜੀ ਕੋਈ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਦਸੇ ਤਿਨਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਰਾਵਿਆ ਤਿਨ ਪੀਛੈ ਲਾਗਿ ਫਿਰਾਉ ॥ਕਰਿ ਮਿੰਨਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੋਦੜੀ ਮੈ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਮਿਲਣੈ ਕਾ ਚਾਉ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ਜਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਮੋ ਕਉ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥ਹਉ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਵਿਟਹੁ ਵਾਰਿਆ ਜਿਨਿ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਦੀਆ ਦਿਖਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਹੋਇ ਨਿਮਾਣੀ ਢਹਿ ਪਵਾ ਪੂਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪਾਸਿ ॥ਨਿਮਾਣਿਆ ਗੁਰੁ ਮਾਣੁ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਕਰੇ ਸਾਬਾਸਿ ॥ਹਉ ਗੁਰੁ ਸਾਲਾਹਿ ਨ ਰਜਊ ਮੈ ਮੇਲੇ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਪਾਸਿ ॥੨॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਨੋ ਸਭ ਕੋ ਲੋਚਦਾ ਜੇਤਾ ਜਗਤੁ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਭਾਗਾ ਦਰਸਨੁ ਨਾ ਥੀਐ ਭਾਗਹੀਣ ਬਹਿ ਰੋਇ ॥ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਭਾਣਾ ਸੋ ਥੀਆ ਧੁਰਿ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਨ ਮੇਟੈ ਕੋਇ ॥੩॥ਆਪੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਆਪਿ ਹਰਿ ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥ਆਪਿ ਦਇਆ ਕਰਿ ਮੇਲਸੀ ਗੁਰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪੀਛੈ ਪਾਇ ॥ਸਭੁ ਜਗਜੀਵਨੁ ਜਗਿ ਆਪਿ ਹੈ ਨਾਨਕ ਜਲੁ ਜਲਹਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੪॥੪॥੬੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 41 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ (ਤਾਂਘ ਵਿਚ) ਖਲੋਤੀ ਹੋਈ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਦੇਸ ਦਾ) ਰਾਹ ਪੁੱਛਦੀ ਹਾਂ (ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਲੋਚਦੀ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ) ਕੋਈ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸ ਪਾਏ, ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਹੈਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਪਹੁੰਚਾਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ (ਸਤਿਸੰਗੀ ਸਹੇਲੀਆਂ) ਨੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਤਰਲਾ ਕਰਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਲੱਗੀ ਫਿਰਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਤਰਲਾ ਕਰਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਲੱਗੀ ਫਿਰਾਂ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਦਾ ਚਾਉ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਰਾਵੋ ! ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਧਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲਾ ਦਿਉ (ਪਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੌਣ ਮਿਲਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ?) ਮੈਂ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਖਾਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੋ ਵਿਖਾਲ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਲੋਚਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਮੈਂ ਹੋਰ ਮਾਨ ਆਸਰਾ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਡਿੱਗ ਪਵਾਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਣ-ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ, (ਨਿਮਾਣਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦਿਲਾਸਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਕਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਰੱਜਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ । ਗੁਰੂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ-ਪਾਸ-ਹੀ-ਵੱਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲਾਣ ਦੇ ਸਮਰੱਥ ਹੈ ।੨। ਜਿਤਨਾ ਇਹ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਹੈ ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਲਈ ਤਾਂਘਦਾ ਹੈਪਰ ਚੰਗੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ) । (ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਵਿੱਛੁੜ ਕੇ) ਮੰਦ-ਭਾਗਣ ਜੀਵ‑ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਬੈਠੀ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਧੁਰੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਲਿਖੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਮਿਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।੩। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ) ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ  ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਲੜ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾਣ ਦੇ ਸਮਰੱਥ ਹੈਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜਗਤ (ਦੇ-ਜੀਵਾਂ)-ਦਾ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਆਪ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਇਉਂ ਇਕ-ਮਿਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਪਾਣੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ-ਰੂਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੪।੬੮।\\""},{"question":"Hebben de volgende twee zinnen de zelfde betekenis? Ja of nee?1) In 1927 trouwde Seale met Marion (Ann) Bothwell, een medestudent van Oregon State. Ze kregen twee kinderen: zoon Lindley Jr. en dochter Bonnie. 2) In 1927 trouwde Seale en Marion (Ann) Bothwell, zij was een klasgenote van hem in Oregon State. Het stel kreeg twee kinderen: zoon Lindley Jr. en dochter Bonnie. ","answer":"Ja."},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং তারপর অনুচ্ছেদটি হিসাবে একই ভাষায় পরে প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিনঃ  প্যাসেজ: নেপোলিয়নের মৃত্যুর পর, লংউড হাউস ইস্ট ইন্ডিয়া কোম্পানি এবং পরে ক্রাউন-এর কাছে ফিরে আসে এবং কৃষি উদ্দেশ্যে ব্যবহৃত হয়। এর অবহেলার খবর নেপোলিয়ন তৃতীয়ের কাছে পৌঁছেছিল, যিনি ১৮৫৪ সাল থেকে ব্রিটিশ সরকারের সাথে ফ্রান্সে স্থানান্তরের জন্য আলোচনা করেছিলেন। ১৮৫৮ সালে এটি ফরাসি সরকারের কাছে হস্তান্তর করা হয়, টুম্বের উপত্যকার সাথে ৭,১০০ পাউন্ডের বিনিময়ে। তখন থেকে তারা ফরাসি পররাষ্ট্র মন্ত্রণালয়ের নিয়ন্ত্রণে ছিল এবং একটি ফরাসি সরকারের প্রতিনিধি দ্বীপে বসবাস করেছে এবং উভয় সম্পত্তি পরিচালনার জন্য দায়ী ছিল। ১৯৫৯ সালে তৃতীয় সম্পত্তি, দ্য ব্রায়ার্স, যেখানে লংউড প্রস্তুত হওয়ার সময় নেপোলিয়ন প্রথম দুই মাস কাটিয়েছেন, ডেম মেবেল ব্রুকস দ্বারা ফরাসি সরকারকে দেওয়া হয়েছিল।  প্রশ্নঃ লংউড হাউস কে চেয়েছিল?","answer":"তৃতীয় নেপোলিয়ন লংউড হাউস চেয়েছিল |"},{"question":"Mặt Trời là một?a. Hành tinhb. Vệ tinhc. Không có đáp án đúngd. Ngôi sao","answer":"Đáp án đúng là d. Ngôi sao. "},{"question":"Na nga def?","answer":"comment vas-tu?"},{"question":"أريد إيجاد عنوان مناسب للنص التالي: كشف البنك الأهلي عن تقديمه تمويلات لعدد 45 ألف مشروع صغير بإجمالي محفظة تقارب حاليا 19 مليار جنيه بخلاف التسهيلات غير المباشرة وبمعدل نمو يصل إلى 600% عن مثيلتها في عام 2008 و300% عن إجمالي تلك المحفظة في عام URL البنك، في بيان اليوم السبت، إنه شارك في مبادرة البنك المركزي المصري لدعم المشروعات الصغيرة، حيث قام بتطوير آليات التمويل المطبقة لديه بما يتوافق مع القواعد والضوابط والتيسيرات غير المسبوقة التي توفرها المبادرة وبما يسمح بتمويل المشروعات الصغيرة والصغيرة جدا سواء القائمة أو الجديدة التي عرفها البنك المركزي وفقا حجم أعمالها ورءوس URL البنك أن نسبة تمويل تلك المشروعات تصل إلى 90%، وبآجال سداد تمتد إلى 7 سنوات حيث يتم منح التمويل بسعر عائد 5% بسيط ومتناقص بشروط ميسرة وبإجراءات سريعة، الأمر الذي يقلل تكلفة المشروعات ويزيد من فرص نجاحها ويساعد في توافر سلع محلية ذات جودة عالية وأسعار مناسبة تشبع احتياجات المواطنين وتقلل إلى حد كبير من الاعتماد على استيراد السلع الاستهلاكية. المصدر: البوابة نيوز.","answer":"البنك الأهلي: 19 مليار جنيه لتمويل المشروعات الصغيرة."},{"question":"Heesaha ay qaado Kinsi Xaaji Aadan.Heesta midhaheeda yaa curiyay ?Heestan magaceeda waxa la yidhaa:-Ololka iga baxayaa Horta yaa abaal gala","answer":"Heesaha ay qaado Kinsi Xaaji Aadan.Heesta midhaheeda yaa curiyay ?Heestan magaceeda waxa la yidhaa:-Ololka iga baxayaa Horta yaa abaal galaCaashaqaa hadduu go'maxaa adiga kaa galaylaba guur ku kulantiyolaba gaar isugu wacangarashooy maxaad noqongacan gacan waxsiisiyogacan u gragaarta yaa helihorta ya abaal galahaddu jire se yaa gudacaashaqaa haddu galomaxaa adiga kaa galaygorigii ilmaha tabayiyo gabanti uu dhalaymidba gees u xidhanagacan gacan wa siisiyogacan u gargaarta yaa helihorta yaa abaal galahadduu jiro se yaa gudaSoo saxa soona dhameeya"},{"question":"ස්වභාවික නොවන , මිනිසා විසින් නිර්මාණය කරනලද එකිනෙකට සම්බන්ධ ජලාශයන් 5 කට හිමිකම් කියන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ස්වභාවික නොවන , මිනිසා විසින් නිර්මාණය කරනලද එකිනෙකට සම්බන්ධ ජලාශයන් 5 කට හිමිකම් කියන ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය මාදුරුඔය රක්ෂිතයයි. එම ජලාශ 5 වන්නෙ: මාදුරුඔය , උල්හිටිය , හේනානිගල , එන්.ඩී.කේ, රක්කව. "},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Islande nékk","answer":"Réwum Islande mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Europe"},{"question":"Halk Eğitim bilgisayar Kursu kaç ay sürüyor?","answer":"Kurs yaklaşık 2 ay sürecektir. Kurs hafta içi her gün yapılacaktır."},{"question":"Akeredolu ṣe ifilọlẹ ikọ Amọtẹkun l’Ondo","answer":"Ṣe ni papa iṣere Gani Fawẹhinmi to wa l’Alagbaka, niluu Akurẹ, kun fọfọ fawọn eeyan lasiko ti Gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, Rotimi Akeredolu, ṣe ifilọlẹ ẹsọ alaabo Amọtẹkun ẹka tipinlẹ Ondo l’ọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ ta a wa yii.Inu oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun yii, ni Alakooso ẹgbẹ naa nipinlẹ Ondo, Oloye Adetunji Adelẹyẹ, kede pe aaye ti wa fawọn eeyan lati waa forukọ silẹ gẹgẹ bii ọmọ ẹgbẹ Amọtẹkun.Osu diẹ sẹyin ni wọn bẹrẹ idanilẹkọọ fun gbogbo awọn to fẹẹ kopa, oni ọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ni wọn si feto si lati ṣayẹyẹ ikẹkọọ-jade fawọn to yege ninu idanilẹkọọ naa.Akeredolu lo asiko ifilọlẹ naa lati fawọn araalu lọkan balẹ lori awọn ipenija eto aabo to n sẹlẹ lọwọ.O ni ọrọ eto aabo nipinlẹ Ondo ko ni i ri bii ti tẹlẹ mọ nitori pe ko sibi tawọn oniṣẹẹbi wọnyi fẹẹ sapamọ si tọwọ ko ni i tẹ wọn.Ọkunrin yii ni ero awọn eeyan kan nigba toun kọkọ dabaa ṣiṣe agbekalẹ ẹgbẹ Amọtẹkun niluu Ibadan ni ibẹrẹ ọdun ta a wa yii ni pe ṣe loun fẹẹ lo wọn ki wọn le ṣiṣẹ fun saa keji oun lasiko idibo. O ni oun fi n da awọn eeyan loju pe ikọ Amọtẹkun ko ni i woju ẹnikẹni to ba fẹẹ huwa jagidijgan ninu eto idibo to n bọ lọna.Ninu ọrọ tirẹ, aṣofin to n ṣoju awọn eeyan ijọba ibilẹ Ẹsẹ-Odo, Ọnarebu Success Taiwo Torhukerhijo, bẹ ijọba Akeredolu lati ranti awọn eeyan ori omi ninu eto Amọtẹkun naa."},{"question":"Көпөлөктөр эмнелер менен азыктанат?","answer":"Көпөлөктөрдүн көпчүлүгү гүлдөрдүн ширесинен азыктанат. Чаңчаларды, ширелерди, анын ичинде чириген мөмөлөрдү жана башка чириген азыктардан."},{"question":"Abdullahi Sule","answer":"Abdullahi Sule (a bi ni ọjọ kẹ́rìndínlọ́gbọ̀n, Oṣu kejila, ọdun 1959) jẹ oniṣowo ati olóṣèlú Naijiria ti o jẹ Gómìnà Ìpínlẹ̀ Nasarawa. Wọ́n yàn án gẹ́gẹ́ bí Gómìnà Ìpínlẹ̀ Nasarawa nínú ìdìbò Gómìnà ọdún 2019 lábẹ́ ètò ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú All Progressive Congress (APC).Wọ́n bí Sule ní Gudi, Akwanga ní ìpínlẹ̀ Nasarawa ní ọjọ́ kẹrindinlogbon oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 1959. Ni ọdún 1968, Ó kẹ́kọ́ ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Roman Catholic Mission (RMC) tí ó wà ní Gudi Station, ti o sí parí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gírámà ní Zang Secondary School ní ọdún 1974.Ni ọjọ kẹwà oṣù kẹta ọdún 2019, wón kede Adullahi Sule gẹgẹ bi gómìnà Ipínlè Nasarawa ti wón dibo yan."},{"question":"Parafrasea la oración: Las sugerencias de Met para realizar la ampliación desde Paddington hasta South Kensington y del este desde Moorgate hasta Tower Hill hacia el sur,  se aceptaron el 29 de julio de 1864 y recibieron la aprobación real.","answer":"El 29 de julio de 1864, las propuestas de Met para extender las rutas desde Paddington hasta South Kensington y desde Moorgate hasta Tower Hill hacia el sur fueron aprobadas y recibieron la aprobación real."},{"question":"Isikan tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang sesuai. \\"Ayah dan abang menonton televisyen ____________ berbual-bual.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah sambil."},{"question":"把以下的文章成现代汉字：永公住吴兴永欣寺，积年学书，后有秃笔头十瓮，每瓮皆数石。人来觅书并请题额者如市，所居户限为之穿穴，乃铁叶裹之，人谓“铁门限”。后以笔头瘗(音缢)之，号为“退笔冢”。","answer":"智永住在吴兴永欣寺，多年学习书法，之后就有十几瓮写坏的毛笔头，每瓮都有几石(那么重)。前来求取墨迹、并请他写匾额的人多得像吵闹的集市一样。他居住的地方的门槛因此被踏出洞来，于是就用铁皮包裹住门槛，人们称它为“铁门槛”。后来智永把笔头全部都埋了，称它为“退笔冢(坟)”。"},{"question":"Tohizo ity oha-pitenenana ity:  “Mitoka-monina ........................”","answer":"“Mitoka-monina ohatra ny boka.”"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو الحيوان الذي أجري عليه الاستنتنساخ؟","answer":"الإجابة: نعجة"},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Менин жашоомдогу супермен болгон үчүн рахмат. Сиз мени ар дайым сүйүүңүз жана камкордугуңуз менен өзгөчө сезип турдуңуз. Туулган күнүң менен!"},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Japón?","answer":"Tokio, la capital de Japón, se presenta como una metrópolis vibrante donde la cultura tradicional se cruza con la alta tecnología. La energía dinámica de la ciudad es evidente en sus bulliciosos barrios, desde el histórico distrito de Asakusa con sus antiguos templos hasta distritos futuristas como Shibuya, donde el icónico paso de peatones muestra el ritmo implacable de la ciudad."},{"question":"شحال عدد الجنحين عند النحلة؟","answer":"-(4 الجنحين) "},{"question":"How does the greenhouse effect influence global warming?","answer":"The greenhouse effect plays a crucial role in global warming, which is the gradual increase in Earth's average surface temperature. Here's how the greenhouse effect influences this process:Basic Mechanism of the Greenhouse Effect: The Earth's atmosphere contains gases like carbon dioxide (CO2), methane (CH4), water vapor, and others, known as greenhouse gases (GHGs). These gases allow sunlight to enter the atmosphere freely. When the Earth's surface absorbs sunlight, it heats up and emits infrared radiation (heat) back towards space. Greenhouse gases trap some of this heat, preventing it from escaping into space, much like the glass panels of a greenhouse. This natural greenhouse effect is crucial for life on Earth, as it keeps our planet warm enough to sustain ecosystems.Enhancement of the Greenhouse Effect: Human activities, particularly the burning of fossil fuels and deforestation, have increased the concentration of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere. This enhanced greenhouse effect results in more heat being trapped, leading to an increase in Earth's average surface temperature.Impact on Climate: The increase in global temperatures due to the enhanced greenhouse effect leads to various changes in the climate system. These include more frequent and severe weather events (like hurricanes and heatwaves), melting glaciers and ice caps, rising sea levels, changes in precipitation patterns, and shifts in ecosystems and wildlife habitats.Feedback Loops: The warming induced by the enhanced greenhouse effect can trigger feedback mechanisms that further intensify global warming. For example, melting ice reduces the Earth's albedo (reflectivity), causing the planet to absorb more sunlight, which further increases temperatures. Similarly, warming can release more greenhouse gases from permafrost and ocean reserves.In summary, the greenhouse effect is a natural process that keeps Earth's climate habitable, but human-induced increases in greenhouse gases have enhanced this effect, leading to global warming and significant changes in the Earth's climate system. Addressing this challenge involves reducing greenhouse gas emissions and adopting strategies to mitigate and adapt to climate change impacts."},{"question":"O filme “Pretty Woman” se passa em qual cidade?","answer":"O filme \\"Pretty Woman\\" se passa em Los Angeles, Califórnia, nos Estados Unidos. Lançado em 1990 e dirigido por Garry Marshall, o filme conta a história de um empresário bem-sucedido interpretado por Richard Gere, que contrata uma prostituta vivida por Julia Roberts para acompanhá-lo durante eventos sociais. Ao longo da trama, os dois personagens desenvolvem um relacionamento improvável e romântico. O filme recebeu críticas mistas dos críticos. Rotten Tomatoes relata que 62% de 55 críticos de cinema deram ao filme uma revisão positiva, com uma avaliação média de 5,7 dos 10."},{"question":"Пассаттар деген эмне?","answer":"Пассаттар-океандардын тропиктик кеңдиктеринде жыл бою туруктуу соккон шамалдар."},{"question":"Курт-кумурскалар түркүмүнөн эң бат учканы кайсы?","answer":"Бул - Ийнелик. Ал алдына да, артына да, капталына да уча алат жана саатына 100 км учуп, курт-кумурскалар түркүмүнөн эң бат учуучуп болуп эсептелинет."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਸੰਤ ਸੁਣਹੁ ਜਨ ਭਾਈ ਹਰਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਇਕ ਸਾਖੀ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਧੁਰਿ ਭਾਗੁ ਹੋਵੈ ਮੁਖਿ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਤਿਨਿ ਜਨਿ ਲੈ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਰਾਖੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਕਥਾ ਸਰੇਸਟ ਊਤਮ ਗੁਰ ਬਚਨੀ ਸਹਜੇ ਚਾਖੀ ॥ਤਹ ਭਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸੁ ਮਿਟਿਆ ਅੰਧਿਆਰਾ ਜਿਉ ਸੂਰਜ ਰੈਣਿ ਕਿਰਾਖੀ ॥ਅਦਿਸਟੁ ਅਗੋਚਰੁ ਅਲਖੁ ਨਿਰੰਜਨੁ ਸੋ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਆਖੀ ॥੧੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 87 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨ ਪਿਆਰਿਓ ! ਆਪਣੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਸੁਣੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਤੇ ਤੁਰੋ)ਇਸ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰੋ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉਤੇ ਧੁਰੋਂ ਹੀ ਭਾਗ ਹੋਵੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹੀ ਅਡੋਲ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਉੱਤਮ ਪਵਿਤਰ ਤੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਕਣੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਲਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ(ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਹਿਰਦਾ ਇਕ ਵਾਰੀ ਧਾਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਵਿਚ (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ) ਚਾਨਣ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ) ਹਨੇਰਾ ਇਉਂ ਦੂਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਸੂਰਜ ਰਾਤ (ਦੇ ਹਨੇਰੇ) ਨੂੰ ਖਿੱਚ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਨਾਲ) ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ, ਇੰਦ੍ਰਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਅਲੱਖ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੋਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਅੱਖੀਂ ਦਿੱਸ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧੨।\\""},{"question":"Tẹ ẹ ba fẹ ka wa niṣọkan, ẹ yi orukọ Naijiria pada si… – Jokotoye","answer":"Ipe ti lọ sọdọ awọn aṣofin ilẹ wa lati ṣatunyẹwo orukọ orileede yii, ki wọn si yi i pada kuro ni Naijiria, awọn oyinbo amunisin ni wọn sọ orukọ naa, ki i ṣe awa funra wa.Ọgbẹni Adelẹyẹ Jokotoye to jẹ ọga oṣiṣẹ agbowo-ori l’Ekoo lo kọ amọran naa ranṣẹ sawọn aṣofin l’Abuja, l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, pe ki wọn le yiri ẹ wo nigba ti wọn ba n ṣatunyẹwo iwe ofin ilẹ wa, eyi ti apero itagbangba n lọ lori ẹ lọwọ bayii.Jokotoye ni obinrin oyinbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Flora Shaw, iyawo Lord Lugard, to jẹ ọkan lara awọn oyinbo amunisin lo sọ orileede yii lorukọ, oun lo pe e ni Naijiria.O ni orukọ ẹni ni ijanu ẹni, ta a ba fẹ ki iṣọkan wa lorileede yii, afi ka kọkọ yi orukọ rẹ pada si eyi to maa mu ki ẹmi iṣọkan ati ifẹ gbilẹ laarin wa.“Lakọọkọ, mo fẹẹ dabaa pe ka yi orukọ Naijiria (Nigeria) pada si United African Republic (Orileede olominira Iṣọkan Africa).Pataki pipaarọ orukọ ilẹ wa ṣe koko gidi. Ninu awọn Iwe Mimọ, Ọlọrun to jẹ Baba gbogbo wa yi awọn orukọ kan pada, fun apẹẹrẹ, o yi Sọọlu pada si Pọọlu, o yi Jekọbu pada si Isreal ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ. O ṣe pataki lati yi orukọ pada, o maa n mu ayipada rere wa ninu ironu ati igbe aye, tori orukọ maa n ro ni.Tori naa, lasiko ta a fẹẹ bẹrẹ igba ọtun yii, o pọn dandan ka yi orukọ wa pada, ka si fi i sinu iwe ofin tuntun ta a ba ṣe. Itumọ ọrọ Greek ni Afrika ni “Ko si otutu,” ṣugbọn orukọ abalaye ti wọn fi n pe wa ni ‘Alkebulan’ eyi to tumọ si ‘Iya gbogbo eeyan’ (latinu Ọgba Edẹni), ọpọ awọn eeyan ilẹ Ethiopia ni wọn mọ wa mọ orukọ naa.Tori naa, ta a ba fẹ, a le kuku sọ orukọ wa ni United Alkebulan Republic, iyẹn orileede Iṣọkan Alkebula).”Bakan naa ni Jokotoye dabaa pe ki wọn ṣe ayipada ati atunto si awọn ileeṣẹ ọba kan lorileede wa."},{"question":"Çocuğa verilen nafaka ne zaman sona erer?","answer":"Erginliğe ulaşılmasından sonra nafaka ödemeleri biter. Ancak boşanmanın ardından gerçekleşen ve iştirak nafakası olarak adlandırılan durum erginlik yaşı 18 yaşına kadar devam etse de bazı durumlar içerisinde farklılık gözlemlendiği görülür."},{"question":"Що таке гризачка?","answer":"Це слово вживється на Закарпатті і означає \\"кавун\\". "},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, ọmọ ọdun mẹrin ja si ṣalanga lasiko ti wọn n gba bọọlu l’Ekiti","answer":"Inu ipayinkeke ati ibanujẹ ni obi ọmọ ọdun mẹrin kan wa bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe sadeede ba oku rẹ ninu ṣalanga kan ni adugbo Aseparisi, lagbegbe Adehun, niluu Ado-Ekiti.Gẹgẹ bi awọn araadugbo naa to ba ALAROYE sọrọ ṣe sọ, wọn ni ọmọde yii atawọn ẹgbẹ rẹ kan ni wọn jọ n gba bọọlu nirọlẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ṣugbọn lẹyin iṣẹju diẹ ti wọn ti n gba bọọlu ọhun ni bọọlu wọn yii ha si aarin igi kan ti wọn gbin si ẹgbẹ ṣalanga yii.Ọmọdekunrin to ti doloogbe yii lo gbiyanju lati mu bọọlu to ha saarin igi naa, ṣugbọn lojiji lo sadeede ja sinu ṣalanga naa.Bo ṣe ja sinu ṣalanga yii ni awọn iyooku rẹ bẹrẹ si i pariwo titi ti awọn araadugbo naa fi jade. Wọn gbiyanju lati yọ oku rẹ kuro, ṣugbọn ki wọn too gbe e jade ni ọmọ naa ti dagbere faye.Iṣẹlẹ yii da jinnijinni silẹ laarin awọn araadugbo naa. Lẹyin ti wọn gbe oku ọmọde yii jade ni wọn gbe e lọ si ile igbokuu-pamọ si kan to jẹ tijọba niluu Ado-Ekiti.Lara awọn olubanikẹdun to ba ALAROYE sọrọ lori iku ọmọdekunrin yii di ẹbi iku ọmọ yii ru awọn ọmọ yii, o ni wọn ko mojuto ọmọ naa to ni.Wọn waa rọ awọn obi ki wọn maa mojuto awọn ọmọ wọn, bẹẹ ni wọn gba awọn to ba n gbẹ ṣalanga niyanju lati maa gbẹ ẹ daadaa.Alukoro awọn ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ekiti, Ọgbẹni Sunday Abutu, sọ pe wọn ti tọju oku ọmọ naa, iwadii si ti bẹrẹ lori ọrọ naa."},{"question":"\\"E\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"E\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ පස්වන අකුර යි."},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny teny hoe \\"lover\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny dikan'ny teny hoe \\"lover\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy dia \\"olon-tiana\\"."},{"question":"Write a continuation for this paragraph - สงครามสิ้นสุดลงด้วยการทิ้งระเบิดนิวเคลียร์ถล่มฮิโรชิมาและนางาซากิ และการทิ้งระเบิดทางอากาศครั้งใหญ่โดยกองทัพอากาศสหรัฐอเมริกา ประกอบกับการรุกรานแมนจูเรียของสหภาพโซเวียต","answer":"เมื่อวันที่ 8 สิงหาคม ค.ศ. 1945 ส่งผลให้ญี่ปุ่นยอมจำนนและเป็นจุดสิ้นสุดของสงครามโลกครั้งที่สองเมื่อวันที่ 15 สิงหาคม ค.ศ. 1945 การยอมจำนนอย่างเป็นทางการเกิดขึ้นบนเรือรบยูเอสเอส มิสซูรี ที่ทอดสมอในอ่าวโตเกียวเมื่อวันที่ 2 กันยายน ค.ศ. 1945"},{"question":" من هو أول من آمن من المدينة المنورة ؟","answer":"- سيدنا أسعد بن زرارة"},{"question":"Web framework တွေက high level architecture ဘယ်လို ကွာကြတာလဲ","answer":"High level architecture ကို web framework တွေ ချဥ်းကပ်တည်ဆောက်ပုံ မတူကြပါဘူး။ ဘယ်အတိုင်းအတာထိ အသေးစိတ် ပေးထားသလဲဆိုတဲ့အပေါ် မူတည်ပြီး Web framework တွေက အရသာ ၂ မျိုးကွဲသွားပါတယ်။LaravelLaravel ဟာ php ecosystem ထဲမှာ အတော်လေး လူသိများတဲ့ framework တခုဖြစ်ပြီးတော့ Laravel သာ မရှိခဲ့ရင် php ကို ဒိုင်နိုဆောတွေနဲ့ တန်းတူ ပြတိုက်မှာပဲ ကြည့်လို့ရတော့မယ်လို့တောင် ဆိုကြပါတယ်။ Python ရဲ့ Django နဲ့ Ruby ရဲ့ ROR တို့လို battery-included framework တခုဖြစ်ပြီး Laravel မှာ တိကျတဲ့ file structure နဲ့ web application တခုရဲ့ အသုံးအများဆုံး feature တွေက အသင့်ပါဝင်ပြီးသား ဖြစ်တယ်။ opinionated framework တခုဖြစ်တဲ့ Laravel က Architecture မှာ ဘယ်လောက် အတိုင်းအတာထိ စွက်ဖက်ထားသလဲ နားလည်ဖို့ လုပ်ကြပါမယ်။Express JSExpressJS ကတော့ Web serving အတွက် လိုအပ်တဲ့ လုပ်ဆောင်ချက်တွေကိုပဲ ပေးနိုင်ဖို့ ရည်ရွယ်ပါတယ်။ Python's Flask နဲ့ Golang ရဲ့ Gin တို့လို lightweight framework တခု ဖြစ်ပြီး feature တွေကို စိတ်တိုင်းကျ configuration လုပ်ခွင့်ပေးထားတဲ့အတွက် လိုချင်တာကို လိုအပ်သလောက်သာ ရေးချင်တဲ့သူတွေအနေနဲ့ ExpressJS ကိုရွေးချယ်ကြပါတယ်။ minimalistic framework တခုဖြစ်တဲ့ Express အနေနဲ့ကော Laravel နဲ့ ဘယ်လိုတွေ ကွာခြားတာလဲ။"},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් ගොයියා  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කුඹුර වගා කරන්නා"},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү белгилүү мечитер жөнүндө айтып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Шейх Зайед мечити:Кийинки сөз боло турган мечит бир канча “рекордду” багындыра алган. Абу-Даби шаарында жайгашкан “Шейх Зайед” мечитин салуу үчүн 12 жыл жана болжол менен 545 миллион доллар сарпталган, мечитти 38 компания жана 3500 адам курган. 41 000 адамды батыра алат. 82 куполдон жана 107 метр бийиктикке жеткен 4 мунарадан турат. Дүйнөдөгү эң чоң килем ушул мечитте төшөлгөн. Анын аянты 5627 чарчы метр, салмагы 47 тоннага жетет. Мечитте алтын жана кристаллдар менен кооздолгон 7 шам чырак асылган. Негизги шам чырагы 2010-жылга чейин (кийин кошуна Катарда илинген) дүйнөдөгү эң чоң шам чырак деп эсептелип келген. Анын диаметри 10 метр, бийиктиги 15 метр, салмагы 12 тоннаны түзөт. Мечит мрамордон жана алтындан салынгандыктан, өзгөчө жаркырап турат, кечкисин атайын жасалма жарыктандырылат."},{"question":"Giả sử bị lạc trong rừng, bạn thấy ba loại cây, một loại có quả màu đỏ, một cây chuối và một cây táo, trong đó hai cây không an toàn và chỉ một cây ăn được. Bạn sẽ chọn cây nào?","answer":"Với bụi cây có quả màu đỏ, bạn có thể thấy nhiều dấu chân động vật đi tới, nhưng không có dấu chân trở ra. Do đó, cây này có thể có độc.Với cây chuối, một con bọ cạp đang ở ngay trước, nên đây cũng không phải lựa chọn an toàn.Bạn nên ăn cây táo."},{"question":"Kedu mgbe agbara ụlo Igwe Oliver Nnaji ","answer":"A gbara ụlọ Igwe Oliver Nnaji nke Ogwu Aniocha Anambra steeti ọkụ n'abalị iri na isii nke ọnwa Nọvemba  nke afọ 2021."},{"question":"\\"සුද්දිලාගේ කථාව\\", \\"ක්ෂීර සාගරය කැලඹිණ\\", \\"ස්වර්ණ වන්නියේ වල්ලි අම්මලා\\" යන කෘතීන් රචනා කළ, ශ්‍රී ලාංකික ලේඛකයා කවුද?","answer":"සයිමන් නවගත්තේගම සූරීන් විසින් \\"සුද්දිලාගේ කථාව\\", \\"ක්ෂීර සාගරය කැලඹිණ\\", \\"ස්වර්ණ වන්නියේ වල්ලි අම්මලා\\" යන කෘතීන් රචනා කරන ලදි."},{"question":"வினா:மொழிக்கு இறுதில் வரும் தமிழ் எழுத்துகள் எத்தனை?அ) பன்னிரண்டுஆ) பதினெட்டுஇ) இருபத்து நான்குஈ) இருபத்து இரண்டு","answer":"விடை:இ) இருபத்து நான்கு1.உயிரெழுத்துக்கள் பன்னிரண்டும், மெய்யெழுத்துக்கள் '2.ஞ,ண,ந,ம,ன,ய,ர,ல,வ,ழ,ள' ஆகிய பதினொன்றும், குற்றியலுகரம் ஒன்றும் என மொத்தமாக இருபத்து நான்கு எழுத்துகள் மொழிக்கு இறுதியில் வரும் என நன்னூல் குறிப்பிடுகிறது."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر البسيط. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"قِف مَوقِفَ الشَكِّ لا يَأسٌ وَلا طَمَعُوَغالِطِ العَيشَ لا صَبرٌ وَلا جَزَعُوَخادِعِ القَلبَ لا يودِ الغَليلُ بِهِإِن كانَ قَلبٌ عَلى الماضينَ يَنخَدِعُوَكاذِبِ النَفسَ يَمتَدُّ الرَجاءُ لَهاإِنَّ الرَجاءَ بِصِدقِ النَفسِ يَنقَطِعُسائِل بِصَحبي أَنّى وُجهَةٍ سَلَكواعَنّا وَأَيَّ الثَنايا بَعدَنا طَلَعواحَدا بِأَظعانِهِم حَتّى اِستَمَرَّ بِهاحادي المَقاديرِ لا يَلوي بِهِم ظَلَعُغابوا فَغابَ عَنِ الدُنيا وَساكِنُهامَرأىً أَنيقٌ عَنِ الدُنيا وَمُستَمَعُبَني أَبي قَد نَكى فيكُم بِشِكَّتِهِوَنالَ ما شاءَ هَذا الأَزلُمَ الجَذَعُكُنتُم نُجوماً لِذي الدَهماءِ زاهِرَةًتُضيءُ مِنها اللَيالي السودُ وَالدُرَعُإِن تَخبُ أَنوارُكُم مِن بَعدِ ما صَدَعَتثَوبَ الدُجى فَلَضَوءِ الشَمسِ مُنقَطَعُفي غُرَّةِ المَجدِ مُذ غُيَّبتُمُ كَلَفٌعَلى الزَمانِ وَفي خَدِّ العُلى ضَرَعُوَبِالمَواضي حِرانٌ في الوَغى وَبِأَعناقِ الضَوامِرِ مُذ أُرحِلتُمُ خَضَعُمَصاعِبٌ ذَعذَعَت أَيدي المَنونِ بِهافَطاعَ مُعتَصِمٌ وَاِنقادَ مُمتَنِعُلَم يَعدَموا يَومَ حَربٍ تَحتَ قَسطَلِهاطَيرُ الدِخامِ عَلى لَبّاتِهِم تَقَعُلَم يَنزِعوا البيضَ مُذلاثوا عَمائِمَهُمإِلّا وَقَد غاضَ مِنها الشَيبُ وَالنَزَعُنُسابِقُ المَوتَ تَطويحاً بِأَنفُسِناحَتّى كَأَنّا عَلى الأَجيالِ نَقتَرِعُأَبكيهِمُ وَيَدُ الأَيّامِ دائِبَةٌتَدوفُ لي فَضلَةَ الكَأسِ الَّتي جَرَعوالا أَمتَري أَنَّني بُجرٍ إِلى أَمَدٍجَروا إِلَيهِ قُبَيلَ اليَومِ أَو نَزَعواوَأَنَّني وارِدُ العِدِّ الَّذي وَرَدوابِالكُرهِ أَو قارِعُ البابِ الَّذي قَرَعواسُدَّت فَواغِرُ أَفواهِ القُبورِ بِهِموَلَيسَ لِلأَرضِ لا رَيٌّ وَلا شَبَعُأَعتادُهُم لا أُرَجّي أَن يَعودَ لَهُمإِلَيَّ ماضٍ وَلا لي فيهِمُ طَمَعُفَما تَوَهُّجُ أَحشايَ عَلى نَفَرٍكانوا عَوادِيَ لِلأَيّامِ فَاِرتَجِعوانُليحُ أَن تَرتَعي الأَقدارُ أَنفُسَناوَكُلُّنا لِلمَنايا السودِ مُزدَرَعُنَلهو وَمانَحنُ إِلّا لِلرَدىأُكَلٌوَالدَهرُ يَمضَغُنا وَالأَرضُ تَبتَلِعُذَوائِبٌ مِن لُبابِ المَجدِ ما فَجِعوابِمِثلِ أَنفُسِهِم يَوماً وَلا فُجِعواكانوا حَوامي جِبالِ العِزِّ فَاِنقَرَضواوَصَدَّعوا قُلَلَ العَليا مُذِ اِنصَدَعوافَوارِسٌ قَوَّضوا عَن سابِقاتِهِمُفَاِستُنزِلوا بِطِعانِ الدَهرِ وَاِقتُلِعواقَومٌ فُكاهَتُهُم ضَربُ الطُلى وَلَهُمتَحتَ العَجاجِ بِأَطرافِ القَنا وَلَعُإِمّا تَؤودُ مِنَ الأَيّامِ نائِبَةٌقاموا بِها وَأَطاقوا الحَملَ وَاِضطَلَعوالا تَستَلينُهُمُ الضَرّاءُ نازِلَةًوَلا تَقودُهُمُ الأَطماعُ وَالنُجَعُكَم خَمصَةٍ كانَ فيها العِزِّ آوِنَةًوَشَبعَةٍ كانَ فيها العارُ وَالضَرَعُمِن كُلِّ أَغلَبَ نَظّارٍ عَلى شَوَسٍلَهُ لِواءٌ عَلى العَلياءِ مُتَّبَعُيَخفى بِهِ التاجُ مِن لَأَلاءِ غُرَّتِهِعَلى جَبينٍ بِضَوءِ المَجدِ يَلتَمِعُذو عَزمَةٍ تُلهِمُ الدُنيا وَساكِنَهاوَهِمَّةٍ تَسَعُ الدُنيا وَما تَسَعُيَلقى الظُبى حاسِراً تَبدو مَقاتِلُهُوَيَرهَبُ الذَمَّ يَوماً وَهوَ مَدَّرِعُإِنَّ المَصائِبَ تُنسي المَرءَ مُقبَلَةًقَصدَ الطَريقِ لِما يُسلي وَما يَزَعُحَتّى إِذا اِنكَشَفَت عَنهُ غَياطِلُهاتَبَيَّنَ المَرءُ ما يَأتي وَما يَدَعُأَرسى النَسيمُ بِواديكُم وَلابَرِحَتحَوامِلُ المُزنِ في أَجداثِكُم تَضَعُوَلا يَزالُ جَنينُ النَبتِ تُرضِعُهُعَلى قُبورِكُمُ العِرّاصَةُ الهَمِعُهَل تَعلَمونَ عَلى نَأيِ الدِيارِ بِكُمأَنَّ الضَميرَ إِلَيكُم شَيِّقٌ وَلِعُلَكُم عَلى الدَهرِ مِن أَكبادِنا شُعَلٌمِنَ الغَليلِ وَمَن آماقِنا دُفَعُلَواعِجٌ أَفصَحَت عَنها الدُموعُ وَقَدكادَت تُجَمجِمُها الأَحشاءُ وَالضِلَعُأَنزَفتُ دَمعِيَ حَتّى ما تَرَكتُ لَهُغَرباً يَفيضُ عَلى رُزءٍ إِذا يَقَعُثُمَّ اِضطُرِرتُ إِلى صَبري فَعُذتُ بِهِوَأَعرَبَ الصَبرُ لَمّا أَعجَمَ الجَزَعُ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gatal tangan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud suka membuat yang bukan-bukan. Contoh ayat: Saya tidak mahu membawa Halizah ke rumah Mak Busu kerana dia suka gatal tangan sehingga habis bunga Mak Busu dirosakkan."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত শিরোনাম উপর ভিত্তি করে একটি নিবন্ধ লিখুন |চিত্রা বন্দ্যোপাধ্যায়ের স্বামীর নাম কী ?","answer":"চিত্রা তাঁর স্বামী মুর্থির সাথে টেক্সাস অঙ্গরাজ্যের হিউস্টনে বসবাস করেন। তাঁর ২ ছেলে আনন্দ এবং অভয় এর নাম তিনি শিশুদের জন্য লেখা গ্রন্থগুলিতে ব্যবহার করেন।"},{"question":"Mene Rabe-Raben Almara?","answer":"Almarar Wasa Ƙwaƙwalwa: ita ce almarar da ke ɗauke da labarin da ke ɗauke da matsalar da bayan an gama bayar da shi za a buƙaci masu sauraro su warware matsalar.Almarar Raha: almara ce da ake yin ta ta hanyar bayar da labarin bandariya, wacce kuma ba ta ɗauke da wata matsalar da a ƙarshe za a nemi mai sauraro ya warware ta."},{"question":"Бышы кулак болуу деген сөздү кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Көндүм болуу, көнүмүш адаттай болуп калуу, эч сезилбөө.Жедеп бышы кулак болуп бүткөн го, айтылган сөзгө Самат териккен жок."},{"question":"Wọn ti sinku Babatunde, akẹkọọ UNIOSUN to binu pa ara ẹ","answer":"Ninu ẹkun, ibanujẹ ati aro ni wọn sinku Juba Babatunde Philips, akẹkọọ ileewe UNIOSUN to gbe majele jẹ lọjọ Tusidee to kọja yii.Itẹ-oku to jẹ ti ijọ First Baptist Church, lagbegbe Sango, niluu Ikire, nijọba ibilẹ Irewọle, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ni wọn sin oku ọmọdekunrin naa si.Babatunde, ẹni to wa nipele akọkọ ni ẹka ti wọn ti n kọ nipa ere ori-itage nileewe naa la sọ fun yin pe o gbe majele (snippers) jẹ nirọlẹ ọjọ naa.Nigba ti awọn ọrẹ rẹ fi maa denu yaara rẹ lọjọ naa, oku rẹ ni wọn ba, wọn si lọọ fi iṣẹlẹ naa to olori ẹṣọ aabo ileewe naa leti, latibẹ si lawọn ọlọpaa ti gbọ.Wọn gbe Babatunde lọ sileewosan Catholic, niluu Apomu, nibẹ ni wọn si ti sọ fun wọn pe o ti jade laye.Alukoro ileewe naa, Adesọji Ademọla, ṣalaye pe awọn obi Babatunde ni wọn lọọ gba oku naa nileewosan to wa, ti wọn si sin in ni itẹ-oku ọhun."},{"question":"පාරු කවියක් සඳහා  උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න. ","answer":"සූරිය උදාවෙන තුරු පිනි            බෑවිල්ලපාරුව පදින තුරු වතුරේ            කැළඹිල්ලමාරුව බල බලා හිත යට           කැරකිල්ලකාරිය කෙරෙන තුරු කාගෙත්   රැවටිල්ල"},{"question":"Descubra qual o herói dada as seguintes características: Voar, visão de calor, Kryptoniano.","answer":"O herói que você está descrevendo provavelmente é o Super-Homem (Superman). É um dos super-heróis mais icónicos da DC Comics, criado por Jerry Siegel e Joe Shuster. Além dos seus poderes, ele é facilmente identificado pelo seu fato azul e vermelho, com um icónico \\"S\\" no peito."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Ишенбешиңиз мүмкүн. Бирок, зажигалка ширеңкеден мурун ойлоп табылган."},{"question":"Bilowga.?","answer":"Dambarka, oo ah caanaha ugu horeeya ee jidhkaagu sameeyo, aad buu ugu fiican yahay ilmahaaga. Dhawrka maalmood ee ku xiga,naasaha waxa aad dareemi doontaa barrar ama buuxsanaan, waxana aad yeelan doontaa caanointii hore ka badan. Caanaha aad samaysaawaxay ku xidhan yihiin sida uu ilmahaagu u jaqonaaska. Marka uu ilmuhu naaska badsado jiqidiisaba, jidhkaagu wuxu soo saaraa caanakasii badan intii hore. Kalkaalisooyinkacaafimaad waxay kaa caawin doonaan adiga iyoilmahaagaba inaad barataan naas nuujinta. Nafisoo sii naftaada waqti aad ku barato. Ilmahaaguwaxa laga yaabaa inuu hurdo bato maalmaha hore. Maadaama ay caloosha ilmahaaguyartahay, wuxuu u baahnan doonaa in dhowr jeer maalintii la quudiyo. Waxad dareemidoontaa harraad markaad nuujinayso ilmaha iyo hurdo marka ilmuhu ku jaqayo iyo ilma-galeenka oo si debecsan u dareento ayaamahahore ee naasnuujinta."},{"question":"Какой металл является самым распространенным на Земле? Выберите один ответ.A) ЗолотоB) СереброC) ЖелезоD) Медь","answer":"Правильный ответ: C) Железо. Железо - это один из наиболее распространенных металлов на Земле и широко используется в различных отраслях промышленности, включая строительство, производство автомобилей и многие другие. Его богатые рудные залежи находятся в разных частях мира, и железо служит основным строительным материалом для многих инфраструктурных проектов."},{"question":"Iza ilay mpanaka merina no lazaina fa nanjaka tapany ?","answer":"I Radama II no mpanjanka nanjaka tapany satria dia roa taona monja izy no nitondra dia maty."},{"question":"ਛੂਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਕੀ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਰੋਕਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਲਾਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਛੂਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਉਹ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਜਰਾਸੀਮ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਬੈਕਟੀਰੀਆ, ਵਾਇਰਸ ਅਤੇ ਪਰਜੀਵੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਛੂਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੂਸ਼ਿਤ ਤਰਲਾਂ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਲਹੂ ਜਾਂ ਲਾਰ ਦੇ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਇੱਕ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਜੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਫੈਲ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਕੁਝ ਛੂਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਟੀਕਾਕਰਣ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਰੋਕਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੋਰ ਛੂਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਇਲਾਜ ਐਂਟੀਬਾਇਓਟਿਕਸ ਜਾਂ ਐਂਟੀਵਾਇਰਲ ਦਵਾਈਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _« Ny _ ny fandraharahana dia ny hanomezana tolotra, izay voa azo ny tombony. »","answer":" Ny tanjon’ ny fandraharahana dia ny hanomezana tolotra, izay voa azo ny tombony."},{"question":"Wọlé Olánipẹ̀kun","answer":"Olóye Wọlé Olánipẹ̀kun tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ kejìdínlógún oṣù kọkànlá ọdún 1951 (November,18th 1951)jẹ́ Adájọ́ ọmọ Yorùbá láti orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Òun ni Ààrẹ Ẹgbẹ́ Ìgbìmọ̀ Àwọn Adájọ́ Nigeria Bar AssociationOlóye Wọlé Olánipẹ̀kun lọ sí Ilé-Ìwè Amoye Grammar School ni Íkẹ́rẹ́-Ekiti,Ípìnlẹ́ Ekiti State. Wọlé,parí ẹ̀kọ̀ mewa West Africa School Certificate ni Ilésa Girama kí ó to rékọ́já si gbogbo gbo University of Lagos, Nïbi tï oti gba oyê kèkerê nínú ise òfin. A pee si inú îgbîmọ́ àwọn adájọ̀ Call to the bar ni orîlẹ́ èdè Naijiria ni Odún 1976. Ni Odún 1991 ó di Agbẹjọ́ró Àgbà fún Ìpínlẹ̀ Ondo . Ó wa ni Ipó yi fún Odûn Mêjî gbàko. Ni odún 2002, wọ́n yan si ipò gẹ́gẹ́bí Ààrẹ fún Nigerian Bar Association. Láti odún 2004 si 2006 ó jé Ògá àgàbà Ìgbìmò àti Olùdárí fún Yunifásítì Ìlú-Ìbàdàn ."},{"question":"ඇතුල අරුත කුමක්ද? (ඇතුළ අරුත දනිමි)","answer":"‍යාකරණානුකුලව වැරැදි වුනත් සුමංගල, කලවුග්, කාටර්, හරිස්චන්ද්‍ර විජයතුංග ආදී සියලු ශබ්දකෝෂවල ඇතුල් = ඇතුළු ලෙස තමයි දෙන්නේ. නමුත් කුමන හේතුවක් නිසා හෝ ඇතුල = ඇතුළ කියලා වචනයක් දෙන්නේ නැහැ. අර්ථ දෙකම එකයි කියන එක තමයි මම හිතන්නේ."},{"question":"Qual è la domanda a: \\"bloccante dei recettori dell'angiotensina (antagonista), un farmaco per il trattamento della pressione alta\\"?","answer":"La domanda è \\"Quali sono i farmaci per l'artrite?\\"."},{"question":"অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন: পথশিশু।","answer":"পথশিশু বলতে পথে পথে কর্মহীন যে শিশু ঘুরে বেড়ায় তাকে বোঝায়। বিশিষ্ট কার্টুনিস্ট রফিকুন্নবী, যিনি রণবী নামে পরিচিত, এসব শিশুদের নাম দিয়েছিলেন ‘টোকাই'। টোকাই নামের মধ্যেই রয়েছে এসব শিশুর বাস্তব পরিচয়। তারা স্কুলে যায় না এবং সমাজের সুযোগ-সুবিধা বঞ্চিত। নোংরা-ময়লা পোশাক পরে পথে-প্রান্তরে এমন কি ডাস্টবিনে ময়লার মধ্যে পরিত্যক্ত জিনিসপত্র টোকায়। খেয়ে না খেয়ে এদের প্রতিটি দিন কাটে। অনিশ্চিত ভবিষ্যতের দিকে পথশিশুদের জীবন চলতে থাকে। অথচ শিশুরাই জাতির ভবিষ্যৎ। উন্নত দেশে শিশুদের ভবিষ্যতের সম্ভাবনার কথা বিবেচনা করে তাদের পরিচর্যা মাতৃগর্ভ থেকেই শুরু হয় সেখানে আমাদের দেশে জন্মের পর হাঁটতে শিখলেই তারা ঘুরতে থাকে অনিশ্চয়তার পথে। অশিক্ষা, দরিদ্রতা আর জীবিকার দুর্ভাবনায় শিশুরা যোগ্য হয়ে বেড়ে উঠতে পারে না। এ ক্ষেত্রে শিশুদের অভিভাবকরা নানা সীমাবদ্ধতার কারণে উদাসীনতার পরিচয় দেয়। এসব শিশুরা একদিকে যেমন যোগ্য হয়ে ওঠে না, অন্যদিকে অল্প বয়সেই তারা মারাত্মক রোগব্যাধিতে আক্রান্ত হয়। এছাড়া এরা বিভিন্ন অপরাধমূলক কর্মকাণ্ডেও জড়িয়ে পড়ে। ফলে সামাজিক মূল্যবোধ ও নৈতিক অবক্ষয়ের সৃষ্টি হয়। এসব পথশিশুদের কল্যাণে বা সুযোগসুবিধা সৃষ্টি করতে সরকার বা বেসরকারি বিভিন্ন প্রতিষ্ঠান বা সমাজের ধনাঢ্য শ্রেণির ব্যক্তিদের এগিয়ে না আসাটা অত্যন্ত দুঃখজনক। পথশিশুদের দায়িত্ব নিলে এরা বেড়ে উঠত সত্যিকারের মানুষরূপে। এরা পথশিশু নয়; পথকলি। এদের বিকাশের সুযোগ দিতে হবে। তাহলেই সমগ্র জাতি সুবাসিত হবে।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਮਨ ਹੀ ਮਨੁ ਸਵਾਰਿਆ ਭੈ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥ਸਬਦਿ ਮਨੁ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਇ ॥ਨਿਜ ਘਰਿ ਵਸਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੀ ਰਜਾਇ ॥੧॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿਐ ਜਾਇ ਅਭਿਮਾਨੁ ॥ਗੋਵਿਦੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਗੁਣੀ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮਨੁ ਬੈਰਾਗੀ ਜਾ ਸਬਦਿ ਭਉ ਖਾਇ ॥ਮੇਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਨਿਰਮਲਾ ਸਭ ਤੈ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਮਿਲੈ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥੨॥ਹਰਿ ਦਾਸਨ ਕੋ ਦਾਸੁ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਮੇਰਾ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਇਨ ਬਿਧਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਏ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਰਾਮ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਏ ॥੩॥ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਬਹੁ ਜੀਵਣੁ ਜਿਤੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਨ ਲਗੈ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਸੇਜ ਸੁਖਾਲੀ ਕਾਮਣਿ ਮੋਹ ਗੁਬਾਰੁ ॥ਤਿਨ ਸਫਲੁ ਜਨਮੁ ਜਿਨ ਨਾਮੁ ਅਧਾਰੁ ॥੪॥ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਧ੍ਰਿਗੁ ਗ੍ਰਿਹੁ ਕੁਟੰਬੁ ਜਿਤੁ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਸੋਈ ਹਮਾਰਾ ਮੀਤੁ ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥੫॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਤੇ ਹਮ ਗਤਿ ਪਤਿ ਪਾਈ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇਆ ਦੂਖੁ ਸਗਲ ਮਿਟਾਈ ॥ਸਦਾ ਅਨੰਦੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਈ ॥੬॥ਗੁਰਿ ਮਿਲਿਐ ਹਮ ਕਉ ਸਰੀਰ ਸੁਧਿ ਭਈ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਨਾ ਸਭ ਅਗਨਿ ਬੁਝਈ ॥ਬਿਨਸੇ ਕ੍ਰੋਧ ਖਿਮਾ ਗਹਿ ਲਈ ॥੭॥ਹਰਿ ਆਪੇ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾ ਕਰੇ ਨਾਮੁ ਦੇਵੈ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਰਤਨੁ ਕੋ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਲੇਵੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕੁ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਵੈ ਹਰਿ ਅਲਖ ਅਭੇਵੈ ॥੮॥੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 232 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਮਨ ਨੂੰ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ) ਰੰਗ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ, ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਤਰ ਆਤਮੇ ਹੀ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਬਣਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, (ਗ੍ਰਿਹਸਤ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਕਿਤੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਜਾਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਈ) । ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਾਜ਼ੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ (ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਮਨ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਤੋਂ ਉਪਰਾਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ-ਸਰੂਪ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਦੋਂ (ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਸ) ਡਰ ਨੂੰ (ਕਿ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਵੱਸ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਦੇ ਦਿਲ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਪਣੇ ਆਤਮੇ ਦੀ) ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਬਣਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ) ਮਿਲਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ) ਮਿਲ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਇਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ (ਹੀ) ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪ੍ਰਾਣਾਯਾਮ ਆਦਿਕ ਨਾਲ ਵਧਾਈ ਹੋਈ) ਲੰਮੀ ਉਮਰ (ਸਗੋਂ) ਫਿਟਕਾਰ-ਜੋਗ ਹੈ, ਜੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ (ਉਸ ਲੰਮੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਾਲੇ ਦਾ) ਪਿਆਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਦਾ । (ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਸੁੰਦਰ) ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਦੀ ਸੁਖਦਾਈ ਸੇਜ (ਭੀ) ਫਿਟਕਾਰ-ਜੋਗ ਹੈ (ਜੇ ਉਹ) ਮੋਹ ਦਾ ਘੱੁਪ ਹਨੇਰਾ (ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਦੀ) ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਸਿਰਫ਼) ਉਹਨਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਕਾਮਯਾਬ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ) ਆਸਰਾ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ ।੪।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਉਹ ਗ੍ਰਿਹਸਤ ਜੀਵਨ ਫਿਟਕਾਰ-ਜੋਗ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ (ਵਾਲਾ ਜੀਵਨ) ਫਿਟਕਾਰ-ਜੋਗ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਦੀ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਸਾਡਾ ਤਾਂ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਵਲ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਦਾ ਹੈ) । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਸਦਾ ਨਾਲ ਨਿਭਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਾਥੀ) ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ।੫।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਹੀ ਅਸੀ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ (ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ) ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਸਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ ਭੀ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਾਂ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਤੇ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਅੱਗ ਬੁੱਝ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ,(ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਕੋ੍ਰਧ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਖਿਮਾ ਧਾਰਨ ਕਰੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।(ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ (ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਰਤਨ ਪੱਲੇ ਬੰਨ੍ਹਦਾ ਹੈ । ਨਾਨਕ (ਤਾਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ) ਉਸ ਅਲੱਖ ਤੇ ਅਭੇਵ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਸਦਾ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੮।\\""},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis beschrijft de volgende tekst: De grens die met Pruisen werd vastgesteld, liep echter zodanig dat een deel van de concessie op Pruisisch gebied kwam te liggen. Het grenstraktaat van 26 juli 1816 bracht echter met zich mee dat de Domaniale Mijn ook dit in Pruisen gelegen concessiegebied van 173 ha mocht blijven ontginnen, maar de steenkool werd op Nederlands grondgebied naar boven gebracht. In de staatsmijn werd in 1823 de eerste stoommachine geplaatst. Op 9 oktober 1830 tijdens de Belgische Opstand, werden de mijnen door opstandelingen bezet. Ze kwamen zo onder controle van de Belgische Staat. In 1839 werden ze, na de ratificatie van het scheidingsverdrag tussen Nederland en België, weer aan Nederland overgedragen.","answer":"Het gaat over de Domaniale Mijnen door de jaren heen."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள்- ஜெனரல் பரமசிவ பிரபாகர் குமாரமங்கலம் அல்லது ஜெனரல் குமாரமங்கலம் (General Paramasiva Prabhakar Kumaramangalam) , (1 சூலை 1913 – 13 மார்ச் 2000) , இந்திய இராணுவத்தின் 7வது தலைமைப் படைத் தலைவராக 1967 முதல் 1970 வரை பணியாற்றியவர். இரண்டாம் உலகப் போர், இந்திய-பாகிஸ்தான் போர், 1947, இந்திய சீனப் போர்","answer":", மற்றும் 1965இந்திய-பாகிஸ்தான் போர்களில் பங்கெடுத்தவர். பிரித்தானிய இந்தியப் பேரரசின் இராணுவ விருதுகளை பெற்றவர்."},{"question":"Ban dëkk la \\"Ping -pong\\" cosaanoo?","answer":"Angleterre."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा  गोगलगाय नि पोटात पाय","answer":"एखाद्याचे खरे स्वरूप न दिसणे."},{"question":"తారిమ్వాయువ్య చైనా లోని తారిమ్ నదీ  ","answer":"వాయువ్య చైనా లోని తారిమ్ నదీ బేసిన్ లో లభ్యం అయిన క్రీ.పూ. ఒకటి, రెండు సహాస్రాబ్దిల నాటి కాకసాయిడ్ జాతికి చెందిన ప్రజల యొక్క మమ్మీలను తారిమ్ మమ్మీలు గా వ్యవహరిస్తారు. ఈ మమ్మీలు క్రీ.పూ 2000 నుండి క్రీ.శ. 100 మధ్య కాలాలకు చెందినవి. ప్రాథమికంగా తొలి కంచుయుగపు నాగరికతా కాలానికి చెందినవి. వీటిని పశ్చిమ యురేషియా మూల ప్రాంతాలనుంచి చైనా లోని తారిం బేసిన్ ప్రాంతానికి వలస వచ్చిన ఆదిమ ఇండో-యూరోపియన్ తెగ ప్రజలకు చెందినవిగా భావించారు. తక్లమకాన్ ఎడారి ప్రాంతంలో ఈ మమ్మీలు వెలికితీయబడటంతో వీటిని తక్లమకాన్ మమ్మీలుగా పిలుస్తారు. వీరు మాట్లాడే భాష ప్రాచీన ఇండో-యూరోపియన్ భాషా కుటుంబానికి చెందిన తొకేరియన్ భాష అయివుండవచ్చని భావించినందున వీటిని తొకేరియన్ మమ్మీలుగా కూడా పిలిచారుఈ మమ్మీల ప్రాచీనతకన్నా ప్రధానంగా కొట్టొచ్చినట్లు కనిపించే యూరోపియన్ ముఖకవళికలు, లక్షణాలుతో కూడిన భౌతిక రూపాలు మరియు వీటి పాశ్చాత్య వస్తు సంస్కృతి (Western material Culture) పురావస్తు శాస్త్రవేత్తల, పురా మానవ శాస్రవేత్తల (anthropologists) దృష్టిని విశేషంగా ఆకర్షించాయి. దీనికి కారణం చైనీయులు మంగోలాయిడ్ కు చెందిన జాతి ప్రజలు కాగా అదే చైనా దేశంలో లభ్యమైన తారిమ్ మమ్మీలు మాత్రం కాకసాయిడ్ జాతికి చెందిన ప్రజలవి కావడం. అంతే కాక ఆయా సమాధులలో ఈ మమ్మీలతో పాటు లభ్యం అయిన వస్తు సంస్కృతి, పశ్చిమ యురేషియా ప్రాంతానికి చెందిన వస్తు సంస్కృతికి చెందినది కావడం.వేలాది సంవత్సరాల క్రితమే పశ్చిమ యురేసియా ప్రాంతం నుంచి చైనాకు వలస వెళ్ళిన ప్రజల మమ్మీలు ఇవి. తమ దేశంలోనే వేలాది సంవత్సరాల క్రితం జీవించిన వీరి ఉనికిని గురించి ప్రాచీన చైనా చరిత్రకారులుకు కూడా తెలియరాలేదు. నేటి పురావస్తు శాస్రవేత్తలు ఈ మమ్మీలనుచైనా, యూరప్ ల కూడలి ప్రాంతాల వద్ద క్రీ. పూ. 2000 - క్రీ. పూ. 1000 ల మధ్య కాలంలో విలసిల్లిన ఒక ప్రాచీన నాగరికతకు చెందిన ప్రజలకు చెందినవిగా భావిస్తున్నారు.తారిమ్ మమ్మీలు - లభ్యమైన ప్రదేశాలుతారిం మమ్మీలు చైనా లోని షిన్జాంగ్–ఉయ్ఘర్ (Xinjiang-Uyghur) అటానమస్ ప్రాంతమలో గల తారిం నదీ పరీవాహక ప్రాంతంలో వున్న తక్లమకాన్ ఎడారిలో లభ్యం అయ్యాయి. ముఖ్యంగా తారిమ్ బేసిన్ దక్షిణ భాగంలోనూ, తూర్పు భాగంలోనూ ఈ మమ్మీలు అధికంగా లభ్యం అయ్యాయి.దక్షిణ తారిమ్ బేసిన్ ప్రాంతంలో మమ్మీలు దొరికిన ప్రాంతాలు: ఖోటాన్ (Khotan), నియా (Niya), చెర్చాన్ (Cherchan), సాంపులా (Shanpula/ Sampul), యింగ్ పాన్..."},{"question":"कुन देशमा राम्रो जीवन प्रत्याशा छ?","answer":"संसारमा सबैभन्दा बढी आयु जापानमा पाइन्छ, जहाँ औसत आयु ८४ वर्ष छ। जापानी आहार, तीव्र शारीरिक व्यायाम र उच्च गुणस्तरीय स्वास्थ्य सेवामा सहज पहुँच प्रमुख कारण मानिन्छ।"},{"question":"Wanne ne \\"Lokaci na Gaba I\\" a Hausa?","answer":"Shi ne lokacin da yake nuni zuwa ga aikin da ake da tabbacin aiwatar da shi a wani lokaci mai zuwa. Kalmar za ce ke bayyana shi. Misali:1. Za na zo gidanku.2. Za su je makaranta."},{"question":"Non jokatzen du athletic-ek?","answer":"San Mamesen jokatzen du"},{"question":"भारतातील सागरी उत्पादनांसाठी भारतातील सर्वात मोठी बाजारपेठ कोणती आहे?(A) फ्रान्स(B) जपान(C) ईयू(EU)(D) यूएसए=>","answer":" (C) ईयू(EU)"},{"question":"Déterminez si les deux phrases suivantes se paraphrasent ou non. Phrase 1 : \\"Il a été formé par son grand-père, Nick Dakin, et est maintenant entraîné par Geoff Barraclough.\\" Phrase 2 : \\"Il a été formé par son grand-père, Geoff Barraclough, et est désormais entraîné par Nick Dakin.\\"","answer":"Non"},{"question":"பகத் சிங் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"புரட்சியாளர்கள் இறக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"दैनिक जीवनमा सकारात्मक सोचको खेती गर्नुको महत्त्व व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"समग्र कल्याणको लागि सकारात्मक सोचको विकास गर्नु आवश्यक छ। यसले चुनौतीहरूको हाम्रो धारणालाई आकार दिन्छ, लचिलोपनलाई बढाउँछ, र आशावाद र अनुग्रहको साथ जीवनको उतार-चढावहरू नेभिगेट गर्ने हाम्रो क्षमतालाई बढाउँछ।"},{"question":"Sidee loo daaweeya timaha gogoa?","answer":" sidee lodaweya timaha gogoa?Waxan kula wadagi doonaa dhowr talo oo muhiim u ah timaha gogoa iyo sida aad xal ugu heleyso:-DHAQIDA Timahada wainaad u dhaqdaa si jadwal leh una doorto shaambada ku haboon waxey yareyne gogoa. SHANLEYNTA markad timaha dhaqdo qalaji kadib shanley waliga tintada oo qoyan hatabsin shanle maxa yeelay timuhu marka eey qoyonyihin aadbey ujilicsanyihin ineey goaana wa fududahay. Shanlaha aad ku shanleysato ha ahaado caag. HURDADA Barkintadu wainey thy mid dabacsan anan adkeyn ogaw barkinta adag iney timaha jajab kukeento.WALWALKA (Stress)Walwalka iyo stress ka waxay kamid yihin waxyabaha keena timaha gogoa marka walshay walwalka iska yareey waxdna sameysa jimicsi(exercise) .CUNTADA walshay wainaad cunto cuno dheeli tiran waliba cuntada laga helo Iron ta protein ka vitamin C. XULBO Xulbada waxey daawo utahay timaha gogoa sidokle waxey kadhgta kuwa kora #qaabka_usticmale  miraha xulbada ladhig weel biyo kujiran hal habeen #kadib aroortii shiid miraha ilaa aad kadhgto cajiin kabcdi mari timaha waxad kula daboosha bac una sug ilaa 40 daqiqo haku dabolnato sidas kuwad ilaa 30 malin isbadal weyn ayad dareeme I.a BASASHA  Dheecanka Basasha waxey aad u korisa timaha waxa kujira madada loyaqan (sulfur) madadaan waxey badineysa wareega dhiiga inu gaaro duleelada timaha taso keneysa in uu yarado cabuqa kudhacaya .dad badan oo isticmalay aya sheegay tintoda ineey aad u kortay. #qaabka_usticmale  3 qaado oo basasha dheecankeda ayad kuqasee 2 qaado oo saliid seytuun ah #kadib madaxa marine ilaa lafta 30 daqiiqo usug kabacdi dhaq isticmalna shaambo fiican.sidaan samey 2 ilaa 3 jeer isbuuc kasta adigo kuwadaya dhoowr asbuuc #cuntoyinka  kaluunka  digagada galeyda hilibka dufantu kuyarthy barbaroni cas ee mac qamadiga digirta  badso. "},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Ở trận ra quân tại Ligue 2, Quang Hải cùng Pau FC đã phải nhận thất bại đậm 0-4 trước Guingamp trên sân khách. Đây là điều không quá bất ngờ khi mà đội chủ nhà sở hữu đẳng cấp vượt trội đồng thời là ứng cử viên cho ngôi vô địch trong mùa bóng năm nay. Hiện tại, chỉ còn duy nhất một cặp đấu chưa diễn ra tại vòng 1. Trong số những màn chạm trán đã có, Pau FC chính là CLB nhận trận thua đậm nhất. Dù vậy, họ vẫn không phải xếp cuối cùng trên bảng xếp hạng. Lý do là bởi, Saint-Etienne mới là đội đang có vị trí ấy. Ở ngày ra quân, CLB này chỉ thua 1-2 trước Dijon. Tuy nhiên, do phải nhận án phạt từ liên đoàn bóng đá Pháp là trừ 3 điểm cộng với việc đá 4 trận sân nhà không khán giả bởi để CĐV gây bạo loạn ở trận play-off trụ hạng hồi tháng 5 nên Saint-Etienne đang xếp cuối bảng ở Ligue 2 với số điểm -3 cùng hiệu số -1. Pau FC của Quang Hải đang có vị trí thứ 19 trên bảng xếp hạng vào thời điểm hiện tại. Ở vòng đấu tới, họ sẽ tiếp đón Dijon trên sân nhà lúc 0h00 ngày 7/8 (Theo giờ Việt Nam). Đây tiếp tục là thử thách khó khăn nữa dành cho đội bóng này. Với cá nhân Quang Hải, trong màn so tài vừa qua, dù chỉ vào sân và có khoảng 30 phút thể hiện bản thân song những gì mà cầu thủ Việt Nam thể hiện là rất ấn tượng. Anh chính là ngôi sao Pau FC được Sofascore chấm điểm cao nhất với số điểm là 6.9. Điều đó giúp cho tiền vệ sinh năm 1997 sáng cửa đá chính ở vòng đấu thứ 2 sắp tới. Đó là mong mỏi từ hàng triệu triệu cổ động viên nước nhà. Chắc chắn, tất cả đều sẽ dành cho Quang Hải sự cổ vũ nhiệt tình để giúp anh có màn trình diễn mãn nhãn nhất. Việc được thi đấu tại Ligue 2 là cơ hội cho ngôi sao gốc Đông Anh học hỏi cũng như hoàn thiện bản thân.","answer":"Thua 0-4, vì sao đội bóng của Quang Hải vẫn không phải xếp cuối bảng?"},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"வகுப்பில் இரண்டு கெட்டிக்காரர்கள் இருந்தால், இரண்டு பேர்களுக்கும் நட்பு ஏற்படுவது இயற்கை; பகைமை ஏற்படுவதும் சகஜம். இவை இரண்டும் அற்று இருப்பது விதிக்கு விலக்கு.புதுமைப்பித்தன் என்ற புனைப்பெயர் கொண்ட சொ. விருத்தாசலம் (ஏப்ரல் 25, 1906 - மே 5, 1948), மிகச்சிறந்த தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவர். நவீன தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் ஒரு முன்னோடியாக இவர் கருதப்படுகிறார். கூரிய சமூக விமர்சனமும் நையாண்டியும், முற்போக்குச் சிந்தனையும், இலக்கியச் சுவையும் கொண்ட இவருடைய படைப்புகள், இவரின் தனித்தன்மையினை நிறுவுகின்றன.மேற்கோள்கள்இலக்கியத்தில் சுவையம்சம் என்பது ஜீவத்துடிப்பில்தான் இருக்கிறது.[1]பேயும் பிசாசும் இல்லை என்றுதான் நம்புகிறேன். ஆனால், பயமாக இருக்கிறது.[1]வார்த்தைகளை வைத்துக்கொண்டு ஜனங்களைப் பயங்காட்டுவது ரொம்ப லேசு.[1]பொதுவாக என்னுடைய கதைகள் உலகத்துக்கு உபதேசம் செய்யும் ஸ்தாபனம் அல்ல! பிற்கால நல்வாழ்வுக்கு சௌகரியம் பண்ணி வைக்கும் இன்ஷ்யூரன்ஸ் ஏற்பாடும் அல்ல. எனக்குப் பிடிக்கிறவர்களையும் பிடிக்காதவர்களையும் கிண்டல் செய்து கொண்டிருக்கிறேன். சிலர் என்னோடு சேர்ந்துகொண்டு சிரிக்கிறார்கள். இன்னும் சிலர் கோபிக்கிறார்கள்.[1]வேதாந்திகள் கைக்குள் சிக்காத கடவுள் மாதிரிதான் நான் பிறப்பித்துவிட்டவைகளும். அவை உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களுக்குள் அடைபடாதிருந்தால் நானும் பொறுப்பாளியல்ல, நான் பிறப்பித்து விளையாடவிட்ட ஜீவராசிகளும் பொறுப்பாளிகளல்ல; உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களைத்தான் என் கதைகளின் அருகில் வைத்து அளந்து பார்த்துக்கொள்கிறீர்கள் என்று உங்களுக்குச் சொல்லிவிட விரும்புகிறேன்.உண்மையே இலக்கியத்தின் ரகசியம்.வாழ்க்கையில் ஒருவெறி ஏற்பட்டால்தான் பிடிப்புடன் முன்னேறி வாழமுடியும். அதைச் சமயம் கொடுக்கிறது. அது சொல்லுகிற மோட்சத்தைக் கொடுக்காவிட்டாலும் இது போதும். அந்த மோட்சத்தைவிட இது மேலானது.[2]கவிதையைப் போதனைக்குரிய கருவிசாக உபயோகப்படுத்தும் வரை அது கவிதையாக இருக் காது. அதன் ரசனை கெட்டு விடுகிறது.[3]நல்ல இலக்கியமென்றால், எத்தனை நந்திகள் வழிமறித்துப் படுத்துக்கொண்டாலும் இவை உரிய ஸ்தானத்தை அடைந்தே தீரும். பனைமரத்தில் ஊசியைச் சொருகிக் கொண்டு சுமந்து நடந்த பரமார்த்த குருவின் சீடர்கள் போல, எத்தனைபேர் சுமந்து வந்தாலும் பரங்கிக்காய் குதிரை முட்டையாகி விடாது.[3]உணர்ச்சி விஷயங்களில், இனிமேல் என்ற பிரச்சினையைப் பெண்களே சீக்கிரத்தில் கவனிக்கக் \uFEFFகூடியவர்கள், தன்னை ஒப்பு க்கொடுப்பது, தன்னுடைய வாழ்க்கையை ஓர் ஆண்மகனிடம் பணயமாக வைப்பது எவ்வளவு சீக்கிரத்தில் நடக்கிறதோ, அவ்வளவு விரைவிலேயே வருங் காலத்தைப் பற்றித் திட்டம் போடும் திறனும் படைத்து விடுகிறார்கள் அப் பெண்கள்.[3]வகுப்பில் இரண்டு கெட்டிக்காரர்கள் இருந்தால், இரண்டு பேர்களுக்கும் நட்பு ஏற்படுவது இயற்கை; பகைமை ஏற்படுவதும் சகஜம். இவை இரண்டும் அற்று இருப்பது விதிக்கு விலக்கு[3]பெரிய மீன் சின்ன மீனைத் தின்னலாம், ஆனால் சின்ன மீன் அதற்கும் சின்ன மீனைத் தின்றால் பெரிய மீன் ‘குற்றம் செய்கிறாய்!’ என தண்டிக்க வருகிறது. இது தான் சமூகம்![3]ஒழுக்கமும், தர்மமும், மோட்சமும் கவிஞனது உள்ளத்தில் ஊறி, இருதயத்தின் கனிவாக வெளிப்படும் இசைதான் கவிதையாகும்.[3]உடற்கூறு நூல் படியாவிட்டால் உயிர் வாழ முடியாதென்று சொல்ல முடியாது. அதைப் போல் இலக்கணம் இல்லாவிட்டால், கவிதை இருக்க முடியாதென்று கூற முடியாது. ஆனால் கவிதையை ரஸிப்பதற்குக் கவிதை என்றால் என்ன வென்று தெரிந்திருக்க வேண்டும். [3]தற்காலத்தில் பண்டிதர்கள் இலக்கியம் எது என்று கவனிக்க முடியாமல் எல்லாவற்றையும் புகழ்ந்து கொண்டு இடர்ப்படுவதற்குக் காரணம் அவர்கள் இலக்கியம் என்றால் என்னவென்று அறியாததுதான்.[3]வாழ்க்கையின் அர்த்தத்தைச் சொல்லுவது தத்துவம், வாழ்க்கையைக் சொல்வது, அதன் ரசனையைச் சொல்வது இலக்கியம்.[3]சிறுகதை, வாழ்க்கையின் சாளரங்கள். வாழ்க்கையின் ஒரு பகுதியை அல்லது ஒருவரின் தனி உணர்ச்சியை அல்லது ஒரு குண சம்பவத்தை எடுத்துச் சித்திரிப்பது.[3]கலை, தர்ம சாஸ்திரம் கற்பிக்க வரவில்லை; ஒழுக்க நூலை இயற்ற வரவில்லை. உடற்கூறு நூலை எடுத்துக் காட்ட வரவில்லை. பத்துத் தலை ராவணனும், ஆறுதலை சுப்ரமணியனும், உடற்கூறு நூலுக்குப் புறம்பான அபத்தமாக இருக்கலாம். ஆனால் ஒரு கொள்கையை இலட்சியத்தை உணர்த்தக்கூடியது, அது தான் கலையின் இலட்சியம். [3]வாழ்க்கைப் பாதையில் கணவனும், மனைவியுமாகச் செல்லுகையில், மஞ்சள் பூப் போல் இருந்த சமூகம், பந்துக்கள் அவன் பிரிந்தவுடன், முட்களாகக் குத்துகிறார்கள்.[3]தெரிந்ததைச் சொல்லுவதற்குப் புஸ்தகமா, தெரியாததை அறிவதற்குப் புஸ்தகமா? இரண்டிற்கும்தான்.[3]கவிஞன் உலகத்தின் உண்மைகளை, வாழ்க்கையின் ரகஸியங்களை வேறு விதமாகப் பார்க்கிறான். அவன் கண்கள் உணர்ச்சிக் கண்கள். கனவுக் கண்கள்.[3]கவிதையில், சரியான வார்த்தைகள், சரியான இடத்தில் அடைய வேண்டும். கவிஞன் வார்த்தைகளை எடுத்து கோர்ப்பதில்லை. உணர்ச்சியின் பெருக்கு, சரியான வார்த்தைகளைச் சரியான இடத்தில் கொண்டு கொட்டுகிறது. -புதுமைப்பித்தன்[3]கத்தி விழுங்குபவனும் கவிராயனும் ஒன்றல்ல. கவிராயன் நாம் செய்யக் கூடிய காரியத்தைத்தான், நாம் எப்படிச் செய்ய விரும்புகிறோமோ அந்த அளவு ஆணித்தரமான அழுத்தத்துடன் செய்கிறான் என்பவை தவிர நாம் செய்ய முடியாத காரியத்தை அவன் செய்கிறான் என்பதல்ல. -புதுமைப்பித்தன்[3]நமது இலக்கியமானது நெடு நாள் பட்ட வளர்ச்சி கண்டது. அதன் வார்த்தை அமைதிகளே கவிதைப் பண்பு கொண்டு, நடைபயிலும் சிறு குழந்தைக்கு நடைவண்டி போல அமைந்து கிடப்பதால், பேரிகை கொட்டி பிழைப்பதைவிட, கவிதை கட்டிப் பிழைப்பது இலகுவான காரியமாகி விட்டது.-புதுமைப்பித்தன்[3]மோகனமான பகற் கனவுகள் காண்பதில் கவிஞனுக்கு இணையாகக் காதலர்களைத்தான் ஒருவாறு கூறலாம்.-புதுமைப்பித்தன்[3]கவிஞன் எப்பொழுதும் ஒரு இலட்சிய உலகில் வசிப்பவன். அவனது உள் மனத்தின் உணர்ச்சி ஊற்றுக்களிலிருந்து ஜீவசக்தி பெற்று வரும் வார்த்தைகள் தாம் கவிதைகள்.-புதுமைப்பித்தன்கடவுள் இருந்தால் என்ன? இல்லாவிட்டால் என்ன? ஒரு கூட்டத்தின் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு அது அவசியமானால் ஒரு பொய்யைச் சொல்லித்தான், கடவுள் என்ற பிரமையைச் சிருஷ்டித்தால் என்ன?[இந்தக் கடவுள் விஷயம் ரொம்ப ஸ்வாராஸ்யமானது. அது தனிமனிதனுக்கு ஒரு தைரியத்தைக் கொடுக்கிறது. சமூகத்திற்கு ஒரு சக்தியைக் கொடுப்பது போல், நாஸ்திகம் தர்க்கத்தில் நிஜமகே இருக்கலாம். அது சுவாரஸ்யமற்றது. வாழ்க்கையில் ஒரு பிடிப்பை ஏற்படுத்த முடியாதது.சிறுகதைகளில் இருந்து மேற்கோள்கள்நான் ஓடினால் காலம் ஓடும். நான் அற்றால் காலம் அற்றுப்போகும்.இருட்டுக்கும் பயத்துக்கும் ஒளிவிடம் இல்லாத பகலிலே எல்லாம் வேறு மாதிரியாகத் தான் தோன்றுகிறது.[5]மதுரைக்கு வழி வாயிலே.[6]சிக்கிரிப் பவுடர் காப்பி மாதிரிதான் இருக்கும்; ஆனால் காப்பி அல்ல; சில பேர் தெய்வத்தின் பேரைச் சொல்லிக்கொண்டு ஊரை ஏமாற்றி வருகிற மாதிரி.மனிதன் கடவுளைப் படைத்தான். அப்புறம் கடவுள் மனிதனை சிருஷ்டிக்க ஆரம்பித்தான்.மனிதன் தன் திறமையை அறிந்து கொள்ளாமல் செய்த பிசகுக்கு கடவுள் என்று பெயர்.மனிதனுக்கு உண்டாக்கத்தான் தெரியும். அழிக்கத் தெரியாது. அழியும் வரை காத்திருப்பதுதான் அவன் செய்யக்கூடியது.சென்னையிலே தர்ம சிந்தனை ஒரு போக வஸ்து.அந்த சிங்கிகுளத்துப் பெண் மூவாயிரம் ரூபாயைப் பணயமாக வைத்து, அவனுடன் வாழ்க்கையைப் பிணைத்துக் கொள்ள சம்மதிக்கும் பொழுது, ஐந்து ரூபாய்க்கு இரண்டு மணிநேரம் சரி தானே? "},{"question":"هل يمكنك مساعدتي في إنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الطويل؟","answer":"بالطبع، تفضل هذه القصيدة: لَكَ القَلَمُ الجَوّالُ إِذ لا مُثَقَّفٌيَجولُ وَلا عَضبٌ تُهابُ مَواقِعُهسَواءٌ إِذا غَشَّيتَهُ النَقسَ رَهبَةًوَذو لَهذَمٍ غُشّي مِنَ الدَمِّ رادِعُهلَجلِجُ مِن فَوقِ الطُروسِ لِسانُهُوَلَيسَ يُؤَدّي ما تَقولُ مَسامِعُهوَيَنطِقُ بِالأَسرارِ حَتّى تَظُنُّهُحَواها وَصِفرٌ مِن ضَميرٍ أَضالِعُهإِذا اِسوَدَّ خَطبٌ دونَهُ وَهوَ أَبيَضٌيُسَوِّدُ وَاِبيَضَّت عَلَيهِ مَطالِعُه."},{"question":"Irú ènìyàn wo ni àwon Yorùbá ń pè ní Alóńgẹ́? ","answer":"Alóńgẹ́ jẹ́ orúkọ ìnagijẹ fún ènìyàn kúkurú. "},{"question":"పాటెంపాడు context: పాటెంపాడు కృష్ణా జిల్లా, చందర్లపాడు మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన చందర్లపాడు నుండి 5 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన జగ్గయ్యపేట నుండి 48 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 82 ఇళ్లతో, 270 జనాభాతో 500 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 138, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 132. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 19 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 0. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 589181[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 521183.","answer":"పాటెంపాడు గ్రామ పిన్ కోడ్ ఏంటి?"},{"question":"दक्षिणेतील प्रचंड विजयनगर साम्राज्य कोणी स्थापन केले ?","answer":"दक्षिणेतील  विजयनगर साम्राज्य हरिहर व बुक्क या भावांनी स्थापन केले."},{"question":"Em que esporte Neil Adams se destacou?","answer":"judo"},{"question":"Mo ri i daadaa, ọkọ mi fẹẹ fi mi ṣoogun owo ni","answer":"Iyawo ile kan, Modupẹ Oyelade, ti rọ kootu ibilẹ Ọja’ba to wa laduugbo Mapo n’Ibadan lati fopin si igbeyawo ọlọdun mẹtadinlogun (17) to wa laarin oun atọkọ ẹ, Aderẹmi Oyelade, o lọkunrin naa fẹẹ foun ṣoogun owo.Modupẹ, ẹni to fi adugbo Iyana-Church n’Ibadan ṣebugbe sọ lỌjọruu, Wẹsidee, to kọja pe ife ẹtan lọkọ oun ni si oun ati pe ọpọlọpọ irọ lo pa foun lati fi tan oun jẹ ti oun fi gba lati fẹ ẹ nigba naa lọhun-un.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “mo fẹẹ kawe giga, ko jẹ ki n ka a. Bẹẹ, mi o beere owo lọwọ ẹ, emi ni mo fẹẹ ran ara mi. Awọn ọmọ wa gan-an tun n sọ fun un pe ti mo ba kawe ọhun, ṣebi fun anfaani gbogbo wa naa lo maa jẹ.“Aṣe nitori pe oun ọkọ mi ko kawe ni ko ṣe fẹ ki emi naa kawe. Ẹni to ti kawe jade ni yunifasiti lo pera ẹ fun mi ki n too fẹ ẹ, bẹẹ ko niwee ẹri iwe girama paapaa lọwọ. Mo ti bi gbogbo ọmọ tan fun un ki n too mọ pe ko niwee ẹri iwe girama gan-an lọwọ depodepo ti yunifasiti. Ẹyin igba yẹn lawọn ẹ̣bi mi fun mi lowo ti mo fi lọ si UNIOSUN (Fasiti Ipinlẹ Ọṣun) bo tilẹ jẹ pe mo pada da owo yẹn pada fun wọn.”Nigba to n fẹsun kan ọkọ ẹ pe o fẹẹ foun ṣoogun owo, Modupẹ ṣalaye pe, “Ọpọ igba ni mo maa n lalaa pe o gbe igba le mi lori. Mo tun maa n ri igbá yẹn loju aye gan-an, nibi igun yara wa. Ṣugbọn ti mo ba bi awọn ọmọ mi leere pe ṣe wọn ko ri igba ninu yara ni, wọn aa lawọn ko ri igba kankan.“Mo lọọ ri wolii, wọn lọkọ mi fẹẹ fi mi ṣoogun owo ni. Iyẹn lo jẹ ki ẹru ẹ ba mi ti mo fi sa kuro ninu ile ko too di pe awọn pasitọ ba wa pari ẹ ni ṣọọṣi ti mo fi pada sinu ile.“Igba kan wa to ran awọn háyákilà si mi. Mo jade nile nirọlẹ ọjọ kan lawọn agbanipa n sọ fun mi loju ọna pe maddam, ẹ ki i ṣe ẹni ta a le pa ni o. Ẹ yee rinrin alẹ o, nitori wọn ti sanwo ẹmi yin o. Bi wọn ṣe sọ bẹẹ lemi naa yaa tete fere ge e.”Pẹlu bi olujẹjọ, Aderẹmi Oyelade, ko ṣe fara mọ ki wọn tu igbeyawo naa ka, o kọ lati fẹsun kan iyawo ẹ niwaju igbimọ awọn adajọ. Ṣugbọn o ni irọ lobinrin naa pa mọ oun, oun ko gbero lati fi i ṣoogun owo.Amọ ṣaa, igbimọ awọn adajọ kootu naa, labẹ akoso Oloye Ọdunade Ademọla ti fopin si igbeyawo ọlọdun mẹtadinlogun to seso ọmọ mẹrin naa.Olupẹjọ ni wọn yonda awọn ọmọ mẹrẹẹrin fun. Wọn si pa baba wọn laṣẹ lati maa san ẹgbẹrun lọna ogun Naira (N20,000) fun iya wọn loṣooṣu gẹgẹ bii owo ounje.ọn ọmọ wọnyi."},{"question":"Núi Bà Đen, nóc nhà của Nam Bộ, cao bao nhiêu m?","answer":"Núi Bà Đen cao 986 m, nằm ở phía Đông Bắc thành phố Tây Ninh, tỉnh Tây Ninh. Đây là ngọn núi cao nhất Nam Bộ, nằm trong quần thể khu di tích lịch sử - văn hoá và thắng cảnh Núi Bà Đen và được công nhận là khu du lịch quốc gia."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Yëgle bu Soxna Xadi Faal mi jiite kurel gi'y dàlal jamp ga, bi mu'y tontu laaj yu \\"Libération\\": \\"Jot na noo dàlal ñu àme ay gaañu-gaañuy sox, ñu àme ay gaañu-gaañu yu yeneen i ngànnaay. Lu àju ci gaañu-gaañu yi, kenn (1) rekk moo des ca bulub xettli ba, kenn (1) ca xàyu ba ak ñeneen ñent (4) ngìr raglu.\\".","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Yëgle bu Soxna Xadi Faal mi jiite kurel gi'y dàlal jamp ga, bi mu'y tontu laaj yu \\"Libération\\": \\"Jot na noo dàlal ñu àme ay gaañu-gaañuy sox, ñu àme ay gaañu-gaañu yu yeneen i ngànnaay. Lu àju ci gaañu-gaañu yi, kenn (1) rekk moo des ca bulub xettli ba, kenn (1) ca xàyu ba ak ñeneen ñent (4) ngìr raglu.\\".\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Yëgle: NOUNbu: PRONSoxna: PROPNXadi: PROPNFaal: PROPNmi: PRONjiite: VERBkurel: NOUNgi: PRON'y: AUXdàlal: VERBjamp: NOUNga: DET,: PUNCTbi: SCONJmu: PRON'y: AUXtontu: VERBlaaj: NOUNyu: PRON\\": PUNCTLibération: NOUN:: PUNCT\\": PUNCT.: PUNCT\\": PUNCTJot: VERBna: AUXnu: PRONa: AUXdàlal: VERBñu: PRONàme: ADJay: DETgaañu-gaañuy: NOUNsox: NOUN,: PUNCTñu: PRONàme: ADJay: DETgaañu-gaañu: NOUNyu: PRONyeneen: DETi: ADPngànnaay: NOUN.: PUNCTLu: PRONàju: ADJci: ADPgaañu-gaañu: NOUNyi: DET,: PUNCTkenn: NUM(: PUNCT1: NUM): PUNCTrekk: ADVmu: PRONa: AUXdes: ADJca: ADPbulub: NOUNxettli: NOUNba: DET,: PUNCTkenn: NUM(: PUNCT1: NUM): PUNCTca: ADPxàyu: NOUNba: DETak: CCONJñeneen: ADJñent: NUM(: PUNCT4: NUM): PUNCTngìr: ADPraglu: NOUN.: PUNCT\\": PUNCT.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Tambaya:  wanene wanda ya lashe gasar zakarun mata ta Wimbledon 2013? ","answer":"Amsa: Sabine Lisicki"},{"question":"人體中最先衰老的器官是？","answer":"胸腺"},{"question":"कृपया रिक्त स्थानों को पूरा करें: \\"मेरे पिता हमेशा __________ से मुझे __________ देते थे, क्योंकि वे जानते थे कि __________ में शिक्षा का महत्व है.\\"","answer":"मेरे पिता हमेशा समझदारी से मुझे सलाह देते थे, क्योंकि वे जानते थे कि बुद्धिमता में शिक्षा का महत्व है."},{"question":"சோப்பு தயாரிக்கப் பயன்படுவது \\t1. மெக்னீசியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு2. அம்மோனியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு3. சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு4. கால்சியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு","answer":"3. சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு"},{"question":"*في أي قارة يقع كهف ناجاما؟","answer":"قارة أستراليا"},{"question":"1240ع جي شهنشاهه جو 1175ع جي شهنشاهه سان ڪهڙو تعلق هو؟ پوئين سوال کي نظر ۾ رکندي ، هڪ تناظر لکو جنهن ۾ جواب شامل آهي. اهو 1 - 20 جملا ٿي سگهي ٿو. پس منظر:","answer":"شروعاتي اعليٰ وچين دور ۾ ، جرمني تي عثماني خاندان جي حڪومت هئي ، جيڪو مهاجر دور کان وٺي علائقائي ڊچين تي حڪمراني ڪندڙ طاقتور ڊيوڪن کي ڪنٽرول ڪرڻ جي جدوجهد ڪئي. 1024 ۾ ، انهن جي جاءِ تي سالين خاندان طرفان تبديل ڪيو ويو ، جيڪو مشهور طور تي ايمپائر هينري چوٿين جي تحت پاپائيت سان ٽڪراءُ ٿيو چرچ جي تقرري تي سيڙپڪاري جي تڪرار جي حصي جي طور تي. هن جي جانشين پوپ جي خلاف جدوجهد جاري رکي ۽ گڏوگڏ جرمن امير جي خلاف. امپائر هينري پنجين جي موت کانپوءِ هڪ عدم استحڪام جو دور هو ، جيڪو وارثن کان سواءِ فوت ٿي ويو ، جيستائين فريڊرڪ آءِ باربراسسا  شاهي تخت تي ويٺو. جيتوڻيڪ هن موثر طريقي سان حڪمراني ڪئي ، بنيادي مسئلا برقرار رهيا ، ۽ هن جا جانشين 13 صدي تائين جدوجهد جاري رکيا. بارباروسا جو پوٽو فريڊرڪ II ، جيڪو پنهنجي ماءُ جي ذريعي سسلي جي تخت جو وارث پڻ هو ، پوپ سان بار بار ٽڪراءُ ٿيو. هن جي درٻار پنهنجي عالمن لاءِ مشهور هئي ۽ هن تي اڪثر بدعت جو الزام لڳندو هو. هن ۽ هن جي جانشين ڪيترن ئي مشڪلاتن کي منهن ڏنو، جن ۾ 13 صديءَ جي وچ ۾ منگولن جي يورپ تي حملو شامل آهي. منگول پهريان ڪيفان روس جي اميرن کي ٽوڙي ڇڏيو ۽ پوءِ 1241ع، 1259ع ۽ 1287ع ۾ اوڀر يورپ تي حملو ڪيو."},{"question":"地理学的研究方法有哪些？","answer":"答：地理学的研究方法包括实地考察、遥感技术、地理信息系统(GIS)等。实地考察可以直接观察和记录地理现象，遥感技术可以通过卫星或飞机获取大范围的地理信息，GIS可以处理和分析空间数据。"},{"question":"アメリカ５０州のなかで一番面積の広いのは何州でしょう？","answer":"アラスカ州です。"},{"question":"Awọn agbalẹ ṣewọde l’Ekiti, wọn lowo osu awọn ko too na mọ","answer":"L’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii ni ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ ti ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti gba siṣẹ, ti wọn n gba ilẹ niluu Ado-Ekiti, ṣe iwọde ta ko bi ijọba ipinlẹ naa ṣe n fi iya owo oṣu jẹ wọn.Awọn ẹgbe oṣiṣẹ naa ti gbogbo wọn jẹ obinrin, ti wọn ko si din ni ọgọrun wọn sọ pe awọn ṣe iwọde naa lati ke pe ijọba ki wọn fi kun owo oṣu awọn to jẹ ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira.Wọn ni o ti to ki ijọba fi kun owo-oṣu awọn lati ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira si ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn naira, ko le ba ti awọn oṣiṣẹ to ku labẹ ijọba ipinlẹ naa mu.Iwọde naa ni wọn bẹrẹ ni deede aago meje aarọ, lati gbangan Fajuyi to wa niluu Ado-Ekiti, ti wọn si gbe patako oriṣiiriṣii dani.Lara awọn akọle to wa lara patako ọhun ni “Ẹ dawọ sisan owo oṣu kekere fun awa agbalẹ”  “Ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn naira ni owo oṣu to kere ju ju lọ fawọn oṣiṣẹ.”  ” Gomina Kayọde, jowọ, ma fi wa silẹ.” “Iya n jẹ wa.” “Owo oṣu wa ti kere ju, ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira ko tẹ wa lọrun.” ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.Olori awọn oṣiṣẹ agbalẹ, Titilayo Faweya, ṣalaye  pe awon ṣe iwọde naa lati ta ko ipinnu ijọba ati bi iya ṣe n jẹ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ awọn.O ni awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oun ti ni suuru latigba ti Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi ti ṣe ileri fun awọn ni ọdun mẹta sẹyin pe oun yoo fi kun owo oṣu awọn ni kete toun ba ti gun ori aleefa.“Idi pataki ti a fi ṣe iwọde yii, ni pe ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti n fiya jẹ wa pupọ, ki i ṣe pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa n ba ijọba ja, tabi boya a ko fi ọkan ijọba balẹ, ṣugbọn awọn ẹgbẹ wa ti ni suuru to.”“Ẹgbẹrun marun-un naira pere ni owo oṣu wa, ti ẹ ba gbọ iye ti wọn n ta gaari lọja bayii, bawo ni a ṣe fẹẹ fi owo kekere tijọba yii n san fun wa bọ awọn ọmọ wa, awọn to pọ ju lara wa jẹ opo ti ko ni ọkọ sile.”Nigba to n ba awọn agbalẹ naa sọrọ, Kọmiṣanna fun eto ayika nipinlẹ Ekiti, Arabinrin Iyabọ Fakunle, sọ pe gbogbo nnkan ti awọn oṣiṣẹ naa sọ ni oun yoo fi to Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi leti."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Chương trình với tên gọi Alibaba Cloud Empowerment sẽ cung cấp cho hơn 2.000 doanh nghiệp trong nước quyền tiếp cận các dịch vụ tư vấn chuyên nghiệp, bộ công nghệ đám mây tiên tiến và các khóa đào tạo miễn phí. Các khóa đào tạo sẽ được tổ chức bởi Alibaba Cloud và VDCA, bao gồm những lĩnh vực như điện toán đám mây, phân tích dữ liệu và xây dựng các trang web cùng ứng dụng thương mại điện tử. Alibaba Cloud cũng cung cấp hỗ trợ kỹ thuật và tư vấn cho các doanh nghiệp đang tìm cách nâng cao năng lực kỹ thuật số và sử dụng các giải pháp đám mây. Hỗ trợ này bao gồm đánh giá toàn diện về kiến trúc hiện có của một công ty nhất định, phân tích các bước cần thiết để di chuyển qua đám mây một","answer":"cách hiệu quả và đề xuất về cách vượt qua những thách thức mà doanh nghiệp phải đối mặt trên các lĩnh vực truyền thông, giải trí, trò chơi, Internet và FinTech. Theo ông Nguyễn Minh Hồng – Chủ tịch Hội Truyền thông số Việt Nam: \\"Tốc độ phát triển của Việt Nam dẫn đến nhu cầu ngày càng tăng về năng lực kỹ thuật số từ cộng đồng doanh nghiệp của chúng tôi, đặc biệt đối với các dịch vụ hỗ trợ truyền thông kỹ thuật số và trao đổi thông tin\\". \\"Bằng cách hợp tác với Alibaba Cloud, chúng tôi mong muốn cung cấp công cụ và chương trình đào tạo cần thiết cho các doanh nghiệp Việt Nam để nắm bắt những xu hướng, cơ hội mới cũng như xây dựng vị thế của các doanh nghiệp trong nước ở tương lai\\", ông Hồng nói. VDCA và Alibaba Cloud đã khởi động chương trình này trong một sự kiện do Intel tổ chức tại TP Hồ Chí Minh. Sự kiện quy tụ nhiều nhà lãnh đạo công nghệ nổi bật từ khắp Việt Nam để thảo luận về các xu hướng và sự phát triển chính liên quan đến đám mây. Trọng Đạt"},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Enrico Fermi para a física?","answer":"Enrico Fermi desempenhou um papel crucial no desenvolvimento da física nuclear. Ele liderou a primeira reação em cadeia controlada, demonstrando a viabilidade da energia nuclear controlada. Fermi também foi fundamental na compreensão da força fraca, contribuindo para a teoria eletrofraca."},{"question":"What is the largest US state (by landmass)?","answer":"Alaska is the the largest state in the USA in terms of total area. Covering a staggering 665,384 square miles, Alaska is more than twice the size of the second-largest state, Texas."},{"question":"為什麼地球有四季？","answer":"地球自轉和公轉的不同位置導致不同區域在不同時間接收到的陽光量有所變化，所以就有了四季的變化。"},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Sudão?","answer":"Cartum."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා​වේ 1833 වර්ෂයේ දී පිහිටුවන ලද ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභාවට ඇතුලත් ​වූ සාමාජිකයන් 15 දෙනා​ගේ ස‍ංයුතිය දක්වන්න.","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා​වේ 1833 වර්ෂයේ දී පිහිටුවන ලද ව්‍යවස්ථාදායක සභාවට ඇතුලත් ​වූ සාමාජිකයන් 15 දෙනා​ගේ ස‍ංයුතිය පහත පරිදි වේ.1. නිල ලත් - 92. නිල නොලත් 6මෙයින් නිල නොලත් 6 දෙනාගෙන් යුරෝපීයන් වෙනුවෙන් තිදෙනෙක් හා සිංහල, දෙමළ, බර්ගර් යන ජන කොටස් වෙනුවෙන් එක් අයෙකු බැගින් තෝරා පත් කරන ලදී."},{"question":"What is the largest satellite in the solar system?","answer":"The largest satellite in the Solar System is Ganymede, a moon of Jupiter. Ganymede is not only the largest moon of Jupiter but also the largest in the entire Solar System. It is even larger than the planet Mercury, although it has only about half its mass. Ganymede measures about 5,268 kilometers (3,273 miles) in diameter, making it significantly larger than the Earth's moon, which has a diameter of about 3,474 kilometers (2,159 miles).Ganymede is particularly notable for several reasons beyond its size. It is the only moon in the Solar System known to have its own magnetosphere, a magnetic field surrounding the moon. Additionally, Ganymede is believed to have a subsurface ocean, which may contain more water than all of Earth's oceans combined. This makes Ganymede a subject of interest for scientists studying the potential habitability of moons in the outer Solar System."},{"question":"கணவன் மற்றும் மனைவியை வைத்து ஒரு கடி ஜோக் சொல்லவும்.","answer":"மனைவி: என்னங்க, எங்க ஆபிஸ்ல இன்னைக்கு உங்களை விசாரிச்சாங்க.கணவன்: என்னனு விசாரிச்சங்க மா?மனைவி: தினமும் ஒரு வயசானவர் கொண்டு வந்து விடுறாரே அவர்தான் உங்க அப்பாவான்னு."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Gambiya ƙaramar ƙasa ce ta yammacin Afirka da Senegal ke kewaye da ita. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: (a) GaskiyaWannan magana daidai ce. Gambiya karamar kasa ce ta yammacin Afirka wacce ke kewaye da kasar Senegal gaba daya, in ban da gabar tekun Atlantika."},{"question":"Wygeneruj bardziej szczegółową wersję tego zdania: \\"Nagrodzony Latin Grammy Award 2010 za jego pracę w Hombre Invisible Ely Guerra.\\"","answer":"Oczywiście, bardziej szczegółowa wersja zdania brzmi: \\"Nagrodzony Latin Grammy Award 2010 za swoją pracę w Hombre Invisible Ely Guerra, jest aktywnym członkiem ponad 20 zespołów jazzowych, rockowych, muzyki światowej i elektroniki w Europie, USA i Meksyku.\\""},{"question":"شنو هو الجهاز اللي كيقيسو بيه سرعه الرياح؟","answer":"الانيمومتر"},{"question":"பாரதிதாசனாரின் சிறப்புப் பெயர்கள் யாவை?","answer":"பாரதிதாசனாரின் சிறப்புப் பெயர்கள் : புரட்சிக் கவி, பாவேந்தர்"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny tselatra atosiky ny varatra, ny orana atosiky ny rahona, _\\"","answer":"\\"fa ny olona atosikiny fitiavana.\\""},{"question":"ටෙනිස් පිත්තක්(racket)  තෝරාගැනීමේදී මා  සලකා බැලිය යුතු කරුණු මොනවාද?","answer":"ටෙනිස් පිත්තක්  මිලදී ගැනීමේදී සාධක මාලාවක් තිබේ. ප්‍රාථමික සාධක අතරට හිසේ ප්‍රමාණය, දිග, බර, තද ගතිය සහ පැද්දෙන බර හිසේ ප්‍රමාණය ඇතුළත් වේ - බලය හිස ප්‍රමාණයට සමීපව සම්බන්ධ වේ - හිස විශාල වන තරමට වැඩි බලයක් ජනනය කළ හැකිය, අනෙක් සියලුම සාධක සමාන වේ. විශාල හිස ප්‍රමාණය විශාල පහර ප්‍රදේශයක් සහ 'පැණිරස' ද සපයයි. කුඩා  හිස ප්‍රමාණය වැඩි පාලනයක් සහ උපාමාරු වලට සමාන වේ. දිග - සම්මත දිග අඟල් 27, නමුත් අඟල් 26.5 සිට අඟල් 29 දක්වා විය හැක. දිගු රැකට් එකක් වැඩි ප්‍රවේශයක් ලබා දෙන අතර බොහෝ විට වැඩි බලයක් ලබා දෙයි. හිස ප්‍රමාණයට සමාන, දිගු රැකට් උපාමාරු සහ පාලනය සීමා කළ හැකිය. බර - පිත්තයේ බර වැඩි වන තරමට, ඔබ වැඩි බලයක් ජනනය කරනු ඇත ('swingweight' වැඩි කිරීම). පිත්ත සැහැල්ලු වන තරමට, ක්‍රීඩකයින්ට ජාවාරම නිවැරදි පැද්දීමේ ස්ථානයට ගෙන ඒම වඩාත් උපාමාරු සහ පහසු වනු ඇත. බරෙහි කොටසක් ලෙසද රැකට් සමතුලිතතාවය ඉතා වැදගත් වේ. වැඩි හෙඩ් ලයිට් ජාවාරමක් (හැඩයේ වැඩි බරක්) වැඩි උපාමාරු ලබා දෙයි, විශේෂයෙන් බරින් යුත් ජාවාරමක් භාවිතා කරන විට. පන්දුව පිටුපස ස්කන්ධය පවත්වා ගැනීම සඳහා වඩා සමබර හෝ හිස බර ජාවාරමක් බොහෝ විට සැහැල්ලු ජාවාරම් සඳහා වෙන් කර ඇත තද බව - සාමාන්‍යයෙන් කිවහොත්, ජාවාරම දැඩි වන විට, පන්දුව ඔබේ ජාවාරමෙන් හරවා යවන විට අඩු ශක්තියක් අහිමි වන අතර එමඟින් වැඩි බලයක් නිර්මාණය වේ. වඩාත් නම්‍යශීලී රැකට් වැඩි හැඟීමක් සහ පාලනයක් සඳහා ඉඩ සලසයි. නම්‍යශීලී පිත්ත අඩු කම්පනයක් සහ බලපෑම අත සහ වැලමිට වෙත මාරු වන බැවින් වැඩි පහසුවක් ලබා දේ. Swingweight - Swingweight මගින් ඔබ එය දෝලනය කරන විට එය කොතරම් බරක් දැනෙනවාද යන්න සහ ඔබට පන්දුවට මාරු කළ හැකි බලය ප්‍රමාණය මනිනු ලබයි. ඉහළ පැද්දීමේ බර රැකට් එකේ වැඩි ස්ථාවරත්වයක් ලබා දෙන නමුත් උපාමාරු කැප කරයි."},{"question":"Iza no planeta antsoina matetika hoe \\"planeta mena\\"?","answer":"Martsa no planeta antsoina matetika hoe \\"planeta mena\\"."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake magana a wannan maudu'in mai zuwa? \\"matsalar sufuri a babban birnin tarayya Abuja\\". ","answer":"\\"matsalar sufuri \\""},{"question":"日清戦争勝利後の日本に対して「三国干渉」を行った三つの国とは、ロシア、ドイツとどこでしょう？","answer":"フランス"},{"question":"漫画「ドラゴンボール」で孫悟空が体力を回復するのに食べるものといったら何？","answer":"仙豆（せんず）です。"},{"question":"Adamu lagi mọ ọlọkada lori n’Ibafo, lo ba gbe alupupu ẹ lọ","answer":"Bo tilẹ jẹ pe meji ni wọn, iyẹn awọn ọkunrin Hausa ti wọn gba ọkada Bajaj lọwọ ẹnikan n’Ibafo lọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii, ọkan ninu wọn torukọ ẹ n jẹ Muhammed Adamu lọwọ awọn fijilante VGN ipinlẹ Ogun ba, o si ti jẹwọ fun wọn pe igi loun ati ekeji oun to ti sa lọ bayii la mọ ọlọkada naa lori tawọn fi gbe maṣinni rẹ lọ.Fijilante to fi iṣẹlẹ naa to ALAROYE leti, David Ọlatayọ, ṣalaye pe Yuniiti Ibafo lawọn wa toun fi ri awọn meji kan lori ọkada, ti wọn n wo yeleyele bii ole, ti irisi wọn si mu ifura dani. O ni iyẹn lawọn ṣe da wọn duro, ṣugbọn to jẹ niṣe ni wọn bẹrẹ si i sa lọ titi ti wọn fi wọnu igbo to wa nitosi.Nibi ti wọn ti n le wọn lọ naa ni ọwọ ti ba Adamu pẹlu ọkada naa, bi wọn ṣe n mu un bọ ni wọn ri ọlọkada ti wọn gba maṣinni lọwọ ẹ tiyẹn n kigbe ole bọ pẹlu ori ẹ ti wọn lagi mọ.Ọlọkada naa ṣalaye pe oun gbe awọn Mọla naa gẹgẹ bii ero ni, afi bawọn ṣe de ibi ti wọn pe foun ti wọn gbe ẹgbẹrun kan naira le oun lọwọ pe koun mu ṣenji wa, bẹẹ, idaji kutu ni,oun ko ni ṣenji, ko si sẹni to le ṣẹ oun lowo naa lasiko yẹn.O ni nibi toun ti n sọ pe ko si ṣenji naa ni ọkan ninu awọn ọkunrin meji ọhun ti lagi mọ oun lori, bi wọn ṣe gbe oun ṣubu, ti wọn gbe ọkada oun lọ niyẹn.Nigba to n ṣalaye ara ẹ, Adamu; ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun, sọ pe ojule keji, Opopona Ọla, l’Ogijo, loun n gbe, ṣugbọn Ibafo nibi toun yan laayo fun jija ọkada gba.O ni ekeji oun to sa lọ naa lọga oun ninu iṣẹ yii, oun naa loun si n wo lawokọṣe.Ọdọ awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Ibafo ni Adamu wa lasiko ti a n kọ iroyin yii, nitori awọn fijilante ti fa a le wọn lọwọ. Ọsẹ yii ni wọn ni yoo foju bale-ẹjọ."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 総務省は毎月、家庭が買う物や利用するサービスの値段を調べて、物価がどのぐらい変わったか発表しています。10月の物価は、1年前と比べて3.6%高くなりました。物価が前に3.6%上がったのは、40年8か月前の1982年2月でした。物価が上がった大きな原因は、多くの食料品の値段が上がったことです。食料品は、原料が高くなったり、円が安くなったりして、1年前より5.9％高くなりました。ほかには、電気代が20.9％、ガス代が20％、携帯電話が16.5％、エアコンが13.3％上がりました。総務省は「10月はたくさんの食料品の値段が上がったため、物価が9月より0.6ポイント上がりました。これからも食料品の値段は上がり続けると思います」と話しています。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"Темир жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Темирди эриткен көмүр, адамды эриткен көңүл."},{"question":"जैन धर्म में महावीर को क्या माना जाता है?","answer":"उत्तर: संस्थापक"},{"question":"‘பால்வகை தெரிந்த பகுதிப் பாண்டமொடுகூலம் குவித்த கூல வீதியும்’ – இடஞ்சுட்டிப் பொருள் விளக்குக.","answer":"இடம் :சிலப்பதிகாரம் புகார்க்காண்டத்தில் இந்திர விழா காதையில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.பொருள்:மருவூர்ப்பாக்க வணிக வீதியில் நடைபெற்ற வணிகம்.விளக்கம் :மருவூர்ப்பாக்கத் தெருக்களில் பலப்பல பண்டங்களின் (பொருட்களின்) விற்பனை நடைபெறுகின்றது. எட்டுவகைத் தானியங்களும் குவிந்து கிடக்கும் கூலக்கடைத் தெருக்களும் உள்ளன."},{"question":"Maak de volgende passages af: Veljko Kadijević (Servo-Kroatisch: Вељко Кадијевић) (Glavina Donja (bij Imotski), 21 november 1925 – Moskou 2 november 2014) was minister van defensie van de Socialistische Federale Republiek van Joegoslavië van 1988 tot 1992 en daardoor commandant van de Joegoslavisch Volksleger gedurende de","answer":"Sloveense Onafhankelijkheidsoorlog. Zijn titel was Generaal van het Leger."},{"question":"Кандай кызыктуу факты билесиз","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты: Эгерде Фейсбук өлкө болсо, калкынын саны боюнча биринчи орунга чыкмак. Facebookтун 2,6 миллиард колдонуучусу бар."},{"question":"Siapakah Harith Iskander? Huraikan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 160 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Harith Iskander Musa (lahir 7 Ogos 1966) ialah seorang pelakon, pelawak, dan pengacara Malaysia. Beliau dikenali sebagai \\"Godfather of the Stand-Up Comedy\\" telah memenangi Anugerah Asia’s Best Stand-Up Comedian oleh majalah Asia pada 2014.Harith merupakan salah seorang daripada pelawak berdiri antarabangsa dicalonkan untuk Laugh Factory’s Funniest Person In The World. Beliau turut berlakon dalam filem Hollywood, Anna and the King sebagai Nikorn pada tahun 1999. Beliau turut menulis cerita bagi filem Cuci dan Hanya Kawan. Restoran Samsaraa Kuala Lumpur miliknya terletak di Desa Sri Hartamas, Kuala Lumpur. Beliau juga pernah menyumbangkan suaranya untuk filem dokumentari pendek yang bertajuk Senaman Asas Kesihatan terbitan Kementerian Kesihatan Malaysia pada 1998. Beliau memenangi pertandingan The Funniest Person in the World pada Disember 2016.Filem-filem yang dibintangi beliau termasuklah Selubung, Hanya Kawan, Anna and the King, Sepet, Baik Punya Cilok, Buli Balik, Gubra, Cuci, Talentime, Aku Tak Bodoh, Lemak Kampung Santan dan Kongsi Raya."},{"question":"Wat is de Sint-Janskerk en waar ligt het?","answer":"De Sint-Janskerk, bijgenaamd “De Peperbus”, is een parochiekerk aan de Sint-Jansstraat te Borgerhout."},{"question":"Unsay mga paborito na mga holidays sa mga Filipino?","answer":"Sa Pilipinas daghan mga holidays nga gina celebrate sa mga Filipino.Tungod kay ang main relihiyon sa Pilipinas kay Katoliko, daghan sa mga holidays kay base sa Katolik na relihoyon.Naay Christmas, Holy Week, ug All Saints Day. Mao kini ang mga example sa mga paboritong holidays sa mga Filipino"},{"question":"ලෝකයේ බුදුවරුන් පහලවන කල්ප පහ (5 ) මොනවාද ?","answer":"ලෝකයේ බුදුවරුන් පහලවන කල්ප පහ (5 ) වන්නෙ සාර කල්පය , මණ්ඩල කල්පය , වර කල්පය , සාර මණ්ඩල කල්පය , මහා භද්‍ර කල්පය ."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 日本のいろいろなところでとても暖かくなっています。今年はいつもの年より桜が早く咲きそうです。天気予報を出す会社などは毎年、ソメイヨシノという桜が咲く日を予想しています。日本気象協会とウェザーマップの9日の予想では、東京と福岡市は今月16日、大阪市は22日です。仙台市は日本気象協会が29日、ウェザーマップが25日です。どちらも、いつもの年より数日から1週間ぐらい早くなりそうだと言っています。日本気象協会は、これから数日は日本の多くのところで20℃ぐらいの暖かさになって、そのあとも高い気温が続くためだと言っています。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"વિક્રમ સંવત પંચાંગ મુજબ વર્ષના કેટલા મહિનાઓ હોય છે. તેના વિષે વિસ્તૃત માં જણાવો.","answer":"વિક્રમ સંવત પંચાંગ મુજબ વર્ષના બાર મહિનાઓ હોય છે. જેના દિવસોની ગણતરી ચંદ્રની કળાને આધારે કરવામાં આવે છે. ગુજરાતી પંચાંગ મુજબ દરેક મહિનાની મધ્યમાં એટલે કે પંદરમા દિવસે પૂનમ આવે છે, જ્યારે મહિનાને અંતે એટલે કે ત્રીસમા દિવસે અમાસ આવે છે. દરેક મહિનામાં બે પખવાડિયાં હોય છે, સુદ અને વદ (શુક્લ પક્ષ અને કૃષ્ણ પક્ષ).આ વિક્રમ સંવત મુજબ વર્ષના મહિનાઓ નીચે મુજબ છે.પહેલો: કારતક મહિનોબીજો: માગશર મહિનોત્રીજો: પોષ મહિનોચોથો: મહા મહિનોપાંચમો: ફાગણ મહિનોછઠ્ઠો: ચૈત્ર મહિનોસાતમો: વૈશાખ મહિનોઆઠમો: જેઠ મહિનોનવમો: અષાઢ મહિનોદસમો: શ્રાવણ મહિનોઅગિયારમો: ભાદરવો મહિનોબારમો: આસો મહિનોલગભગ દર ત્રણ વર્ષે: પુરૂષોત્તમ માસ/અધિક માસ (જેનો પૂર્વનિર્ધારિત ક્રમ નથી)ગુજરાતમાં દિવાળી પછીનો દિવસ વિક્રમ સંવત પ્રમાણે નવા વર્ષનો પહેલો દિવસ (કારતક મહિનો) ગણાય છે."},{"question":"纽约的气候如何？","answer":"纽约的气候是温带大陆性气候，夏季炎热潮湿，冬季寒冷干燥。"},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨ: ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਸਾਡੇ ਘਰ ਲਈ ਕਿਉਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰ: ਅਸੀਂ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਸਮਾਂ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ।ਘਰ ਦਾ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸੁਥਰਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ। ਹਰ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸੁਥਰੇ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦਾ ਅਨੰਦ ਮਾਣ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"పర్యావరణం మీద వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"పర్యావరణం అంటే పరిసరాల వాతావరణం. మనచుట్టూ ఉండేది పరిసరం. పరిసరమంతా కాలుష్యంతో నిండిపోయింది. మానవ జీవితంపై యీ పరిసరాల కాలుష్య ప్రభావం ఉంటుంది. అదే అనారోగ్యానికి కారణమవుతుంది. కాబట్టి పరిసరాలు శుభ్రంగా ఉంచుకోవాలి.పరిసరాలలో కాలుష్యం మూడు రకాలుగా ఉంటుంది. అవి :జలకాలుష్యంధ్వని కాలుష్యంవాతావరణ కాలుష్యం.1) జలకాలుష్యం :నదుల్లో, కాలువల్లో, చెరువుల్లో స్నానాలు చేయడం, బట్టలుతకడం, పశువుల్ని కడగడం మొదలైన కారణాల వల్ల నీరు కలుషితమౌతుంది.2) ధ్వనికాలుష్యం :రోడ్లపై కార్లు, మోటార్ల హారన్స్, భారీ యంత్రాల కదలికలు, కర్మాగారాల శబ్దాలు మొదలైన వాటివల్ల ధ్వని కాలుష్యం ఏర్పడుతుంది.3) వాతావరణ కాలుష్యం :కర్మాగారాలు, బస్సులు, కార్లు, స్కూటర్లు మొదలైన వాటి నుండి వ్యర్థ వాయువులు పొగరూపంలో వాతావరణంలో ప్రవేశిస్తాయి. అందువల్ల వాతావరణ కాలుష్యం ఏర్పడుతుంది.పర్యావరణం కాలుష్యం కాకుండా ఉండాలంటే ప్రజలు తగిన జాగ్రత్తలు తీసుకోవాలి. కాలుష్యాలను నిరోధించాలంటే ఇంటా బయటా అంతటా చెట్లు విరివిగా పెంచాలి. ఇందువల్ల మంచి గాలి వస్తుంది. పరిసరాలు సమతుల్యం అవుతాయి."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：印度歷史上著名的「斯瓦拉詩歌比賽」是哪位詩人發起的？","answer":"答案：印度歷史上著名的斯瓦拉詩歌比賽是由聖詩人薩滿塔爾（Sant Tukaram）發起的。這項比賽是為了讚美神聖的神明而舉行，參賽者通過詩歌表達自己的虔誠和崇敬之情。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada wang abang saya, tak ada wang abang paya\\"?","answer":" Orang yang disukai semasa ia kaya (berharta) sahaja"},{"question":"Awọn ileewe to n fa wahala lori Hijaabu di abawọle ileewe wọn pa n’Ilọrin","answer":"Latari aṣẹ tijọba Kwara pa fun gbogbo awọn ọga ati olukọ ileewe ti wahala ti n ṣẹlẹ lori ọrọ lilo hijaabu lati pada sẹnu iṣẹ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, wamuwamu lawọn ọmọ ijọ Kerubu ati Serafu duro si abawọle ileewe C & S to wa niluu Ilọrin lati ma gba ẹnikẹni laaye lati wọle.Awọn ileewe mẹwẹẹwa ti wahala ti n ṣẹlẹ lori hijaabu ni; C&S College, Sabo-Oke; St. Anthony’s Secondary School, Offa Road; ECWA School, Ọja Iya; Surulere Baptist Secondary School, Bishop Smith Secondary School, Agba Dam, CAC Secondary School, Asa Dam; St. Barnabas Secondary School, Sabo-Oke; St. John School Maraba; St. Williams Secondary School, Taiwo Isale, ati St. James Secondary School, Maraba.ALAROYE ṣakiyesi pe awọn ọmọ ijọ naa ninu aṣọ funfun pẹlu amure ti wọn san mọdii n kọrin ti wọn si n gbadura kikankikan bii awọn afadura-jagun, lati ta ko bi wọn ṣe ni ijọba fẹẹ kan Hijaabu le awọn ọmọ wọn lori.Yatọ si awọn ọmọ ijọ to di gbogbo iwaju geeti to wọnu ọgba ileewe naa, wọn tun ja loodu yẹẹpẹ siwaju ibẹ lati dina awọn olukọ atawọn akẹkọọ.Bakan naa lọrọ ri ni ileewe Saint Anthony atawọn mi-in. Awọn olukọ ati ọga ileewe wa gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ tijọba pa, ṣugbọn nigba ti wọn ko raaye wọle wọn duro kaakiri, ti wọn si n jiroro.Nibi ti awọn ọmọ ijọ duro si lawọn agbofinro ti ya bo wọn ti wọn si fi tipa ṣi abawọle awọn ileewe naa.Ni ileewe Baptist, nibi ti rogbodiyan ti ṣẹlẹ laipẹ, alaafia ti pada sibẹ bayii pẹlu bawọn olukọ ṣe wa nikalẹ."},{"question":"Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"anjing kurap\\".","answer":"Hidup Rama seperti anjing kurap yang melarat ke sana ke mari."},{"question":"Qual é a diferença entre um círculo e uma circunferência?","answer":"A diferença entre um círculo e uma circunferência é que:Um círculo é uma figura geométrica plana, que consiste no conjunto de todos os pontos que estão a uma mesma distância de um ponto fixo chamado de centro. Um círculo tem uma área, que é dada pela fórmula A = πr^2, onde r é o raio do círculo.Uma circunferência é uma curva fechada e simples, que consiste na fronteira de um círculo. Uma circunferência tem um comprimento, que é dado pela fórmula C = 2πr, onde r é o raio da circunferência."},{"question":"Розв'язати задачу та дати відповідь: У 12-літровій бочці було 7 літрів води, а у відрі - 8 літрів.Водою з відра доповнили бочку по вінця. Скільки літрів води залишилося у відрі?","answer":"Розв'язання: спочатку рахуємо скільки літрів можна додати у бочку: 12-7= 5, потім рахуємо наскільки більше води в відрі ніж потрібно: 8-5= 3. Відповідь: 3 літра. "},{"question":"Shorten and Summarize the following Urdu Essay in Urdu Language:Essay:قاہرہ (انگریزی: Cairo) (تلفظ: /ˈkaɪroʊ/ KY-roh; عربی: القاهرة، تلفظ [ælqɑ(ː)ˈheɾɑ]) مصر کا دار الحکومت ، افریقہ، عرب دنیا اور مشرق وسطیٰ میں سب سے بڑا شہری مجموعہ ہے۔ قاہرہ کبری میٹروپولیٹن علاقہ، جس کی آبادی 21.9 ملین ہے، [3] آبادی کے لحاظ سے دنیا کا بارہواں بڑا میگا شہر ہے۔ قاہرہ کا تعلق قدیم مصر سے ہے، کیونکہ اہرامات جیزہ اور قدیم شہر ممفس اور عين شمس اس کے جغرافیائی علاقے میں واقع ہیں۔ نیل ڈیلٹا کے قریب واقع، [4][5] شہر سب سے پہلے فسطاط کے طور پر آباد ہوا، ایک بستی جس کی بنیاد مسلمانوں کی فتح مصر کے بعد 640ء میں ایک موجودہ قدیم رومی قلعے، بابلیون کے ساتھ رکھی گئی تھی۔ دولت فاطمیہ کے تحت 969ء میں قریب ہی ایک نئے شہر القاہرہ کی بنیاد رکھی گئی۔ اس نے بعد میں ایوبی سلطنت اور سلطنت مملوک (مصر) ادوار (بارہویں-سولہویں صدی) کے دوران میں فسطاط کو مرکزی شہری مرکز کے طور پر پیچھے چھوڑ دیا۔[6] قاہرہ طویل عرصے سے اس خطے کی سیاسی اور ثقافتی زندگی کا مرکز رہا ہے، اور اسلامی فن تعمیر کی پیش رفت کی وجہ سے اسے \\"ہزار میناروں کا شہر\\" کا عنوان دیا گیا ہے۔ قاہرہ کے تاریخی مرکز (قاہرہ المعز) کو 1979ء میں یونیسکو عالمی ثقافتی ورثہ کا درجہ دیا گیا۔ [7] عالمگیریت اور عالمی شہر تحقیق نیٹ ورک کے مطابق قاہرہ کو \\"بیٹا +\\" درجہ بندی کے ساتھ عالمی شہر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ [8]آج، قاہرہ میں عرب دنیا کی سب سے قدیم اور سب سے بڑی سنیما اور موسیقی کی صنعت ہے، نیز دنیا کا دوسرا قدیم ترین اعلیٰ تعلیم کا ادارہ، جامعہ الازہر بھی یہیں واقع ہے۔ بہت سے بین الاقوامی میڈیا، کاروباری اداروں اور تنظیموں کے علاقائی ہیڈ کوارٹر شہر میں ہیں۔ عرب لیگ کا صدر دفتر قاہرہ میں اپنے زیادہ تر وجود میں رہا ہے۔453 مربع کلومیٹر (175 مربع میل) پر پھیلا ہوا 10 ملین[9] سے زیادہ آبادی کے ساتھ، قاہرہ مصر کا سب سے بڑا شہر ہے۔ مزید 9.5 ملین باشندے شہر کے قریب رہتے ہیں۔ قاہرہ، بہت سے دوسرے شہروں کی طرح، آلودگی اور ٹریفک کی اعلیٰ سطح کے مسائل کا شکار ہے۔ قاہرہ میٹرو، جو 1987ء میں کھولی گئی، افریقہ کا سب سے پرانا میٹرو نظام ہے، [10][11] اور اس کا شمار دنیا کے پندرہ مصروف ترین نظاموں میں ہوتا ہے، جس میں سالانہ 1 بلین[12] مسافروں کی سواری ہوتی ہے۔ قاہرہ کی معیشت 2005ء میں مشرق وسطیٰ میں پہلے نمبر پر تھی، [13] اور فارن پالیسی (رسالہ) کے 2010ء گلوبل سٹیز انڈیکس میں عالمی سطح پر 43 ویں نمبر پر ہے۔[14]اشتقاقیاتخلیفہ معز لدین اللہ کے دور کا ایک سکہمصری اکثر قاہرہ کو مصری عربی، یں مصر (کلمہ نویسی Maṣr (بین الاقوامی اصواتی ابجدیہ: [mɑsˤɾ]; مَصر) کہتے ہیں، جو ملک کے لیے شہر کی اہمیت پر زور دیتے ہیں۔ [15][16] اس کا رسمی نام القاہرہ (القاهرة) کا مطلب ہے 'فتح کرنے والا' یا 'قاتح، اس حقیقت کی وجہ سے کہ سیارہ مریخ، نجم القاہر (النجم القاہر، 'فتح کرنے والا ستارہ')، اس وقت عروج پر تھا جب شہر کی بنیاد رکھی گئی تھی۔[17] ممکنہ طور پر دولت فاطمیہ کے خلیفہ معز لدین اللہ کی آمد کے حوالے سے بھی جو 973ء میں فاطمیوں کے پرانے دار الحکومت مہدیہ (شہر) سے قاہرہ پہنچے تھے۔ قدیم شہر عين شمس کا مقام عين شمس (قاہرہ) (عربی زبان: عين شمس، 'سورج کی آنکھ') قاہرہ کا مضافاتی علاقہ ہے۔شہر کے چند قبطی نام ہیں۔ Tikešrōmi (قبطی: Ϯⲕⲉϣⲣⲱⲙⲓ موخر قبطی: [di.kɑʃˈɾoːmi]) 1211 کی عبارت (The Martyrdom of John of Phanijoit) میں تصدیق شدہ ہے اور یا تو ایک کالک ہے جس کا مطلب ہے 'مرد توڑنے والا' (Ϯ-، 'the'، ⲕⲁϣ-، 'to break'، and ⲣⲱⲙⲓ، 'man')، عربی القاہرہ کے مشابہ۔","answer":"یہ رہا shorten مضمون:قاہرہ مصر کا دارالحکومت اور افریقہ، عرب دنیا اور مشرق وسطیٰ کا سب سے بڑا شہری علاقہ ہے۔ یہ قدیم مصر کے ساتھ اپنی وابستگی کے لئے جانا جاتا ہے اور مشہور نشانیوں کا گھر ہے جیسے اہرام گیزا۔ اس شہر کی آبادی 21.9 ملین ہے اور اسے عالمی شہر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ اس کی ایک بھرپور تاریخ ہے اور یہ صدیوں سے خطے میں سیاسی اور ثقافتی زندگی کا مرکز رہا ہے۔ قاہرہ کے تاریخی مرکز کو یونیسکو کے عالمی ثقافتی ورثے کے طور پر نامزد کیا گیا ہے۔قاہرہ عرب دنیا کی سب سے قدیم اور سب سے بڑی فلم اور موسیقی کی صنعت کے لیے جانا جاتا ہے۔ یہ الازہر یونیورسٹی کا گھر بھی ہے، جو دنیا کی دوسری قدیم ترین یونیورسٹی ہے۔ مزید برآں، بہت سے بین الاقوامی میڈیا، کاروبار، اور تنظیموں کے قاہرہ میں اپنے علاقائی دفاتر ہیں۔ عرب لیگ کافی عرصے سے شہر میں مقیم ہے۔قاہرہ مصر کا سب سے بڑا شہر ہے جس کی آبادی 10 ملین سے زیادہ ہے اور اس کے آس پاس مزید 9.5 ملین رہتے ہیں۔ اسے آلودگی اور ٹریفک کے مسائل کا سامنا ہے۔ قاہرہ میٹرو، جو 1987 میں قائم کی گئی تھی، افریقہ کا سب سے پرانا میٹرو سسٹم ہے اور دنیا کے مصروف ترین نظاموں میں سے ایک ہے، جو سالانہ 1 بلین سے زیادہ مسافروں کی خدمت کرتا ہے۔ 2005 میں، قاہرہ کی معیشت مشرق وسطیٰ میں سرفہرست تھی، اور 2010 کے گلوبل سٹیز انڈیکس میں اسے عالمی سطح پر 43 ویں نمبر پر رکھا گیا تھا۔مشتقات مالیاتی آلات ہیں جو اپنی قیمت کسی بنیادی اثاثہ یا بینچ مارک سے اخذ کرتے ہیں۔ وہ عام طور پر مالیاتی منڈیوں میں ہیجنگ یا قیاس آرائی کے مقاصد کے لیے استعمال ہوتے ہیں۔مصر کے دارالحکومت قاہرہ کو اکثر مصری عربی میں مصر کہا جاتا ہے، ملک کے لیے اس کی اہمیت پر زور دیا جاتا ہے۔ اس کا سرکاری نام، القاہرہ، کا مطلب ہے 'فاتح' اور اس کا تعلق سیارہ مریخ سے ہے۔ اس نام کا تعلق 973 میں فاطمی خلیفہ معیز الدین اللہ کی آمد سے بھی ہو سکتا ہے۔ قاہرہ کا نواحی علاقہ عین شمس قدیم شہر عین شمس کے مقام پر واقع ہے۔شہر کے متعدد قبطی نام ہیں، جن میں سے ایک Tikešrōmi ہے۔ اس نام کا تذکرہ 1211 کے ایک متن میں کیا گیا ہے جسے The Martyrdom of John of Phanijoit کہا جاتا ہے۔ Tikešrōmi کی تشریح عربی اصطلاح القائرہ کی طرح 'مرد توڑنے والا' کے طور پر کی جا سکتی ہے۔"},{"question":"గొల్లభామ అనే కీటకంలో రక్తం వర్ణరహితం. మరో ఉదాహరణ ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"బొద్దింక"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Macédoine du Nord","answer":"Péeyum réwum Macédoine du Nord mu ngi tudu Skopje"},{"question":"క్రింది వానిలో అంతర్జాతీయ వలసను గుర్తించి, రాయండి.→ శ్రీకాకుళం నుండి ఢిల్లీకి.→ తిరుపతి నుండి అమరావతికి.→ విశాఖపట్టణం నుండి సౌదీ అరేబియాకి.→ బెంగుళూరు నుండి ముంబైకి.","answer":"విశాఖపట్టణం నుండి సౌదీ అరేబియాకి."},{"question":"வினா : உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய பாலைவனம் எது?","answer":"விடை: சகாரா"},{"question":" Dhig Sumadda kolmobar? ","answer":" Sumadda kolmobar (;) "},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ny tany efitra mangatsiaka lehibe indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny tany efitra mangatsiaka indrindra eran-tany dia ny Antarctica."},{"question":"Bada misalin Mahaɗi mai Haɗe jimla da jimla.","answer":"1. Ka sayo naman akuya \\"ko\\" a siyo naman tinkiya.2. Ado ya ci tuwo \\"amma\\" bai ƙoshi ba."},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Vụ án Jamal Khashoggi: Cảnh sát Thổ tiếp tục tìm kiếmTóm tắt: Cảnh sát tại Thổ Nhĩ Kỳ đã mở rộng cuộc tìm kiếm quanh cáo buộc một nhà báo Saudi Arabia, Jamal Khashoggi, bị giết.","answer":"Cảnh sát Thổ Nhĩ Kỳ bên ngoài lãnh sự quán Saudi Arabia ngày 17/10 ở IstanbulAnh và Mỹ 'có thể tẩy chay' hội nghị ở Ả Rập Saudi Thổ Nhĩ Kỳ: Erdogan và đối thủ chê bai nhauGiới chức Thổ giấu tên được dẫn lời nói thi thể người này có thể đã bị tiêu hủy trong khu rừng Belgrad hoặc trên đất nông nghiệp.Ông Khashoggi mất tích sau khi đi vào tòa lãnh sự Saudi ở Istanbul ngày 2/10.Sau đó chính quyền Thổ Nhĩ Kỳ cáo buộc ông đã bị Saudi Arabia hạ sát.Saudi Arabia bác bỏ, nói rằng không biết chuyện gì xảy ra.Giới chức đã lấy mẫu từ tòa lãnh sự Saudi và nhà viên tổng lãnh sự để so sánh với mẫu DNA của ông Khashoggi.Trong khi đó, Ngoại trưởng Mỹ Mike Pompeo khẳng định ông chưa hề nghe đoạn ghi âm mà Thổ nói là bằng chứng vụ giết người.\\"Tôi không hề nghe băng nào, không có đoạn ghi chép,\\" Ngoại trưởng Mỹ nói.Vụ việc đang gây rạn nứt giữa Saudi Arabia và các đồng minh phương Tây.Bộ trưởng tài chính Mỹ Secretary Steven Mnuchin và Bộ trưởng thương mại quốc tế Anh Liam Fox đã rút không tham dự một hội nghị ở Riyadh tuần sau.Giới chức Thổ tin rằng ông Khashoggi bị nhóm đặc vụ Saudi giết chết bên trong tòa lãnh sự, sau đó xóa dấu vết.Saudi Arabia bác bỏ cáo buộc, và lúc đầu tuyên bố ông này đã tự do rời khỏi tòa nhà.Truyền thông Thổ quan hệ thân cận với chính phủ đã đăng các chi tiết ghê rợn, nói rằng có đoạn băng ghi âm cho thấy có giọng nói viên tổng lãnh sự Mohammed al-Otaibi.Báo Yeni Safak, gần gũi với chính phủ Thổ, đăng tin ông này nói với đặc vụ Saudi được gửi tới Istanbul: \\"Làm việc này bên ngoài đi. Tôi sẽ gặp rắc rối vì các anh.\\"Truyền thông Thổ còn nói rằng đã xác định có 15 đặc vụ Saudi bay vào rồi ra khỏi Istanbul cùng ngày nhà báo mất tích.Saudi Arabia tuyên bố họ sẵn sàng hợp tác và rằng tin tức vụ giết người \\"hoàn toàn sai lạc\\".Ông Khashoggi là một nhà báo nổi tiếng viết cho nhiều tờ báo Saudi.Ông từng làm cố vấn cho các quan chức Saudi nhưng sau này mâu thuẫn với chính phủ.Năm ngoái, ông chuyển sang Mỹ sống, viết cột báo hàng tháng cho Washington Post."},{"question":"Ku bëgg a xàm nu mu'y def?","answer":"Soo bëggee àm xàm-xàm, man nga a def ñatt:- jàngi- laaj- luññtuTekkiwul ne da nga'y def benn, bàyyi ya ca des. Man nga léen a defandoo ndàx ñaare ñoo'y ànd.Te ìt, àm na xàmìin wow, Yàlla moo'y sol ki Mu namm a xàmal te du ko sàkku walla du ci sonn."},{"question":"Що таке арогенез? ","answer":"Арогенез (від грец. αϊρω - піднімати і γένεσνς - зародження, розвиток, виникнення) супроводжується переходом групи в іншу адаптивну зону шляхом вироблення принципово нових адаптацій - ароморфозів. Арогенез відбувається з порівняно великою швидкістю. Прикладом може бути еволюція класу птахів. Предки сучасних птахів вийшли в нову адаптивну зону завдяки виникненню крила як органа польоту, чотирикамерного серця, теплокровності, розвитку відділів головного мозку, які координують рухи в повітрі. Еволюція груп всередині класу в подальшому відбувалася за алогенезом шляхом виникнення окремих пристосувань - ідіоадаптацій (аломорфозів), внаслідок чого утворилися птахи лісів, пустель, водойм тощо. "},{"question":"Before Mike Myers was selected to perform Shrek’s voice, who was the other Saturday Night Live performer initially cast as Shrek?","answer":"Before Mike Myers was cast as the voice of Shrek in the \\"Shrek\\" film series, the role was initially given to Chris Farley, another \\"Saturday Night Live\\" performer. Farley had reportedly recorded a significant portion of the dialogue for the character before his untimely death in 1997. After his passing, the role was eventually recast with Mike Myers, who then re-recorded the dialogue, bringing his own unique spin to the character, including the now-iconic Scottish accent."},{"question":"Wace kasa ce ta fi yawan shinkafar da ta fi fitar a 2021?","answer":"kasar Indiya ce ta fi yawan fitar da shinkafar a 2021."},{"question":"இராமானுஜரின் குரு யார்?","answer":"திருக்கோட்டியூர் நம்பி இராமானுஜரின் குரு ஆவார் ."},{"question":"Sobre qual importante evento esse texto fala: O pacto foi rompido pela União Soviética em 28 de novembro de 1939, dois dias antes da invasão da Finlândia, alegando que a Finlândia tinha bombardeado uma aldeia soviética. De acordo com o Artigo Quinto, as partes deveriam recorrer a uma comissão conjunta para investigar o incidente, a Finlândia tentou fazê-lo, mas a União Soviética se recusou.","answer":"Invasão da Finlândia"},{"question":"Point out one feature in the practice of federalism in India that is similar to and one feature that is different from that of Belgium.","answer":"ndia and Belgium are similar in the aspect of ‘holding together’ federations."},{"question":"“Tichitarisa ndima iyi, spidhi yeKia Stinger ndeipi? uye 3.3-litre peturu zvichiteerana.Munguva yekuyedzwa neMota uye Mutyairi, ino-vhiri-mavhiri yeU.S. spec GT 3.3T ine Michelin Pilot Sport 4 matayi yakawana 0–60 mph (0–97 km/h) mumasekonzi 4.6 panjanji, yakasvika 0.91 g pa skidpad uye yakakwanisa kumira kubva 70 mph (113 km/h) mu164 tsoka (50 m). Zvinoenderana nebhuku rino, iyo US modhi yekumhanya kwepamusoro inotongwa pa167 mph (269 km/h) paKia specs. Mubvunzo dzakaitwa neMotor Trend, mana-cylinder U.S. spec Stinger 2.0 RWD pamatayi eBridgestone Potenza akasvika 60 mph (97 km/h) mumasekonzi 6.6, akapedza 1⁄4-mamaira (0.4 km) kumhanya mumasekonzi 15 ndokumira. kubva 60 mph (97 km/h) mu126 tsoka (38 m). Avhareji yekukwiridzira yakarekodhwa mukuyedzwa kwe track yaive 0.85 g.\\"","answer":"Kumhanya kwepamusoro kweKia Stinger i269km/h (167mph) maringe nechinyorwa chino."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ ?","answer":"ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਅਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਸ਼ੁਮਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਬਤੌਰ ਬਾਲ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਨਿਭਾਈਆਂ। 15 ਜੂਨ 1939 ਨੂੰ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਪੰਜਾਬ (ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ) ਵਿਚ ਜਨਮੀ ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਨੇ ‘ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਹਾ ਥਾ’ (1937) ਅਤੇ ‘ਤਾਜ ਮਹਿਲ’ (1934) ਵਿਚ ਬਾਲ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ। ਆਲ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਰੇਡੀਓ ਤੋਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਆਵਾਜ਼ ਦਾ ਜਾਦੂ ਬਿਖੇਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਇਸ ਗਾਇਕਾ ਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਦੀ ਆਵਾਜ਼ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਨੌਸ਼ਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਇੰਨੀ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕਾਰਦਾਰ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਸ਼ਾਰਦਾ’ ਲਈ ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਨੂੰ ਗਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਗਾਉਣਾ ਉਸ ਜ਼ਮਾਨੇ ਦੀ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਮਹਿਤਾਬ ’ਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਸਟੇਸ਼ਨ ਮਾਸਟਰ’ ਤੇ ‘ਕਾਨੂੰਨ’ ਵਿਚ ਗਾਏ ਗੀਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਇਕ ਜਾਣੀ ਪਛਾਣੀ ਗਾਇਕਾ ਬਣ ਗਈ। 1942 ਵਿਚ ਬਣੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤਮੰਨਾ’ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਦੋਗਾਣਾ ਮੰਨਾ ਡੇਅ ਨਾਲ ਗਾਇਆ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਇਸ਼ਾਰਾ’ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ‘ਅਨਮੋਲ ਘੜੀ’ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਉਸਦੀ ਗਾਇਕੀ ਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ੂਬ ਸਰਾਹਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਵਿੱਦਿਆ’, ‘ਜੀਤ’, ‘ਅਫ਼ਸਰ’, ‘ਨੀਲੀ’ ਅਤੇ ‘ਦੋ ਸਿਤਾਰੇ’ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਦੇਵ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਨਾਇਕਾ ਬਣੀ।ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਉਸਦੇ ਬਚਪਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਥੀ ਰਹੇ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਮਦਨ ਮੋਹਨ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦੀ ਚੰਗੀ ਨਿਭੀ, ਪਰ ਉਸਦਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮੀ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਲਬੂਤੇ ਹੀ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਵਧਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਹੋਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਫਰੈਂਡਜ਼’, ‘ਗਜਨੀ’ ਅਤੇ ‘ਸ਼ਮਾ’ ਵੀ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਸੰਦ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ। ‘ਸ਼ਮਾ’ ਵਿਚ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਸਨੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਦੇ ਜੌਹਰ ਦਿਖਾਏ ਉੱਥੇ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ ਵੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਜ਼ੁਬਾਨ ’ਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹੇ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਿਰਜ਼ਾ ਗ਼ਾਲਿਬ’ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਉਸਦੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਤੇ ਗੀਤਾਂ ਨੇ ਤਹਿਲਕਾ ਮਚਾਇਆ।ਗੁਜਰਾਂਵਾਲਾ ਦੀ ਜੰਮਪਲ ਇਸ ਗਾਇਕਾ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਦਾ ਮਾਮਾ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸਨੇ ਸੁਰੱਈਆ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਣ ਵਿਚ ਮਦਦ ਕੀਤੀ। ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਉਸ ਜ਼ਮਾਨੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਰਗਿਸ, ਮੀਨਾ ਕੁਮਾਰੀ, ਮਧੂ ਬਾਲਾ ਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀਆਂ ਵੀ ਸਨ,ਪਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਸਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਤੇ ਸੰਗੀਤਕਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਖਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਵਿਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਸੀ, ਉਹ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ। ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਇਹੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਨਅਤ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਸੀ ਜਿਸਨੂੰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵੇਲਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਇਕ ਲੱਖ ਰੁਪਿਆ ਮਿਹਨਤਾਨਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਸੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵਾਰਿਸ’ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਪਿੱਠਵਰਤੀ ਗਾਇਕ ਤਲਤ ਮਹਿਮੂਦ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਬਣੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਦਾਸਤਾਨ’ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਬਚਪਨ ਦੇ ਸਾਥੀ ਰਾਜ ਕਪੂਰ ਨਾਲ ਨਾਇਕਾ ਬਣੀ ਅਤੇ ਗਾਇਕ ਮੁਕੇਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਨੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਮਾਸ਼ੂਕਾ’ ਵਿਚ ਬਤੌਰ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ।"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Di manakah kawasan titik buta(blind spot) kenderaan?A. Kawasan bawah kenderaanB, Kawasan atas kenderaanC. Kawasan di sebelah kiri dan kanan kenderaan anda yang tidak dapat dilihat melalui cermin pandang belakang dan sisi","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Kawasan di sebelah kiri dan kanan kenderaan anda yang tidak dapat dilihat melalui cermin pandang belakang dan sisi"},{"question":"Mety mampihena ve ny tsy fihinanana sakafo alohan'ny hatoriana?","answer":"Eny, ny tsy fihinanana sakafo alohan'ny hatory dia afaka manampy amin'ny fihenana. Kanefa mety hankarary vetivety ihany koa izany raha atao matetika."},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவில் எத்தனை மாநிலங்கள் உள்ளன?","answer":"விடை: இந்தியாவில் தற்போது மொத்தம் 28 மாநிலங்கள் மற்றும் 8 யூனியன் பிரதேசங்கள் உள்ளன."},{"question":"Waxaa Sheeg Todobadii Asxaabi ee axaadiista ugu badan ka wariyeen Rasuul-ka (N.N.K.H.)?","answer":"Waxay kala yihiin:-1-Abuu hureyra Rc, 2-Caa’isha Bintu Abii-bakar Rc, 3-C/laahi Bin Cabaas. 4-C/laahi Bin Cumar, 5-Jaabir Bin C/laahi, 6-Aanis Bin Maalik, 7-Sacad Bin Malik,"},{"question":"لدي هذا السؤال في أي عام تم إسقاط القنبلة النووية علي مدينة هيروشيما ؟ ، أجب عليه بطريقة مبسطة.","answer":"حسناً. الإجابة هي أغسطس 1945."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Cuba.","answer":"A bandeira de Cuba tem cinco faixas horizontais: três faixas azuis e duas faixas brancas alternadas, com um triângulo vermelho no canto esquerdo contendo uma estrela branca."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:\\"mandiso fanantenana tahaka ny afrikanina milanja _\\"","answer":"\\"mandiso fanantenana tahaka ny afrikanina milanja pecto\\""},{"question":"Viết bài báo với tiêu đề sau: Canada kêu gọi Ấn Độ hợp tác điều tra vụ ám sát thủ lĩnh người Sikh","answer":"Canada kêu gọi Ấn Độ hợp tác điều tra vụ một thủ lĩnh ly khai người Sikh bị ám sát gần Vancouver, sau khi Ottawa cho rằng New Delhi có liên quan.\\"Chúng tôi kêu gọi chính phủ Ấn Độ phối hợp để thiết lập các quy trình nhằm tìm ra sự thật và cho phép thực thi công lý\\", Thủ tướng Canada Justin Trudeau nói ngày 21/9.Ông Trudeau ngày 18/9 cáo buộc \\"đặc vụ của chính phủ Ấn Độ\\" liên quan vụ sát hại Hardeep Singh Nijjar, một thủ lĩnh người Sikh, gần Vancouver hồi tháng 6. New Delhi bác bỏ, cho rằng cáo buộc Ottawa đưa ra là \\"lố bịch và có động cơ\\". Nijjar, 45 tuổi, là công dân Canada.Thủ tướng Canada từ chối cung cấp bằng chứng khiến ông đưa ra cáo buộc trên, cho rằng việc này sẽ do tòa án quyết định, nếu sự việc được xét xử.Bộ Ngoại giao Ấn Độ cho biết Canada chưa cung cấp thông tin cụ thể nào về vụ ám sát Nijjar. New Delhi và Ottawa đã trục xuất một nhà ngoại giao cấp cao của nhau. Ấn Độ ngày 21/9 còn đình chỉ dịch vụ cấp thị thực cho công dân Canada, với lý do an toàn của nhân viên nước này tại lãnh sự quán ở Canada bị đe dọa."},{"question":"Awọn ọdọ to n ṣewọde SARS ti gboro o, kaakiri ipinlẹ ni wọn ti dina pa","answer":"Kaakiri ipinlẹ ni ilẹ Yoruba, o fẹẹ ma si ibi ti iwọde ifẹhonu han ta ko awọn SARS yii ko ti i de. Ni ba a ṣe n sọ yii, gbogbo awọn oju ọna kaakiri ipinlẹ Eko, Ọyọ, Ogun, Ekiti ati awọn ilu mi-in kaakiri ni wọn ti di patapata.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹfa aarọ ni awọn ọdọ yii ti bọ soju titi, ti wọn si di awọn oju ọna pa. Eyi ko yọ oju ọna marose to lọ lati ilu Eko si Ibadan silẹ. Awọn to fẹẹ jade ko rọna lọ, bẹ ẹ ni awọn to fẹẹ wọle ko le wọle.Niṣe ni awọn ọdọ to n fẹhonu han yii da awọn oṣiṣẹ sẹkiteria to yẹ ki wọn bẹrẹ iṣẹ loni pada sile. Ọpọ wọn ni ko rọna kọja sibi iṣẹ, niṣe ni awọn to ba si jaja rọna lọ n pada sile wọn.Lati ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii ni awọn ara ipinle Ogun ti kede ni tiwọn. Awọn ọdọ to n fẹhonu han yii ni lati aarọ lawọn yii ti bẹrẹ, nibi ileepo NNPC. Bẹẹ ni wọn ṣeto jijẹ mimu fun awọn to ba fẹẹ wa sibẹ. Gbogbo abẹ buriiji Mọlete, ti ile ijọba, Orita challenge ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ ni awọn ọdọ yii ti di pa.Ohun ti wọn ṣaa n sọ ni pe awọn yoo ba ijọba Buhari mu nnkan nilẹ bi ko ba ṣe ohun ti awọn fẹ."},{"question":"नेपाली विद्यालयको पाठ्यक्रम विगतका वर्षहरूमा कसरी विकसित भएको छ ?","answer":"सीप विकासमा जोड दिँदै थप व्यावहारिक र समावेशी दृष्टिकोण समावेश गर्न नेपाली विद्यालयहरूको पाठ्यक्रममा परिवर्तनहरू भएका छन्।"},{"question":"Thứ tự thực hiện phép tính nào sau đây đúng với biểu thức có dấu ngoặc?A. [ ] → ( ) → {}B. ( ) → [ ] → {}C. {} → [ ] → ( )D. [ ] → {} → ( )","answer":"Lời giảiTrong biểu thức có dấu ngoặc thì thứ tự thực hiện phép tính là ( ) → [ ] → {}Chọn đáp án B."},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Fairy Tail\\" ?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Fairy Tail\\" dia Hiro Mashima."},{"question":"அமெரிக்கர்கள் பேரார்வத்துடன் ஈடுபட்டதுறை \\t1. பங்கு வணிகச்சந்தை2. சினிமா்3. சூதாட்டம்4. வணிகம்","answer":" \\t1. பங்கு வணிகச்சந்தை"},{"question":"ਫਾਰਮੂਲਾ ਯੂਨਿਟ ਪੁੰਜ ਕੀ ਹੈ? ਇਹ ਅਣੂ ਪੁੰਜ ਤੋਂ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਵੱਖਰਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਕਿਸੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦਾ ਫਾਰਮੂਲਾ ਯੂਨਿਟ ਪੁੰਜ ਇੱਕ ਮਿਸ਼ਰਣ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਫਾਰਮੂਲਾ ਇਕਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਰਮਾਣੂਆਂ ਦੇ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਪੁੰਜ ਦਾ ਜੋੜ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫਾਰਮੂਲਾ ਯੂਨਿਟ ਪੁੰਜ ਦੇ ਸੰਘਟਕ ਕਣ ਆਇਨ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਅਣੂ ਪੁੰਜ ਦੇ ਸੰਘਟਕ ਕਣ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"६/९  बाट ४/७  घटाउनुहोस् । घटाऊको परिणामलाई सरल गरी देखाउनुहोस् ।","answer":"भिन्न अंश भएक अंकहरु घटाउनको लागि एउटा साझा भाग खोज्नु पर्दछ । दुबै ९ र ७ को भागा मिलाउन ६३ चाहिन्छ । त्यसैले, (६/९) - (४/७) = (६*७/९*७) - (४*९/७*९) =  (४२/६३) - (३६/६३)  = ६/६३सरल गर्द २/२१ हुन्छ ।"},{"question":"परिचरितव्याः सन्तो यद्यपि कथयन्ति नो सदुपदेशम् |यास्तेषां स्वैरकथास्ता एव भवन्ति शास्त्राणि ||","answer":"अर्थ :जरी सज्जनांनी आपल्याला उपदेश केला नाही तरी त्यांची सेवा करावी. कारण ते सहजच ज्या गप्पा मारतात ते सुद्धा शास्त्रीय वचनच असत."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.උඩිනුත් ගින්දර යටිනුත් ගින්දර මැද්දෙ සවුන්දර","answer":"ආප්ප"},{"question":"ਸਾਚਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਾਚੁ ਨਾਇ ਭਾਖਿਆ ਭਾਉ ਅਪਾਰੁ ॥ ਆਖਹਿ ਮੰਗਹਿ ਦੇਹਿ ਦੇਹਿ ਦਾਤਿ ਕਰੇ ਦਾਤਾਰੁ ॥ਫੇਰਿ ਕਿ ਅਗੈ ਰਖੀਐ ਜਿਤੁ ਦਿਸੈ ਦਰਬਾਰੁ ॥ ਮੁਹੌ ਕਿ ਬੋਲਣੁ ਬੋਲੀਐ ਜਿਤੁ ਸੁਣਿ ਧਰੇ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਵੇਲਾ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਉ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ ਕਰਮੀ ਆਵੈ ਕਪੜਾ ਨਦਰੀ ਮੋਖੁ ਦੁਆਰੁ ॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਏਵੈ ਜਾਣੀਐ ਸਭੁ ਆਪੇ ਸਚਿਆਰੁ ॥੪॥","answer":" ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਸਦਾ = ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨੀਯਮ ਭੀ ਸਦਾ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਬੋਲੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਹੈ। ਅਸੀਂ ਜੀਵ ਉਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਮੰਗਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਆਖਦੇ ਹਾਂ,'(ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! ਸਾਨੂੰ ਦਾਤਾਂ) ਦੇਹ'। ਉਹ ਦਾਤਾਰ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ਾਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।(ਜੇ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਬਖਸ਼ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਫਿਰ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਭੇਟਾ ਉਸ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਰੱਖੀਏ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਸਦਕੇ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਦਿੱਸ ਪਏ? ਅਸੀਂ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਕਿਹੜਾ ਬਚਨ ਬੋਲੀਏ (ਭਾਵ, ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰੀਏ) ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਹਰੀ (ਸਾਨੂੰ) ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰੇ।ਪੂਰਨ ਖਿੜਾਉ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਹੋਵੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਪ੍ਰਭਾਤ ਵੇਲਾ ਹੋਵੇ) , ਨਾਮ (ਸਿਮਰੀਏ) ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰੀਏ। (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ 'ਸਿਫਤਿ'-ਰੂਪ ਪਟੋਲਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾ-ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਨਾਲ 'ਕੂੜ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਿ' ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਰੱਬ ਦਾ ਦਰ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਆ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਹੋਂਦ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਸਭ ਥਾਈਂ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਹੈ।4।"},{"question":"Ole wọle igbimọ aṣofin Ogun, wọn ji ọpa aṣẹ wọn lọ","answer":"Bi ẹ ṣe n ka iroyin yii, ko si ọpa aṣẹ agbara mọ nile igbimọ awọn aṣofin ipinlẹ Ogun, awọn ole ti gba abẹ orule wọ ọfiisi abẹnugan ibẹ, wọn si ti gbe ọpa naa lọỌjọbọ, ọsẹ yii, ti i ṣe ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kejila, ọdun yii niṣẹlẹ yii ṣẹlẹ, nigba ti awọn ole kan wọ ọgba ile-igbimọ naa to wa l’Oke-Mosan, l’Abẹokuta.Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi,  tilẹ ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pẹlu, pe awọn kan ti gbe ọpa ti wọn n pe ni Mace lede oyinbo naa lọ.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ti ri abala ọpa naa ti wọn ya ami asia orilẹ-ede yii si, apa keji rẹ to jẹ ọpa gan-an ko ti i jẹ riri, wọn ṣi n wa a lasiko ta a pari iroyin yii ni.Alukoro ọlọpaa sọ pe awọn ko ti i mu ẹnikẹni gẹgẹ bii afurasi lori iṣẹlẹ yii, o ni ṣugbọn iwadii ṣi n tẹsiwaju, awọn yoo si mu awọn to wa nidii ọpa aṣẹ ti wọn gbe lọ naa.Nigba to n ba awọn akọroyin sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Ọlakunle Oluọmọ, olori ile naa, sọ pe oun ko fura si ẹnikẹni. O ni oun ri ohun to ṣẹlẹ naa bii ole jija, awọn ọlọpaa ni yoo tuṣu desalẹ ikoko, ti wọn yoo si fi oju awọn aṣebi naa han.Nipa bo ṣe jẹ dandan ki ọpa yii wa ninu ile lasiko ti wọn ba n jokoo ipade nile naa, Oluọmọ ni bo ṣe sọnu yii ko ni kawọn ma jokoo ipade. O ni to ba to asiko fawọn lati jokoo, ọpa aṣẹ yoo jade."},{"question":"مدیر چا ته ویل کیږی ؟.","answer":"ځواب : مدیر په لغت کی ادار کوونکي او کار چلوونکې ته وایی او په اصطالح کی مدیر هغه څوک دی چی د خپل ټیم د اجرائتومسؤلیت په غاړه لری او د خپلو مارمورینو محموله ) ورسپارل شوی ( وظائف اداره کړی "},{"question":"Ọwọ ẹsọ Amọtẹkun tẹ Ṣeun to ta ọmọ oojọ to bi lẹgbẹrun marun-un fun wolii l’Ondo","answer":"Kayefi nla lo jẹ loju awọn eeyan to wa nibi tawọn ẹsọ Amọtẹkun ti n fọrọ wa obinrin ẹni ọdun mọkanlelogun kan, Ṣeun Ọladayọ, lẹnu wo lori bo ṣe fẹẹ lu ọmọ oojọ to bi ninu ara rẹ ta ni gbanjo niluu Ondo.ALAROYE fidi rẹ mulẹ pe Ṣeun ti bimọ meji tẹlẹ ko too tun bi omiiran to jẹ ẹkẹta lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja.Funra rẹ lo da ọmọ tuntun naa bi sinu ile baba iya rẹ to wa laduugbo Abẹjoye, lagbegbe Odojọmu, niluu Ondo, lai fu ẹnikẹni lara pe oun ti bimọ.Bo ṣe bimọ tan lo sare pe ẹgbọn rẹ kan to n jẹ Yinka sori aago, to si ni ko tete ba oun wa ẹni ti yoo ra ọmọ tuntun jojolo ọhun ki ọrun oun le fuyẹ diẹ.Ẹgbọn rẹ to ransẹ pe naa ko si fi akoko ṣofo to fi lọọ ba wolii kan pe ko tete wa owo jade, o ni oun lọmọ toun fẹẹ ta fun un.Ninu alaye ti wolii ọhun, Ọlawale, ṣe fun akọroyin ALAROYE, o ni oun ti mọ Yinka ṣaaju ọjọ tiṣẹlẹ yii waye.O ni oun kọkọ fẹẹ kọ jalẹ lati ra iru ọja bẹẹ lọwọ awọn mejeeji, ṣugbọn oun gba lati ra a ki wọn ma lọọ pinnu ati ta a fun ẹlomi-in to le fẹẹ lo o fun iṣẹ ibi.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lo ti bimọ, inu agbara ẹjẹ lo ṣi ba ọmọ tuntun ọhun ati olubi rẹ lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to lọ sile wọn.O ni ẹgbẹrun marun-un Naira loun ba wọn dunaa dura si, funra tẹgbon-taburo naa ni wọn si gbe ọmọ wọn sinu baagi gana mọs go kan, ti wọn ni ko maa gbe e lọ.Ni kete to gbe ọmọ naa kuro lọdọ wọn lo sare pe ọkan ninu awọn ẹsọ Amọtẹkun pe ko tete maa bọ lati waa wo oun toju oun ri.Oun ati oṣiṣẹ Amọtẹkun yii ni wọn jọ gbe ọmọ tuntun ọhun ati olubi rẹ lọ sile, nibi ti wọn ti kọkọ wẹ fun un, ti wọn si tun wọṣọ si i lọrun.Lẹyin eyi ni wọn pe Alaaji Akewuṣọla Tajudeen to jẹ ọga awọn Amọtẹkun nijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo lati fohun to ṣẹlẹ to o leti.Ṣeun to jẹ iya ọmọ tuntun yii nikan ni wọn ri mu nigba ti wọn yoo fi pada debẹ, wọn ko ba Yinka ẹgbọn rẹ mọ.Wọn mu iya ọlọmọ mẹta naa lọ si ọfiisi wọn lagbegbe Civic Centre, niluu Ondo, nibi ti wọn ti fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo ki wọn too fa a le awọn ọlọpaa Area Command lọwọ.Ṣeun ni ki i ṣe pe oun fẹẹ ta ọmọ ti oun ṣẹṣẹ bi ọhun gẹgẹ bawọn eeyan ṣe ro. O ni ọkunrin kan ti wọn n pe ni Tọpẹ lo fun oun loyun, ati pe ọjọ to ti gbọ nipa oyun naa lo ti sa lọ, ti oun ko si tun laju ri i titi ti oun fi bimọ.O ni ohun ti oun sọ fun Yinka ẹgbọn oun lori ago ni pe ko ba oun wa ẹni ti yoo ba oun tọju rẹ nitori iya to n jẹ oun.O ni ẹgbẹrun marun-un Naira ti oun fẹẹ fun dokita kan to waa gbẹbi fun oun lo ṣokunfa ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa tí oun n beere fun lọwọ wolii to fẹẹ gbe ọmọ lọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe Iya Ṣeun ati Yinka ti pada yọju si agọ ọlọpaa, nibi ti wọn mu iya ọmọ tuntun naa lọ, lati lọọ sọ ohun ti wọn mọ nipa iṣẹlẹ ọhun."},{"question":"その形がある動物に似ていることから名がついた、パソコンで、画面上のポインタを動かしたり、アイコンをクリックするのに使われる周辺機器は何でしょう？","answer":"マウスです。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੪ ਘਰੁ ੧ ॥ਮੈ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਬਿਰਹੁ ਅਤਿ ਅਗਲਾ ਕਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮੁ ਮਿਲੈ ਘਰਿ ਆਇ ॥ਜਾ ਦੇਖਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਆਪਣਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਦੇਖਿਐ ਦੁਖੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ਜਾਇ ਪੁਛਾ ਤਿਨ ਸਜਣਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਕਿਤੁ ਬਿਧਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਮਿਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ਮੇਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰਾ ਮੈ ਤੁਝ ਬਿਨੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ਹਮ ਮੂਰਖ ਮੁਗਧ ਸਰਣਾਗਤੀ ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਮੇਲੇ ਹਰਿ ਸੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਆਪਿ ਮਿਲਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਬੁਝਿਆ ਗੁਰ ਜੇਵਡੁ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥ਹਉ ਗੁਰ ਸਰਣਾਈ ਢਹਿ ਪਵਾ ਕਰਿ ਦਇਆ ਮੇਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸੋਇ ॥੨॥ਮਨਹਠਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਨ ਪਾਇਆ ਕਰਿ ਉਪਾਵ ਥਕੇ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ਸਹਸ ਸਿਆਣਪ ਕਰਿ ਰਹੇ ਮਨਿ ਕੋਰੈ ਰੰਗੁ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਕੂੜਿ ਕਪਟਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਨ ਪਾਇਓ ਜੋ ਬੀਜੈ ਖਾਵੈ ਸੋਇ ॥੩॥ਸਭਨਾ ਤੇਰੀ ਆਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸਭ ਜੀਅ ਤੇਰੇ ਤੂੰ ਰਾਸਿ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਤੁਧਹੁ ਖਾਲੀ ਕੋ ਨਹੀ ਦਰਿ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾ ਨੋ ਸਾਬਾਸਿ ॥ਬਿਖੁ ਭਉਜਲ ਡੁਬਦੇ ਕਢਿ ਲੈ ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਕੀ ਅਰਦਾਸਿ ॥੪॥੧॥੬੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 39 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ (ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ) ਵਿਛੋੜੇ ਦਾ ਭਾਰੀ ਦਰਦ ਹੈ (ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਤੜਪ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਕਿਵੇਂ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੇਰੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆ ਮਿਲੇ  ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਮੇਰਾ (ਵਿਛੋੜੇ ਦਾ) ਦੁੱਖ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਤਸੰਗੀ ਸੱਜਣਾਂ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ) ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਸੱਜਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਪੁੱਛਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਕਿਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾਇਆਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ! ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੇਰਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਸਹਾਰਾ) ਨਹੀਂ ਹਅਸੀ ਜੀਵ ਮੂਰਖ ਹਾਂ, ਅੰਞਾਣ ਹਾਂ, (ਪਰ) ਤੇਰੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਏ ਹਨ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਗੁਰੂ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਇਹ ਦਾਤਿ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ) ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਹਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਜੇਡਾ (ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਾਲਾ) ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ (ਮੇਰੀ ਇਹੀ ਤਾਂਘ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ, ਆਪਾ‑ਭਾਵ ਮਿਟਾ ਕੇ, ਆ ਪਵਾਂ । (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪਿਆਂ ਹੀ) ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਮਨ ਦੇ ਹਠ ਨਾਲ (ਕੀਤੇ ਤਪ ਆਦਿਕ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ) ਕਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਾ । (ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੇ) ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਉਪਾਵ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਸਭ ਥੱਕ ਹੀ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਤਪ ਆਦਿਕ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ) ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਸਿਆਣਪਾਂ (ਜੇਹੜੇ ਲੋਕ) ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪੇ੍ਰਮ ਵਲੋਂ ਕੋਰਾ ਹੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ) ਜੇ ਮਨ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪੇ੍ਰਮ ਤੋਂ) ਕੋਰਾ ਹੀ ਰਹੇ ਤਾਂ ਨਾਮ ਰੰਗ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੜ੍ਹਦਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸੇ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ (ਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਹਠ-ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੀ) ਠੱਗੀ ਨਾਲ ਕਦੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭਾ । (ਇਹ ਪੱਕਾ ਨਿਯਮ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਕੋਈ ਬੀਜਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਉਹ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।੩।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੀ (ਸਹੈਤਾ ਦੀ) ਹੀ ਆਸ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਹੀ (ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ) ਹਨ, ਤੂੰ ਹੀ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਆਤਮਕ) ਰਾਸ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਹੈਂ  ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਖ਼ਾਲੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੁੜਦਾ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਆਦਰ ਮਾਣ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੀ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਅਰਜ਼ੋਈ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਦੇ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ) ਜ਼ਹਰ ਵਿਚ ਡੁੱਬਦੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪ ਕੱਢ ਲੈ ।੪।੧।੬੫।\\""},{"question":"Hoos waxad ka heli kartaa email tusaale ah.","answer":"Salaam (Magaca qofka),Waxaan rajeynayaa emailkaan in uu kugu soo gaaray si wanaagsan.Fadlan hel dukumintiska hoos yaala si aad u saxiixdo, dibna inoogu soo dir isagoo  saxiixan.Mahadsanid,(Magacaaga)"},{"question":"వాక్యం 1: హార్వెస్ట్, హంట్స్విల్లేలోని స్పార్క్మన్ హై స్కూల్, అలబామాలోని స్పార్క్మన్ స్కూల్, అలబామాలోని సోమర్విల్లేలోని స్పార్క్మన్ డ్రైవ్, అన్నీ అతని గౌరవార్థం పేరు పెట్టబడ్డాయి. వాక్యం 2: స్పార్క్మన్ హై స్కూల్ హార్వెస్ట్, అలబామా, స్పార్క్మన్ స్కూల్ సోమర్విల్లే, అలబామా, స్పార్క్మన్ డ్రైవ్ హంట్స్విల్లే అన్ని అతని గౌరవార్ధం పేరు పెట్టారు. ప్రశ్న: 1వ వాక్యం, 2వ వాక్యం రెండూ ఒకే అర్థాన్ని ఇస్తున్నాయా? అవును లేదా కాదు?","answer":"1వ వాక్యం, 2వ వాక్యం రెండూ ఒకే అర్థాన్ని ఇవ్వడం లేదు."},{"question":"麻雀の待ちで、一番多いのは何面待ちでしょう？","answer":"１３面"},{"question":"Kinsa ang imong hinanaling mentor sa imong trabaho?","answer":"Daghan nako nanga mentor sa akung trabaho."},{"question":"窒素、酸素に次いで空気中に多く含まれる、原子番号18、元素記号Arの元素は？","answer":"アルゴンです。"},{"question":"लोकमान्य टिळकांना काळ्या पाण्याच्या शिक्षेसाठी कोठे पाठविले होते ?","answer":"मंडालेच्या तुरूंगात"},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, ‘Dudu Heritage’, ọkọ Bimbọ Ọshin, ku lojiji","answer":"Ajalu buruku ni iku iku Ọla Ibironkẹ ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Dudu Heritage to jẹ ọkọ gbajumọ oṣere ilẹ wa nni, Bimbọ Ọṣhin to ku lojiji.Ilu oyinbo ni ọkunrin naa n gbe, bo tilẹ jẹ pe o maa n wa si Naijiria daadaa, to si gbajumọ laarin awọn oṣere atawọn olorin.ALAROYE gbọ pe lojiji ni ọkunrin naa dagbere faye ni alẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii.Ko ti i sẹni to le sọ iru iku to pa ọkunrin naa lasiko ta a n ko iroyin yii jọ.Awọn olorin ni ọkunrin yii maa n gbe jade, beẹ lo si gbe awọn oṣere diẹ jade pẹlu.Ọmọ meji, ọkunrin, kan obinrin kan, loun ati Bimbọ Ọṣin bi funra wọn kọlọjọ too de."},{"question":"மனிதனை ஒரு முறை தாக்கிய பிறகு மீண்டும் தாக்காத நோய்?","answer":"விடை: பெரிய அம்மைபெரியம்மை, மனிதர்களை மட்டும் தாக்கும் அதிகத் தொற்றுத் தன்மை கொண்ட நோயாகும். இது வரியோலா மேசர்  மற்றும் வரியோலா மைனர் (Variola minor) ஆகிய இரு அதி நுண் நச்சுயிர்களால் உண்டாகிறது. இவற்றுள் வரியோலா மேசர் அதிக உயிர்ப்பலிகளை உண்டாக்க வல்லதாகும். இக்கிருமி தாக்கியவர்களுள் 20 முதல் 40 விழுக்காட்டினர் இறந்து விடுகின்றனர். வரியோலா மைனர் கிருமி தாக்கியவர்களுள் ஒரு விழுக்காட்டினர் மட்டுமே இறக்கின்றனர். உயிர் பிழைத்தவர்களில் பலரும், (ஒன்று அல்லது) இரண்டு கண்கள் குருடாவதுடன், நீங்காத தழும்புகளையும் பெறுகின்றனர். 20ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் இந்நோய் காரணமாக 300-500 மில்லியன் மக்கள் இறந்தனர். 1967ல் உலக சுகாதார நிறுவனம் வெளியிட்ட அறிக்கையின்படி அந்த ஆண்டு மட்டும் 15 மில்லியின் மக்கள் அந்நோய்யால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டு அவர்களுள் இரண்டு மில்லியன் மக்கள் இறந்தனர். எட்வர்ட் ஜென்னர் இந்நோய்க்கான தடுப்பு மருந்தை 1796 ஆம் ஆண்டு கண்டுபிடித்தார். 1978 ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் ஐக்கிய இராச்சியத்தில் ஜேனட் பார்க்கர் என்பவர் இந்நோய் தாக்கி இறந்தார். அதன் பின் இந்நோயின் தாக்குதல் எங்கும் அறியப்படவில்லை."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 北海道の平取町には、たくさんのすずらんの花が咲く所があります。広さは15haぐらいあります。すずらんの花が咲き始めると、夏が始まると言われています。町は、今年も花が咲き始めたため、観光に来た人などが見ることができるようにして、すずらんを楽しむ会を開いています。会場に来たたくさんの人は、花の甘い香りを楽しんだり、白くて小さい花の写真を撮ったりしていました。7歳の女の子は「かわいくてきれいでした」と話していました。すずらんを楽しむ会は6月4日までです。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- すずらん: 1）山や、寒い地方に生える草花。初夏に、つり鐘のようなかわいらしい白い花を咲かせる。- ha: 1）メートル法で、土地の面積の単位の一つ。記号は「ha」。1ヘクタールは、100アールで、一万平方メートル。- 観光: 1）景色のよい所や名所などを見物して回ること。- 香り: 1）いいにおい。2）そのものから感じられる品の高さ。"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Ko si ki eeyan ma beere pe kin ni wahala Bọọda Lai Muhammed. Bi eeyan ba ri idaamu ti ọkunrin naa ko ara rẹ si, ko si ki eeyan ma beere pe ki lo kuku de bayii nitori Ọlọrun. Okun n ho yee, ọsa n ho yee, ọmo buruku tori bọ ọ, iru ẹ gan-an ni iṣẹ ti Bọọda Lai yii gbe fun ara rẹ ṣe. Lọsẹ to kọja yii, ọkunrin kan sọrọ lori redio, Mailafia lorukọ ẹ, ara ilẹ Hausa lọhun-un naa ni. Ohun to sọ ni pe gomina ilẹ Hausa kan ni olori awọn Boko Haram, o ni awọn ti ijọba dariji ninu awọn ọmọ ogun afẹmiṣofo naa ni wọn sọ bẹẹ foun. Nitori pe eeyan nla lati ilẹ Hausa ni, ti oun naa si ti figba kan jade poun naa fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii ri, ni awọn ti wọn beere ọrọ lọwọ ẹ fi bi i pe ki lohun to ri si ọrọ awọn Boko Haram ti wọn n daamu ilu yii. Idahun rẹ ko si ruju, o sọ ẹni to sọrọ foun, oun naa si lorukọ. Nigba ti ọrọ ti foju han bayii, ki waa ni wahala ijọba. Awọn DSS mu Mailafia, ọjọ ti wọn mu un naa ni wọn fi i silẹ, o tun jade kuro lọdọ wọn, o ni ododo ọrọ loun n sọ, ko ṣeni to le pa ohun mọ oun lẹnu. Awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa funra wọn jade, wọn ni ki ijọba apapọ gbe iwadii gidi dide lati mọ hulẹhulẹ ohun ti ọkunrin yii sọ. Ṣugbọn Lai Muhammed ko duro de iwadii ijọba, bẹẹ ni ko lọ si ọdọ awọn DSS ko lọọ beere lọwọ wọn idi ti wọn fi fi ọkunrin to sọ iru ọrọ bẹẹ silẹ, kaka bẹẹ, ileeṣẹ redio to n ṣe iṣẹ tiwọn jẹẹjẹ lo gba lọ, o ni wọn gbọdọ san miliọnu marun-un lẹsẹkẹsẹ, nitori wọn jẹ ki ọkunrin naa sọ ọrọ ẹnu rẹ jade. O daju pe ko le jẹ Buhari lo ran ọkunrin Lai yii ni iṣẹ to n ṣe yii, o si daju pe ko le jẹ pe ijọba yii fẹẹ pa gbogbo oniroyin ati akọroyin lẹnu mọ pe wọn ko gbọdọ wi kinni kan mọ, koda, ki awọn yagbẹ sara ni. Tabi nibo ni wọn ti n ṣe eyi ti Lai ṣe yii! Wọn fi ẹtẹ silẹ, wọn n pa lapalapa; wọn fi onija silẹ, wọn gba alapẹpẹ mu. Ẹni to sọrọ ko ku, ko si sa lọ, ko si sọ pe oun ko sọrọ ti redio gbe jade, o tun sọ ni gbangba pe ohun ti oun sọ ni redio gbe jade. Ṣe araalu ko lẹtọọ lati sọ ọrọ ẹnu rẹ mọ ni, abi redio ni ko lẹtọọ lati ṣiṣẹ! Kaka ki ijọba yii wa ọna ti wọn yoo fi yanju ọrọ ogun awọn afẹmiṣofo, iranu ni wọn n le kiri. Bi wọn ti n ṣe niyi o. Nigba ti wọn ba ra pala wọ ile ijọba, ti ijọba ba wa lọwọ wọn, wọn yoo maa huwa bii ẹni pe ibẹ ni wọn fẹẹ ku si. O digba ti iṣẹ ijọba ba tan ki oju wọn too walẹ, ti wọn yoo waa maa rin kiri bii igbona laarin ilu, ti wọn ko waa ni i ja mọ kinni kan mọ, ti wọn ko si ni i niyi lọdọ ẹni kan. Tabi nibo ni iru awọn eeyan bii Lai Muhammed yii yoo gba nigba ti ijọba yii ba bọ kuro lọwọ wọn! Oju wa yii naa ni yoo ṣe, ẹ sọ fun un ko mura si i daadaa.Bi eeyan ba jokoo, to ni ọrọ Minisita Lai Muhammed yii loun yoo maa sọ, oluwarẹ ko ni i ri iṣẹ mi-in ṣe. Bẹẹ ni ọkunrin yii ro pe oun n fi awọn irọ ati ọrọ ẹtan to n jade lẹnu oun si araalu tun ijọba yii ṣe ni o, ṣugbọn o n fi awọn ọrọ naa ba ijọba yii jẹ loju gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria ni. Lati ọdun 2015 ni Lai Muhammed ti n pariwo pe awọn ti ṣẹgun Boko Haram, o ni awọn ṣẹgun wọn pata. Ko sigba ti wọn bi i, bi yoo ti wi nu-un, koda, ko jẹ awọn Boko Haram yii ṣẹṣẹ pa odidi ilu kan run ni. Ọkunrin Lai Muhammed yii yoo sọ fun yin pe awọn ti ṣẹgun Boko Haram, awọn ti wọn n kiri igboro Maiduguri, ti wọn n paayan kiri yẹn ki i ṣe Boko Haram, ralẹralẹ lasan ni wọn. Ṣugbọn fun igba akọkọ lọsẹ to kọja yii, Lai Muhammed sọ ododo. Ohun to sọ ni pe ijọba Buhari iba ti ṣẹgun awọn Boko Haram, ṣugbọn awọn orilẹ-ede agbaye ko ta irinṣẹ ijagun fawọn ni. Awọn ko ri awọn ibọn nla nla ati ọta, pẹlu awọn maṣingan-annu ti awọn fi le rẹyin Boko Haram ra lọwọ awọn oyinbo wọnyi ni, nitori wọn ko jẹ ta awọn irinṣẹ ogun yii fawọn. Lọrọ kan, ohun ti Lai n sọ ni pe awọn ko ti i ṣẹgun Boko Haram, ohun ti ko si jẹ ki awọn ṣẹgun naa ni pe ko si eelo irinṣẹ ogun to to. Ṣugbọn lọjọ yii kan naa ni Fẹmi Adeṣina toun jẹ agbẹnusọ fun Buhari ni eelo ijagun to to wa lọwọ awọn ologun Naijiria, nitori ko si ọga ologun kan to kun si awọn leti pe awọn ko ni eelo ijagun to. O ni eelo ijagun to pọ jaburata wa lọdọ awọn ṣọja ti wọn n jagun. Afi bii igba ti oludamọran Aarẹ yii ni ki Lai gbẹnu sọhun-un, ko mọ ohun to n sọ ni. Ṣugbọn ta ni eeyan yoo gbagbọ ninu awọn mejeeji yii, ṣe Lai ni abi Fẹmi, ṣe irinṣẹ ijagun wa loootọ abi ko si! Ta ni n parọ, ta ni n sọ ododo. Ninu ijọba kan naa ni wọn jọ wa o, ẹni kan naa ni wọn n ba ṣiṣẹ o, sibẹ, ọrọ wọn ko ye ara wọn. Ta ni yoo waa la wọn bayii, nibi ti wọn ba aye Naijiria jẹ de lẹ ri yẹn.O ti n lọ si bii ọsẹ meji bayii ti iroyin jade pe wọn ti gbe Aishat Buhari lọ si Dubai, nitori aiyaara. Ọrun ni wọn sọ pe o n dun un, wọn si ni kinni naa le gan-an. Bi ko ba tilẹ le, ṣe wọn yoo waa gbe e gba ọna Dubai bi! Awọn eeyan kan ko tilẹ gba pe ọrun lo n dun un, wọn ni o le jẹ Korona lo kọ lu u, nigba to jẹ arun awọn olowo ni. Ṣugbọn ko tun ju ọjọ mẹta lọ ti iroyin mi-in bẹrẹ si i jade, iroyin to si n jade naa ni pe ki i ṣe pe ara obinrin naa ko ya, wọn fi ọrun ati aiyaara yẹn tan awọn ọmọ Naijiria jẹ ni. Iroyin ti Sahara gbe jade naa sọ pe ọmọ obinrin yii lo fẹẹ ṣegbeyawo, ọmọ rẹ kan to n jẹ Hanan, wọn loun lo fẹẹ ṣeyawo, nitori lati ra awọn ohun ti yoo lo fun igbeyawo rẹ ni Aishat ṣe lọ, ti wọn gbe ẹronpileeni ọkunrin olowo ilẹ Hausa kan, Muhammed Indimi, lọ. Ko jẹ jẹ bẹẹ lawọn eeyan n wi, ti kaluku si n pe iroyin naa ni iroyin ẹlẹjẹ, ti wọn ni ko si bi Aishat yoo ṣe daju to bẹẹ, ti yoo huwa bẹẹ fun awọn ọmọ Naijiria ti wọn n ṣadura fun un nigba ti wọn gbọ pe o fẹ si i. Ṣugbọn o ṣe gate, ko ṣe gate, kinni naa jọ pe o n fi ẹsẹ mejeeji duro bayii o. Iroyin mi-in ti jade pe loootọ ni ọmọ Buhari yii yoo ṣegbeyawo ni ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu kẹsan-an to n bọ yii, iyẹn bii ọsẹ mẹta si asiko ti a wa yii, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọkunrin Hausa kan to ti ba Babatunde Faṣọla ṣiṣe ri, Muhammad Turad, lo fẹẹ fi ṣe ọkọ. Wọn ti ni ninu Aso Rock ni wọn yoo ti ṣegbeyawo naa, ki i ṣe ti alariwo ti wọn yoo pe opọlọpọ ero sibẹ, kidaa awọn alagbara aye nikan ni. Ohun to jẹ ki ọrọ yii jọ ootọ ni pe bi ọmọ Buhari yoo ba ṣeyawo, o waa le ṣe e nigba ti iya rẹ n gba itọju ni Dubai bi! Itumọ eyi ni pe ki i ṣe pe ara Aishat ko ya, o lọọ ra nnkan iyawo ni. Tabi ta lo tun gbọ iroyin kankan nipa irin-ajo yii mọ lati bii ọsẹ meji sẹyin naa. Ṣugbọn bi Aishat ba tun n fi aiyaara tan gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria jẹ, ta lo waa ku ta a fẹẹ gbagbọ ninu ijọba yii gan-an! Eeyan gidi wo lo waa wa laarin awọn arufin ti wọn n ṣe olori wa yii! Bẹẹ, Ọlọrun yoo si ṣedajọ awọn naa nijọ kan o. Oju lo n kan wa. Ki wọn maa ṣe e niṣo, Ọlọrun n bọ ti yoo beere iwa wọn lọwọ wọn. Tabi awọn ti wọn ṣe e lanaa da!Ohun to ba ijọba yii jẹ ree, ohun ti ko si ṣe si ẹnikan to ka wọn si ijọba to nikan i ṣe niyẹn. Awọn naa ko yee huwa bii alainikan-an-se, nitori otubantẹ ni gbogbo ileri wọn. Gbogbo igba, gbogbo ọjọ, ni wọn yoo fi sọ pe awọn n gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ, ṣugbọn to ba di ibi ti wọn yoo ti fi kinni naa han gbogbo aye, wọn yoo kuna patapata. Ẹyin lẹ pariwo pe Ibrahim Magu huwa ibajẹ, o kowo jẹ, owo sọnu mọ ọn lọwọ, o ṣe awọn owo to gba baṣubaṣu, o ra ile, o ra ilẹ, ati awọn iwa oriṣiiriṣii bẹẹ, ohun ti gbogbo araalu n gbọ niyẹn. Ṣugbọn lati bii oṣu kan aabọ ti wọn ti mu Magu ni gbangba ode, ti wọn ti i mọle, ti wọn si ti gba beeli ẹ, ko tun sẹni to gbọ kinni kan mọ o. Ọrọ Naijiria ko le, awọn ti wọn n dari wa ti mọ pe ariwo lasan la le pa, pe bi ọrọ kan ba ti di ariwo bẹẹ, ti a pa a lọ, ti a pa a bọ, kaluku yoo dakẹ, wọn yoo si sinmi. Tabi nibo ni wọn ti n ṣe eyi ti awọn eeyan yii n ṣe wọnyi. Ṣe pe awọn igbimọ ti wọn jokoo, ti wọn n wadii ọrọ Magu ko ni ẹri to dara lọwọ ni wọn ni ki ọlọpaa lọọ mu un ni, abi nigba ti wọn mu un tan, ẹri to ko silẹ kan araale, o kan ara oko, wọn si mọ pe aṣiri awọn ọrọ kan ko gbọdọ tu sita. Tabi iru ilu wo ree paapaa. Ẹ mu eeyan, ẹ ko ọkan gbogbo ilu soke, eeyan nla bẹẹ yẹn, ẹ ko si jẹ ki araalu tun gbọ kinni kan mọ. Koda, igbimọ to n wadii ọrọ ko sọrọ mọ, ohun gbogbo pa kese. Ẹjọ naa ti daru ree o, o ti daru pata. Bi ọrọ ba ti pẹ nilẹ, o maa n gbọn si i ni, ọrọ Magu yii ti gbọn mọ awọn ti wọn mu un lọwọ, o si daju pe wọn yoo bo kinni naa mọlẹ gbẹyin ni. Eleyii ko daa, ko daa rara. Ko le gbe wa debi kan ni, bo ba si gbe wa debi kan rara, ibi ifasẹyin ni. Awọn nnkan ti ko jẹ ki Naijiria nilọsiwaju lẹ n ri yii, nitori bo ba n lọ bayii, ko si ibi kankan ti a fẹẹ lọ ju ka wa lẹyin lọ. Ọlọrun o, waa gba wa lọwọ awọn ẹni ibi wọnyi o. Ma jẹ ko pẹ, ma jẹ ko jinna o jare.Ọrọ ẹsin ilẹ Yoruba ati ti ilẹ Hausa ko ni i dọgba laye, nitori awọn aṣaaju ilẹ Hausa ko ni i ṣe ohun ti Ọlọrun ni ki wọn ṣe, awọn mẹkunnu ni wọn yoo maa da laamu, bẹẹ aaye iru rẹ ko si ni ilẹ Yoruba, ọhun naa ni gbogbo raurau bẹẹ yoo ti mọ. Ki i ṣe tuntun mọ bayii pe wọn ti dajọ iku fun ọmọkunrin akọrin kan ni Kano. Yahaya Shariff Aminu lorukọ ẹ, ọmọ Hausa bii tiwọn naa ni. Wọn lo kọrin kan to fi bu Anọbi ni, n lawọn adajọ wọn ba jokoo, ni wọn dajọ iku fun un. Awọn eeyan yii ni wọn n jẹ ki ẹsin Islam da bii ẹsin lile tabi ẹsin buruku loju awọn ti ki i ṣe Musulumi, ati loju awọn Musulumi mi-in paapaa. Ta ni le gbeja Ọlọrun bi ko ṣe Ọlọrun funra rẹ! Agbara wo ni ẹda kan ni ti yoo ni oun n gbeja Ọlọrun. Ṣugbọn nitori abosi ati agabagebe, awọn eeyan yii yoo maa fi ofin Sharia dẹruba awọn eeyan wọn, wọn yoo si maa fi ofin to yẹ ko jẹ idunnu awọn eeyan ni wọn lara. Nigba ti wọn bẹrẹ Sharia nijọsi, ọkunrin to bẹrẹ ẹ ni Zamfara, Yerima, ni ki wọn ge ọwọ ẹni to ji maaluu kan gbe, ṣugbọn nigba ti oun kuro ni ijọba ti aṣiri owo to ko jẹ tu, owo buruku to pọ nipọkupọ, ariwo to n pa ni pe ki wọn ma fi Sharia ṣedajọ oun, oun ko fẹ ẹjọ Sharia. Bẹẹ oun lo bẹrẹ ẹ o, oun lo si ti lo ofin naa lati fi ge ọmọ talaka lọwọ. Iru ẹ naa leleyii, iru orin wo ni tọhun ibaa kọ ti yoo jẹ iku ni adajọ yoo da fun un, ti ko tilẹ si ki wọn kilọ fun un rara. Laakaye tabi ifẹ Ọlọrun wo lo wa ninu iru idajọ bẹẹ. Wọn yoo kan maa le awọn eeyan kuro nidii ẹsin naa ni, bẹẹ awọn ti wọn n ṣe bayii, onibajẹ ati alagabagebe kan ni wọn. Ṣugbọn gomina Kano ko gbọdọ faaye gba eleyii o, bi bẹẹ kọ, bi oun naa ba kuro, awọn eeyan yoo hu ọrọ owo dọla ti oun naa ji ko nijọsi jade, ofin Sharia ni wọn yoo si lo, bo jẹ wọn ni ki wọn ge e lọwọ mejeeji ni, bo si jẹ wọn ni ki wọn juko pa a ni, ọkan yoo ṣe ninu mejeeji. Ṣugbọn ẹ ma pa ọmọ kekere akọrin yii o, ẹmi eeyan kan ko gbọdọ ti ọwọ ẹni to ba bẹru Ọlọrun loootọ bọ."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp câu sau: Sau khi đất nước giải phóng","answer":", Việt Nam tiếp quản sân bay và khu quân sự. Hiện nay sân bay đã không còn thay thế vào đó là doanh trại đội Việt Nam."},{"question":"Apakah maksud anak emas?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah anak yang sangat disayangi oleh keluarga. Contoh ayat: Aliza adalah anak emas keluarga Pak Darus."},{"question":"ما هو العضو الذي يُعتبر أكبر عضو في جسم الإنسان؟","answer":"الجلد."},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  Em 2003, os Estados Unidos voltaram a invadir o Iraque, em uma","answer":"guerra sangrenta que teve mais de 100.000 civis iraquianos e quase 4.500 soldados americanos mortos. Este conflito teve o seu início devido à desconfiança norte-americana de que o Iraque, na época governado por Saddam Hussein, estivesse desenvolvendo armas de destruição em massa, e que o ditador teria ligações com a organização terrorista islâmica Al-Qaeda. Em 18 de dezembro de 2011, o presidente Barack Obama, que se opôs profundamente à guerra no Iraque, retirou os últimos soldados americanos, deixando o país atolado em uma grave crise política."},{"question":"Giải thích chi tiết về Cơ năng","answer":"Cơ năng: Vật có cơ năng khi vật có khả năng sinh công.- Các dạng của cơ năng:+ Động năng: Do chuyển động mà có. Phụ thuộc vào khối lượng và vận tốc của vật.+ Thế năng: gồm:* Thế năng hấp dẫn: Phụ thuộc vào khối lượng và độ cao của vật so với vị trí chọn làm mốc.* Thế năng đàn hồi: Phụ thuộc vào độ biến dạng của vật.- Sự chuyển hóa và bảo toàn cơ năng:* Động năng có thể chuyển hóa thành thế năng và ngược lại.* Trong quá trình cơ học, động năng và thế năng có thể chuyển hóa lẫn nhau, nhưng cơ năng được bảo toàn."},{"question":"Уран планетасы тууралуу кызыктуу фактыларды жазып берчи..","answer":"1. Урандын атмосферасы эң суук деп таанылып, -224°C ге барабар.2. Уран планетасында бир күн болжол менен 17 саатка созулат.3. Уран - көк түстүү планета.4. Бул планетанын атмосферасы суутек, гелий жана метандан турат.5. Планетанын бир бөлүгүндө жай мезгили болуп, күндүн күйүп жаткан нурлары ар бир уюлга тийсе, экинчи бөлүгү караңгыда катуу кышка дуушар болот.6. Уран өз огунун айланасында 17 саат 14 мүнөттө толук айланат.7. Планетанын өзөгү таштан турат.8. Окумуштуулар тарабынан ачылган Урандын биринчи жана ири айлары Обертон жана Титания болгон."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  ബംഗാൾ വിഭജനം, റൗലറ്റ് നിയമം ,","answer":"ജാലിയൻവാലാബാഗ് കൂട്ടക്കൊല , സൈമൺ കമ്മീഷൻ എന്നിവയ്ക്കെതിരായ പ്രതിഷേധങ്ങളിൽ സത്യമൂർത്തി പങ്കെടുത്തു. ക്വിറ്റ് ഇന്ത്യാ പ്രക്ഷോഭത്തിനിടെ 1942 -ൽ സത്യാമൂർത്തിയെ ജയിലിലടച്ചു. പിന്നീട് അദ്ദേഹത്തെ മോചിപ്പിക്കുകയും, 1943 മാർച്ച് 28 ന് ഹൃദയാഘാതം കാരണം അദ്ദേഹം മരണമടയുകയും ചെയ്തു."},{"question":"சிறந்த உரையாடலின் ஆறு நன்மைகள் யாவை?","answer":"சிறந்த உரையாடலின் நன்மைகள் பின்வருமாறு:உரையாடல் என்பது ஒருவர் மற்றவருடன் கலந்து பேசிக் (உரை) கொள்வதைக் குறிக்கும். உரையாடலின் போது ஒருவருக்கொருவர் அளவளாவி, பேசி, கருத்துப் பரிமாற்றம் செய்து கொள்கின்றனர். எழுத்து வழியாக செய்திப் பரிமாற்றம் நடந்தால், அதுவும் உரையாடல் என்றே வழங்கும். உரையாடல் என்பது குமுகாயத்தில் ஒரு இன்றியமையாத திறனாகக் கருதப் படுகின்றது. ஒரு மொழியைக் கற்கும் போது, அதில் உரையாடல் செய்வது எவ்வாறு என்பதையும் கற்றுக்கொள்ளல் வேண்டும்.உரையாடல் பகுப்பாய்வு என்பது சமூகவியலில் ஒரு ஆராய்ச்சிப் பிரிவாகும். இதில், மனிதர்கள் எவ்வாறு ஒருவருக்கொருவர் அளவளாவிக் கொள்கின்றனர், அந்த அளவளாவுதல் அமைப்பு, அமைப்பாண்மை ஆகியன எவ்வாறு உள்ளன என்பன பற்றி விரிவாக அலசப் படுகின்றது.வரையறைஅ) நன்றாக புரிந்து கொள்ளுதல்\\t\\t\\t\\t\\tஆ) சிறந்த புரிதல்இ) சிறந்த தன்னம்பிக்கைஈ) பணியிட மதிப்புஉ) சிறந்த சுய பாதுகாப்புஊ) சிறந்த உறவுகள் "},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny 26 janoary 2009?","answer":"Ny 26 janoary 2009 no nisy ny lundi noir (na “alatsinainy misaona”) nahitana rotaka, fandrobana, fandorana sy fanimban-javatra, nitarika fahafatesan’olona sy fahaverezam-bola goavana tany tamin’ny faritra sasany teto amin’ny nosy. "},{"question":"Hees ","answer":"Raga doorkii aan ka dugsanayooNafta daa'in ebid dayneyninoo.Waxaan donaya inan dadab galneDaaqadaha rajada ha daboolinoo*Laab dooxantaa dawadeda tahayDeero haka dhigin X2, dabna hayguShidin ee ila dadaal. x2Dareenkeygi baa duwatoo adaanDadka kaa xushe naftaanaa doc kaleDabayshedu marin e kuu ildaranUsoo diir naxoo dawadeedu garo.*Laab dooxantaa dawadeda tahayDeero haka dhigin X2, dabna hayguShidin ee ila dadaal. x2!."},{"question":"Berikan ayat contoh untuk peribahasa \\"ada air adalah ikan\\".","answer":"Walau ke mana-mana sahaja kita pergi, janganlah cepat kecewa kerana di mana ada air adalah ikan."},{"question":"Kodi malungo amatha popanda chithandizo?","answer":"Ayi, sichoncho ayi. Malungo amatha kuchiza. Ngati mankhwala oyenerera agwiritsidwa ntchito, anthu omwe ali ndi malungo amatha kuchiritsidwa ndipo tizilombo toyambitsa matenda a malungo tingachotsedwe m’thupi mwawo. Komabe, matendawa amatha kupitilira ngati sakulandira chithandizo kapena ngati apatsidwa mankhwala olakwika."},{"question":"ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਅੰਦਰੂਨੀ ਜਲ ਸਾਗਰ ਕਿਹੜਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"-ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਅੰਦਰੂਨੀ ਜਲ ਸਾਗਰ ਕੈਸਪੀਅਨ ਸਾਗਰ ਹੈ ।-371000 ਵਰਗ ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਦੇ ਖੇਤਰ ਅਤੇ 1,025 ਮੀਟਰ ਦੀ ਡੂੰਘਾਈ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ, ਇਹ ਕਾਕੇਸ਼ਸ ਪਹਾੜਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੂਰਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਤੇ ਮੱਧ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਦੇ ਸਟੈਪ ਦੇ ਪੱਛਮ  ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਕਾਲੇ ਸਾਗਰ ਦੇ ਪੂਰਬ ਵੱਲ 500 ਕਿਲੋਮੀਟਰ ਦੀ ਦੂਰੀ 'ਤੇ ਵੀ ਸਥਿਤ ਹੈ।-.ਇਹ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਲੂਣ ਝੀਲ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਐਂਡੋਰਹੀਕ ਬੇਸਿਨ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਡਰੇਨੇਜ ਬੇਸਿਨ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰੀ ਵਹਾਅ ਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣ ਦਿੰਦਾ।-ਵੋਲਗਾ ਨਦੀ, ਉਰਾਲ ਨਦੀ, ਕੁਰਾ ਨਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਟੇਰੇਕ ਨਦੀ ਕੈਸਪੀਅਨ ਸਾਗਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਗਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵੋਲਗਾ ਨਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਫੀਡਰ ਹੈ ਜੋ 80% ਪ੍ਰਵਾਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।-ਇਹ ਰੂਸ, ਈਰਾਨ, ਅਜ਼ਰਬਾਈਜਾਨ, ਕਜ਼ਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ, ਤੁਰਕਮੇਨਿਸਤਾਨ, ਨਾਲ ਘਿਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।-ਕੈਸਪੀਅਨ ਸਾਗਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਦੇ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਕਿਨਾਰੇ ਅਤੇ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਕਿਨਾਰੇ ਖੇਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੇਲ ਅਤੇ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਗੈਸ ਦੇ ਭੰਡਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਸਰੋਤ ਹਨ। ਊਰਜਾ ਸਰੋਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਵੰਡ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਸਰਹੱਦੀ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਸਮੁੰਦਰੀ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ।-ਕੈਸਪੀਅਨ ਸਾਗਰ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਰੂਸ, ਕਜ਼ਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ, ਈਰਾਨ, ਤੁਰਕਮੇਨਿਸਤਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਅਜ਼ਰਬਾਈਜਾਨ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਦੂਜੇ ਦੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਫੌਜੀ ਸ਼ਮੂਲੀਅਤ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਊਰਜਾ ਸਰੋਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੰਡਣ ਲਈ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ 'ਤੇ ਪਹੁੰਚਣ 'ਤੇ ਹਸਤਾਖਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ।"},{"question":" Sheeg Maskaxda Bili’aadanka Waa Imisa Qeybood","answer":" Maskaxda Bili’aadanka Waxa Loo Qeybiyaa Seddex (3) Qeybood."},{"question":"\\"Raha tsy resahana fotsiny ny tsy fanajana ny lalàmpanorenana izay nataon’ny andrim-panjakana anakiroa dia ny Fitsaràna Avo Momba ny Lalàmpanorenana sy ny governemanta.\\"Inona avy ireo andrim-panjakana anankiroa tsy nanaja lalàmpanorenana?","answer":"Ireo andrim-panjakana anankiroa tsy nanaja lalàmpanorenana dia ny Fitsaràna Avo Momba ny Lalàmpanorenana sy ny governemanta"},{"question":"سوشل میڈیا کے لئے مفت میں مواد تخلیق کرنے کا طریقہ","answer":"1. مواد کی منظمی: اپنے مواد کو منظم طریقے سے پیش کرنا اہم ہے۔ یہ آپ کی پوسٹس کو موزوں ترتیب دینے اور دیکھنے میں آسانی پیدا کرتا ہے۔2. مواد کا تخلیقی کام: اپنی تصویریں اور ویڈیوز کو خود بنائیں۔ آپ اپنے ذاتی تجربات، تخیلات، اور دلچسپیوں پر مبنی مواد تخلیق کر سکتے ہیں۔3. مواد کا موضوع: اپنے مواد کو ایک خاص موضوع کے گرد جمع کریں تاکہ وہ مخاطبین کو دلچسپی دینے میں مدد فراہم کرے۔4. مواد کا تجدید: پرانے مواد کو نئی زندگی دینے کے لئے ان میں تجدید لائیں۔ مثلاً، پرانی پوسٹ کو ایک نئے نظریے سے دیکھنے کی کوشش کریں یا اُسے تازہ معلومات کے ساتھ اپ ڈیٹ کریں۔5. کوئی قیمتی معلومات: مواد میں ایسی معلومات شامل کریں جو آپ کے مخاطبین کے لئے مفید ہو۔ یہ مواد کو مخاطبین کے لئے اہم بناتی ہیں اور آپ کی قدرتی اختصاص کو ظاہر کرتی ہیں۔6. تشہیر اور اشتراک: اپنے مواد کو دوستوں، خاندان اور فالوئرز کے ساتھ شیئر کریں۔ ان میں کہیں تک اسے وائرل بھی کرنے کی کوشش کریں۔7. ہیش ٹیگز اور تگ کریں: اپنے مواد میں موضوع سے متعلق ہیش ٹیگز اور دوسرے مواد کے موضوعات سے متعلق تگز شامل کریں۔8. مواد کی ترجمہ و تبدیلی: اگر آپ کے پاس دوسری زبانوں میں ترجمہ کرنے کی صلاحیت ہے، تو اپنے مواد کو مختلف زبانوں میں ترجمہ کرکے نئے حوالے کی مدد سے نئے حاشیے پیدا کر سکتے ہیں۔9. قدرتی مناظریں اور خود کی تصویریں: اپنی جگہ کی خوبصورتی کو کیمرے میں پکڑیں اور دوستوں کے ساتھ شیئر کریں۔10. اختصاصی مواد کا استعمال: اگر آپ کا کوئی خصوصی مواد ہے جیسے کہ اپنی اشتہاری مواد یا پروڈکٹس، تو ان کو بھی شیئر کریں۔یہ تمام طرائق آپ کو مفت مواد تخلیق کرنے میں مدد فراہم کر سکتے ہیں۔"},{"question":"Nafteydaay gacalo?","answer":"\\"Ogowna, wax waliba in aanay ahayn sida ay u muuqdaan.Sidaada ayaad ku fiican tahay, cilladahaaga iyo iimahaagu xitaa waa kuwo qurux badan. Aqbal waxyaabaha aanad kaga fiicnayn dadka kale, oo ku dhegganow waxyaabaha aad kaga soocan tahay iyaga\\"____^_____♥︎ Nafteydaay Gacalo*\\"Waa buug aan ka helay waxaa ku duugganna Dhiiri-gellin iyo xaqiiqooyin asal ah\\"Hassan Abdijabar Waxaan kasoo xigtey Buuga Nafteydaay Gacalo.\\"!!!  "},{"question":"ما هي الرياضة التي تُلعب بكرة صغيرة تُسدل من منصة مرتفعة ويُحاول الفريقان ضربها باستخدام مضرب؟","answer":"رياضة تنس الطاولة."},{"question":"\\"ഫോണിന്റെ സ്‌ക്രീൻ തകർന്നു, എനിക്ക് എന്റെ പണം തിരികെ വേണം\\" മുൻ പ്രസ്താവനയുടെ വികാരം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഈ വാചകം ഒരു നെഗറ്റീവ് വികാരത്തെ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു, കാരണം വ്യക്തി തന്റെ തകർന്ന ഫോൺ സ്‌ക്രീനിൽ നിരാശനാണ്."},{"question":"njinsi ya kupika sambusa za nyama","answer":"kwanza kabisa naanda jiko kwa ajili ya kupikia naandaa maji kwa ajili ya kukandia unga wangano naanda nyama naandaa mafuta nadaa mafuta pamoja na kikaangio baada ya hapo naazkwa kukanda unga nasukuma chapati nyepesi lain baada ya hapo naweka nyama kwenye chapati nanza kukaanga nazitoa jikon tayari kwa kula  "},{"question":"दाँत नहुने सरीसृप कुन हो ?","answer":"दाँत नहुने सरीसृप कछुवा हो।"},{"question":"Bisọla da omi gbigbona sọkọ ẹ lara l’Ọta, o lọmuti ni","answer":"Bisọla Awodele lẹ n wo yii, obinrin ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogoji (43) to bimọ marun-un fun ọkọ ẹ, Peter Philips, ṣugbọn to mọ-ọn-mọ da omi gbigbona si i lara lọjọ kẹjọ, oṣu kẹta yii, nile wọn ni Sango Ọta. O ni nitori ọkọ oun ko wulo ni, ko si mọ ju ko maa mu ọti kiri lọ.DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi lo fi iṣẹlẹ yii to AKEDE AGBAYE leti laaarọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde ọsẹ yii. Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun naa ṣalaye pe Peter Philips, ọkọ Bisọla, lo gbe ara bibo lọ si teṣan ọlọpaa lọjọ naa, to si ni iyawo oun lo da omi gbigbona soun lara.Nigba ti awọn ọlọpaa lọọ mu iyawo yii nile, o ni loootọ loun da omi gbigbona sọkọ oun lara, ohun to fa a ni pe o maa n mu ọti yo ni, alẹ lo si maa n wọle to ba ti yo binaku tan.O ni ọkọ oun ki i gbọ bukaata lori awọn ọmọ toun bi fun un, oun naa loun n da gbọ gbogbo ẹ.Bisọla sọ fawọn ọlọpaa pe lọjọ toun da omi gbigbona si i lara yii, niṣe lo tun mu ọti yo wale bii iṣe rẹ, oun si n sọrọ si i pẹlu bo ṣe mu ọti yo naa.O ni bi Philip ṣe bẹrẹ si i bu oun, to tun n sọrọ sawọn obi oun niyẹn.Eyi lobinrin naa sọ pe o bi oun ninu toun fi gbe omi gbigbona, toun da a si i lara.Iwadii wọn lori obinrin yii fidi ẹ mulẹ pe o bimọ kan ni nnkan bii oṣu mẹjọ sẹyin, ṣugbọn niṣe lo pa ọmọ naa funra ẹ, to si da a sin, lai jẹ ki ẹnikẹni mọ. Wọn ni nitori bi nnkan ṣe ri fun un naa ni.Ikọ atọpinpin to ri aṣiri yii, de ibi to sin ọmọ naa si i, wọn si ti hu iyooku ara ọmọde naa jade gẹgẹ bi Alukoro ṣe sọ.Ọkọ to da omi gbigbona lu naa lẹ n wo ti wọn we ni bandeeji lọsibitu yii, wọn si ti gbe Bisọla funra ẹ lọ sẹka itọpinpin iwa ọdaran."},{"question":"Muna 1901, ndiani akatanga kutumira masaini eredhiyo mhiri kweAtlantic?","answer":"Muna 1901, muvambi weItaly Guglielmo Marconi akawana nhoroondo yekufambisa masaini eredhiyo ekutanga mhiri kweAtlantic Ocean. Marconi akaita zviedzo zvakatevedzana uye akashandisa musanganiswa wechibatiso chine simba nemaantenna marefu kutumira masaini kubva kuPoldhu muCornwall, England, kuenda kuSt. John's, Newfoundland, Canada. Kubudirira uku kwakaratidza kufambira mberi kwakakosha muhunyanzvi hwekutaurirana husina waya uye kwakaita basa rekutanga mukuvandudza redhiyo yemazuva ano yekutaurirana nenharembozha. Kufambisa kwakabudirira kwaMarconi mhiri kweAtlantic kwakaratidza kugona kwemasaisai eredhiyo pakutaurirana kure."},{"question":"waxaad Sheegtaa Magaca qoraaga Soomaaliyeed ee qoray Buugga “Taariikhda Daraawiishta”?","answer":"Waxaa qoray Aw Jaamac Cumar Ciise (A.N).."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Mbola tsy niomana akory isika anefa ilay fifaninanana efa rahampitso sahady.\\"","answer":"Ity fanambarana ity dia maneho tahotra. Matahotra ianao satria mbola tsy niomana hiatrika an'ilay fifaninanana akory ianareo anefa ilay fotoana anaovana azy efa atomotra."},{"question":"استخرج من المقطع إجابة السؤال: أين تقع مدينة بيدوا؟بَيْدَوَا هي مدينة في وسط جنوب الصومال، تبعد 256كم عن الطريق الشمالي الغربي للعاصمة مقديشو.[1][2][3] وهي ثالث أكبر مدن الصومال، والرابعة أهميةً بعد كيسمايو. ويقدر عدد سكانها أكثر من 800 ألف. تحتل مركزا استراتيجيا هاما بالنسبة لقربها من الحدود المشتركة مع الحبشة وكينيا.","answer":"وسط جنوب الصومال."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的宮廷舞蹈是哪一種？","answer":"答案：法國的古典芭蕾舞"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  bisha uu soo degay qur’anka?","answer":"Qur’an ka wuxuu soo degay bisha Ramadan."},{"question":"Niasa mafy i Maya mba hahazoana ny mari-pahaizana ara-pitsaboana ary nanonofy ny ho tonga dokotera any amin'ny faritra sahirana.","answer":"Nanatevin-daharana fikambanana ara-pitsaboana maha-olona i Maya ary nandany taona maro tamin'ny fikarakarana ara-pahasalamana tena ilaina any amin'ny faritra lavitra. Nisy fiantraikany lehibe teo amin’ny fiainan’ny olona sahirana ny asany."},{"question":"حداکثر سرعت در جاده های اصلی برون شهری چند کیلومتر است؟","answer":"حداکثر میزان سرعت مجاز در جاده های اصلی برای انواع وسایل نقلیه، روزها ۹۵ و شب ها ۸۵ کیلومتر در ساعت می باشد."},{"question":"வினா : வட இந்திய செய்தித்தாள்கள் காமராசரை எப்படி போற்றினர்?","answer":"விடை : காலா காந்தி"},{"question":"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ ਡੂੰਗਰੁ ਦੇਖਿ ਡਰਾਵਣੋ ਪੇਈਅੜੈ ਡਰੀਆਸੁ ॥ ਊਚਉ ਪਰਬਤੁ ਗਾਖੜੋ ਨਾ ਪਉੜੀ ਤਿਤੁ ਤਾਸੁ ॥ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਗੁਰਿ ਮੇਲੀ ਤਰੀਆਸੁ ॥੧॥ ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਭਵਜਲੁ ਬਿਖਮੁ ਡਰਾਂਉ ॥ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਰਸਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਗੁਰੁ ਤਾਰੇ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਉ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਚਲਾ ਚਲਾ ਜੇ ਕਰੀ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਲਣਹਾਰੁ ॥ ਜੋ ਆਇਆ ਸੋ ਚਲਸੀ ਅਮਰੁ ਸੁ ਗੁਰੁ ਕਰਤਾਰੁ ॥ ਭੀ ਸਚਾ ਸਾਲਾਹਣਾ ਸਚੈ ਥਾਨਿ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥੨॥ ਦਰ ਘਰ ਮਹਲਾ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਪਕੇ ਕੋਟ ਹਜਾਰ ॥ ਹਸਤੀ ਘੋੜੇ ਪਾਖਰੇ ਲਸਕਰ ਲਖ ਅਪਾਰ ॥ ਕਿਸ ਹੀ ਨਾਲਿ ਨ ਚਲਿਆ ਖਪਿ ਖਪਿ ਮੁਏ ਅਸਾਰ ॥੩॥ ਸੁਇਨਾ ਰੁਪਾ ਸੰਚੀਐ ਮਾਲੁ ਜਾਲੁ ਜੰਜਾਲੁ ॥ ਸਭ ਜਗ ਮਹਿ ਦੋਹੀ ਫੇਰੀਐ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਸਿਰਿ ਕਾਲੁ ॥ ਪਿੰਡੁ ਪੜੈ ਜੀਉ ਖੇਲਸੀ ਬਦਫੈਲੀ ਕਿਆ ਹਾਲੁ ॥੪॥ ਪੁਤਾ ਦੇਖਿ ਵਿਗਸੀਐ ਨਾਰੀ ਸੇਜ ਭਤਾਰ ॥ ਚੋਆ ਚੰਦਨੁ ਲਾਈਐ ਕਾਪੜੁ ਰੂਪੁ ਸੀਗਾਰੁ ॥ ਖੇਹੂ ਖੇਹ ਰਲਾਈਐ ਛੋਡਿ ਚਲੈ ਘਰ ਬਾਰੁ ॥੫॥ ਮਹਰ ਮਲੂਕ ਕਹਾਈਐ ਰਾਜਾ ਰਾਉ ਕਿ ਖਾਨੁ ॥ ਚਉਧਰੀ ਰਾਉ ਸਦਾਈਐ ਜਲਿ ਬਲੀਐ ਅਭਿਮਾਨ ॥ ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਿਸਾਰਿਆ ਜਿਉ ਡਵਿ ਦਧਾ ਕਾਨੁ ॥੬॥ ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਜਾਇਸੀ ਜੋ ਆਇਆ ਜਗ ਮਾਹਿ ॥ ਸਭੁ ਜਗੁ ਕਾਜਲ ਕੋਠੜੀ ਤਨੁ ਮਨੁ ਦੇਹ ਸੁਆਹਿ ॥ ਗੁਰਿ ਰਾਖੇ ਸੇ ਨਿਰਮਲੇ ਸਬਦਿ ਨਿਵਾਰੀ ਭਾਹਿ ॥੭॥ ਨਾਨਕ ਤਰੀਐ ਸਚਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਿਰਿ ਸਾਹਾ ਪਾਤਿਸਾਹੁ ॥ ਮੈ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਵੀਸਰੈ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਤਨੁ ਵੇਸਾਹੁ ॥ ਮਨਮੁਖ ਭਉਜਲਿ ਪਚਿ ਮੁਏ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਤਰੇ ਅਥਾਹੁ ॥੮॥੧੬॥ ","answer":"ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਇਹ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ (ਬੜਾ) ਡਰਾਉਣਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ (ਤਰਨਾ) ਔਖਾ ਹੈ। ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਕੇ (ਇਸ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ।1। ਰਹਾਉ।(ਇਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਹੈ; ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ, ਇਸ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਣ ਲਈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਰਸਤਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਉਹ ਰਸਤਾ ਪਹਾੜੀ ਰਸਤਾ ਹੈ। ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਸਿਖਰ ਤੇ ਪਹੁੰਚਣਾ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਇਕ ਬੜੇ ਉੱਚੇ ਡਰਾਉਣੇ ਪਹਾੜ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਨਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ) ਡਰਾਉਣੇ ਪਹਾੜ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਪੇਕੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ (ਮਾਂ ਪਿਉ ਭੈਣ ਭਰਾ ਆਦਿਕ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਗ੍ਰਸੀ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ) ਡਰ ਗਈ (ਕਿ ਇਸ ਪਹਾੜ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ, ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ, ਆਪਾ ਵਾਰਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ) । (ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਸਿਖਰ ਤੇ ਅੱਪੜਨਾ, ਮਾਨੋ) ਬੜਾ ਉੱਚਾ ਤੇ ਔਖਾ ਪਹਾੜ ਹੈ; ਉਸ ਪਹਾੜ ਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਨ ਲਈ ਉਸ (ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ) ਦੇ ਪਾਸ ਕੋਈ ਪੌੜੀ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਮਿਲਾ ਲਿਆ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੀ ਵੱਸਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣ ਲਿਆ, ਤੇ, ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਗਈ।1।ਜੇ ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਚੇਤੇ ਰੱਖਾਂ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਜਗਤ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਚਲੇ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇ ਮੈਂ ਸਮਝ ਲਵਾਂ ਕਿ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਹੀ ਚਲੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਭੀ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਖ਼ਰ ਚਲਾ ਜਾਇਗਾ, ਮੌਤ-ਰਹਿਤ ਇਕ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਫਿਰ ਸਤਸੰਗ ਵਿਚ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ) ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ (ਬੱਸ! ਇਹੀ ਹੈ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਲਹਿਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਦਾ ਤਰੀਕਾ) ।2।ਸੋਹਣੇ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਿਆਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਘਰ ਤੇ ਮਹੱਲ, ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਪੱਕੇ ਕਿਲ੍ਹੇ, ਹਾਥੀ, ਘੋੜੇ, ਕਾਠੀਆਂ, ਲੱਖਾਂ ਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਲਸ਼ਕਰ = ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਭੀ ਕਿਸੇ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਏ। ਬੇਸਮਝ ਐਵੇਂ ਹੀ ਖਪ ਖਪ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤੇ ਮਰਦੇ ਰਹੇ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਗਵਾ ਗਏ) ।3।ਜੇ ਸੋਨਾ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਜਾਈਏ, ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਮਾਲ ਧਨ (ਜਿੰਦ ਨੂੰ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਾਣ ਲਈ) ਜਾਲ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਫਾਹੀ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਦੀ ਦੁਹਾਈ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਫਿਰਾ ਸਕੀਏ, ਤਾਂ ਭੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੌਤ ਦਾ ਡਰ (ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ) ਹੈ। ਜਦੋਂ ਜਿੰਦ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਖੇਡ ਖੇਡ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਸਰੀਰ (ਮਿੱਟੀ ਹੋ ਕੇ) ਢਹਿ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ (ਧਨ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਮੰਦੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਭੈੜਾ ਹਾਲ ਹੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।4।ਪਿਉ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਪੁੱਤਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਖਸਮ (ਆਪਣੀ) ਸੇਜ ਉਤੇ ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਖਿੜਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਇਸ ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ) ਅਤਰ ਤੇ ਚੰਦਨ ਲਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸੋਹਣਾ ਕੱਪੜਾ, ਰੂਪ, ਗਹਿਣਾ ਆਦਿਕ (ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਮਨ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ; ਪਰ ਆਖ਼ਰ ਸਰੀਰ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਵਿਚ ਰਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮਾਣ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ (ਜੀਵ) ਘਰ ਬਾਰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ (ਸੰਸਾਰ ਤੋਂ) ਚਲਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।5।ਸਰਦਾਰ, ਬਾਦਸ਼ਾਹ, ਰਾਜਾ, ਰਾਉ ਜਾਂ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਅਖਵਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ। (ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ) ਚੌਧਰੀ, ਰਾਇ (ਸਾਹਿਬ ਆਦਿਕ) ਸਦਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਇਸ ਵਡੱਪਣ ਦੇ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸੜ ਮਰੀਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਪੂਰਾ ਮਾਣ-ਆਦਰ ਨਾਹ ਕਰੇ) । (ਪਰ ਇਤਨਾ ਕੁਝ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਭੁਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਤੇ (ਇਉਂ ਦਿੱਸਿਆ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਜੰਗਲ ਦੀ ਅੱਗ ਨਾਲ ਸੜਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਾਨਾ ਹੈ (ਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਚਮਕਦਾ, ਤੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਸੜ ਕੇ ਕਾਲਾ) ।6।ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਭੀ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ 'ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ, ਮੈਂ ਵੱਡਾ' ਆਖ ਆਖ ਕੇ (ਆਖ਼ਰ ਇਥੋਂ) ਚਲਾ ਜਾਇਗਾ। ਇਹ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਕੱਜਲ ਦੀ ਕੋਠੜੀ (ਸਮਾਨ) ਹੈ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਭੀ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਤਨ ਮਨ ਸਰੀਰ ਸੁਆਹ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਅੱਗ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ, ਉਹ (ਇਸ ਕੱਜਲ-ਕੋਠੜੀ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਸਾਫ਼-ਸੁਥਰੇ ਹੀ ਰਹੇ।7।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਭ ਸ਼ਾਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਖ–) ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਕਦੇ ਨਾ ਭੁੱਲੇ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਤਨ ਨਾਮ-ਪੂੰਜੀ (ਮੇਰੇ ਪਾਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹੇ) । ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਵਿਚ ਖਪ ਖਪ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤੇ ਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਇਸ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਡੂੰਘੇ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਉਹ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਹਿਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਡੁੱਬਦੇ) ।8।16।"},{"question":"උස්වැල්ලේ මහානාග මහතෙරණුවෝ  ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"තලගුරු වෙහෙර විසූ ධම්මදින්න මහතෙරුන්ගේ ආචාර්‍ය්‍යවරයා උච්චවාලිකවාසී මහානාග මහතෙර යයි විභංග අටුවාහි (346) කියවේ. ධම්මදින්න ස්ථවිරතුමා වනාහ පිළිසිඹියාපත් රහත් නමකි. එක්දිනක් එතුමා දිවාස්ථානයෙහි හිඳ ස්වකීයාචාර්‍ය උච්චවාලික හෝ උච්චතලංකවාසී මහානාග තෙරුන් ගේ ශ්‍ර‍මණ කෘත්‍යය මස්තකප්‍රාප්ත වී දැයි දිවැසින් බලා එතුමන් ඒතාක් පෘථග්ජන බව දැක සෘද්ධියෙන් අහසට නැග ගොස් තෙරුන් ඉදිරියෙහි අහසින් බැස වැඳ වත් දක්වා වාඩි විය. “ධම්මදින්නය, කුමක් හෙයින් නොකල්හි ආයෙහිදැ” යි ඇසූවිට “ප්‍ර‍ශ්නයක් විචාරන්ටය”ය කීය. “ඇවැත්නි, විචාරව, දන්නා දෙයක් කියමි”යි මහතෙරුන් කීවිට ධම්මදින්න තෙර ප්‍ර‍ශ්න දහසක් විචාළේය. තෙරණුවෝ විචාළ ප්‍ර‍ශ්න සියල්ල නොපැකිලි විසඳූහ. “ස්වාමීනි, ඔබගේ නුවණ ඉතා සියුම්ය, කවර කලක මේ ධර්‍මය අවබෝධ කරන ලද්දේදැ”යි ඇසූ විට “මින් අවුරුදු සැටකට පෙරදී” යය කීහ. “සෘද්ධිබල පෑමෙහිත් සමත් වෙත්දැ’යි ඇසූ විට එසේය” යි උත්තර දුන් බැවින් “ස්වාමීනි, ඇතකු මැව්ව මැනවැ”යි කීය. එතුමන් විශාල සුදු ඇතකු මැවූවිට “ස්වාමීනි, මේ ඇතා කෙළින් කොට ගත් කන් ඇතිව, දික් කළ නඟුට ඇතිව, සොඬය කටේ දමාගෙන, භයානක ශබ්ද කරමින් ඔබ ඉදිරියට එනසේ කළ මැනවැ”යි කීය. මහතෙරණුවෝ ඒ කී සේ කොට වේගයෙන් එන ඇතාට භයවී නැගිට දුවන්ට සැරසුණේ ය. එවිට ධම්මදින්න ස්ථවිරතුමා එතුමාග් සිවුරුකොණ අල්වා නවත්වා “ස්වාමීනි, රහතුන්ට භය උපදීදැ”යි ඇසීය. ඒ අවස්ථාවේ දී තමා රහත් නොවන බව දැන මහස්ථවිරතුමා “ධම්ම දින්නය, මට පිහිට වෙව”යි කියමින් ශිෂ්‍යයාගේ පාමුල ඇණතබාගෙන වාඩි විය. ධම්මදින්න තෙර එතුමාට කමටහනක් කීය. මහතෙරනම කමටහන් ගෙන සක්මනට බැස තෙවෙනි පියවරේ දී රහත්ඵලය ලැබුවේ ය.මැදුම්සඟිඅටුවාහි සල්ලෙඛසූත්‍ර‍වර්‍ණනාවෙහි කියවෙන්නේ හඞ්කන විහාරයෙහි විසූ තෙරනමක් ධම්මදින්නතෙරුන් විසින් රහත් කරවන ලද බවයි.ගිරුවා දනව්වෙහි කොන්තරකට්ඨ’පබ්බත මහාවිහාරයෙහි විසූ මහානාග නම් තෙරනමක් ගැන රසවාහිනියෙහි දුටුගැමුණු කථාවෙහි කියවේ. එතුමා දුටුගැමුණු කුමරු උපදින්ට ආසන්න කලක අපවත් වූ බව ඒ කථාවෙන් පෙනේ. තලගුරුවෙහෙර ධම්මදින්න තෙරුන් දුටුගැමුණු කාලයෙහි විසූ බව ඔප්පු වෙන හෙයින් එතුමාගේ ආචාර්‍ය්‍යවූ මහානාග තෙරුන් කාවන්තිස්ස කාලයේ දී විසීම සිදුවිය යුත්තකි.අංගුත්තරඅටුවාහි එකනිපාතවණ්ණනාවෙහි (29) උච්චවාලිකවාසී මහානාග ස්ථවිරතුමා කායික වීර්‍ය්‍ය-චෛතසික වීර්‍ය්‍යය යන ද්විවිධ වීර්‍ය්‍යයෙන්ම ආරබ්ධ වීර්‍ය්‍ය ඇත්තේ වීයයි ද එතුමා සතියක් මුළුල්ලේ සක්මන් කිරීමද තවත් සතියක් මුළුල්ලේ සිටීමද සතියක් මුළුල්ලේ හිඳීමද සතියක් මුළුල්ලේ නිදීමද කෙළේයයි කියන ලදි."},{"question":"Which actor won the best actor Oscar for the films Philadelphia (1993) and Forrest Gump (1994)?","answer":"Tom Hanks"},{"question":"PlayStation 5 stok sorunu ne zaman bitecek?","answer":"PlayStation 5 stok sorunu 2023'te çözülecekSony CEO'su Jim Ryan'dan gelen yeni açıklama ise PlayStation 5 dağıtımının hızlanacağını gösteriyor. Sony Japonya'da yer alan açıklamaya göre, Asya ve Japonya'daki stok sorunu 2023'te çözülecek."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Mba ho tahaka ny rano sy vary ........................... \\"","answer":"\\"  Mba ho tahaka ny rano sy vary ka an-tsaha tsy mifanary, an-tanànana tsy mifandaho.  \\" "},{"question":"Qui était l'artiste Minouk Lim ?","answer":"Minouk Lim, un artiste sud-coréen, travaille à travers divers médias, notamment la vidéo, la performance et l'installation, pour aborder des problèmes sociaux et politiques. Ses « Navigation ID » et « Dressed for a Public Option » explorent les thèmes de la migration, de la mémoire et de la relation de l'individu aux environnements urbains."},{"question":"س194- كم عدد الأولاد الذكور للملك عبد العزيز ؟","answer":"ج194- 36 ذكر"},{"question":"Firy ny laharana manaraka ny telo ?","answer":"Efatra no laharana manaraka ny telo "},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو تعريف الصوم لغة؟","answer":"الإجابة: مطلق الإمساك"},{"question":"Ndedzipi nzvimbo dzine vanhu vakawanda pasefa pasi rose","answer":"Snapper Rocks, Gold Coast, Australia - Rincon, California - Malibu, California - Trestles, California"},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahan'ny fanabeazana  mandray anjara amin'ny fandriampahalemana sy famahana ny ady?","answer":"Ny fanabeazana  dia afaka mitondra anjara biriky amin'ny fandriampahalemana amin'ny fampiroboroboana ny fandeferana, ny fiaraha-miasa ary ny fifankahazoana eo amin'ny kolontsaina sy ny vahoaka. Izy io koa dia mampianatra ny soatoavin'ny fanajana ny zon'olombelona sy ny famahana ny fifandirana am-pilaminana, ka manampy amin'ny fisorohana ny disadisa sy ny herisetra."},{"question":"கேள்வி: \\"இறைவனையே  தமிழ்\\" என்ற சொல்லால் குறிப்பிட்டவர் யார்.? ","answer":"பதில்: \\"இறைவனையே  தமிழ்\\" என்ற சொல்லால் குறிப்பிட்டவர்திருமங்கையாழ்வார்.                                                                                                                            திருமங்கையாழ்வார்  என்பவர் வைணவ நெறியைப் பின்பற்றிய  பக்தியில் சிறந்து விளங்கிய பன்னிரு ஆழ்வார்களுள் இளையவர் மற்றும் இறுதியானவர். சோழ நாட்டில் உள்ள திருவாலிதிருநகரி என்னும் ஊருக்கு அருகில் உள்ள திருக்குரையலூரில் கள்ளர் குடியில் பிறந்தார். இவரது இயற்பெயர் கலியன். ஆதியில் இவர் சோழமன்னனுக்குப் படைத்தலைவனாக இருந்தார். ஒருமுறை போர்க்களத்தில் இவருடைய வீரத்தைக் கண்ட அரசன் இவரைச் சோழதேசத்தின் 'திருமங்கை' நாட்டின் மன்னனாக்கினான். அன்று முதல் இவர் \\"திருமங்கை மன்னன்\\" என அழைக்கப்படுபவர்.                                                                                                                                      எழுதிய நூல்கள்:                                                                                                                                       1.திருவெழுக்கூற்றிருக்கை (ஒரு பாடல் - 47 அடிகள்)2.சிறிய திருமடல் (ஒரு பாடல் - 155 அடிகள்)3.பெரிய திருமடல் (ஒரு பாடல் - 297 அடிகள்)4.திருநெடுந்தாண்டகம் (30 பாடல்கள்)5.திருக்குறுந் தாண்டகம் (20 பாடல்கள்)6.பெரிய திருமொழி (1084 பாடல்கள்)"},{"question":"57 alayın özelliği ne?","answer":"\\"Sarı Bayraklılar\\" olarak da bilinen 57. Alay, Türk Silahlı Kuvvetleri'nin önemli bir birliğidir. Türk askeri tarihinde özel bir yere sahip olan bu alay, Kore Savaşı'ndaki üstün başarıları ve fedakarlıkları nedeniyle tanınmıştır.57. Alay, Türk Silahlı Kuvvetleri'nin Kore Savaşı'na katılan birinci birliğidir. 1950-1953 yılları arasında gerçekleşen Kore Savaşı'nda Birleşmiş Milletler Güçleri'ne destek amacıyla Türkiye, ABD liderliğindeki koalisyon güçlerine bir tabur gönderdi. Bu tabur, 57. Alay'a bağlı olarak görev yapmıştır.Kore Savaşı'ndaki çeşitli savaşlarda gösterdiği üstün başarı ve kahramanlıkla tanınan 57. Alay, Türk milleti için gurur kaynağı olmuştur. Sarı bayraklarıyla bilinirler ve Türk askeri geleneğinde önemli bir yer tutarlar."},{"question":"ක්ලික් රසායන විද්යාව යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ක්ලික් රසායන විද්යාව (Click chemistry) යනු Barry Sharpless විසින් සංවර්ධනය කරන රසායන විද්‍යාවේ ආකාරයකි."},{"question":"સૌરાષ્ટ્ર મા હોળી કેવી રીતે ઉજવાય છે?","answer":"સૌરાષ્ટ્રમાં, હોળીને 'હુતાસણી'થી પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે, હોળીના બીજા દિવસ ધુળેટીને 'પડવો' કહેવામાં આવે છે. અમુક વિસ્તારોમાં હોળી પછીનાં બે કે ત્રણ દિવસ આ તહેવાર ઉજવાય છે, જેને 'બીજો પડવો','ત્રીજો પડવો' એમ ગણવામાં આવે છે. આ દિવસોમાં પુરુષો દ્વારા દાંડીયા રાસ રમવાનો રિવાજ પણ, ખાસ કરીને પોરબંદર વિસ્તારમાં, છે. ઘણાં આદિવાસી વિસ્તારોમાં હોળી પ્રગટાવ્યા પછી તેની આસપાસ પારંપારીક નૃત્ય કરવામાં આવે છે. યુવાનો દ્વારા આ દિવસોમાં શોર્યપુર્ણ રમતો રમવામાં અને વિવિધ પારંપારીક હરીફાઇ યોજવામાં આવે છે, જેમકે ઘોડાદોડ, આંધળો પાટો, શ્રીફળ ફેંકવાની હરીફાઇ વગેરે. ગ્રામ્ય વિસ્તારોમાં ગામને પાદર આવેલા પૂર્વજોનાં પાળિયાઓનું પૂજન અર્ચન કરવામાં આવે છે. ઘણાં વિસ્તારોમાં હોળીનાં દિવસોમાં ગામ લોકો વાજતે ગાજતે ગામમાં બધાજ લતાઓ કે વિસ્તારોમાં ફરી અને હોળી માટેનો ફાળો (ગોઠ) ઉઘરાવવા નિકળે છે, આ લોકોને ઘેરૈયાઓ કહેવાય છે.હોળીનાં દિવસે જેને ત્યાં ગત વર્ષમાં દિકરાનો જન્મ થયો હોય તે લોકો બાળકને શણગારીને હોળીની પ્રદક્ષિણા કરાવે છે,તથા ગામલોકોને પતાસા તથા ખજુર વગેરેની 'લાણ' વહેંચે છે, આ પ્રસંગને દિકરાની વાડ કહેવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":" प्राचीन हिन्दुस्थानचा नेपोलियन कोणाला म्हणतात ?","answer":" प्राचीन हिन्दुस्थानचा नेपोलियन समुद्रगुप्तला म्हणतात . "},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny HMF?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny HMF dia: Hetsiky ny Mpitondra Fivavahana"},{"question":"ಅಬ್ಬಬ್ಬ ಹಬ್ಬ ಬಂತು, ಸಿಹಿಕಹಿ ಎರಡೂ ತಂತು. ಇದು ಯಾವ ಹಬ್ಬ?","answer":"ಕೊಟ್ಟಿರುವ ಸಾಲು ಯುಗಾದಿ ಹಬ್ಬವನ್ನು ವಿವರಿಸುತ್ತದೆ."},{"question":"Aiza no misy  an'i Jerosalema?","answer":"Jerosalema dia eo anelanelan'ny Israely sy Palestina."},{"question":"Write me a trivia question that contains the words","answer":"Sure, a possible question is \\"Which countries were not colonized"},{"question":"Як виглядав козак?","answer":"Одяг запорізького козацтва включав білу сорочку, шаро­вари, часто оздоблені широким золотим позументом уздовж бокових швів, пояс, черкеску, сукняний напівкунтуш, каптан, жупан, виготовлений з грубого сукна, хутряну шапку з чорних лисиць, шапку із шликом, який закінчувався золотою китицею, чоботи. Характерними були зачіски козаків. У XVI-XVIII ст. побутували зачіски з підголюванвям волосся; залишали і відро­щували пасмо волосся - чуб (від перського \\"чоб\\" - китиця, пасмо). Про цю зачіску згадує ще візантійський історик Х ст. Лев Диякон. Вона зображена на українських народних картинах (\\"Козак Мамай\\"). Бороди козаки голили, але носили вуса. Серед козацької старшини, дворянства переважала зачісжа із зали­шеним кружком волосся на маківці. "},{"question":"Tôm hùng bông Australia có trọng lượng tới 4-5 kg, giá đắt đỏ, song không phải lúc nào loài tôm hùm này cũng có hàng để nhập về Việt Nam.Vốn là loại hải sản cao cấp đắt đỏ nhất trong dòng tôm, tôm hùm bông trọng lượng 4-5 kg một con khai thác ngoài tự nhiên có số lượng ít. Tại Việt Nam, loại này đa phần là tôm nuôi ở các vùng biển Nha Trang hoặc Phú Yên nhưng số lượng cũng không nhiều.Mới đây một công ty ở TP HCM đã nhập lô tôm hùm bông thiên nhiên Australia gần 100 con.Tôm hùm bông tự nhiên ở  Australia có trọng lượng 4 kg tại cửa hàng hải sản ở TP HCM. Ảnh: Linh ĐanTôm hùm có trọng lượng 4 kg tại cửa hàng hải sản ở TP HCM. Ảnh: Linh ĐanÔng Trần Văn Trường, CEO chuỗi Hải sản Hoàng Gia, cho biết lần đầu tiên ông nhập được lô tôm hùm bông có kích cỡ khủng trước dịp lễ. Các năm trước, loại này cả năm mới có một lần hoặc 2-3 tháng khách mới báo có hàng. Trong 100 con tôm cập cảng TP HCM hồi đầu tuần có khoảng 10 con trọng lượng 4-5 kg nhưng đều được khách đặt mua dịp lễ 2/9. \\"Chúng tôi chỉ còn loại có trọng lượng 1-3kg\\", ông Trường nói.Theo ông, giá bán lên tới gần 3,5 triệu một kg. Loại 2 kg một con có giá 7 triệu đồng, con 4-5 kg có giá 14-17 triệu đồng. Những con tôm này có chiều dài 40 cm và chiều ngang 18 cm, không tính phần chân và râu.Cũng từng bán 20 con tôm hùm bông nhập khẩu, anh Toàn, chủ vựa hải sản trên đường Phạm Văn Đồng (TP Thủ Đức) cho biết, tôm hùm bông tự nhiên loại 2 kg một con có số lượng ít, con 4-5 kg là \\"cực hiếm\\". Đặc biệt, với loại được đánh bắt ở vùng biển sạch, được bảo vệ nghiêm ngặt như Australia lại càng đắt đỏ. Do đó, anh Toàn thường phải gom đơn và đề nghị khách đặt cọc trước 50% mới dám nhập hàng.Đưa ra một tiêu đề cho đoạn văn bản trên. ","answer":"Tôm hùm bông Australia giá 15 triệu đồng một con"},{"question":"ਏਸ਼ਿਆਈ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਕਿਸ ਦੇ ਯਤਨ ਨਾਲ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ?","answer":"ਮਹਾਰਾਜਾ ਪਟਿਆਲਾ ਸਰਦਾਰ ਯਾਦਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਜੀ. ਡੀ. ਸੋਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਯਤਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ।"},{"question":"- من هو سيف الله المسلول ؟","answer":"- سيدنا خالد بن الوليد"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai anjing tiada bercawat ekor\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hina dan tidak berguna"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:ఏడురంగులను కలిగియున్నా ఇంద్రధనస్సునీడ ఒకటే ఏడు రంగులతో ఉన్నా చంద్రుని కాంతి తెలుపే! మానవులలో వివిధ వర్ణాల వారు ఉన్నా అందరిని నడిపించేది. మానవత్వమే.","answer":"సప్తరంగుల సంగమమైనా.ఇంద్ర ధనస్సు ఛాయ ఒకటేఏడు రంగుల కూడికఐనాభానుకాంతి తెలుపేరంగులు వేరైనా నరజాతి.స రంగు మానవత్వమేచంద్రికలను వెదజల్లే చందమామ నలుపైనాచంద్రుడు నలుపని మనమనగలమా!"},{"question":"Đọc các câu sau và thực hiện các yêu cầu bên dưới: Đoạn văn : “Đại dương bao quanh lục địa. Rồi mạng lưới sông ngòi chăng chịt. Lại có những hồ năm sâu trong đất liền lớn chăng kém gì biển cả.”a) Xếp các từ in nghiêng vào hai nhóm: từ thuần Việt, từ Hán Việt.b) Xếp các từ thuần Việt, Hán Việt thành các cặp đồng nghĩa.c) Tìm thêm hoặc đặt câu có sử dụng một trong các từ đại đương, lục địa.","answer":"a) Từ thuần Việt: đất liền, biển cả. Từ Hán Việt: đại dương, lục địab) Các từ thuần Việt, Hán Việt thành các cặp đồng nghĩa: đại dương và biển cả, đất liền và lục địa.c) Tìm thêm hoặc đặt câu có sử dụng một trong các từ đại đương, lục địa.Bề mặt của Trái Đất được bao phủ bởi 70,8% là nước biển và được chia thành 5 đại dương."},{"question":"11-5х=2х+4х=?","answer":"x=1"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي التقمه الحوت؟","answer":"الإجابة: يونس عليه السلام"},{"question":"Maninona i Madagasikara no antsoina hoe firenena?","answer":"Firenena i Madagasikara satria:- manana ny teniny: teny Malagasy.- manana ny fanevany: ny sainam-pirenena fotsy mena ary maintso.- manana ny hiram-pirenena: Ry tanindrazanay malala ô!- manana ny taniny: Madagasikara."},{"question":"\\"ඇලක් හරහා යාමට දැමූ ලීය\\" යන්නට වඩාත්ම ගැලපෙන කෙටි පදය කුමක්ද? (ඔබට භාවිතා කල හැක්කේ එක වචනයක් පමණි)","answer":"\\"ඒදණ්ඩ\\" වඩාතම ගැලපෙන තනි පදයයි."},{"question":"Me ya kashe shugaban Rwanda a 1994?","answer":"Makami mai linzami ne ya kashe shi."},{"question":"Iya kọ lo n jẹ awọn to fọ ile ounjẹ kiri, o lohun to n ṣe wọn – Fẹmi Adeṣina","answer":"Fẹmi Adeṣina, oluranlọwo fun Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari nipa eto iroyin ati ohun to ni ṣe pẹlu awujọ, ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu ohun ti ajọ agbaye kan, Amnesty International sọ wi pe ebi ati bi inu ṣe n bi araalu lo mu kawọn eeyan kan maa ji ẹru ijọba ko kiri.Adeṣina ninu ọrọ ẹ sọ pe ki i ṣe ebi tabi ibinu lo mu wọn ṣe e bi ko ṣe pe rogbodiyan to n ṣẹlẹ laarin ilu, ti ko si si ilana ofin mọ, tabi agbofinro to le bu wọn so, iyẹn lo fun awọn eeyan kan lanfaani lati huwa ọdaran ọhun.O fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe, ajọ Amnesty International kuna patapata ninu ọrọ ti wọn sọ wi pe bi awọn ṣọja ṣe kọlu awọn ọdọ to n ṣewọde ni Lẹkki lo fa sababi bi awọn ọdọ kan ṣe n ba nnkan jẹ kiri, nigba ti inu buruku bẹrẹ si bi wọn.O ni ṣaaju ki ọrọ Lẹkki too ṣẹlẹ lawọn eeyan kan ti kọlu awọn ọlọpaa ati teṣan wọn, ti wọn sọna si teṣan ọlọpaa to wa l’Orile, l’Ekoo.  Bakan naa lo tun fi kun un pe ọgba ẹwọn to wa ni Benin ati Oko ti wọn kọlu naa, ki i ṣe ibinu kan lo n ṣe awọn eeyan bi ko ṣe pe wọn lo anfaani rogbodiyan to wa nita nigba yẹn lati fi ṣiṣẹ ibi."},{"question":" Em qual país foi detectado o primeiro caso de Covid-19?","answer":"Na China, mais precisamente na província de Wuhan."},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Allemagne nékk?","answer":"Réewum Allemagne mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Europe."},{"question":"පහත  නාම පදයට අදාළ ස්ත්‍රී ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද?සභාපති ","answer":"සභාපතිනිය "},{"question":"A que explorador português é creditada a primeira circunavegação do globo?","answer":"O explorador português creditado com a primeira circunavegação do globo foi Fernando Magalhães."},{"question":"గోళము, స్థూపము, శంఖువు ఒకే ఎత్తు, ఒకే వ్యాసార్ధాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటే వాటి వక్రతల వైశాల్యాల నిష్పత్తి ఎంత ?","answer":"4: 4: √5"},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر الخفيف.","answer":"أَقعَدَتنا زَمانَةٌ وَزَمانٌجائِرٌ عَن قَضاءِ حَقِّ الشَريفِوَلَئِن ثَقَّلا عَنِ الخِدمَةِ الخَطوَلَعَن خاطِرٍ إِلَيها خَفيفِفَاِقتَصَرنا فيما نُؤَدّي مِنَ العَرضِ عَلى الكُتبِ وَالرَسولِ الحَصيفِوَالفَتى ذو الشَبابِ يَبسُطُ في التَقصيرِ عُذرَ الشَيخِ العَليلِ الضَعيفِ"},{"question":"Кайсы жылы интернет жалпыга колдонгонго берилди?","answer":"1993-жылы интернет жалпыга колдонууга берилген."},{"question":"વાનગી કઢી વિશે માહિતી આપો","answer":"કઢી એ દહીં કે છાશમાંથેએ બનતી સૂપ કે દાળ જેવી તરલ વાનગી છે. કઢી સંપૂર્ણ ભારતમાં બનાવવામાં આવે છે. તેને ખીચડી સાથે ખવાય છે. ગુજરાતી ભોજન કે ગુજરાતી થાળીમાં કઢી અવશ્ય હોય છે. ઉત્તર ભારતમાં,ખાટા દહીંને તેમાં સ્વાદ ઉમેરવામાં આવે છે. તેઓ ક્યાંક તો બાફેલા ચોખા અથવા રોટી સાથે ખાવામાં આવે છે. રાજસ્થાન અને ગુજરાતમાં, તે સામાન્ય રીતે ખીચડી, રોટી, પરાઠા અથવા ચોખા સાથે પીરસવામાં આવે છે. તે હલકો ખોરાક ગણાય છે. રાજસ્થાની અને ગુજરાતી કઢી ઉત્તર પ્રદેશની વિવિધતાથી અલગ છે.ગુજરાતી કઢી છાશથી પ્રાધાન્ય આપવામાં આવે છે કારણ કે તે દહીંની તુલનામાં વધુ સરળ છે. આ મૂળભૂત વાનગી પરની ભિન્નતા ચોક્કસ શાકભાજીના ઉમેરાનો સમાવેશ થાય છે, ખાસ કરીને ભિંડી (ઓકરા) જેમાં તેને 'ભીંડા ની કઢી' તરીકે ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. પંજાબ કઢીમાં એક સરળ, ઝડપી શિયાળુ ભોજન છે. સુસંગતતા વધારવા માટે બેસાના (જેને ચણાના લોટ અથવા ગ્રામ ફ્લોર તરીકે પણ ઓળખાય છે) બનાવવામાં આવે છે, અને પકોરા ઉમેરી રહ્યા છે, તે લાંબા સમય સુધી અનાજ બાસમતી ચોખા અથવા, (વધુ સામાન્ય રીતે) રોટી સાથે ખાવામાં આવે છે. બાકીના ભારતની જેમ, ખાટા દહીં ઉમેરવામાં આવતો નથી, માત્ર સંપૂર્ણ ચરબીનો છાશ, અથવા નકામા દહીં."},{"question":"Firy kilometatra no elanelana eo amin'ny Tany mankany amin'ny Volana?","answer":"Manodidina ny 384.400 kilometatra eo ho eo ny elanelan’ny Tany mankany amin’ny Volana."},{"question":"नेपालमा चुकौनी खानेकुरा के हो ?","answer":"चुकौनी पश्चिमी नेपाल, विशेष गरी पाल्पा र वरपरका जिल्लाहरूमा लोकप्रिय सलाद तयारी हो। दही, प्याज, मसला र आलुको प्रयोग गरेर यसमा दही मिसाएर बनाउँदा यसलाई पौष्टिक नुस्खा बनाइन्छ। दहीले आलुबाट कार्बोहाइड्रेट प्रशोधन गर्न मद्दत गर्दछ जबकि समग्र डिशको मसला स्तरलाई सन्तुलनमा राख्छ। यो नेपाली आलु दही सलाद एक स्वादिलो साइड डिश हो जसलाई भात, रोटी वा सेल रोटीसँग जोड्न सकिन्छ। न्यानो होस् वा चिसोमा परोस यो पश्चिमी नेपालमा प्रख्यात ब्रेकफास्ट डिश मानिन्छ।"},{"question":"రాక్షసి – తంగడి యుద్ధం గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"రాక్షసి – తంగడి యుద్ధం క్రీ.శ. 1565లో విజయనగరానికి 10 మైళ్ళ దూరంలో ఉన్న రాక్షసి తంగడి అను గ్రామాల మధ్య విజయనగర సైన్యాలకు, బహమనీ సైన్యాలకు మధ్య జరిగింది. ఈ యుద్ధంలో విజయనగర సైన్యాలు ఓడి, సర్వనాశనమయ్యాయి. బహమనీ సైన్యాలు రామరాయలను అతిక్రూరంగా హతమార్చాయి. ఈ యుద్ధానంతరం ముస్లిం సైన్యాలు రక్షణ లేని విజయనగరంలో ప్రవేశించి, దోచుకొని, రాజప్రాసాదాలను, ఆలయాలను ధ్వంసం చేశాయి. ఈ యుద్ధంతో విజయనగర సామ్రాజ్యం పతనమైంది."},{"question":"கேள்வி : ஒளிசுழற்ச்சி மாற்றியம்  என்பது என்ன எது ? ","answer":"பதில் : மெண்டலிக் அமிலம்."},{"question":"Namuhla olwamanqamu. Imilomo yoDlamini izovaleka ngoba abantubazokhuluma njengoba bakhuluma mhlazane bevota.Akukho okunye. Namuhla kunamuhla. Uyabona leli kilasi sengathilizoba yinkinga ngenxa yobuningi babantu abazofika bezothamela lomhlangano. Phela thina asizile ukuzoqoqa imali yabantu kodwasizobanika isihlonti abantu.Akusona nesihlonti kodwa yilanga. Mina intuthuko ngiyifanisa nelangalona eliphuma maqede kujabule yonke into esemhlabeni. Ngishonalabo abangamazisi uJehova kodwa bayajabula. Kanjalo nalaphakule ndawo labo abebengayingeni eyakho bazothokoza maqedebayingene shiqe! Ngempela bazokuthanda. Uqale kahle impela.Uyabona eyamanzi ingungqa phambili.Umuhle wena ngoba uphila ngethemba. Nomuntu osondelene naweuyakhuthazeka.(Kuzwakale abantu abahhomuzelayo phandle.)Mbandlwa, sebekhona abantu lapha ngaphandle. Awubatshelebangene.(Asukume aqonde emnyango.) Bakwethu! Bakwethu, ngenani bo!Ikhansela selimi ngomumo.(Abuyele etafuleni. Nabantu bangene kodwa bayidlanzana nje.)(Asukume.) Ngiyanibingelela bakwethu! (Bavume abantu.) Sekuyisoisikhathi lesi sokuqala umhlangano oyingqophamlando. BesicelauMbandlwa asivulele ngomthandazo.(Asukume nabantu basukume.) Masivaleni amehlo. Baba oseZulwini,siyabonga ngokusivikela silele ebusuku. Uphinde usinike amandlanomdlandla wokusukumela izinto ezizosithuthukisa. Manje-ke Babawethu sisize ngomoya wakho oyiNgcwele ukuze sikwazi ukubonisanangomoya omuhle. Baba hlehlisa amadimoni angasihlasela. Konkelokhu sikucela ngegama lenkosi uJesu Kristu, Amen.1. Inkulumo-mpendulwano isebenze kahle kulesi siqeshana. Sekela impenduloyakho ngamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Inkulumo kaMbandlwa iyona emvezayo ukuthi ungumuntu onjaninjengoba kuyiyo eyasiza ukumisa uDuma isibindi. Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza nokusivezela isizinda njengoba sibonalapha ukuthi umhlangano wawuzoba sekilasini elalingelikhulu. Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza nokusivezela ukuthi abantu bakusiphiisimo njengoba kuvela ukuthi abantu abeze emhlanganwenibayamhlonipha uDuma.  Inkulumo mpendulwano iyasiza nokuveza udweshu olwalukhonaendabeni. Iyasiza nokuveza izigameko ezazisazokwenzeka njengokuthi lomhlangano wawuzoba yingqophamlando.(Nokunye okunembayo okungashiwo ngumfundi.)"},{"question":"రేఖీయ బహుపది ax + b యొక్క శూన్య విలువ ఎంత?","answer":"ax + b = 0 ⇒ ax = -b ⇒ x = −b/a∴ ax + b యొక్క శూన్య విలువ −b/a"},{"question":"Waa maxay Non-Energy giving food wax aka mid ah kuwaan hoos ku xusan?","answer":"Waa b)Vitamins  t) Minerals x) Water"},{"question":"Akin gbe ọrẹbinrin rẹ lọ sile Kabiru, lẹyin to fipa ba a lo pọ tan ni wọn ge e si wẹwẹ l’Apomu","answer":"Ọwọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti tẹ Kabiru Ayedun, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlogoji, lori ẹsun pe o lẹdi apo pọ mọ ọrẹ rẹ lati pa ọmọdebinrin kan, ti wọn si kun ẹya-ara rẹ wẹlẹwẹlẹ.A gbọ pe Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹfa, ni aṣiri Kabiru, ọmọbibi agboole Mọniun, niluu Ikoyi, tu, ti awọn ọlọpaa si ti n dọdẹ ọrẹ rẹ, Akin, ti wọn jọ ṣiṣẹ ibi naa bayii.Nigba to n ba ALAROYE sọrọ, Kabiru ṣalaye pe ilu Apomu loun n gbe, iṣẹ birikila loun si n ṣe, o ni toun ba ti de latibi iṣẹ loun tun maa n lọ sidii iṣẹ ọdẹ adugbo toun n ṣe lalaalẹ nitori ọmọ ẹgbẹ OPC loun.O ni, “O pẹ diẹ ti mo ti mọ Akin, ẹni ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Clumsy tabi Alupayida, ṣugbọn n ko mọ ile to n gbe ni Ikoyi. Iṣẹ Ifa lo n ṣe, o si sọ fun mi laipẹ yii pe oun fẹẹ fi ọrẹbinrin oun kan ṣe oogun owo, o ni ti mo ba le fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu oun, oun yoo fun mi ni ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta naira.“Loju ẹsẹ naa ni mo sọ fun un pe n ko ṣe, n ko si le fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu rẹ nitori mo niṣẹ mi lọwọ. Nigba to di  ọjọ Tọsidee, o gbe ọmọbinrin yii wa sọdọ mi, n ko morukọ ọmọ yẹn, n ko si mọ ibi to ti wa.“Nigba to gbe e de, mo jade fun wọn ninu yara, lẹyin to ba a sun tan, o fọwọ fun un lọrun, o si fọwọ bo o lẹnu, emi naa wọle, mo ba a di i lẹsẹ mu titi ti ẹmi fi bọ lara rẹ.“Nigba to ku tan ni Akin mu ọbẹ nla kan, to bẹrẹ si i ṣa a, o ge ori rẹ, o ge atẹlẹwọ, itan, ẹsẹ ati ọyan rẹ. O tu ifun rẹ, o si ko gbogbo rẹ sinu ike nla kan.“Awọn ti wọn n gbe layiika ile mi, ti wọn n gbọ bi Akin ṣe n ṣa ọmọ naa ni wọn lọọ sọ fawọn ọga mi, iyẹn awọn OPC. Akin ti lọ ko too di pe wọn de, bi mo ṣe ri wọn ni mo sọ pe mo ti mọ nnkan ti wọn mu mi fun.“Mo tẹle wọn, mo si sọ bi wọn ṣe le ri Akin mu, ṣugbọn wọn ko tẹle imọran mi, iyẹn lo jẹ ki Akin sa lọ ki wọn too de ibi to wa”Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde, ṣalaye pe laipẹ lọwọ yoo tẹ Akin, ati pe Kabiru yoo foju bale-ẹjọ ni kete tiwadii ba ti pari.O waa ke si awọn obi lati mojuto awọn ọmọbinrin wọn, ki wọn mọ irin wọn, bẹẹ ni ki awọn ọdaran yẹra funpinlẹ Ọṣun nitori aṣiri wọn ko ni i bo rara."},{"question":"සුදු ළුුනු පොඩි කරනවා  වගේ,පාලු ගෙයි වළං බිදින්නා  සේ.මේවගේ අදහස කුමද්ද ?","answer":"සුුවඳ නොදැනී සුදු ලූණු පොඩි කිරීමට බැරි ය. රහස හෙළි වේ.පාළු ගෙයි වළං බිඳීම: නිෂ්ඵල වැඩක් ."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mihozongozona\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mihozongozona\\" dia\\"Mihovotrovotra\\"."},{"question":"昔話「ネズミの嫁入り」で雲が俺より強いと言ったのは風。では風が俺よりも強いと言ったものは何？","answer":"かべです。"},{"question":"கவுந்தியடிகள் எந்த மதத்தைச் சார்ந்த துறவி?(1) சமணத் துறவி                                               (2) பௌத்தத்துறவி(3) இஸ்லாமியத் துறவி                                       (4) சைவ துறவி","answer":" கவுந்தி அடிகள் சிலப்பதிகாரக் கதை மாந்தர்களுள் ஒருவர். இவர் ஒரு சமணபெண் துறவி ஆவார்.கோவலனையும் கண்ணகியையும் மதுரைக்கு கூட்டி வருவது கவுந்தி அடிகளேயாகும். வரும் வழியில் சிலர் கண்ணகியையும் கோவலனையும் பார்த்து வினவ கவுந்தி அடிகளோ \\"இவர்கள் எம் மக்கள்\\" என்கிறார். கேட்டவர்களோ \\"உம் மக்கள் ஒருவரையொருவர் மணமுடிப்பரோ\\" என்று கேலி பேச அவர்களை நரிகளாகுமாறு சாவிக்கிறார். இது இவரது தவவலிமைக்கு தக்க சான்றாகும். பின்னர் மாதரி என்னும் விருந்தோம்பலில் சிறந்த பெண் வீட்டில் கண்ணகியை தங்கவும் வைக்கிறார்."},{"question":"පහත ගීතයේ පද රචනය කාගේද?නොතැවෙන් සූරියකාන්තානොහඬන් සූරියකාන්තානොතැවෙන් සූරියකාන්තානොහඬන් සූරියකාන්තාසූරිය නාමෙන් නම ලදිමීසූරිය වත මෙන් රුව ලදිමීසූරිය පැහැයෙන් සළු ලදිමීසූරිය කුමරුනි ඔබ පතමීපිනි මල් ගඟුලේ මුව දෝවන්නේමිහි මත රන් සළු පිළි පළඳන්නේසූරිය මල් කිම තවම තැවෙන්නේහිනැහෙන්නයි මා දවස ගෙනෙන්නේනෙලුම් විලේ නැත ඔබෙ ලන්දූසුවඳ කුලේ නැත ඔබෙ ලන්දූකොපමණ තැවුනත් මල් ලන්දූමා නොවෙදෝ ඔබ දිණු ලන්දූඅහස පොළොව කෙදිනද හමුවන්නේමලකට හිමිකම් කෙලෙස පුදන්නේලොව මෙහෙවර මගෙ උරුමය වන්නේමා එන පෙරමඟ බලා සිටින්නේනෙලුම් විලේ නැත ඔබෙ ලන්දූසුවඳ කුලේ නැත ඔබෙ ලන්දූකොපමණ තැවුනත් මල් ලන්දූමා නොවෙදෝ ඔබ දිණු ලන්දූ","answer":"පද රචනය - දයා ද අල්විස්"},{"question":"Iza no filoham-panjakana eto Madagasikara?1-    Ny praiminisitra2-   FILOHA3-   Ny lehiben’ny Fitsarana Tampony","answer":"Valiny: Safidy 2 - Filoham-pirenena eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"Apakah maksud Gulai sedap nasi mentah, nasi sedap gulai mentah?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah Tindakan yang tidak sempurna"},{"question":"シナモン、クローブ、ナツメグの三つの香りを合わせた風味を持つとされる事から名のついた香辛料は何でしょう？","answer":"オールスパイス"},{"question":"Kàñ la ñu màralewoon Gàmbi ak Senegaal ?","answer":"1982 ba 1989"},{"question":" त्वचेला काळा रंग कोणत्या पदार्थामुळे प्राप्त होतो?A. मेलानिन B. जीवनसत्वC. लोहD. यांपैकी काहीही नाही","answer":"A. मेलानिन "},{"question":"Iza no nanjanaka an’i Madagasikara ?","answer":"Ny frantsay no nanjanaka an’i Madagasikara tamin'ny 1897 hatramin'ny 1946."},{"question":"Wat staat er aan het eind van de regenboog? ","answer":"Soms is het een pot met goud, in dit geval is het de letter 'g'."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay tononkalo sinoa malaza, heverina ho iray amin'ireo zava-bita lehibe indrindra amin'ny tononkalo sinoa?","answer":"Ny \\"Bokin'i Odes\\" no tononkalo sinoa malaza, heverina ho iray amin'ireo zava-bita lehibe indrindra amin'ny tononkalo sinoa."},{"question":"صياغة إجابة على هذا السؤال المفصل: من أي بلد توني كروس؟","answer":"توني كروس هو لاعب ألماني شهير لعب في ألمانيا مع بايرن ميونخ و في أسبانيا مع ريال مدريد."},{"question":"س214 - متى اغتيل المهاتما غاندي ؟","answer":"ج214 - 1948"},{"question":"Àt mi ñaata jàmono yi?","answer":"Àt mi 4 jàmono la:- Nawet: ñatt i weer la. Taw bu bàri, ay dënnu, ñàx mu sax, naataange, nëtax.- Lolli: ñatt i weer la. Su mbay ñoree ba manees koo jariñoo lolli dugg na; sedd bi ñaare di dugg, di sedd bur faral a tàr, ñu naa ko seddub nguutuut.- Noor: ñatt i weer la. Noor nag da'y faral a ànd ak ngelaw lu bàri, lu'y riddi aka upp, pënd bi ne kur, ñu naa ko pàllare, tàng jérr ìt, cat la mooy noor kundung.- Cooroon: ñatt i weer la. Jàmono ju tàng la'y doon te du àm ngelaw, foo toll di ñaq, ñenn ñi di bul (ñaq wu'y siit ci'y yoxo mbaa ay tànk), nga'y gìs njundux yi ci digg-bëccag gi."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Sedan 2010 är Jeglertz tränare för Finlands damfotbollslandslag. Hans första mål var att ta laget till VM 2011, men laget blev utslaget i kvalet. Han lyckades däremot lotsa laget till EM 2013 i Sverige, där de blev utslagna i gruppspelet. Laget kvalificerade sig inte till","answer":"VM 2015. Jeglertz har kontrakt med finska damlandslaget till 2016."},{"question":"Kíni 640 ní èdè Yorùbá? ","answer":"Ọ̀jìlélẹ́gbẹ̀ta"},{"question":"Gwam ọgba aka arị ọjị","answer":"Ahụhụ "},{"question":"Fantatrao ve i Albert Zafy ?","answer":"Albert Zafy  dia Dokotera mizaka ny zom-pirenena Malagasy teraka ny 1 Mey 1927 tao Ambilobe ary maty ny 13 Oktobra 2017 tao Saint-Pierre. Lehiben’ny mpanohitra tamin’ny faran’ny Repoblika faharoa, izy no filohan’ny Repoblikan’i Madagasikara nanomboka ny taona 1993 ka hatramin’ny 1996."},{"question":"வினா: கேண்டி திரவம் என்பது எது ?1.பாலியெஸ்டர்2.நைலான்3.ரேயான்4.பொட்டாசியம் பெர்மாங்கனேட்","answer":"விடை: 4.பொட்டாசியம் பெர்மாங்கனேட்"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Hans racingkarriär tog slut när han skulle tävla i Indianapolis 500","answer":"1992, men han skadade fötterna svårt i en träningskrasch."},{"question":"Дарыя алабы деген эмне ?","answer":"Дарыя алабы-бир дарыя тармагын камтыган, башка дарыя тармактарынан суу бөлгүчтөр менен бөлүнүп турган жер бетинин бир бөлүгү."},{"question":"ब्लॅक होल म्हणजे काय?","answer":"ब्लॅक होल हा अंतराळातील एक असा प्रदेश आहे जिथे गुरुत्वाकर्षण इतकं मजबूत आहे की त्यातून काहीही, अगदी प्रकाश देखील बाहेर पडू शकत नाही. जेव्हा एखादा मोठा तारा त्याच्या जीवनचक्राच्या शेवटी गुरुत्वाकर्षणाने कोसळतो तेव्हा तो तयार होतो. ताऱ्याचा गाभा त्याच्या स्वतःच्या गुरुत्वाकर्षणाच्या खाली कोसळतो आणि त्याचे अणुइंधन संपते आणि गुरुत्वाकर्षणाच्या आतील खेचण्याच्या विरूद्ध त्याच्या बाह्य स्तरांना समर्थन देऊ शकत नाही.गाभ्याचे सर्व वस्तुमान एक आश्चर्यकारकपणे दाट आणि संक्षिप्त बिंदूमध्ये केंद्रित होईपर्यंत संकुचित होत राहते, ज्याला एकलता म्हणतात. ही एकलता घटना क्षितिजाने वेढलेली आहे, जी एक सीमा आहे ज्याच्या पलीकडे जाणारी कोणतीही गोष्ट एकलतेच्या गुरुत्वाकर्षणाच्या खेचातून सुटू शकत नाही. कार्यक्रमाच्या क्षितिजाला कधीकधी \\"पॉइंट ऑफ नो रिटर्न\\" म्हणून संबोधले जाते."},{"question":"Ẹ fura o, awọn ayederu ayanilowo ti pọ l’Ekiti, eyi lọgbọn ti wọn n da","answer":"Ki awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ekiti ma baa ko sọwọ awọn onijibiti ti wọn n fi eto ẹyawo parọ fun araalu, ijọba ti ni ki awọn eeyan ṣọra lati ma ṣe ko sọwọ gbaju-ẹ.Lọjọ, Aje, Mọnde, ni wọn gbe ikede yii sita fun awọn araalu lati ṣọra pẹlu awọn ileeṣẹ kan ti wọn n parọ faraalu pe awọn le ya wọn lowo, nitori jibiti ni pupọ ninu wọn n fi eto ọhun lu, ti wọn ko si ni iwe aṣẹ ijọba.Kọmiṣanna feto iroyin, Ọgbẹni Akin Ọmọle, lo sọrọ yii niluu Ado-Ekiti, nibi to ti sọ pe owo tawọn ọlẹdarun yii ko ni lọwọ ni wọn n parọ pe awọn fẹẹ ya araalu, bẹẹ ọgbọn lati lu wọn ni jibiti ni.Lati le fidi ọrọ ẹ mulẹ lo mu un ṣapejuwe fidio awọn obinrin kan to n lọ kaakiri ẹrọ ayelujara bayii ti awọn eeyan kan ti lu ni jibiti.O ni iṣẹlẹ ọhun jẹ nnkan to ba ni lọkan jẹ, bẹẹ ni inu ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti paapaa ko dun si i rara. Kọmiṣanna ni kiru iṣẹlẹ bẹẹ ma baa waye lo mu ijọba gbe eto ẹyawo kalẹ fawọn eeyan nipinlẹ Ekiti, eyi ti yoo fun awọn oniṣowo keekeeke atawọn oniṣẹ ọwọ lanfaani lati ri owo gba, ti wọn yoo si maa san an pada lọna ti ko ni i ni wọn lara.Ọmọle waa rọ awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ekiti ti wọn ba fẹẹ yawo lati tọ ileeṣẹ ijọba to n mojuto okoowo ati ọrọ aje lọ lati ṣewadii iru eto ẹyawo ti wọn ba fẹ. Bakan naa lo ni ki wọn yago fawọn ileeṣẹ to le fi eto ẹyawo awuruju lu wọn ni jibiti owo wọn."},{"question":"Ngozi Ezeonu","answer":"Ngozi Ezeonu tí orúkọ àbísọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Ngozi Ikpelue ni wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ kẹtàlélógún oṣù karùn-ún ọdún 1965 (May 23rd 1965) jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ òṣèrébìnrin sinimá àgbéléwò àti akọ́ṣẹ́mọṣẹ́ òníròyìn tẹ́lẹ̀ ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ òṣèrébìnrin ìlúmọ̀ọ́kà nípa ṣíṣe ẹ̀dá-ìtàn Ìyá nínú sinimá àgbéléwò lédè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì àti Ìgbò. Lọ́dún 2012, ó kópa nínú sinimá àgbéléwò kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Adesuwa, èyí ló mú un gba àmìn ẹ̀yẹ Akádẹ́mì nínú sinimá gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèrébìnrin tó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ igbàmìẹ̀ẹ ẹlẹ́ẹ̀kẹjọ 8th Africa Movie Academy Awards.Wọ́n bí ní Ngozi Ezeonu ní ìlú Owerri. Kí ó tó di gbajúmọ̀ òṣèré ìlúmọ̀ọ́kà, ó kàwé gbàwé ẹ̀rí nínú ìmọ̀ iṣẹ́ ìròyìn ní Nigerian Institute of Journalism, ó sìn ṣiṣẹ́ ní Radio Lagos àti Eko FM.Bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé ó gbajúmọ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí kíkópa ẹ̀dá-ìtàn ìyá, ó ti kọ́kọ́ kópa gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀dá-ìtàn ọlọ́mọgé ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ tíátà rẹ̀ ṣíṣe. Lọ́dún 1993, ni gbajúgbajà olùdarí sinimá-àgbéléwò nì, Zeb Ejiro fún ní ipa amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ ẹ̀dá-ìtàn, tí ó pè ní Nkechi nínú sinimá àgbéléwò kan lédè Ìgbò, tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Nneka The Pretty Serpent. Lẹ́yìn èyí, ó kópa nínú sinimá àgbéléwò mìíràn tí wọ́n pe àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ní Glamour Girls lọ́dún 1994, ó kópa gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀dá-ìtàn kan."},{"question":"ကမ္ဘာမှာ နံပါတ်တစ် လူကြိုက်အများဆုံယ အစားအစာက ဘာလဲ။","answer":"ပီဇာသည် ကမ္ဘာပေါ်တွင် လူကြိုက်အများဆုံး အစားအစာဖြစ်သည်။ ယနေ့ကမ္ဘာ၏နေရာ တိုင်းနီးပါးတွင် ပီဇာကို သင်ရှာတွေ့နိုင်သည်။ ဤအီတလီရိုးရာဟင်းလျာကို ဒိန်ခဲ၊ ခရမ်းချဉ်သီးများနှင့် ရောထားပြီး အပြားလိုက်အ၀ိုင်းပုံစံ ပြုလုပ်ထားပြီး ပင်စိမ်း၊ သံလွင်နှင့် အော်ရီဂနိုတို့ဖြင့် အလှဆင်ထားသည်။"},{"question":"问题：护手霜的保质期是多久？","answer":"回答：护手霜的保质期通常为1年至2年，具体以产品标签上的说明为准。"},{"question":"సంస్థాపన పత్రం అంటే ఏమిటి ? అందులోని క్లాజులను పేర్కొనండి. ","answer":"భారత కంపెనీల చట్టము క్రింద నమోదైన అన్ని కంపెనీలకు ఆవశ్యకమైన పత్రము సంస్థాపన పత్రము. సంస్థాపనా పత్రమనే పునాది మీదనే కంపెనీ అనే భవనము నిర్మాణము అవుతుంది. ఈ పత్రము కంపెనీ అధికార ఎల్లలను, కంపెనీ వ్యవహారాలకు హద్దులను ఏర్పాటు చేస్తుంది. కంపెనీ ధ్యేయాలను, అధికారాలను, కార్యకలాపాలను వాటాదారులు, ఋణదాతలు, కంపెనీతో ప్రత్యక్షముగా సంబంధమున్న ప్రతివారికి ఖచ్చితముగా తెలియపరచడమే ఈ పత్రము ముఖ్య ఉద్దేశ్యము. కనుక దీనిని కంపెనీ రాజ్యాంగము అంటారు.ఈ పత్రము కంపెనీకి, బయటవారికి గల సంబంధాలను నిర్వచిస్తుంది. ఈ పత్రములో పొందుపరిచిన వ్యవహారాలు, నిర్వచించిన అధికారాలను, నిర్ణయించిన సంబంధాలను అతిక్రమించి ఏ కంపెనీ నడుచుకోవడానికి వీలులేదు. అలా నడుచుకుంటే ఆ వ్యవహారాలు, అధికారాలు, సంబంధాలు న్యాయవిరుద్ధము అవుతాయి. అవి చెల్లుబాటు కావు:దీనిని పేరాలుగా విభజించి, వరుసగా సంఖ్యలు వేసి ముద్రించవలెను. పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ అయితే ఏడుగురు, ప్రైవేటు కంపెనీ అయితే ఇద్దరు సాక్షి సమక్షములో ఈ పత్రాల మీద సంతకాలు చేయవలెను. సంతకము చేసిన ప్రతి వ్యక్తి కనీసం ఒక వాటానైనా తీసుకొనవలెను.సంస్థాపనా పత్రములోని క్లాజులు.1) నామధేయపు క్లాజు : ఈ క్లాజులో కంపెనీ పూర్తి పేరు వ్రాయవలెను. పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ అయితే పేరు చివర ‘లిమిటెడ్’, ప్రైవేటు కంపెనీ అయితే పేరు చివర ‘ప్రైవేటు లిమిటెడ్’ అనే పదములు ఉండాలి. కంపెనీ ఏ పేరునైనా పెట్టుకోవచ్చుగాని అంతకముందు స్థాపితమైన మరొక కంపెనీ పేరును పోలిగాని, సమీపములోగాని ఉండరాదు. అంతేగాక అవాంఛనీయమైన పేర్లు, చట్టముచే బహిష్కరింపబడిన పేర్లు కంపెనీకి పెట్టరాదు.2) కంపెనీ స్థానపు క్లాజు : కంపెనీ రిజిష్టర్డ్ ఆఫీసు ఏ రాష్ట్రములో ఉన్నదో ఆ రాష్ట్రము పేరు ఈ క్లాజులో తెలిపాలి. కంపెనీతో ఉత్తర ప్రత్యుత్తరాలు జరపడానికి కార్యాలయ చిరునామా అవసరము. కంపెనీ నమోదు సమయములో గాని, నమోదు అయిన 30 రోజులలోపు కార్యాలయపు చిరునామాను రిజిస్ట్రారుకు3) ధ్యేయాల క్లాజు : ఇది అతి ప్రధానమైన క్లాజు. ఇందులో కంపెనీ ధ్యేయాలు, అధికారాలు, వ్యాపార వ్యవహారాల పరిధి స్పష్టముగా పేర్కొనబడి ఉంటాయి. న్యాయపూరితమైన ఎన్ని ధ్యేయాలనైనా ఇందులో చేర్చవచ్చును. వాటినన్నింటిని కంపెనీ చేపట్టనవసరం లేదు. ఈ క్లాజులో చేర్చని కార్యకలాపాలను, ధ్యేయాలను అతిక్రమించి ఏ పని చేయరాదు. అలా చేస్తే అవి న్యాయవిరుద్ధము అవుతాయి.4) ఋణబాధ్యత క్లాజు : కంపెనీ వాటాదారుల యొక్క స్వభావాన్ని ఈ క్లాజులో వ్రాయవలెను. వాటాదారుల ఋణబాధ్యత వారు తీసుకున్న వాటాల విలువ మేరకు పరిమితమని తెలియజేస్తుంది. ఒకవేళ వాటాలో కొంత మొత్తము చెల్లిస్తే, వారి ఋణబాధ్యత ఆ చెల్లించని మొత్తానికే పరిమితము అవుతుంది.5) మూలధనపు క్లాజు : ఎంత మూలధనాన్ని జారీ చేయడానికి అనుమతి కావలెనో ఈ క్లాజులో తెలియజేస్తారు. దీనిని అధీకృత మూలధనము, నమోదు మూలధనము అంటారు. ఈ మూలధనాన్ని ఎన్ని వాటాలుగా విభజించినారు, వాటా విలువ ఎంతో తెలియపరచవలెను.6) వ్యవస్థాపన – చందాల క్లాజు : తాము కంపెనీని స్థాపించడానికి ఒక సంస్థగా ఏర్పడినట్లు, తమ పేర్లకు ఎదురుగా ఉన్న వాటాలను తీసుకోవడానికి ఒప్పుకున్నట్లు ఒక ప్రకటన ద్వారా ఈ క్లాజులో తెలియజేయాలి. వారందరూ సాక్షి సమక్షములో సంతకాలు చేయాలి."},{"question":"મને ગુજરાતી પ્રસિદ્ધ  વાનગીઑ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ખીચડી - કે જે ચોખા અને મગની દાળનાં મિશ્રણ નું પકવાન છે, તેને થોડા મસાલા અને ધી સાથે પ્રેશર-કુકરમાં રાંધવામાં આવે છે, જે ગુજરાતી થાળીની પ્રસિધ્ધ વાનગી છે અને સામાન્ય રીતે દરેક ગુજરાતી ઘરોમાં બને છે. ખીચડી દાળ, કઢી, દહી, અથાણું, વિવિધ શાક, પાપડ અને દાણાંદાર દેશી ઘી, વગેરે સાથે ખાઈ શકાય છે. તે ઉપરાંત કાઠીયાવાડની જાડી કઢી અને મોળા દાળભાત પણ ઘણા પ્રખ્યાત છે. કેટલીક વાનગીઓતો ગુજરાતની ખાસીયત છે, જેમંકે વાટી દાળના ખમણ, પાટુડી, ખીચું, ઘારી, લોચો, ઉંધીયું, ઉંબાળીયું, વગેરે. આસો માસની પુનમે દુધ-પૌઆ ખાંડ ઉમેરીને ખાય તો ફાગણની પૂનમે ખજૂર-ધાણી-ચણા ખાય. જમ્યા પછી ગુજરાતીઓ મુખવાસ અથવા પાન ખાય છે. આ ઉપરાંત લાપસી: કે જે ઘઉં ના ફાડાં ની ગોળ અને ઘી મિશ્રિત એકદમ સરળ અને ખુબજ સ્વાદિષ્ટ વાનગી પણ એટલી જ મહત્વની છે. કાઠિયાવાડ માં ઘરે કોઈ મહત્ત્વ ની વ્યક્તિ આવે કે કોઈ શુભ પ્રસંગે \\"લાપસી ના આંધણ\\" મુકવાનું પણ કહેવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"شحال درجة غليان الماء بالفهرنهايت ؟","answer":"212 درجة"},{"question":"அசை போடும் விலங்குகளின் இரைப்பையில் எத்தனை பகுதிகள் உள்ளன?","answer":"அசை போடும் விலங்குகளின் (ரூமினன்ட்) வயிற்றில் நான்கு பெட்டிகள் உள்ளன: ருமென், ரெட்டிகுலம், ஓமாசம் மற்றும் அபோமாசம்."},{"question":"Bir karınca kaç kilogram?","answer":"Dünya çapında 13 binden fazla türü bulunan karıncaların uzunluğu 1 ila 30 mm arasında değişiyor. Ağırlıklarında da farklılıklar olsa da çoğu uzman karıncaların ortalama ağırlığının 10 mg'den az olduğunu düşünüyor."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ti ranṣẹ pe ẹni to ni otẹẹli ti wọn ti fi kamẹra si yara awọn alejo l’Ayepe","answer":"Kọmandi ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun ti ranṣẹ pe ẹni to ni Otẹẹli Pavilion, eyi to wa ni Ayepe, nijọba ibilẹ Odogbolu, nipinlẹ Ogun, nitori kamẹra ti wọn fi si yara awọn alejo lai jẹ pe awọn to n sanwo lo yara naa mọ rara.Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ṣalaye pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe Eko lẹni  to ni otẹẹli yii n gbe, o lawọn ti ranṣẹ pe e lati waa ṣalaye idi ẹ to fi faaye gba kamẹra ti yoo maa ka gbogbo ohun tawọn alejo ba ṣe ni yara ti wọn sanwo fun silẹ, nitori eyi lodi labẹ ofin.Ṣe lopin ọsẹ to kọja yii ni fidio kan gun ori ayelujara, nibi ti ọkunrin kan ti n fibinu sọrọ, to si n ja awọn kamẹra ti wọn fi sinu awọn yara otẹẹli yii nikọọkan.Ọkunrin naa n sọrọ pẹlu ibinu, o ni awọn ara otẹẹlu yii ti ri ihooho ẹgbọn oun, bẹẹ ni wọn ri ti iya oun pẹlu, nitori awọn eeyan oun naa ti gba yara ninu otẹẹli naa ti wọn sun sibẹ, wọn ko si mọ pe kamẹra wa loke yara ti kaluku wọn n sun, to n ka ihooho wọn silẹ gedegbe.Kamẹra mẹrin lọkunrin naa ti tu kalẹ to si fi han ninu fọnran fidio naa, ẹlẹẹkarun-un lo n tun lọwọ lasiko to n ṣe fidio ọhun, bẹẹ lawọn eeyan wa nibẹ, ti kaluku n sọ pe titẹ ẹtọ onibaara loju mọlẹ ni ohun ti awọn ara otẹẹli Pavilion yii n ṣe, awọn yoo si gbe orukọ wọn saye pẹlu pinpin fidio naa kiri.Ni bayii ṣa, fidio naa ti de ọdọ awọn ọlọpaa, wọn si ni kẹni to ni in waa ṣalaye idi to fi jẹ ki kamẹra wa ni yara alejo, nigba to jẹ ofin ko faaye gba iru ẹ nilẹ wa."},{"question":"I maamu ibnu cuqeyb iyo hanka sare. ","answer":"Imaamu ibu cuqayl wuxuu yiri iima haboona in aan saacad waqtigayga ka mid ah lumiyo, marka carabkaygu noogo oo wax akhrin waayo, indhahayguna daalaan oo wax arkin waayaan, maskaxdaydaan ka shaqaysiinayaa xattaa markaan jiifo ilaa aan soo kaco iyadoo ay iigu diyaarsan tahay maskaxdayda wixii aan qorilahaa, isagoo hadalka siiwata ayaa wuxuu yiri:- maanta ma jiro qof iga cilmi jecel anigoo maraayaa sideetan sano. Ardaygiisii Ibnujawzi oo ka sheekaynayaa wuxuu leeyahay :- wuxuu ahaa mid har iyo habeen ku mashquulsan cilmiga, kutubtiisana waxaa ugu wayn kitaabka loo yaqaan ( Funuun), kitaabkaas faa'iidooyin badan ayaa ku jira sida cilmiga tafsiirka, xadiiska, luuqada carabiga, naxwaha, fiqiga iwm. Imaamu dahabi oo ka sheekaynaaya kitaabka funuun ee uu qoray Imaamu ibnu cuqayl wuxuu yiri :- kitaab la mid ah oo ka wayn adduunka laguma qorin waana 800 Mujalad !!!!. "},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండితగ్గుతున్న నిల్వల పద్దతిని గురించి వ్రాయుము.","answer":"ఈ పద్ధతిలో ప్రతి సంవత్సరము ఆస్తి యొక్క పుస్తక విలువ మీద ఒక స్థిరమైన శాతాన్ని తరుగుదలగా రద్దు చేస్తారు. తరుగుదలను రద్దు చేయడం ద్వారా దాని పుస్తక విలువ తగ్గుతున్నందున ఈ పద్ధతిని ‘తగ్గుతున్న నిల్వల పద్ధతి’ అంటారు. ఈ పద్ధతిలో తరుగుదల శాతము మాత్రము అన్ని సంవత్సరాలకు స్థిరముగా ఉంటుంది. కాని తగ్గుతున్న ఆస్తి పుస్తక విలువ మీద తరుగుదలను లెక్కిస్తున్నందువలన, తరుగుదల మొత్తాలు స్థిరముగా ఉండక తగ్గుతూ ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"Apakah kesan rumah hijau?","answer":"Kesan rumah hijau atau kesan rumah kaca ialah proses negatif yang terlaku menyebabkan sinaran dari atmosfera planet memanaskan permukaan planet tersebut kepada suatu suhu melebihi suhunya tanpa atmosfera. Kesan rumah hijau yang berlaku secara semulajadi di bumi amat penting untuk menyokong kehidupan. Namun, aktiviti manusia terutamanya pembakaran bahan api fosil dan penebangan hutan secara berleluasa telah meningkatkan kesan rumah hijau dan menyebabkan pemanasan global."},{"question":"लिओनार्डो दा विंची कोण होते?","answer":"लिओनार्डो दा विंची (१४५२-१५१९) हे एक उल्लेखनीय इटालियन पुनर्जागरण बहुपयोगी होते ज्यांच्या कलागुणांनी चित्रकला, शरीरशास्त्र, अभियांत्रिकी, गणित, संगीत आणि बरेच काही यासारख्या विविध क्षेत्रांचा विस्तार केला. तो आतापर्यंत जगलेल्या महान आणि विविध कुशल व्यक्तींपैकी एक मानला जातो.दा विंची कलेतील त्यांच्या योगदानासाठी, विशेषतः त्यांच्या उत्कृष्ट चित्रांसाठी सर्वात प्रसिद्ध आहे. त्याच्या काही प्रसिद्ध कामांमध्ये हे समाविष्ट आहे:1. मोना लिसा: गूढ स्मित असलेल्या स्त्रीचे हे प्रतिष्ठित पोर्ट्रेट जगातील सर्वात प्रसिद्ध आणि प्रसिद्ध चित्रांपैकी एक आहे.2. द लास्ट सपर: येशू ख्रिस्ताचे त्याच्या शिष्यांसोबतचे शेवटचे जेवण दर्शवणारे एक स्मारक भित्तिचित्र, जे त्याच्या भावनिक खोलीसाठी आणि दृष्टीकोनाच्या नाविन्यपूर्ण वापरासाठी ओळखले जाते.3. विट्रुव्हियन मॅन: प्राचीन रोमन वास्तुविशारद विट्रुवियसच्या मते मानवी शरीराचे प्रमाण स्पष्ट करणारे रेखाचित्र, लिओनार्डोची शरीरशास्त्र आणि भूमितीमध्ये स्वारस्य दर्शविते.त्याच्या कलात्मक कामगिरीव्यतिरिक्त, लिओनार्डो दा विंचीच्या नोटबुक स्केचेस, निरीक्षणे आणि कल्पनांनी भरलेल्या आहेत ज्यात त्याचे जिज्ञासू मन आणि त्याच्या आवडीची रुंदी प्रतिबिंबित होते. त्याने शरीरशास्त्रीय अभ्यास केला, आविष्कारांची रचना केली आणि अभियांत्रिकी, जलविज्ञान आणि वैमानिकी यांसारख्या क्षेत्रात प्रगती केली. उडणारी यंत्रे, युद्ध यंत्रे आणि विविध उपकरणांची त्यांची रेखाचित्रे त्यांच्या काळाच्या अनेक शतके पुढे होती.लिओनार्डो हे नैसर्गिक जग समजून घेण्याची उत्सुकता आणि समर्पण यासाठी ओळखले जात होते. त्यांनी मानवी शरीराचे तपशीलवार विच्छेदन आणि चित्रण करून शरीरशास्त्र आणि जीवशास्त्र या क्षेत्रात महत्त्वपूर्ण योगदान दिले.एकंदरीत, लिओनार्डो दा विंचीचा वारसा कला आणि विज्ञान यांच्यातील अंतर कमी करण्याच्या क्षमतेमध्ये आहे, पुनर्जागरण युगात मानवी ज्ञान आणि सर्जनशीलतेच्या सीमांना धक्का देत आहे. त्यांचे कार्य आजही जगभरातील लोकांना प्रेरणा आणि मोहित करत आहे."},{"question":"What was the main aim of the French revolutionaries?","answer":"The main aim of the French revolutionaries was to create a sense of collective identity among the French people."}]`),I={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:T},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:O,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},C={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},x=["disabled"],P={key:0},E={key:1};function D(e,a,s,d,t,u){const h=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",C,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),w(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[y,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),o(p,null,c(u.filteredPoems,(r,m)=>(i(),j(h,{key:m,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",E,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",P,"See more"))],8,x)):f("",!0)])}const K=g(I,[["render",D],["__scopeId","data-v-f4b4c72a"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"library/4.md","filePath":"library/4.md"}'),L={name:"library/4.md"},G=Object.assign(L,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(K)]))}});export{F as __pageData,G as default};
